<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 138—</num>
<heading>COOPERATIVE AGREEMENTS WITH NATO ALLIES AND OTHER COUNTRIES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ACQUISITION AND CROSS-SERVICING AGREEMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2341.</num>
<heading> Authority to acquire logistic support, supplies, and services for elements of the armed forces deployed outside the United States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to <ref>section 2343 of this title</ref> and subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquire from the Governments of North Atlantic Treaty Organization countries, from North Atlantic Treaty Organization subsidiary bodies, and from the United Nations Organization or any regional international organization logistic support, supplies, and services for elements of the armed forces deployed outside the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> acquire from any government not a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization logistic support, supplies, and services for elements of the armed forces deployed (or to be deployed) outside the United States if that country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has a defense alliance with the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> permits the stationing of members of the armed forces in such country or the homeporting of naval vessels of the United States in such country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has agreed to preposition materiel of the United States in such country; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> serves as the host country to military exercises which include elements of the armed forces or permits other military operations by the armed forces in such country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–323, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1016</ref>, § 2321; renumbered § 2341 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1304(a)(1)</ref>, (4), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3963</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIII, § 1312(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1317(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2899</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XII, § 1204</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3456</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2342.</num>
<heading> Cross-servicing agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to <ref>section 2343 of this title</ref> and to the availability of appropriations, and after consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense may enter into an agreement described in paragraph (2) with any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The government of a North Atlantic Treaty Organization country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A subsidiary body of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The United Nations Organization or any regional international organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The government of a country not a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization but which is designated by the Secretary of Defense, subject to the limitations prescribed in subsection (b), as a government with which the Secretary may enter into agreements under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An agreement referred to in paragraph (1) is an agreement under which the United States agrees to provide logistic support, supplies, and services to military forces of a country or organization referred to in paragraph (1) in return for the reciprocal provisions of logistic support, supplies, and services by such government or organization to elements of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may not designate a country for an agreement under this section unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of State, determines that the designation of such country for such purpose is in the interest of the national security of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a country that is not a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, the Secretary submits to the appropriate committees of Congress notice of the intended designation not less than 30 days before the date on which such country is designated by the Secretary under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a country that is not a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, the Secretary of Defense may not enter into an agreement under this section unless the Secretary submits to the appropriate committees of Congress a notice of intent to enter into such an agreement not less than 30 days before the date on which the Secretary enters into the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may not use the authority of this subchapter to procure from any foreign government or international organization any goods or services reasonably available from United States commercial sources.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may not use an agreement with any government or an organization described in subsection (a)(1) to facilitate the transfer of logistic support, supplies, and services to any country or organization with which the Secretary has not signed an agreement described in subsection (a)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> An agreement described in subsection (a)(2) may not provide or otherwise constitute a commitment for the introduction of the armed forces into hostilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020, the Secretary of Defense shall designate an existing senior civilian or military official who shall have primary responsibility for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> accounting for logistic support, supplies, and services received or provided under acquisition and cross-servicing agreements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensuring consistent standards and guidance to the armed forces and combatant commands in executing acquisition and cross-servicing agreements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> overseeing and monitoring the implementation of acquisition and cross-servicing agreements in coordination with the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> such other responsibilities as may be prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020, the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to ensure that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contracts entered into under this subchapter are free from self-dealing, bribery, and conflict of interests;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> adequate processes and controls are in place to provide for the accurate accounting of logistic support, supplies, and services received or provided under the authority of this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> personnel responsible for accounting for logistic support, supplies, and services received or provided under such authority are fully trained and aware of such responsibilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Not later than 270 days after the issuance of the regulations under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of the implementation by the Secretary of such regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The review conducted under subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assess the effectiveness of such regulations and the implementation of such regulations to ensure the effective management and oversight of an agreement under subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> include any other matter the Comptroller General considers relevant.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than January 15 each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on acquisition and cross-servicing activities that sets forth, in detail, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A list of agreements that have entered into force or were applied provisionally pursuant to subsection (a)(1) during the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The date on which each agreement listed under paragraph (1) was signed, and, in the case of an agreement with a country that is not a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, the dates on which the Secretary notified Congress—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B) of the designation of such country under subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> pursuant to subsection (b)(2) of the intent of the Secretary to enter into the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The class of supply, total dollar amount, the amount collected, and the outstanding balance of logistic support, supplies, and services provided during the preceding fiscal year under each such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The class of supply, total dollar amount, the amount collected, and the outstanding balance of logistic support, supplies, and services received during the preceding fiscal year under each such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to any transaction for logistic support, supplies, and services that has not been reconciled more than one year after the date on which the transaction occurred, a description of the transaction that includes the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The date on which the transaction occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The country or organization to which logistic support, supplies, and services were provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The value of the transaction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> An explanation of any waiver granted under section 2347(c) during the preceding fiscal year, including an identification of the relevant contingency operation or non-combat operation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> In this section, the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–323, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1016</ref>, § 2322; renumbered § 2342 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1304(a)(1)</ref>, (4), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3963</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XII, § 1231(9)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1160</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 931(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1451(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1692</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1317(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XII, § 1204</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3456</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1271</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2065</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XII, § 1203</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1620</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2343.</num>
<heading> Waiver of applicability of certain laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sections 4651, 3201, 3351, 3352(a), 3352(c), 3701 through 3708, and 3841 of this title and <ref>section 6306 of title 41</ref> shall not apply to acquisitions made under the authority of <ref>section 2341 of this title</ref> or to agreements entered into under <ref>section 2342 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–323, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1017</ref>, § 2323; renumbered § 2343 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title IX, § 961(b)</ref>, title XIII, § 1304(a)(1), (5), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 703</ref>, 741; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1233(d)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2057</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 931(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1473</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1317(c)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(20)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3844</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1817(h), 1831(j)(3), 1862(c)(1), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4188</ref>, 4216, 4278, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(10)(I)(i)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2134</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2344.</num>
<heading> Methods of payment for acquisitions and transfers by the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Logistics support, supplies, and services may be acquired or transferred by the United States under the authority of this subchapter on a reimbursement basis or by replacement-in-kind or exchange of supplies or services of an equal value.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In entering into agreements with the Government of another North Atlantic Treaty Organization country or other foreign country for the acquisition or transfer of logistic support, supplies, and services on a reimbursement basis, the Secretary of Defense shall negotiate for adoption of the following pricing principles for reciprocal application:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The price charged by a supplying country for logistics support, supplies, and services specifically procured by the supplying country from its contractors for a recipient country shall be no less favorable than the price for identical items or services charged by such contractors to the armed forces of the supplying country, taking into account price differentials due to delivery schedules, points of delivery, and other similar considerations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The price charged a recipient country for supplies furnished by a supplying country from its inventory, and the price charged a recipient country for logistics support and services furnished by the officers, employees, or governmental agencies of a supplying country, shall be the same as the price charged for identical supplies, support, or services acquired by an armed force of the supplying country from such governmental sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent that the Secretary of Defense is unable to obtain mutual acceptance by the other country involved of the reciprocal pricing principles for reimbursable transactions set forth in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the United States may not acquire from such country any logistic support, supply, or service not governed by such reciprocal pricing principles unless the United States forces commander acquiring such support, supply, or service determines (after price analysis) that the price thereof is fair and reasonable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transfers by the United States to such country under this subchapter of any logistic support, supply, or service that is not governed by such reciprocal pricing principles shall be subject to the pricing provisions of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To the extent that indirect costs (including charges for plant and production equipment), administrative surcharges, and contract administration costs with respect to any North Atlantic Treaty Organization country or other foreign country are not waived by operation of the reciprocal pricing principles of paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense may, on a reciprocal basis, agree to waive such costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The pricing principles set forth in paragraph (2) and the waiver authority provided in paragraph (3) shall also apply to agreements with North Atlantic Treaty Organization subsidiary bodies and the United Nations Organization or any regional international organization under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> In acquiring or transferring logistics support, supplies, or services under the authority of this subchapter by exchange of supplies or services, the Secretary of Defense may not agree to or carry out the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Transfers in exchange for property the acquisition of which by the Department of Defense is prohibited by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Transfers of source, byproduct, or special nuclear materials or any other material, article, data, or thing of value the transfer of which is subject to the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Transfers of chemical munitions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–323, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1017</ref>, § 2324; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 11(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 138</ref>; renumbered § 2344, <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1304(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XI, § 1104(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3964</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX</ref>, §§ 931(e)(1), 938(a), (b), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1539; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1317(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XII, § 1204</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3456</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2345.</num>
<heading> Liquidation of accrued credits and liabilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Credits and liabilities of the United States accrued as a result of acquisitions and transfers of logistic support, supplies, and services under the authority of this subchapter shall be liquidated not less often than once every 12 months by direct payment to the entity supplying such support, supplies, or services by the entity receiving such support, supplies, or services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Payment-in-kind or exchange entitlements accrued as a result of acquisitions and transfers of logistic support, supplies, and services under authority of this subchapter shall be satisfied within 12 months after the date of the delivery of the logistic support, supplies, or services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any credits of the United States accrued as a result of the provision of logistic support, supplies, and services under the authority of this subchapter that remain unliquidated more than 18 months after the date of delivery of the logistic support, supplies, or services may, at the option of the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, be liquidated by offsetting the credits against any amount owed by the Department of Defense, pursuant to a transaction or transactions concluded under the authority of this subchapter, to the government or international organization to which the logistic support, supplies, or services were provided by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The amount of any credits offset pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be credited as specified in <ref>section 2346 of this title</ref> as if it were a receipt of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–323, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1018</ref>, § 2325; renumbered § 2345, <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1304(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 741</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XI, § 1104(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3965</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 931(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1317(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1083(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2420</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2346.</num>
<heading> Crediting of receipts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any receipt of the United States as a result of an agreement entered into under this subchapter shall be credited, at the option of the Secretary of Defense, to (1) the appropriation, fund, or account used in incurring the obligation, or (2) an appropriate appropriation, fund, or account currently available for the purposes for which the expenditures were made.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–323, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1018</ref>, § 2326; renumbered § 2346, <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1304(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 741</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 931(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1317(f)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2347.</num>
<heading> Limitation on amounts that may be obligated or accrued by the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except during a period of active hostilities involving the armed forces, the total amount of reimbursable liabilities that the United States may accrue under this subchapter (before the computation of offsetting balances) with other member countries of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, subsidiary bodies of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, or from the United Nations Organization or any regional international organization of which the United States is a member may not exceed $200,000,000 in any fiscal year, and of such amount not more than $50,000,000 in liabilities may be accrued for the acquisition of supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except during a period of active hostilities involving the armed forces, the total amount of reimbursable liabilities that the United States may accrue under this subchapter (before the computation of offsetting balances) with a country which is not a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, but with which the United States has one or more acquisition or cross-servicing agreements, may not exceed $60,000,000 in any fiscal year, and of such amount not more than $20,000,000 in liabilities may be accrued for the acquisition of supplies. The $60,000,000 limitation specified in this paragraph is in addition to the limitation specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except during a period of active hostilities involving the armed forces, the total amount of reimbursable credits that the United States may accrue under this subchapter (before the computation of offsetting balances) with other member countries of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, subsidiary bodies of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, or from the United Nations Organization or any regional international organization of which the United States is a member may not exceed $150,000,000 in any fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except during a period of active hostilities involving the armed forces, the total amount of reimbursable credits that the United States may accrue under this subchapter (before the computation of offsetting balances) with a country which is not a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, but with which the United States has one or more acquisition or cross-servicing agreements may not exceed $75,000,000 in any fiscal year. Such limitation specified in this paragraph is in addition to the limitation specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> When the armed forces are involved in a contingency operation or in a non-combat operation (including an operation in support of the provision of humanitarian or foreign disaster assistance or in support of peacekeeping operations under chapter VI or VII of the Charter of the United Nations), the restrictions in subsections (a) and (b) are waived for the purposes and duration of that operation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The amount of any sale, purchase, or exchange of petroleum, oils, or lubricants by the United States under this subchapter in any fiscal year shall be excluded in any computation for the purposes of subsection (a) or (b) of the amount of reimbursable liabilities or reimbursable credits that the United States accrues under this subchapter in that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–323, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1018</ref>, § 2327; renumbered § 2347, <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1304(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 741</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XI, § 1104(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3965</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title X, § 1001</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2037</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 931(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIII, § 1312(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 202(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 101</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1317(g)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title XII, § 1221(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2348.</num>
<heading> Inventories of supplies not to be increased</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Inventories of supplies for elements of the armed forces may not be increased for the purpose of transferring supplies under the authority of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–323, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1018</ref>, § 2328; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 11(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 138</ref>; renumbered § 2348, <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1304(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XI, § 1104(e)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3965</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 931(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1535</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2349.</num>
<heading> Overseas Workload Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A firm of any member nation of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or of any major non-NATO ally shall be eligible to bid on any contract for the maintenance, repair, or overhaul of equipment of the Department of Defense located outside the United States to be awarded under competitive procedures as part of the program of the Department of Defense known as the Overseas Workload Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Site of Performance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract awarded to a firm described in subsection (a) may be performed in the theater in which the equipment is normally located or in the country in which the firm is located.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of a military department may restrict the geographic region in which a contract referred to in subsection (a) may be performed if the Secretary determines that performance of the contract outside that specific region—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> could adversely affect the military preparedness of the armed forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> would violate the terms of an international agreement to which the United States is a party.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “major non-NATO ally” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2350a(i)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIV, § 1431(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1832</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(18)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2062</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2349a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1955</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “logistic support, supplies, and services” means food, billeting, transportation (including airlift), petroleum, oils, lubricants, clothing, communications services, medical services, ammunition, base operations support (and construction incident to base operations support), storage services, use of facilities, training services, spare parts and components, repair and maintenance services, calibration services, and port services. Such term includes temporary use of general purpose vehicles and other nonlethal items of military equipment which are not designated as significant military equipment on the United States Munitions List promulgated pursuant to section 38(a)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “North Atlantic Treaty Organization subsidiary bodies” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any organization within the meaning of the term “subsidiary bodies” in article I of the multilateral treaty on the Status of the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation, National Representatives and International Staff, signed at Ottawa on <date date="1951-09-20">September 20, 1951</date> (TIAS 2992; 5 UST 1087); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any international military headquarters or organization to which the Protocol on the Status of International Military Headquarters Set Up Pursuant to the North Atlantic Treaty, signed at Paris on <date date="1952-08-28">August 28, 1952</date> (TIAS 2978; 5 UST 870), applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “military region” means the geographical area of responsibility assigned to the commander of a unified combatant command (excluding Europe and adjacent waters).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “transfer” means selling (whether for payment in currency, replacement-in-kind, or exchange of supplies or services of equal value), leasing, loaning, or otherwise temporarily providing logistic support, supplies, and services under the terms of a cross-servicing agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–323, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1019</ref>, § 2331; renumbered § 2350, <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1304(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 741</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XI, § 1104(f)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3965</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 931(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1317(h)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title XII, § 1222</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1937</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>OTHER COOPERATIVE AGREEMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2350a.</num>
<heading> Cooperative research and development agreements: NATO organizations; allied and friendly foreign countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Engage in Cooperative</inline> R&amp;D <inline class="small-caps">Projects</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may enter into a memorandum of understanding (or other formal agreement) with one or more countries or organizations referred to in paragraph (2) for the purpose of conducting cooperative research and development projects on defense equipment and munitions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The countries and organizations with which the Secretary may enter into a memorandum of agreement (or other formal agreement) under paragraph (1) are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A NATO organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A member nation of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A major non-NATO ally.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any other friendly foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The European Union, including the European Defence Agency, the European Commission, and the Council of the European Union, and their suborganizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If such a memorandum of understanding (or other formal agreement) is with a country referred to in subparagraph (E) of paragraph (2), such memorandum (or agreement) may go into effect only after the Secretary submits to the Committees on Armed Services and on Foreign Relations of the Senate and to the Committees on Armed Services and on International Relations of the House of Representatives a report with respect to the proposed memorandum (or agreement) and a period of 30 days has passed after the report has been submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement That Projects Improve Conventional Defense Capabilities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may not enter into a memorandum of understanding (or other formal agreement) to conduct a cooperative research and development project under this section unless the Secretary determines that the proposed project will improve, through the application of emerging technology, the conventional defense capabilities of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or the common conventional defense capabilities of the United States and a country or organization referred to in subsection (a)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary to make a determination under paragraph (1) may only be delegated to the Deputy Secretary of Defense, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, or the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cost Sharing.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), each cooperative research and development project entered into under this section shall require sharing of the costs of the project (including the costs of claims) between the participants on an equitable basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A cooperative research and development project may be entered into under this section under which costs are shared between the participants on an unequal basis if the Secretary of Defense, or an official specified in subsection (b)(2) to whom the Secretary delegates authority under this paragraph, makes a written determination that unequal cost sharing provides strategic value to the United States or another participant in the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “cost” means the total value of cash and non-cash contributions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restrictions on Procurement of Equipment and Services</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In order to assure substantial participation on the part of countries and organizations referred to in subsection (a)(2) in cooperative research and development projects, funds made available for such projects may not be used to procure equipment or services from any foreign government, foreign research organization, or other foreign entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A country or organization referred to in subsection (a)(2) may not use any military or economic assistance grant, loan, or other funds provided by the United States for the purpose of making the contribution of that country or organization to a cooperative research and development program entered into with the United States under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Opportunities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In order to ensure that opportunities to conduct cooperative research and development projects are considered at an early point during the formal development review process of the Department of Defense in connection with any planned project of the Department, opportunities for such cooperative research and development shall be addressed in the acquisition strategy for the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A cooperative opportunities discussion referred to in paragraph (1) shall consider the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Whether or not a project similar to the one under consideration by the Department of Defense is in development or production by any country or organization referred to in subsection (a)(2) or NATO organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If a project similar to the one under consideration by the Department of Defense is in development or production by one or more countries and organizations referred to in subsection (a)(2), an assessment as to whether that project could satisfy, or could be modified in scope so as to satisfy, the military requirements of the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An assessment of the advantages and disadvantages with regard to program timing, developmental and life cycle costs, technology sharing, and Rationalization, Standardization, and Interoperability (RSI) of seeking to structure a cooperative development program with one or more countries and organizations referred to in subsection (a)(2) or NATO organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A recommendation to the milestone decision authority as to whether the Department of Defense should explore the feasibility and desirability of a cooperative development program with one or more countries and organizations referred to in subsection (a)(2) or NATO organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(f)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1597</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Side-by-Side Testing</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> It is the sense of Congress—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that the Secretary of Defense should test covered equipment, munitions, and technologies to determine the ability of such covered equipment, munitions, and technologies to satisfy United States military requirements or to correct operational deficiencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that while the testing of nondevelopmental items and items in the late state of the development process are preferred, the testing of such covered equipment, munitions, and technologies may be conducted to determine procurement alternatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may acquire covered equipment, munitions, and technologies for the purpose of conducting the testing described in that paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The use of side-by-side testing under this subsection may be considered to be the use of competitive procedures for purposes of chapter 137 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002090">1</ref> of this title, when procuring items within 5 years after an initial determination that the items have been successfully tested and found to satisfy United States military requirements or to correct operational deficiencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Equipment, Munitions, and Technologies Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection, the term “covered equipment, munitions, and technologies” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conventional defense equipment, munitions, and technologies manufactured and developed by countries referred to in subsection (a)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conventional defense equipment, munitions, and technologies manufactured and developed domestically.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary To Encourage Similar Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall encourage member nations of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, major non-NATO allies, and other friendly foreign countries to establish programs similar to the one provided for in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “cooperative research and development project” means a project involving joint participation by the United States and one or more countries and organizations referred to in subsection (a)(2) under a memorandum of understanding (or other formal agreement) to carry out a joint research and development program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to develop new conventional defense equipment and munitions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to modify existing military equipment to meet United States military requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “major non-NATO ally” means a country (other than a member nation of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization) that is designated as a major non-NATO ally for purposes of this section by the Secretary of Defense with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “NATO organization” means any North Atlantic Treaty Organization subsidiary body referred to in <ref>section 2350(2) of this title</ref> and any other organization of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1531</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1331(4)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1673</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1053</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1471</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 843(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2469</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1301</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2888</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)(1)</ref>, title X, § 1067(1), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 717</ref>, 774; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, title XII, § 1212(a)–(e)(1), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>, 1248–1250; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1041(a)(9), 1062(f)(2), <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2645</ref>, 2651; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title II, § 237</ref>, title XII, § 1251, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 48</ref>, 401; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title IX, § 901(j)(4)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4324</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 865</ref>, title X, § 1061(14), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1526</ref>, 1583; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 821(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 827</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2280</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(54)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1549</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 211</ref>, title VIII, § 882, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3455</ref>, 3790; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350b.</num>
<heading> Cooperative projects under Arms Export Control Act: acquisition of defense equipment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the President delegates to the Secretary of Defense the authority to carry out section 27(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2767(d)</ref>), relating to cooperative projects (as defined in such section), the Secretary may utilize his authority under this title in carrying out contracts or obligations incurred under such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (c), chapter 137 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002091">1</ref> of this title shall apply to such contracts (referred to in paragraph (1)) entered into by the Secretary of Defense. Except to the extent waived under subsection (c) or some other provision of law, all other provisions of law relating to procurement, if otherwise applicable, shall apply to such contracts entered into by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When contracting or incurring obligations under section 27(d) of the Arms Export Control Act for cooperative projects, the Secretary of Defense may require subcontracts to be awarded to particular subcontractors in furtherance of the cooperative project.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2), when entering into contracts or incurring obligations under section 27(d) of the Arms Export Control Act outside the United States, the Secretary of Defense may waive with respect to any such contract or subcontract the application of any provision of law, other than a provision of the Arms Export Control Act or section 2304 <sup>1</sup> of this title, that specifically prescribes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> procedures to be followed in the formation of contracts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> terms and conditions to be included in contracts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> requirements for or preferences to be given to goods grown, produced, or manufactured in the United States or in United States Government-owned facilities or for services to be performed in the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> requirements regulating the performance of contracts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A waiver may not be made under paragraph (1) unless the Secretary determines that the waiver is necessary to ensure that the cooperative project will significantly further standardization, rationalization, and interoperability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary to make waivers under this subsection may be delegated only to the Deputy Secretary of Defense or the Acquisition Executive designated for the Office of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall notify the Congress each time he requires that a prime contract be awarded to a particular prime contractor or that a subcontract be awarded to a particular subcontractor to comply with a cooperative agreement. The Secretary shall include in each such notice the reason for exercising his authority to designate a particular contractor or subcontractor, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall also notify the Congress each time he exercises a waiver under subsection (c) and shall include in such notice the particular provision or provisions of law that were waived.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A report under this subsection shall be required only to the extent that the information required by this subsection has not been provided in a report made by the President under section 27(e) of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2767(e)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In carrying out a cooperative project under section 27 of the Arms Export Control Act, the Secretary of Defense may agree that a participant (other than the United States) or a NATO organization may make a contract for requirements of the United States under the project if the Secretary determines that such a contract will significantly further standardization, rationalization, and interoperability. Except to the extent waived under this section or under any other provision of law, the Secretary shall ensure that such contract will be made on a competitive basis and that United States sources will not be precluded from competing under the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a participant (other than the United States) in such a cooperative project or a NATO organization makes a contract on behalf of such project to meet the requirements of the United States, the contract may permit the contracting party to follow its own procedures relating to contracting.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> In carrying out a cooperative project, the Secretary of Defense may also agree to the disposal of property that is jointly acquired by the members of the project without regard to any laws of the United States applicable to the disposal of property owned by the United States. Disposal of such property may include a transfer of the interest of the United States in such property to one of the other governments participating in the cooperative agreement or the sale of such property. Payment for the transfer or sale of any interest of the United States in any such property shall be made in accordance with the terms of the cooperative agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to waive any of the financial management responsibilities administered by the Secretary of the Treasury; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to waive the cargo preference laws of the United States, including <ref>section 2631 of this title</ref> and <ref>section 55305 of title 46</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XI, § 1102(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 710</ref>, § 2407; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XI, § 1103(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), title XIII, § 1343(a)(15), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3963</ref>, 3993; renumbered § 2350b and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 931(b)(1)</ref>, (e)(3), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1534</ref>, 1535; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XIII, § 1335</ref>, div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(b)(10), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 484</ref>, 672; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(19)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2062</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350c.</num>
<heading> Cooperative military airlift agreements: allied countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the availability of appropriations, and after consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense may enter into cooperative military airlift agreements with the government of any allied country for the transportation of the personnel and cargo of the military forces of that country on aircraft operated by or for the military forces of the United States in return for the reciprocal transportation of the personnel and cargo of the military forces of the United States on aircraft operated by or for the military forces of that allied country. Any such agreement shall include the following terms:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The rate of reimbursement for transportation provided shall be the same for each party and shall be not less than the rate charged to military forces of the United States, as determined by the Secretary of Defense under <ref>section 2208(h) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Credits and liabilities accrued as a result of providing or receiving transportation shall be liquidated as agreed upon by the parties. Liquidation shall be either by direct payment to the country that has provided the greater amount of transportation or by the providing of in-kind transportation services to that country. The liquidation shall occur on a regular basis, but not less often than once every 12 months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> During peacetime, the only military airlift capacity that may be used to provide transportation is that capacity that (A) is not needed to meet the transportation requirements of the military forces of the country providing the transportation, and (B) was not created solely to accommodate the requirements of the military forces of the country receiving the transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Defense articles purchased by an allied country from the United States under the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.) or from a commercial source under the export controls of the Arms Export Control Act may not be transported (for the purpose of delivery incident to the purchase of the defense articles) to the purchasing allied country on aircraft operated by or for the military forces of the United States except at a rate of reimbursement that is equal to the full cost of transportation of the defense articles, as required by section 21(a)(3) of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2761(a)(3)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subject to the availability of appropriations, and after consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense may enter into nonreciprocal military airlift agreements with North Atlantic Treaty Organization subsidiary bodies for the transportation of the personnel and cargo of such subsidiary bodies on aircraft operated by or for the military forces of the United States. Any such agreement shall be subject to such terms as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Any amount received by the United States as a result of an agreement entered into under this section shall be credited to applicable appropriations, accounts, and funds of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “allied country” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A country that is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Australia, New Zealand, Japan, and the Republic of Korea.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any other country designated as an allied country for the purposes of this section by the Secretary of Defense with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “North Atlantic Treaty Organization subsidiary bodies” has the meaning given to it by <ref>section 2350 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–252, title XI, § 1125(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 757</ref>, § 2213; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1304(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 742</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; renumbered § 2350c and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 931(b)(2)</ref>, (e)(4), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1534</ref>, 1535; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIII, § 1311</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XII, § 1222], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–328.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350d.</num>
<heading> Cooperative acquisition and logistics support agreements: NATO countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may enter into bilateral or multilateral agreements known as Support or Procurement Partnership Agreements with one or more governments of other member countries of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) participating in the operation of the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies. Any such agreement shall be for the purpose of providing cooperative acquisition and logistics support for the armed forces of the countries which are parties to the agreement. Any such agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be entered into pursuant to the terms of the charter of the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall provide for the common acquisition and logistics support of activities common to the participating countries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such an agreement may provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the transfer of logistics support, supplies, and services by the United States to the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the acquisition of armaments and logistics support, supplies, and services by the United States from that Organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under the terms of a Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement or Arrangement, the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may agree that the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies may enter into contracts for supply, services, support, and acquisition, including armaments for requirements of the United States, to the extent the Secretary determines that the procedures of such Organization governing such supply, services, support, and acquisition are appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may share the costs of set-up charges of facilities for use by the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies to provide cooperative acquisition and logistics support and in the costs of establishing a revolving fund for initial acquisition and replenishment of supply stocks to be used by the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies to provide cooperative acquisition and logistics support.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sharing of Administrative Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement shall provide for joint management by the participating countries and for the equitable sharing of the administrative costs and costs of claims incident to the agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of Chapter</inline> 137.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the provisions of chapter 137 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002092">1</ref> of this title apply to a contract entered into by the Secretary of Defense for the acquisition of logistics support under a Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of Arms Export Control Act</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any transfer of defense articles or defense services to a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or to the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies for the purposes of a Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement shall be carried out in accordance with this chapter and the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supplemental Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary of Defense under this section is in addition to the authority of the Secretary under subchapter I and any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX</ref>, §§ 931(c), 938(c), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1534</ref>, 1539; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 843(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2469</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XII, § 1250(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 926</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1279(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2072</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1244(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350e.</num>
<heading> NATO Airborne Warning and Control System (AWACS) program: authority of Secretary of Defense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority Under AWACS Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, in carrying out an AWACS memorandum of understanding, may do the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Waive reimbursement for the cost of the following functions performed by personnel other than personnel employed in the United States Air Force Airborne Warning and Control System (AWACS) program office:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Auditing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Quality assurance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Codification.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Inspection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Contract administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Acceptance testing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Certification services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Planning, programming, and management services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Waive any surcharge for administrative services otherwise chargeable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In connection with that Program, assume contingent liability for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> program losses resulting from the gross negligence of any contracting officer of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identifiable taxes, customs duties, and other charges levied within the United States on the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the United States share of the unfunded termination liability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract Authority Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Authority under this section to enter into contracts shall be effective for any fiscal year only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in appropriation Acts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “AWACS memorandum of understanding” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Multilateral Memorandum of Understanding Between the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Ministers of Defence on the NATO E–3A Cooperative Programme, signed by the Secretary of Defense on <date date="1978-12-06">December 6, 1978</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Memorandum of Understanding for Operations and Support of the NATO Airborne Early Warning and Control Force, signed by the United States Ambassador to NATO on <date date="1984-09-26">September 26, 1984</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Addendum to the Multilateral Memorandum of Understanding Between the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Ministers of Defence on the NATO E–3A Cooperative Programme (dated <date date="1978-12-06">December 6, 1978</date>) relating to the modernization of the NATO Airborne Early Warning and Control (NAEW&amp;C) System, dated <date date="1990-12-07">December 7, 1990</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any other follow-on support agreement for the NATO E–3A Cooperative Programme.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 932(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1536</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1051</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1470</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIV, § 1413</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1829</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350f.</num>
<heading> Procurement of communications support and related supplies and services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> As an alternative means of obtaining communications support and related supplies and services, the Secretary of Defense, subject to the approval of the Secretary of State, may enter into a bilateral arrangement with any allied country or allied international organization or may enter into a multilateral arrangement with allied countries and allied international organizations, under which, in return for being provided communications support and related supplies and services, the United States would agree to provide to the allied country or countries or allied international organization or allied international organizations, as the case may be, an equivalent value of communications support and related supplies and services. The term of an arrangement entered into under this subsection may not exceed five years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any arrangement entered into under this section shall require that any accrued credits and liabilities resulting from an unequal exchange of communications support and related supplies and services during the term of such arrangement would be liquidated by direct payment to the party having provided the greater amount of communications support and related supplies and services. Liquidations may be made at such times as the parties in an arrangement may agree upon, but in no case may final liquidation in the case of an arrangement be made later than 30 days after the end of the term for which the arrangement was entered into.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Parties to an arrangement entered into under this section shall annually reconcile accrued credits and liabilities accruing under such agreement. Any liability of the United States resulting from a reconciliation shall be charged against the applicable appropriation available to the Department of Defense (at the time of the reconciliation) for obligation for communications support and related supplies and services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Payments received by the United States shall be credited to the appropriation from which such communications support and related supplies and services have been provided.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(c)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2645</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “allied country” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a country that is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Australia, New Zealand, Japan, or the Republic of Korea; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other country designated as an allied country for purposes of this section by the Secretary of Defense with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “allied international organization” means the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) or any other international organization designated as an allied international organization for the purposes of this section by the Secretary of Defense with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title X, § 1005(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2578</ref>, § 2401a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; renumbered § 2350f and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 933(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1484(k)(8)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350g.</num>
<heading> Authority to accept use of real property, services, and supplies from foreign countries in connection with mutual defense agreements and occupational arrangements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Accept</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may accept from a foreign country, for the support of any element of the armed forces in an area of that country—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> real property or the use of real property and services and supplies for the United States or for the use of the United States in accordance with a mutual defense agreement or occupational arrangement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> services furnished as reciprocal international courtesies or as services customarily made available without charge.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Use Property, Services, and Supplies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Property, services, or supplies referred to in subsection (a) may be used by the Secretary of Defense without specific authorization, except that such property, services, and supplies may not be used in connection with any program, project, or activity if the use of such property, services, or supplies would result in the violation of any prohibition or limitation otherwise applicable to that program, project, or activity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Periodic Audits by</inline> GAO.—</heading>
<content>The Comptroller General of the United States shall make periodic audits of money and property accepted under this section, at such intervals as the Comptroller General determines to be warranted. The Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the results of each such audit.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1451(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1692</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1105(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1749</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1032(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 751</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350h.</num>
<heading> Memorandums of agreement: Department of Defense ombudsman for foreign signatories</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall designate an official to act as ombudsman within the Department of Defense on behalf of foreign governments who are parties to memorandums of agreement with the United States concerning acquisition matters under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense. The official so designated shall assist officials of those foreign governments in understanding and complying with procedures and requirements of the Department of Defense (and, as appropriate, other departments and agencies of the United States) insofar as they relate to any such memorandum of agreement.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1452(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350i.</num>
<heading> Foreign contributions for cooperative projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crediting of Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the United States participates in a cooperative project with a friendly foreign country or the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) on a cost-sharing basis, any contribution received by the United States from that foreign country or NATO to meet its share of the costs of the project may be credited to appropriations available to an appropriate military department or another appropriate organization within the Department of Defense, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Amounts Credited</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The amount of a contribution credited pursuant to subsection (a) to an appropriation account in connection with a cooperative project referred to in that subsection shall be available only for payment of the share of the project expenses allocated to the foreign country or NATO making the contribution. Payments for which such amount is available include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Payments to contractors and other suppliers (including the Department of Defense and other participants acting as suppliers) for necessary articles and services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Payments for any damages and costs resulting from the performance or cancellation of any contract or other obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Payments or reimbursements of other program expenses, including program office overhead and administrative costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Refunds to other participants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “cooperative project” means a jointly managed arrangement, described in a written cooperative agreement entered into by the participants, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is undertaken by the participants in order to improve the conventional defense capabilities of the participants; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> provides for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> one or more participants (other than the United States) to share with the United States the cost of research and development, testing, evaluation, or joint production (including follow-on support) of defense articles;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the United States and another participant concurrently to produce in the United States and the country of such other participant a defense article jointly developed in a cooperative project described in clause (i); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the United States to procure a defense article or a defense service from another participant in the cooperative project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “defense article” has the meaning given such term in section 47(3) of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2794(3)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “defense service” has the meaning given such term in section 47(4) of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2794(4)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1047(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1467</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350j.</num>
<heading> Burden sharing contributions by designated countries and regional organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Accept Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretary of State, may accept cash contributions from any country or regional organization designated for purposes of this section by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, for the purposes specified in subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accounting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Contributions accepted under subsection (a) which are not related to security assistance may be accepted, managed, and expended in dollars or in the currency of the host nation (or, in the case of a contribution from a regional organization, in the currency in which the contribution was provided). Any such contribution shall be placed in an account established for such purpose and shall remain available until expended for the purposes specified in subsection (c). The Secretary of Defense shall establish a separate account for such purpose for each country or regional organization from which such contributions are accepted under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Contributions accepted under subsection (a) shall be available only for the payment of the following costs:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Compensation for local national employees of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Military construction projects of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Supplies and services of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Military Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Contributions placed in an account established under subsection (b) may be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by the Secretary of Defense to carry out a military construction project that is consistent with the purposes for which the contributions were made and is not otherwise authorized by law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by the Secretary of a military department, with the approval of the Secretary of Defense, to carry out such a project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and Wait Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> When a decision is made to carry out a military construction project under subsection (d), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report containing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an explanation of the need for the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the then current estimate of the cost of the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a justification for carrying out the project under that subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may not commence a military construction project under subsection (d) until the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Defense submits the report under paragraph (1) regarding the project in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A military construction project under subsection (d) may be carried out without regard to the requirement in paragraph (1) and the limitation in paragraph (2) if the project is necessary to support the armed forces in the country or region in which the project is carried out by reason of a declaration of war, or a declaration by the President of a national emergency pursuant to the National Emergencies Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.), that is in force at the time of the commencement of the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> When a decision is made to carry out a military construction project under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a notice of the decision; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a statement of the current estimated cost of the project, including the cost of any real property transaction in connection with the project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Report on Contributions Received From Designated Countries.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than January 15 each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the burden sharing contributions received under this section from designated countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following for the preceding fiscal year:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A list of all designated countries from which burden sharing contributions were received.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An explanation of the purpose for which each such burden sharing contribution was provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A description of any written agreement entered into with a designated country under this section, including the date on which the agreement was signed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> For each designated country—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount provided by the designated country; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount of any remaining unobligated balance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The amount of such burden sharing contributions expended, by eligible category, including compensation for local national employees, military construction projects, and supplies and services of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Any other matter the Secretary of Defense considers relevant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate committees of congress defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection, the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIV, § 1402(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1825</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1070(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2856</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XIII, § 1331</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2801, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>, 845; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1031(a)(18), 1043(b)(12), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1597</ref>, 1611; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(15)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2801(f), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1561</ref>, 1845; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299B</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3998</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350k.</num>
<heading> Relocation within host nation of elements of armed forces overseas</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Accept Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may accept contributions from any nation because of or in support of the relocation of elements of the armed forces from or to any location within that nation. Such contributions may be accepted in dollars or in the currency of the host nation. Any such contribution shall be placed in an account established for such purpose and shall remain available until expended for the purposes specified in subsection (b). The Secretary shall establish a separate account for such purpose for each country from which such contributions are accepted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may use a contribution accepted under subsection (a) only for payment of costs incurred in connection with the relocation concerning which the contribution was made. Those costs include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Design and construction services, including development and review of statements of work, master plans and designs, acquisition of construction, and supervision and administration of contracts relating thereto.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Transportation and movement services, including packing, unpacking, storage, and transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Communications services, including installation and deinstallation of communications equipment, transmission of messages and data, and rental of transmission capability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Supply and administration, including acquisition of expendable office supplies, rental of office space, budgeting and accounting services, auditing services, secretarial services, and translation services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Personnel costs, including salary, allowances and overhead of employees whether full-time or part-time, temporary or permanent (except for military personnel), and travel and temporary duty costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> All other clearly identifiable expenses directly related to relocation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Method of Contribution</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Contributions may be accepted in any of the following forms:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Irrevocable letter of credit issued by a financial institution acceptable to the Treasurer of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Drawing rights on a commercial bank account established and funded by the host nation, which account is blocked such that funds deposited cannot be withdrawn except by or with the approval of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Cash, which shall be deposited in a separate trust fund in the United States Treasury pending expenditure and which shall accrue interest in accordance with <ref>section 9702 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XIII, § 1332(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 482</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350l.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agreements for reciprocal use of test facilities: foreign countries and international organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, may enter into a memorandum of understanding (or other formal agreement) with a foreign country or international organization to provide for the testing, on a reciprocal basis, of defense equipment (1) by the United States using test facilities of that country or organization, and (2) by that country or organization using test facilities of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A memorandum or other agreement under subsection (a) shall provide that, when a party to the agreement uses a test facility of another party to the agreement, the party using the test facility is charged by the party providing the test facility in accordance with the following principles:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The user party shall be charged the amount equal to the direct costs incurred by the provider party in furnishing test and evaluation services by the providing party’s officers, employees, or governmental agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The user party may also be charged indirect costs relating to the use of the test facility, but only to the extent specified in the memorandum or other agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of Indirect Costs; Delegation of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall determine the appropriateness of the amount of indirect costs charged by the United States pursuant to subsection (b)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may delegate the authority under paragraph (1) only to the Deputy Secretary of Defense and to one other official of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention of Funds Collected by the United States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts collected by the United States from a party using a test facility of the United States pursuant to a memorandum or other agreement under this section shall be credited to the appropriation accounts from which the costs incurred by the United States in providing such test facility were paid.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “direct cost”, with respect to the use of a test facility pursuant to a memorandum or other agreement under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means any item of cost that is easily and readily identified to a specific unit of work or output within the test facility where the use occurred, that would not have been incurred if such use had not occurred; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> may include costs of labor, materials, facilities, utilities, equipment, supplies, and any other resources of the test facility that are consumed or damaged in connection with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the use; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the maintenance of the test facility for purposes of the use.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “indirect cost”, with respect to the use of a test facility pursuant to a memorandum or other agreement under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means any item of cost that is not easily and readily identified to a specific unit of work or output within the test facility where the use occurred; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may include general and administrative expenses for such activities as supporting base operations, manufacturing, supervision, procurement of office supplies, and utilities that are accumulated costs allocated among several users.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “test facility” means a range or other facility at which testing of defense equipment may be carried out.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XII, § 1213(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1250</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1844(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350m.</num>
<heading> Participation in European program on multilateral exchange of surface transportation services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Participation Authorized.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, may authorize the participation of the Department of Defense in the Surface Exchange of Services program (in this section referred to as the “SEOS program”) of the Movement Coordination Centre Europe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of participation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Participation of the Department of Defense in the SEOS program under paragraph (1) may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the reciprocal exchange or transfer of surface transportation on a reimbursable basis or by replacement-in-kind; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the exchange of surface transportation services of an equal value.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Written Arrangement or Agreement.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Participation of the Department of Defense in the SEOS program shall be in accordance with a written arrangement or agreement entered into by the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, and the Movement Coordination Centre Europe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall provide to the congressional defense committees notification of any arrangement or agreement entered into under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding arrangements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If Department of Defense facilities, equipment, or funds are used to support the SEOS program, the written arrangement or agreement under paragraph (1) shall specify the details of any equitable cost-sharing or other funding arrangement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other elements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any written arrangement or agreement entered into under paragraph (1) shall require that any accrued credits or liability resulting from an unequal exchange or transfer of surface transportation services shall be liquidated through the SEOS program not less than once every five years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out any arrangement or agreement entered into under subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pay the equitable share of the Department of Defense for the operating expenses of the Movement Coordination Centre Europe and the SEOS program from funds available to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assign members of the armed forces or Department of Defense civilian personnel, within billets authorized for the United States European Command, to duty at the Movement Coordination Centre Europe as necessary to fulfill Department of Defense obligations under that arrangement or agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crediting of Receipts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any amount received by the Department of Defense as part of the SEOS program shall be credited, at the option of the Secretary of Defense, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the appropriation, fund, or account used in incurring the obligation for which such amount is received; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an appropriate appropriation, fund, or account currently available for the purposes for which the expenditures were made.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year in which the authority under this section is in effect, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on Department of Defense participation in the SEOS program during such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of the equitable share of the costs and activities of the SEOS program paid by the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of any amount received by the Department of Defense as part of such program, including the country from which the amount was received.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Statutory Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize the use of foreign sealift in violation of section 2631.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3908</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350n.</num>
<heading> North Atlantic Treaty Organization Joint Force Command</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall authorize the establishment of, and the participation by members of the armed forces in, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Joint Force Command (in this section referred to as the “Joint Force Command”), to be established in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Department of Defense Facilities and Equipment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may use facilities and equipment of the Department of Defense to support the Joint Force Command.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense shall be available to carry out the purposes of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XII, § 1249(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1664</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350o.</num>
<heading> Participation in programs relating to coordination or exchange of air refueling and air transportation services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Participation Authorized.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, may authorize the participation of the Department of Defense in programs relating to the coordination or exchange of air refueling and air transportation services, including in the arrangement known as the Air Transport and Air-to-Air Refueling and other Exchanges of Services program (in this section referred to as the “ATARES program”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of participation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Participation of the Department of Defense in programs referred to in paragraph (1) may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the reciprocal exchange or transfer of air refueling and air transportation services on a reimbursable basis or by replacement-in-kind; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the exchange of air refueling and air transportation services of an equal value.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations with respect to participation in atares program.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Department of Defense balance of executed flight hours in participation in the ATARES program under paragraph (1), whether as credits or debits, may not exceed a total of 500 hours.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Air refueling</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Department of Defense balance of executed flight hours for air refueling in participation in the ATARES program under paragraph (1) may not exceed 200 hours.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Written Arrangement or Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Participation of the Department of Defense in a program referred to in subsection (a)(1) shall be in accordance with a written arrangement or agreement entered into by the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out any arrangement or agreement entered into under subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pay the equitable share of the Department of Defense for the recurring and nonrecurring costs of the applicable program referred to in subsection (a)(1) from funds available to the Department for operation and maintenance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assign members of the armed forces or Department of Defense civilian personnel to fulfill Department obligations under that arrangement or agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1203(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3910</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350p.</num>
<heading> Reciprocal patient movement agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, may enter into a bilateral or multilateral memorandum of understanding or other formal agreement with one or more governments of partner countries that provides for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the interchangeable, nonreimbursable use of patient movement personnel, either individually or as members of a patient movement crew or team, and equipment, belonging to one partner country to perform patient movement services aboard the aircraft, vessels, or vehicles of another partner country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the reciprocal recognition and acceptance of —</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> national professional credentials, certifications, and licenses of patient movement personnel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> national certifications, approvals, and licenses of equipment used in the provision of patient movement services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the acceptance of agreed-upon standards for the provision of patient movement services by aircraft, vessel, or vehicle, including, as determined to be beneficial and otherwise permitted by law, the harmonization of patient treatment standards and procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Before entering into a memorandum of understanding or other formal agreement with the government of a partner country under this section, the Secretary of Defense shall certify in writing that the professional credentials, certifications, licenses, and approvals for patient movement personnel and patient movement equipment of the partner country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> meet or exceed the equivalent standards of the United States for similar personnel and equipment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will provide for a level of care comparable to, or better than, the level of care provided by the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A certification under paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> submitted to the appropriate committees of Congress not later than 15 days after the date on which the Secretary of Defense makes the certification; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reviewed and recertified by the Secretary of Defense not less frequently than annually.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Suspension</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of Defense is unable to recertify a partner country as required by subsection (b)(2)(B), use of the personnel or equipment of the partner country by the Department of Defense under a memorandum of understanding or other formal agreement concluded pursuant to subsection (a) shall be suspended until the date on which the Secretary of Defense is able to recertify the partner country.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate committees of congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the congressional defense committees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Partner country</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “partner country” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Australia.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Japan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> New Zealand.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Republic of Korea.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Any other country designated as a partner country by the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, for purposes of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Patient movement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “patient movement” means the act or process of moving wounded, ill, injured, or other persons (including contaminated, contagious, and potentially exposed patients) to obtain medical, surgical, mental health, or dental care or treatment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1204(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3911</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350q.</num>
<heading> Execution of projects under the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Execute Projects</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the United States is designated as the Host Nation for purposes of executing a project under the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program (in this section referred to as the “Program”), the Secretary of Defense may accept such designation and carry out such project consistent with the requirements of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Project Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may fund authorized expenditures of projects accepted under subsection (a) with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> contributions under subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> appropriations of the Department of Defense for the Program when directed by the North Atlantic Treaty Organization to apply amounts of such appropriations as part of the share of contributions of the United States for the Program; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any combination of amounts described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Accept Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may accept contributions from the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and member nations of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization for the purpose of carrying out a project under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Contributions accepted under paragraph (1) shall be placed in an account established for the purpose of carrying out the project for which the funds were provided and shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> If contributions are made under paragraph (1) as reimbursement for a project or portion of a project previously completed by the Department of Defense, such contributions shall be credited to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the appropriations used for the project or portion thereof, if such appropriations have not yet expired; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the appropriations for the Program, if the appropriations described in clause (i) have expired.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Funding credited under subparagraph (A) shall merge with and remain available for the same purposes and duration as the appropriations to which credited.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligation Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The construction agent of the Department of Defense designated by the Secretary of Defense to execute a project under subsection (a) may recognize the North Atlantic Treaty Organization project authorization amounts as budgetary resources to incur obligations against for the purposes of executing the project.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Insufficient Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the event that the North Atlantic Treaty Organization does not agree to contribute funding for all costs necessary for the Department of Defense to carry out a project under subsection (a), including necessary personnel costs of the construction agent designated by the Department of Defense, contract claims, and any conjunctive funding requirements that exceed the project authorization or standards of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, the Secretary of Defense, upon determination that completion of the project is in the national interest of the United States, may fund such costs, and undertake such conjunctively funded requirements not otherwise authorized by law, using any unobligated funds available among funds appropriated for the Program for military construction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The use of funds under paragraph (1) from appropriations for the Program may be in addition to or in place of any other funding sources otherwise available for the purposes for which those funds are used.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Expenditures Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “authorized expenditures” means project expenses for which the North Atlantic Treaty Organization has agreed to contribute funding.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXV, § 2503(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4309</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(29)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1921</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350r.</num>
<heading> North Atlantic Treaty Organization Allied Special Operations Forces Command</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year for operation and maintenance for the Army, the Secretary of Defense is authorized to use up to $55,000,000, to be derived from amounts made available for support of North Atlantic Treaty Organization (referred to in this section as “NATO”) operations, for each such fiscal year for the purposes set forth in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall provide funds for the NATO Allied Special Operations Forces Command—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to improve coordination and cooperation between the special operations forces of NATO countries and countries approved by the North Atlantic Council as NATO partners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to facilitate joint operations by the special operations forces of NATO countries and such NATO partners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to support special operations forces peculiar command, control, and communications capabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to promote special operations forces intelligence and informational requirements within the NATO structure; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to promote interoperability through the development of common equipment standards, tactics, techniques, and procedures, and through execution of a multinational education and training program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1271(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2860</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XIII, § 1301(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2350s.</num>
<heading> Authority to contribute to innovation fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Contribute to NATO Innovation Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Within amounts authorized by law for such purpose during the five-year period following the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025, the Secretary of Defense may contribute to the NATO Innovation Fund a total amount of no more than $200,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “NATO” means the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “NATO Innovation Fund” means the multi-sovereign, investment venture capital fund of NATO that provides secure investment in dual-use, high-impact technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title X, § 1051</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2061</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>