<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 145—</num>
<heading>CATALOGING AND STANDARDIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2451.</num>
<heading> Defense supply management</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall develop a single catalog system and related program of standardizing supplies for the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In cataloging, the Secretary shall name, describe, classify, and number each item recurrently used, bought, stocked, or distributed by the Department of Defense, so that only one distinctive combination of letters or numerals, or both, identifies the same item throughout the Department of Defense. Only one identification may be used for each item for all supply functions from purchase to final disposal in the field or other area. The catalog may consist of a number of volumes, sections, or supplements. It shall include all items of supply and, for each item, information needed for supply operations, such as descriptive and performance data, size, weight, cubage, packaging and packing data, a standard quantitative unit of measurement, and other related data that the Secretary determines to be desirable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> In standardizing supplies the Secretary shall, to the highest degree practicable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> standardize items used throughout the Department of Defense by developing and using single specifications, eliminating overlapping and duplicate specifications, and reducing the number of sizes and kinds of items that are generally similar;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> standardize the methods of packing, packaging, and preserving such items; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make efficient use of the services and facilities for inspecting, testing, and accepting such items.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall coordinate with the Administrator of General Services to enable the use of commercial identifiers for commercial products (as defined in <ref>section 103 of title 41</ref>) within the Federal cataloging system.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 33(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1565</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title III, § 341</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1448</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(e)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1870</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2452.</num>
<heading> Duties of Secretary of Defense</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop and maintain the supply catalog, and the standardization program, described in <ref>section 2451 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> direct and coordinate progressive use of the supply catalog in all supply functions within the Department of Defense from the determination of requirements through final disposal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> direct, review, and approve—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the naming, description, and pattern of description of all items;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the screening, consolidation, classification, and numbering of descriptions of all items; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the publication and distribution of the supply catalog;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> maintain liaison with industry advisory groups to coordinate the development of the supply catalog and the standardization program with the best practices of industry and to obtain the fullest practicable cooperation and participation of industry in developing the supply catalog and the standardization program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> establish, publish, review, and revise, within the Department of Defense, military specifications, standards, and lists of qualified products, and resolve differences between the military departments, bureaus, and services with respect to them;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> assign responsibility for parts of the cataloging and the standardization programs to the military departments, bureaus, and services within the Department of Defense, when practical and consistent with their capacity and interest in those supplies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> establish time schedules for assignments made under clause (6); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> make final decisions in all matters concerned with the cataloging and standardization programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 139</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2453.</num>
<heading> Supply catalog: distribution and use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall distribute the parts of the supply catalog described in <ref>section 2451 of this title</ref> as they are completed. Existing catalogs shall be replaced according to schedules established by the Secretary. After replacement no other supply catalog may be used within the Department of Defense with respect to the kinds of items covered by that part. All property reports and records shall use the nomenclature, item numbers, and descriptive data of the supply catalog.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 139</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2454.</num>
<heading> Supply catalog: new or obsolete items</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> After any part of the supply catalog described in <ref>section 2451 of this title</ref> is distributed, and with respect to the kinds of items covered by that part, only the items listed in it may be procured for recurrent use in the Department of Defense. However, a military department may acquire any new item that is necessary to carry out its mission. As soon as such an item is acquired, it shall be submitted to the Secretary for inclusion in the catalog and the standardization program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Obsolete items may be deleted from the catalog at any time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 140</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2455.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1322(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1671</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2456.</num>
<heading> Coordination with General Services Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To avoid unnecessary duplication, the Administrator of General Services and the Secretary of Defense shall coordinate the cataloging and standardization activities of the General Services Administration and the Department of Defense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 140</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2457.</num>
<heading> Standardization of equipment with North Atlantic Treaty Organization members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> It is the policy of the United States to standardize equipment, including weapons systems, ammunition, and fuel, procured for the use of the armed forces of the United States stationed in Europe under the North Atlantic Treaty or at least to make that equipment interoperable with equipment of other members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization. To carry out this policy, the Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assess the costs and possible loss of nonnuclear combat effectiveness of the military forces of the members of the Organization caused by the failure of the members to standardize equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> maintain a list of actions to be taken, including an evaluation of the priority and effect of the action, to standardize equipment that may improve the overall nonnuclear defense capability of the Organization or save resources for the Organization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> initiate and carry out, to the maximum extent feasible, procurement procedures to acquire standardized or interoperable equipment, considering the cost, function, quality, and availability of the equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Progress in realizing the objectives of standardization and interoperability would be enhanced by expanded inter-Allied procurement of arms and equipment within the North Atlantic Treaty Organization. Expanded inter-Allied procurement would be made easier by greater reliance on licensing and coproduction cooperative agreements among the signatories of the North Atlantic Treaty. If constructed to preserve the efficiencies associated with economies of scale, the agreements could minimize potential economic hardship to parties to the agreements and increase the survivability, in time of war, of the North Atlantic Alliance’s armaments production base by dispersing manufacturing facilities. In conjunction with other members of the Organization and to the maximum extent feasible, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify areas in which those cooperative agreements may be made with members of the Alliance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> negotiate those agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It is the sense of Congress that weapons systems being developed wholly or primarily for employment in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization theater should conform to a common Organization requirement in order to proceed toward joint doctrine and planning and to facilitate maximum feasible standardization and interoperability of equipment, and that a common Organization requirement should be understood to include a common definition of the military threat to the members of the Organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> It is further the sense of Congress that standardization of weapons and equipment within the Organization on the basis of a “two-way street” concept of cooperation in defense procurement between Europe and North America can only work in a realistic sense if the European nations operate on a united and collective basis. Therefore, the governments of Europe are encouraged to accelerate their present efforts to achieve European armaments collaboration among all European members of the Organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(d)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(22)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1598</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If the Secretary decides that procurement of equipment manufactured outside the United States is necessary to carry out the policy of subsection (a), the Secretary may determine under <ref>section 8302 of title 41</ref> that acquiring that equipment manufactured in the United States is inconsistent with the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall submit the results of each assessment and evaluation made under subsection (a)(1) and (2) to the appropriate North Atlantic Treaty Organization body to become an integral part of the overall Organization review of force goals and development of force plans.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(30)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1294</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1311(5)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1670</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1503(a)(24)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(22)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(33)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2458.</num>
<heading> Inventory management policies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall issue a single, uniform policy on the management of inventory items of the Department of Defense. Such policy shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish maximum levels for inventory items sufficient to achieve and maintain only those levels for inventory items necessary for the national defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide guidance to item managers and other appropriate officials on how effectively to eliminate wasteful practices in the acquisition and management of inventory items; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> set forth a uniform system for the valuation of inventory items by the military departments and Defense Agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel Evaluations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish procedures to ensure that, with regard to item managers and other personnel responsible for the acquisition and management of inventory items of the Department of Defense, personnel appraisal systems for such personnel give appropriate consideration to efforts made by such personnel to eliminate wasteful practices and achieve cost savings in the acquisition and management of inventory items.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title III, § 323(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1530</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title III, § 347(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1347</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>