<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 57—</num>
<heading>DECORATIONS AND AWARDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1121.</num>
<heading> Legion of Merit: award</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, under regulations to be prescribed by him, may award a decoration called the “Legion of Merit”, having suitable appurtenances and devices and not more than four degrees, to any member of the armed forces of the United States or of any friendly foreign nation who, after <date date="1939-09-08">September 8, 1939</date>, has distinguished himself by exceptionally meritorious conduct in performing outstanding services.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 88</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1122.</num>
<heading> Medal for Merit: award</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, under regulations to be prescribed by him, may award a decoration called the “Medal for Merit”, having distinctive appurtenances and devices and only one degree, to any civilian of any nation prosecuting the war in existence on <date date="1942-07-20">July 20, 1942</date>, under the joint declaration of the United Nations, as then constituted, or of any other friendly foreign nation, who, after <date date="1939-09-08">September 8, 1939</date>, has distinguished himself by exceptionally meritorious conduct in performing outstanding services. The Medal for Merit may be awarded to a civilian of a foreign nation but only for performing an exceptionally meritorious or courageous act in the furtherance of the war efforts of the United Nations as then constituted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 88</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1123.</num>
<heading> Right to wear badges of military societies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force who is a member of a military society originally composed of men who served in an armed force of the United States during the Revolutionary War, the War of 1812, the Mexican War, the Civil War, the Spanish-American War, the Philippine Insurrection, or the Chinese Relief Expedition of 1900 may wear, on occasions of ceremony, the distinctive badges adopted by that society.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force who is a member of the Army and Navy Union of the United States may wear, on public occasions of ceremony, the distinctive badges adopted by that society.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 88</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(Q)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1124.</num>
<heading> Cash awards for disclosures, suggestions, inventions, and scientific achievements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, or the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, may authorize the payment of a cash award to, and incur necessary expense for the honorary recognition of, a member of the armed forces under his jurisdiction who by his disclosure, suggestion, invention, or scientific achievement contributes to the efficiency, economy, or other improvement of operations or programs relating to the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whenever the President considers it desirable, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, are authorized to pay a cash award to, and incur necessary expense for the honorary recognition of, a member of the armed forces who by his disclosure, suggestion, invention, or scientific achievement contributes to the efficiency, economy, or other improvement of operations of the Government of the United States. Such award is in addition to any other award made to that member under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An award under this section may be paid notwithstanding the member’s death, separation, or retirement from the armed force concerned. However, the disclosure, suggestion, invention, or scientific achievement forming the basis for the award must have been made while the member was on active duty or in an active reserve status and not otherwise eligible for an award under chapter 45 of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> A cash award under this section is in addition to the pay and allowances of the recipient. The acceptance of such an award shall constitute—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an agreement by the member that the use by the United States of any idea, method, or device for which the award is made may not be the basis of a claim against the United States by the member, his heirs, or assigns, or by any person whose claim is alleged to be derived through the member; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a warranty by the member that he has not at the time of acceptance transferred, assigned, or otherwise divested himself of legal or equitable title in any property right residing in the idea, method, or device for which the award is made.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Awards to, and expenses for the honorary recognition of, members of the armed forces under this section may be paid from (1) the funds or appropriations available to the activity primarily benefiting; or (2) the several funds or appropriations of the various activities benefiting, as may be determined by the President for awards under subsection (b), and by the Secretary concerned for awards under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The total amount of the award, or awards, made under this section for a disclosure, suggestion, invention, or scientific achievement may not exceed $25,000, regardless of the number of persons who may be entitled to share therein.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Awards under this section shall be made under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, or by the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, a member of the Commissioned Corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration or of the Public Health Service who is serving with an armed force shall be treated as if he were a member of that armed force.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–198, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1965-09-22">Sept. 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 830</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 10</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–623, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–470, title I, § 112(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2240</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(40)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–527, title VII, § 772</ref>, <date date="1980-12-15">Dec. 15, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3093</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1225(a)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 730</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1124a.</num>
<heading> Cyber operations-peculiar awards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments may authorize the payment of a cash award to, and incur necessary expense for the honorary recognition of, a member of the covered armed forces whose novel actions, invention, or technical achievement enables or ensures operational outcomes in or through cyberspace against threats to national security.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions During Service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An award under this section may be paid notwithstanding the member’s death, separation, or retirement from the covered armed forces. However, the novel action, invention, or technical achievement forming the basis for the award must have been made while the member was on active duty or in an active reserve status and not otherwise eligible for an award under chapter 45 of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Awards to, and expenses for the honorary recognition of, members of the covered armed forces under this section may be paid from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the funds or appropriations available to the activity primarily benefiting from the novel action, invention, or technical achievement; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the several funds or appropriations of the various activities benefiting from the novel action, invention, or technical achievement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total amount of the award, or awards, made under this section for a novel action, invention, or technical achievement may not exceed $2,500, regardless of the number of persons who may be entitled to share therein.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Awards under this section shall be made under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense or by the Secretaries of the military departments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Armed Forces Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “covered armed forces” means the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1125.</num>
<heading> Recognition for accomplishments: award of trophies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> award medals, trophies, badges, and similar devices to members, units, or agencies of an armed force under his jurisdiction for excellence in accomplishments or competitions related to that armed force; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide badges or buttons in recognition of special service, good conduct, and discharge under conditions other than dishonorable.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–529, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1966-08-11">Aug. 11, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 339</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1126.</num>
<heading> Gold star lapel button: eligibility and distribution</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A lapel button, to be known as the gold star lapel button, shall be designed, as approved by the Secretary of Defense, to identify next of kin of members of the armed forces—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who lost their lives during World War I, World War II, or during any subsequent period of armed hostilities in which the United States was engaged before <date date="1958-07-01">July 1, 1958</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> who lost or lose their lives after <date date="1958-06-30">June 30, 1958</date>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> while engaged in an action against an enemy of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> while engaged in military operations involving conflict with an opposing foreign force; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> while serving with friendly foreign forces engaged in an armed conflict in which the United States is not a belligerent party against an opposing armed force; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> who lost or lose their lives after <date date="1973-03-28">March 28, 1973</date>, as a result of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an international terrorist attack against the United States or a foreign nation friendly to the United States, recognized as such an attack by the Secretary of Defense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> military operations while serving outside the United States (including the commonwealths, territories, and possessions of the United States) as part of a peacekeeping force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary concerned, upon application to him, shall furnish one gold star lapel button without cost to each next of kin of a member who lost or loses his or her life under any circumstances prescribed in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Not more than one gold star lapel button may be furnished to any one individual except that, when a gold star lapel button furnished under this section has been lost, destroyed, or rendered unfit for use without fault or neglect on the part of the person to whom it was furnished, the button may be replaced upon application and without cost.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “next of kin” means individuals standing in such relationship to members of the armed forces described in subsection (a) as the Secretaries concerned shall jointly specify in regulations for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “World War I” includes the period from <date date="1917-04-06">April 6, 1917</date>, to <date date="1921-03-03">March 3, 1921</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “World War II” includes the period from <date date="1939-09-08">September 8, 1939</date>, to <date date="1947-07-25">July 25, 1947</date>, at 12 o’clock noon.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “military operations” includes those operations involving members of the armed forces assisting in United States Government sponsored training of military personnel of a foreign nation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “peacekeeping force” includes those personnel assigned to a force engaged in a peacekeeping operation authorized by the United Nations Security Council.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–534, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1966-08-11">Aug. 11, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 345</ref>, § 1124; renumbered § 1126, <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 9</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1117</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title XII, § 1268(8)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1143</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1757</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 581</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1411</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1127.</num>
<heading> Precedence of the award of the Purple Heart</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In prescribing regulations establishing the order of precedence of awards and decorations authorized to be displayed on the uniforms of members of the armed forces, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall accord the Purple Heart a position of precedence, in relation to other awards and decorations authorized to be displayed, not lower than that immediately following the bronze star.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 553(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2532</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 533</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 634</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1128.</num>
<heading> Prisoner-of-war medal: issue</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall issue a prisoner-of-war medal to any person who, while serving in any capacity with the armed forces, was taken prisoner and held captive—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> while engaged in an action against an enemy of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> while engaged in military operations involving conflict with an opposing foreign force; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> while serving with friendly forces engaged in an armed conflict against an opposing armed force in which the United States is not a belligerent party.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Under uniform regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary concerned may issue a prisoner-of-war medal to any person who, while serving in any capacity with the armed forces, was held captive under circumstances not covered by paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a), but which the Secretary concerned finds were comparable to those circumstances under which persons have generally been held captive by enemy armed forces during periods of armed conflict.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The prisoner-of-war medal shall be of appropriate design, with ribbons and appurtenances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> In prescribing regulations establishing the order of precedence of awards and decorations authorized to be displayed on the uniforms of members of the armed forces, the Secretary concerned shall accord the prisoner-of-war medal a position of precedence, in relation to other awards and decorations authorized to be displayed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> immediately following decorations awarded for individual heroism, meritorious achievement, or meritorious service, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> before any other service medal, campaign medal, or service ribbon authorized to be displayed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Not more than one prisoner-of-war medal may be issued to a person. However, for each succeeding service that would otherwise justify the issuance of such a medal, the Secretary concerned may issue a suitable device to be worn as the Secretary determines.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> For a person to be eligible for issuance of a prisoner-of-war medal, the person’s conduct must have been honorable for the period of captivity which serves as the basis for the issuance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> If a person dies before the issuance of a prisoner-of-war medal to which he is entitled, the medal may be issued to the person’s representative, as designated by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary concerned, a prisoner-of-war medal that is lost, destroyed, or rendered unfit for use without fault or neglect on the part of the person to whom it was issued may be replaced without charge.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that regulations prescribed by the Secretaries of the military departments under this section are uniform so far as practicable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 532(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 633</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 516(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 584</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1767</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1129.</num>
<heading> Purple Heart: members killed or wounded in action by friendly fire</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For purposes of the award of the Purple Heart, the Secretary concerned shall treat a member of the armed forces described in subsection (b) in the same manner as a member who is killed or wounded in action as the result of an act of an enemy of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A member described in this subsection is a member who is killed or wounded in action by weapon fire while directly engaged in armed conflict, other than as the result of an act of an enemy of the United States, unless (in the case of a wound) the wound is the result of willful misconduct of the member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section applies to members of the armed forces who are killed or wounded on or after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>. In the case of a member killed or wounded as described in subsection (b) on or after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, and before <date date="1993-11-30">November 30, 1993</date>, the Secretary concerned shall award the Purple Heart under subsection (a) in each case which is known to the Secretary before such date or for which an application is made to the Secretary in such manner as the Secretary requires.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1141(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1756</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(18)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1901</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1129a.</num>
<heading> Purple Heart: members killed or wounded in attacks by foreign terrorist organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of the award of the Purple Heart, the Secretary concerned shall treat a member of the armed forces described in subsection (b) in the same manner as a member who is killed or wounded as a result of an international terrorist attack against the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A member described in this subsection is a member on active duty who was killed or wounded in an attack by a foreign terrorist organization in circumstances where the death or wound is the result of an attack targeted on the member due to such member’s status as a member of the armed forces, unless the death or wound is the result of willful misconduct of the member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section, an attack by an individual or entity shall be considered to be an attack by a foreign terrorist organization if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the individual or entity was in communication with the foreign terrorist organization before the attack; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the attack was inspired or motivated by the foreign terrorist organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Foreign Terrorist Organization Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “foreign terrorist organization” means an entity designated as a foreign terrorist organization by the Secretary of State pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1189</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 571(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1130.</num>
<heading> Consideration of proposals for decorations not previously submitted in timely fashion: procedures for review</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Upon request of a Member of Congress, the Secretary concerned shall review a proposal for the award or presentation of a decoration (or the upgrading of a decoration), either for an individual or a unit, that is not otherwise authorized to be presented or awarded due to limitations established by law or policy for timely submission of a recommendation for such award or presentation. Based upon such review, the Secretary shall make a determination as to the merits of approving the award or presentation of the decoration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Upon making a determination under subsection (a) as to the merits of approving the award or presentation of the decoration, the Secretary concerned shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and to the requesting Member of Congress a detailed discussion of the rationale supporting the determination. If the determination includes a favorable recommendation for the award of the Medal of Honor, the Secretary of Defense, instead of the Secretary concerned, shall make the submission under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Determinations under this section regarding the award or presentation of a decoration shall be made in accordance with the same procedures that apply to the approval or disapproval of the award or presentation of a decoration when a recommendation for such award or presentation is submitted in a timely manner as prescribed by law or regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Member of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Senator; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “decoration” means any decoration or award that may be presented or awarded to a member or unit of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 526(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 313</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 524</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1401</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1131.</num>
<heading> Purple Heart: limitation to members of the armed forces</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The decoration known as the Purple Heart (authorized to be awarded pursuant to Executive Order 11016) may only be awarded to a person who is a member of the armed forces at the time the person is killed or wounded under circumstances otherwise qualifying that person for award of the Purple Heart.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 571(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1756</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1132.</num>
<heading> Presentation of decorations: prohibition on entering correctional facilities for presentation to prisoners convicted of serious violent felonies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of the armed forces may not enter a Federal, State, local, or foreign correctional facility to present a decoration to a person who is incarcerated due to conviction of a serious violent felony.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “decoration” means any decoration or award that may be presented or awarded to a member of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “serious violent felony” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 3559(c)(2)(F) of title 18</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 537(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2019</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1133.</num>
<heading> Bronze Star: limitation on persons eligible to receive</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The decoration known as the “Bronze Star” may only be awarded to a member of a military force who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at the time of the events for which the decoration is to be awarded, was serving in a geographic area in which special pay is authorized under section 310 or paragraph (1) or (3) of <ref>section 351(a) of title 37</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> receives special pay under section 310 or paragraph (1) or (3) of <ref>section 351(a) of title 37</ref> as a result of those events.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 541(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–114; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 571(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1134.</num>
<heading> Medal of honor: award to individual interred in Tomb of the Unknowns as representative of casualties of a war</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The medal of honor awarded posthumously to a deceased member of the armed forces who, as an unidentified casualty of a particular war or other armed conflict, is interred in the Tomb of the Unknowns at Arlington National Cemetery, Virginia, is awarded to the member as the representative of the members of the armed forces who died in such war or other armed conflict and whose remains have not been identified, and not to the individual personally.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 561(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1917</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1134a.</num>
<heading> Medal of honor: Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be in the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, the Department of the Air Force, and the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating a roll designated as the “Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enrollment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned shall enter and record on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll the name of each person who has served on active duty in the armed forces and who has been awarded a medal of honor pursuant to section 7271, 8291, or 9271 of this title or <ref>section 2732 of title 14</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuance of Enrollment Certificate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each living person whose name is entered on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll shall be issued a certificate of enrollment on the roll.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Entitlement to Special Pension; Notice to Secretary of Veterans Affairs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned shall deliver to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs a certified copy of each certificate of enrollment issued under subsection (c). The copy of the certificate shall authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to pay the special pension provided by <ref>section 1562 of title 38</ref> to the person named in the certificate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title V, § 563(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 767</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 684</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1135.</num>
<heading> Replacement of military decorations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Replacement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to other authorities available to the Secretary concerned to replace a military decoration, the Secretary concerned shall replace, on a one-time basis and without charge, a military decoration upon the request of the recipient of the military decoration or the immediate next of kin of a deceased recipient.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prompt Replacement Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When a request for the replacement of a military decoration is received under this section or section 7277, 7281, 8303, 9277, or 9281 of this title, the Secretary concerned shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all actions to be taken with respect to the request, including verification of the service record of the recipient of the military decoration, are completed within one year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the replacement military decoration is mailed to the person requesting the replacement military decoration within 90 days after verification of the service record.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Military Decoration Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “decoration” means any decoration or award (other than the medal of honor) that may be presented or awarded by the President or the Secretary concerned to a member of the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 571(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4471</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title V, § 564</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1136.</num>
<heading> Honorable service requirement for award of military decorations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No military decoration, including a medal, cross, or bar, or an associated emblem or insignia, may be awarded or presented to any person, or to a representative of the person, if the service of the person after the person distinguished himself or herself has not been honorable.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 582(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1411</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>