<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 853—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES NAVAL ACADEMY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8451.</num>
<heading> Location</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Naval Academy shall be located at Annapolis, Maryland.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 428</ref>, § 6951; renumbered § 8451, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8451a.</num>
<heading> Superintendent</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is a Superintendent of the United States Naval Academy. The immediate governance of the Naval Academy is under the Superintendent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Superintendent shall be detailed to that position by the President. As a condition for detail to that position, an officer shall acknowledge that upon termination of that detail the officer shall be retired pursuant to <ref>section 8371(a) of this title</ref>, unless such retirement is waived under <ref>section 8371(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An officer who is detailed to the position of Superintendent shall be so detailed for a period of not less than three years. In any case in which an officer serving as Superintendent is reassigned or retires before having completed three years service as Superintendent, or otherwise leaves that position (other than due to death) without having completed three years service in that position, the Secretary of the Navy shall submit to Congress notice that such officer left the position of Superintendent without having completed three years service in that position, together with a statement of the reasons why that officer did not complete three years service in that position.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 603</ref>, § 6951a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 541(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1903</ref>; renumbered § 8451a and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(c)(1), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8452.</num>
<heading> Civilian teachers: number; compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy may employ as many civilians as professors, instructors, and lecturers at the Naval Academy as he considers necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The compensation of persons employed under this section is as prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Navy may, notwithstanding the provisions of subchapter V of chapter 55 of title 5 or section 6101 of such title, prescribe for persons employed under this section the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The work schedule, including hours of work and tours of duty, set forth with such specificity and other characteristics as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any premium pay or compensatory time off for hours of work or tours of duty in excess of the regularly scheduled hours or tours of duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary, to the extent he considers proper, may delegate the authority conferred by this section to any person in the Department of the Navy, with or without the authority to make successive redelegations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 428</ref>, § 6952; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title XI, § 1107(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 778</ref>; renumbered § 8452, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8453.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Midshipmen at the Naval Academy shall be appointed by the President alone. An appointment is conditional until the midshipman is admitted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 429</ref>, § 6953; <ref>Pub. L. 97–60, title II, § 203(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-14">Oct. 14, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1006</ref>; renumbered § 8453, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8454.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: number</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The authorized strength of the Brigade of Midshipmen (determined for any year as of the day before the last day of the academic year) is 4,400 or such lower number as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy under subsection (h). Subject to that limitation, midshipmen are selected as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 65 selected in order of merit as established by competitive examination from the children of members of the armed forces who were killed in action or died of, or have a service-connected disability rated at not less than 100 per centum resulting from, wounds or injuries received or diseases contracted in, or preexisting injury or disease aggravated by, active service, children of members who are in a “missing status” as defined in <ref>section 551(2) of title 37</ref>, and children of civilian employees who are in “missing status” as defined in <ref>section 5561(5) of title 5</ref>. The determination of the Department of Veterans Affairs as to service connection of the cause of death or disability, and the percentage at which the disability is rated, is binding upon the Secretary of the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Five nominated at large by the Vice President or, if there is no Vice President, by the President pro tempore of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Ten from each State, five of whom are nominated by each Senator from that State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Five nominated by each Representative in Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Five from the District of Columbia, nominated by the Delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Four from the Virgin Islands, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Six from Puerto Rico, five of whom are nominated by the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico and one who is a native of Puerto Rico nominated by the Governor of Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Five from Guam, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from Guam.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Three from American Samoa, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from American Samoa.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Three from the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from the commonwealth.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each Senator, Representative, and Delegate in Congress, including the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico, is entitled to nominate 15 persons <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002171">1</ref> for each vacancy that is available to him under this section. Nominees may be submitted without ranking or with a principal candidate and 9 ranked or unranked alternates. Qualified nominees not selected for appointment under this subsection shall be considered qualified alternates for the purposes of selection under other provisions of this chapter. When a nominee of a Senator, Representative, or Delegate is selected for appointment as a midshipman, the Senator, Representative, or Delegate shall be notified at least 48 hours before the official notification or announcement of the appointment is made.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In addition there may be appointed each year at the Academy midshipmen as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> one hundred selected by the President from the children of members of an armed force who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are on active duty (other than for training) and who have served continuously on active duty for at least eight years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are, or who died while they were, retired with pay or granted retired or retainer pay;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> are serving as members of reserve components and are credited with at least eight years of service computed under <ref>section 12733 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> would be, or who died while they would have been, entitled to retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title except for not having attained 60 years of age;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">however, a person who is eligible for selection under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) may not be selected under this paragraph.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 85 nominated by the Secretary of the Navy from enlisted members of the Regular Navy and the Regular Marine Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> 85 nominated by the Secretary of the Navy from enlisted members of the Navy Reserve and the Marine Corps Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> 20 nominated by the Secretary of the Navy, under regulations prescribed by him, from the honor graduates of schools designated as honor schools by the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, or the Department of the Air Force, and from members of the Naval Reserve Officer’s Training corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> 200 <sup>1</sup> selected by the Secretary of the Navy in order of merit (prescribed pursuant to <ref>section 8456 of this title</ref>) from qualified alternates nominated by persons named in paragraphs (3) through (10) of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The President may also appoint as midshipmen at the Academy children of persons who have been awarded the medal of honor for acts performed while in the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Superintendent of the Naval Academy may nominate for appointment each year 50 persons from the country at large. Persons nominated under this paragraph may not displace any appointment authorized under paragraphs (2) through (9) of subsection (a) and may not cause the total strength of midshipmen at the Naval Academy to exceed the authorized number.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy may limit the number of midshipmen appointed under subsection (b)(5). When he does so, if the total number of midshipmen, upon admission of a new class at the Academy, will be more than 3,737, no appointments may be made under subsection (b)(2) or (3) of this section or <ref>section 8456 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Superintendent of the Naval Academy shall furnish to any Member of Congress, upon the written request of such Member, the name of the Congressman or other nominating authority responsible for the nomination of any named or identified person for appointment to the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> For purposes of the limitation in subsection (a) establishing the aggregate authorized strength of the Brigade of Midshipmen, the Secretary of the Navy may for any year permit a variance in that limitation by not more than one percent. In applying that limitation, and any such variance, the last day of an academic year shall be considered to be graduation day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Beginning with the 2003–2004 academic year, the Secretary of the Navy may prescribe annual increases in the midshipmen strength limit in effect under subsection (a). For any academic year, any such increase shall be by no more than 100 midshipmen or such lesser number as applies under paragraph (3) for that year. Such annual increases may be prescribed until the midshipmen strength limit is 4,400.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any increase in the midshipmen strength limit under paragraph (1) with respect to an academic year shall be prescribed not later than the date on which the budget of the President is submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> for the fiscal year beginning in the same year as the year in which that academic year begins. Whenever the Secretary prescribes such an increase, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a notice in writing of the increase. The notice shall state the amount of the increase in the midshipmen strength limit and the new midshipmen strength limit, as so increased, and the amount of the increase in Senior Navy Reserve Officers’ Training Corps enrollment under each of sections 2104 and 2107 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The amount of an increase under paragraph (1) in the midshipmen strength limit for an academic year may not exceed the increase (if any) for the preceding academic year in the total number of midshipmen enrolled in the Navy Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program under chapter 103 of this title who have entered into an agreement under section 2104 or 2107 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “midshipmen strength limit” means the authorized maximum strength of the Brigade of Midshipmen.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 429</ref>, § 6954; <ref>Pub. L. 87–651, title I, § 124</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 514</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–663, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-14">Sept. 14, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–276, § 2</ref>, <date date="1964-03-03">Mar. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 150</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–650, § 1(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="1966-10-13">Oct. 13, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 896</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–374</ref>, <date date="1968-07-05">July 5, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–623, § 2(8)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–405, title II, § 204(c)</ref>, <date date="1970-09-22">Sept. 22, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 852</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–365, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1972-08-07">Aug. 7, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 505</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–171, § 2(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="1973-11-29">Nov. 29, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 690</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–106, title VIII, § 803(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-07">Oct. 7, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–600, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–60, title II, § 203(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-14">Oct. 14, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1006</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(44)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title X, § 1005(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 660</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1602</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 532(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 531</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1657</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1673(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 532(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(62)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1903</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 531(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 602</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 531(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–109; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1228</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 532(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 524(b)</ref>, title X, § 1031(a)(55), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1464</ref>, 1603; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(Q)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VII, § 718(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 869</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 540(b), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4454</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 527(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(40)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 556(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 824</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 566(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2138</ref>; renumbered § 8454 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(c)(1), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 552(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 561(b), 562(b), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 273</ref>, 274.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8454a.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: nomination in event of death, resignation, or expulsion from office of Member of Congress otherwise authorized to nominate</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senators</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the event a Senator does not submit all nominations for midshipmen allocated to such Senator for an academic year in accordance with <ref>section 8454(a)(3) of this title</ref>, due to death, resignation from office, or expulsion from office, and the date of the swearing-in of the Senator’s successor as Senator occurs after the date of the deadline for submittal of nominations for midshipmen for the academic year, the nominations for midshipmen for such academic year, otherwise authorized to be made by the Senator pursuant to such section, may be made instead by the other Senator from the State of such Representative.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Representatives</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the event a Representative does not submit all nominations for midshipmen allocated to such Representative for an academic year in accordance with <ref>section 8454(a)(4) of this title</ref>, due to death, resignation from office, or expulsion from office, and the date of the swearing-in of the Representative’s successor as Representative occurs after the date of the deadline for submittal of nominations for midshipmen for the academic year, the nominations for midshipmen for such academic year, otherwise authorized to be made by the Representative pursuant to such section, may be made instead by the Senators from the State of such Representative, with such nominations divided equally among such Senators and any remainder going to the senior Senator from the State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The nomination of a midshipman by a Member of Congress pursuant to this section shall not be construed to permanently reallocate nominations under <ref>section 8454 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 553(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8455.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: allotment upon redistricting of Congressional Districts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If as a result of redistricting a State the domicile of a midshipman, or a nominee, nominated by a Representative falls within a congressional district other than that from which he was nominated, he is charged to the district in which his domicile so falls. For this purpose, the number of midshipmen otherwise authorized for that district is increased to include him. However, the number as so increased is reduced by one if he fails to become a midshipman or when he is finally separated from the Naval Academy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 430</ref>, § 6955; renumbered § 8455, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8456.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: nomination and selection to fill vacancies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> If the annual quota of midshipmen from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enlisted members of the Regular Navy and the Regular Marine Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enlisted members of the Navy Reserve and the Marine Corps Reserve; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at large by the President;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is not filled, the Secretary may fill the vacancies by nominating for appointment other candidates from any of these sources who were found best qualified on examination for admission and not otherwise nominated.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If it is determined that, upon the admission of a new class to the Academy, the number of midshipmen at the Academy will be below the authorized number, the Secretary may fill the vacancies by nominating additional midshipmen from qualified candidates designated as alternates and from other qualified candidates who competed for nomination and are recommended and found qualified by the Academic Board. At least three-fourths of those nominated under this subsection shall be from qualified alternates under paragraphs (2) through (8) of <ref>section 8454(a) of this title</ref>, and the remainder shall be from qualified candidates who competed for appointment under any other provision of law. An appointment of a nominee under this subsection is an additional appointment and is not in place of an appointment otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The failure of a member of a graduating class to complete the course with his class does not delay the appointment of his successor.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 430</ref>, § 6956; <ref>Pub. L. 88–276, § 3</ref>, <date date="1964-03-03">Mar. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–374</ref>, <date date="1968-07-05">July 5, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–171, § 2(4)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-29">Nov. 29, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 690</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–106, title VIII, § 803(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-07">Oct. 7, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–60, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1981-10-14">Oct. 14, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1007</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 532(b)(2)</ref>, title XIII, § 1322(a)(14), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1563</ref>, 1671; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(R)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(41)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1954</ref>; renumbered § 8456 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(c)(1), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8458.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: qualifications for admission</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Each candidate for admission to the Naval Academy—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> must be at least 17 years of age and must not have passed his twenty-third birthday on July 1 of the calendar year in which he enters the Academy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be examined according to such regulations as the Secretary of the Navy prescribes, and if rejected at one examination may not be examined again for admission to the same class unless recommended by the Academic Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each candidate for admission nominated under clauses (3) through (9) of <ref>section 8454(a) of this title</ref> must be domiciled in the State, or in the congressional district, from which he is nominated, or in the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, or the Virgin Islands, if nominated from one of those places.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Each candidate nominated under clause (2) or (3) of <ref>section 8454(b) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> must be a citizen of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> must have passed the required physical examination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be appointed in the order of merit from candidates who have, in competition with each other, passed the required mental examination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> To be admitted to the Naval Academy, an appointee must take and subscribe to an oath prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy. If a candidate for admission refuses to take and subscribe to the prescribed oath, the candidate’s appointment is terminated.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 431</ref>, § 6958; <ref>Pub. L. 87–663, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-14">Sept. 14, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–171, § 2(5)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-29">Nov. 29, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 690</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 532(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 555(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2527</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 541(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1740</ref>; renumbered § 8458 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(c)(1), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8459.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: service obligation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Each midshipman shall sign an agreement with respect to the midshipman’s length of service in the armed forces. The agreement shall provide that the midshipman agrees to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> That the midshipman will complete the course of instruction at the Naval Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> That upon graduation from the Naval Academy the midshipman—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> will accept an appointment, if tendered, as a commissioned officer of the Regular Navy, the Regular Marine Corps, or the Regular Air Force; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will serve on active duty for at least five years immediately after such appointment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> That if an appointment described in paragraph (2) is not tendered or if the midshipman is permitted to resign as a regular officer before completion of the commissioned service obligation of the midshipman, the midshipman—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> will accept an appointment as a commissioned officer in the Navy Reserve or the Marine Corps Reserve or as a Reserve in the Air Force for service in the Air Force Reserve; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will remain in that reserve component until completion of the commissioned service obligation of the midshipman.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> That if an appointment described in paragraph (2) or (3) is tendered and the midshipman participates in a program under <ref>section 2121 of this title</ref>, the midshipman will fulfill any unserved obligation incurred under this section on active duty, regardless of the type of appointment held, upon completion of, and in addition to, any service obligation incurred under <ref>section 2123 of this title</ref> for participation in such program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> That the midshipman may not obtain employment as a professional athlete until two years after the midshipman graduates from the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (4), the Secretary of the Navy may transfer to the Navy Reserve or the Marine Corps Reserve, and may order to active duty for such period of time as the Secretary prescribes (but not to exceed four years), a midshipman who breaches an agreement under subsection (a). The period of time for which a midshipman is ordered to active duty under this paragraph may be determined without regard to <ref>section 651(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A midshipman who is transferred to the Navy Reserve or Marine Corps Reserve under paragraph (1) shall be transferred in an appropriate enlisted grade or rating, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the purposes of paragraph (1), a midshipman shall be considered to have breached an agreement under subsection (a) if the midshipman is separated from the Naval Academy under circumstances which the Secretary determines constitute a breach by the midshipman of the midshipman’s agreement to complete the course of instruction at the Naval Academy and accept an appointment as a commissioned officer upon graduation from the Naval Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Each academic year, the Secretary of the Navy may transfer not more than three midshipmen, who obtain employment in violation of paragraph (5) of subsection (a), to the Selected Reserve of the Navy or the Selected Reserve of the Marine Corps. Each midshipman so transferred shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> serve as a commissioned officer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in an appropriate grade or rating, determined by the Secretary of the Navy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for a period, determined by the Secretary of the Navy, not longer than 10 years; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> while so serving, participate in efforts to recruit and retain members of the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Navy shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Those regulations shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> standards for determining what constitutes, for the purpose of subsection (b), a breach of an agreement under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> that a midshipman who obtains employment as a professional athlete—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in violation of paragraph (5) of subsection (a) has breached an agreement under such subsection unless such midshipman receives a transfer under paragraph (4) of subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at least two years after the midshipman graduates from the Academy has not breached an agreement under subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> procedures for determining whether such a breach has occurred; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> standards for determining the period of time for which a person may be ordered to serve on active duty under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In this section, “commissioned service obligation”, with respect to a midshipman, means the period beginning on the date of the midshipman’s appointment as a commissioned officer and ending on the sixth anniversary of such appointment or, at the discretion of the Secretary of Defense, any later date up to the eighth anniversary of such appointment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to a midshipman who is not a citizen or national of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a midshipman who is a minor and who has parents or a guardian, the midshipman may sign the agreement required by subsection (a) only with the consent of a parent or guardian.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> A midshipman or former midshipman who does not fulfill each term of the agreement as specified under subsection (a), or an alternative obligation imposed under subsection (b), shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 432</ref>, § 6959; <ref>Pub. L. 88–276, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-03-03">Mar. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–647, title III, § 301(19)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1072</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V</ref>, §§ 541(b), 542(c), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 512(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 624</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 511(c)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 531(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(S)</ref>, title VI, § 687(c)(10), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>, 3335; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(29)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 554(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4221</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 543(b)</ref>, title VI, § 618(a)(1)(L), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1395</ref>, 1426; renumbered § 8459, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 554(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1388</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 553(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 557(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8460.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: clothing and equipment; uniform allowance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy may prescribe the amount to be credited to a midshipman, upon original admission to the Naval Academy, for the cost of his initial issue of clothing and equipment. That amount shall be deducted from his pay. If a midshipman is discharged before graduation while owing the United States for pay advanced for the purchase of required clothing and equipment, he shall turn in as much of his clothing and equipment of a distinctively military nature as is necessary to repay the amount advanced. If the value of the clothing and equipment turned in does not cover the amount owed, the indebtedness shall be canceled.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 432</ref>, § 6960; renumbered § 8460, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8461.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: dismissal for best interests of the service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whenever the Superintendent of the Naval Academy believes that the continued presence of any midshipman at the Academy is contrary to the best interest of the service, he shall report in writing to the Secretary of the Navy a full statement of the facts upon which his belief is based. If the Secretary determines from the report that the Superintendent’s belief is well founded, the Secretary shall serve a copy of the report on the midshipman. Within such time as the Secretary considers reasonable, the midshipman shall show cause in writing why he should not be dismissed from the Academy. The Secretary, after consideration of any cause so shown, and with the written approval of the President, may dismiss the midshipman from the Academy and from the naval service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The truth of any issue of fact raised under subsection (a), except as to the record of demerits, shall be determined by a court of inquiry convened by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 432</ref>, § 6961; renumbered § 8461, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8462.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: discharge for unsatisfactory conduct or inaptitude</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Superintendent of the Naval Academy shall submit to the Secretary of the Navy in writing a full report of the facts—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whenever the Superintendent determines that the conduct of a midshipman is unsatisfactory; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whenever the Academic Board unanimously determines that midshipman possesses insufficient aptitude to become a commissioned officer in the naval service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A midshipman upon whom a report is made under subsection (a) shall be given an opportunity to examine the report and submit a written statement thereon. If the Secretary believes, on the basis of the report and statement, that the determination of the Superintendent or of the Academic Board is reasonable and well founded, he may discharge the midshipman from the Naval Academy and from the naval service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 432</ref>, § 6962; renumbered § 8462, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8463.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: discharge for deficiency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Midshipmen found deficient at any examination shall, unless the Academic Board recommends otherwise, be discharged from the Naval Academy and from the naval service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 433</ref>, § 6963; renumbered § 8463, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8464.</num>
<heading> Hazing: definition; prohibition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In this chapter, the term “hazing” means any unauthorized assumption of authority by a midshipman whereby another midshipman suffers or is exposed to any cruelty, indignity, humiliation, hardship, or oppression, or the deprivation or abridgement of any right.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Superintendent of the Naval Academy shall prescribe regulations, to be approved by the Secretary of the Navy, to prevent hazing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Hazing is an offense that may be dealt with as an offense against good order and discipline or as a violation of the regulations of the Naval Academy. However, no midshipman may be dismissed for a single act of hazing except by sentence of a court-martial.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The finding and sentence of a court-martial of a midshipman for hazing shall be reviewed in the manner prescribed for general court-martial cases.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A midshipman who is sentenced to imprisonment for hazing may not be confined with persons who have been convicted of crimes or misdemeanors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> A midshipman who is dismissed from the Academy for hazing may not be reappointed as a midshipman or be appointed as a commissioned officer in the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force until two years after the graduation of the class of which he was a member.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 433</ref>, § 6964; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1301(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 736</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(e)(8)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1605</ref>; renumbered § 8464, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8465.</num>
<heading> Failure to report violation: dismissal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each officer stationed at the Naval Academy, each midshipman officer, each midshipman petty officer, and each civilian member of the teaching staff of the Academy shall report promptly to the Superintendent of the Naval Academy any fact that tends to show the commission of hazing or any violation of an Academy regulation by a midshipman.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An officer of the naval service who fails to make a report required by subsection (a) shall be tried by court-martial and if convicted shall be dismissed from the naval service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A civilian member of the teaching staff of the Academy who fails to make a report required by subsection (a) shall, with the approval of the Secretary of the Navy, be dismissed by the Superintendent.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 433</ref>, § 6965; renumbered § 8465, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8466.</num>
<heading> Course of study</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The course at the Naval Academy is four years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy shall arrange the course so that classes will not be held on Sunday.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 434</ref>, § 6966; renumbered § 8466, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8467.</num>
<heading> Degree on graduation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy, the Superintendent of the Naval Academy may confer the degree of bachelor of science upon graduates of the Academy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 434</ref>, § 6967; renumbered § 8467, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8468.</num>
<heading> Board of Visitors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A Board of Visitors to the Academy is constituted annually of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the chair of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, or the designee of such chair;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the ranking member of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, or the designee of the ranking member;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> two other members of the Senate designated by the Majority Leader of the Senate, one of whom is a member of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> two other members of the Senate designated by the Minority Leader of the Senate, one of whom is a member of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the chair of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, or the designee of such chair;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the ranking member of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, or the designee of the ranking member;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> two other members of the House of Representatives designated by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, one of whom is a member of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> one other member of the House of Representatives designated by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> six persons designated by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The persons designated by the President serve for three years each except that any member whose term of office has expired shall continue to serve until his successor is appointed by the President. The President shall designate two persons each year to succeed the members whose terms expire that year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If a member of the Board dies or resigns, a successor shall be designated for the unexpired portion of the term by the official who designated the member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Board shall visit the Academy annually. With the approval of the Secretary of the Navy, the Board or its members may make other visits to the Academy in connection with the duties of the Board or to consult with the Superintendent of the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Board shall inquire into the state of morale and discipline, the curriculum, instruction, physical equipment, fiscal affairs, academic methods, and other matters relating to the Academy that the Board decides to consider.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Within 60 days after its annual visit, the Board shall submit a written report to the President and the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives of its action and of its views and recommendations pertaining to the Academy. Any report of a visit, other than the annual visit, shall, if approved by a majority of the members of the Board, be submitted to the President and the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives within 60 days after the approval.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Upon approval by the Secretary, the Board may call in advisers for consultation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> While performing his duties, each member of the Board and each adviser shall be reimbursed under Government travel regulations for his travel expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A majority of the members of the Board may call an official meeting of the Board once per year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A member may attend such meeting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in person, at the Academy; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> remotely, at the election of such member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 434</ref>, § 6968; <ref>Pub. L. 96–579, § 13(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-23">Dec. 23, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1061(e)(2)</ref>, title XV, § 1502(a)(12), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 443</ref>, 503; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; renumbered § 8468, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 554(b), 555(b), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1738</ref>, 1739; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 558(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1898</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8469.</num>
<heading> Band: composition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Naval Academy Band shall be composed of one leader, one second leader, and such enlisted members of the Navy as may be assigned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In determining years of service for the purpose of retirement, and in determining eligibility for reenlistment bonus, the members who are assigned as leader and second leader shall be treated as if they had not been so assigned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The enlisted members assigned to the Naval Academy Band shall be distributed in grade substantially the same as in the United States Navy Band.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 435</ref>, § 6969; <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 14c(52)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 501</ref>; renumbered § 8469, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8470.</num>
<heading> Permanent professors: promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer serving as a permanent professor may be recommended for promotion to the grade of captain or colonel, as the case may be, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy. The regulations shall include a competitive selection board process to identify those permanent professors best qualified for promotion. An officer so recommended shall be promoted by appointment to the higher grade by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective Date of Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If made, the promotion of an officer under subsection (a) shall be effective not earlier than three years after the selection of the officer as a permanent professor as described in that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 508(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 97</ref>, § 6970; renumbered § 8470, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8470a.</num>
<heading> Permanent professors: retirement for years of service; authority for deferral</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retirement for Years of Service</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b), an officer of the Navy or Marine Corps serving as a permanent professor at the Naval Academy in the grade of commander or lieutenant colonel who is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the grade of captain or colonel, as the case may be, shall, if not earlier retired, be retired on the first day of the month after the month in which the officer completes 28 years of active commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b), an officer of the Navy or Marine Corps serving as a permanent professor at the Naval Academy in the grade of captain or colonel who is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the grade of rear admiral (lower half) or brigadier general, as the case may be, shall, if not earlier retired, be retired on the first day of the month after the month in which the officer completes 30 years of active commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuation on Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer subject to retirement under subsection (a) may have his retirement deferred and be continued on active duty by the Secretary of the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subject to <ref>section 1252 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the Navy shall determine the period of any continuation on active duty under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility for Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A permanent professor at the Naval Academy in the grade of commander or lieutenant colonel who is continued on active duty as a permanent professor under subsection (b) remains eligible for consideration for promotion to the grade of captain or colonel, as the case may be.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retired Grade and Retired Pay</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each officer retired under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> unless otherwise entitled to a higher grade, shall be retired in the grade determined under section 1370 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002172">1</ref> of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is entitled to retired pay computed under <ref>section 8333 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 509(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3229</ref>, § 6970; renumbered § 6970a, <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 508(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 96</ref>; renumbered § 8470a and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(c)(1), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8471.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen’s store, trade shops, dairy, and laundry: nonappropriated fund instrumentality and accounts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operation as Nonappropriated Fund Instrumentality</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Superintendent of the Naval Academy shall operate the Naval Academy activities referred to in subsection (b) as a nonappropriated fund instrumentality under the jurisdiction of the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The nonappropriated fund instrumentality required under subsection (a) shall consist of the following Naval Academy activities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The midshipmen’s store.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The barber shop.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The cobbler shop.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The tailor shop.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The dairy (if any).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The laundry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonappropriated Fund Accounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Superintendent of the Naval Academy shall administer a separate nonappropriated fund account for each of the Naval Academy activities included in the nonappropriated fund instrumentality required under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crediting of Revenue</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Superintendent shall credit all revenue received from a Naval Academy activity referred to in subsection (b) to the account administered with respect to that activity under subsection (c), and amounts so credited shall be available for operating expenses of that activity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall be carried out under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 435</ref>, § 6971; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 38</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 376</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2736</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 370(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2871(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2015</ref>; renumbered § 8471, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8472.</num>
<heading> Chapel: crypt and window spaces</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The crypt and window spaces of the Naval Academy Chapel may be used only for memorials to officers of the Navy who have successfully commanded a fleet or squadron in battle or who have received the thanks of Congress for conspicuously distinguished services in time of war. No memorial to an officer may be accepted for, or installed in, the crypt or window spaces until at least five years after the death of that officer.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 435</ref>, § 6972; renumbered § 8472, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8473.</num>
<heading> Gifts, bequests, and loans of property: acceptance for benefit and use of Naval Academy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy may accept, hold, administer, and spend any gift or bequest of personal property, and may accept, hold, and administer any loan of personal property other than money, that is made on the condition that it be used for the benefit of, or for use in connection with, the Naval Academy or the Naval Academy Museum, its collection, or its services. Gifts and bequests of money and the proceeds from the sales of property received as gifts shall be deposited in the Treasury in the fund called “United States Naval Academy Gift and Museum Fund”. The Secretary may disburse funds deposited under this subsection for the benefit or use of the Naval Academy (including the Naval Academy Museum) subject to the terms of the gift or bequest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe written guidelines to be used for determinations of whether the acceptance of money, any personal property, or any loan of personal property under subsection (a) would reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Department of the Navy or any officer or employee of the Department of the Navy to carry out responsibilities or duties in a fair and objective manner, or would compromise either the integrity or the appearance of the integrity of any program of the Department of the Navy or any officer or employee of the Department of the Navy who is involved in any such program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For the purpose of Federal income, estate, and gift taxes, property that is accepted under this section is considered as a gift or bequest to or for the use of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Upon the request of the Secretary of the Navy, the Secretary of the Treasury may invest, reinvest, or retain investments of money or securities comprising any part of the United States Naval Academy Gift and Museum Fund in securities of the United States or in securities guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States. The interest and benefits accruing from those securities shall be deposited to the credit of the United States Naval Academy Gift and Museum Fund and may be disbursed as provided in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 436</ref>, § 6973; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title IX, § 942(c)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–241; renumbered § 8473, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8474.</num>
<heading> United States Naval Academy Museum Fund: references to Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any reference in a law, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the United States Naval Academy Museum Fund formerly maintained under this section shall be deemed to refer to the United States Naval Academy Gift and Museum Fund maintained under <ref>section 8473 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 436</ref>, § 6974; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title IX, § 942(d)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–242; renumbered § 8474 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(c)(1), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8475.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of guarantees with gifts for major projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary of the Navy may accept from a donor or donors a qualified guarantee for the completion of a major project for the benefit of the Naval Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligation Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of a qualified guarantee accepted under this section shall be considered as contract authority to provide obligation authority for purposes of Federal fiscal and contractual requirements. Funds available for a project for which such a guarantee has been accepted may be obligated and expended for the project without regard to whether the total amount of the funds and other resources available for the project (not taking into account the amount of the guarantee) is sufficient to pay for completion of the project.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Proposed Acceptance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may not accept a qualified guarantee under this section for the completion of a major project until after the expiration of 30 days following the date upon which a report of the facts concerning the proposed guarantee is submitted to Congress or, if earlier, the expiration of 14 days following the date on which a copy of the report is provided in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Commingling of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may not enter into any contract or other transaction involving the use of a qualified guarantee and appropriated funds in the same contract or transaction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major project</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “major project” means a project for the purchase or other procurement of real or personal property, or for the construction, renovation, or repair of real or personal property, the total cost of which is, or is estimated to be, at least $1,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified guarantee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “qualified guarantee”, with respect to a major project, means a guarantee that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is made by one or more persons in connection with a donation, specifically for the project, of a total amount in cash or securities that, as determined by the Secretary of the Navy, is sufficient to defray a substantial portion of the total cost of the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is made to facilitate or expedite the completion of the project in reasonable anticipation that other donors will contribute sufficient funds or other resources in amounts sufficient to pay for completion of the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is set forth as a written agreement that provides for the donor to furnish in cash or securities, in addition to the donor’s other gift or gifts for the project, any additional amount that may become necessary for paying the cost of completing the project by reason of a failure to obtain from other donors or sources funds or other resources in amounts sufficient to pay the cost of completing the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> is accompanied by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an irrevocable and unconditional standby letter of credit for the benefit of the Naval Academy that is in the amount of the guarantee and is issued by a major United States commercial bank; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a qualified account control agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified account control agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “qualified account control agreement”, with respect to a guarantee of a donor, means an agreement among the donor, the Secretary of the Navy, and a major United States investment management firm that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensures the availability of sufficient funds or other financial resources to pay the amount guaranteed during the period of the guarantee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides for the perfection of a security interest in the assets of the account for the United States for the benefit of the Naval Academy with the highest priority available for liens and security interests under applicable law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> requires the donor to maintain in an account with the investment management firm assets having a total value that is not less than 130 percent of the amount guaranteed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> requires the investment management firm, at any time that the value of the account is less than the value required to be maintained under subparagraph (C), to liquidate any noncash assets in the account and reinvest the proceeds in Treasury bills issued under <ref>section 3104 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major united states commercial bank</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “major United States commercial bank” means a commercial bank that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is an insured bank (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1813</ref>));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is headquartered in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has net assets in a total amount considered by the Secretary of the Navy to qualify the bank as a major bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major united states investment management firm</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “major United States investment management firm” means any broker, dealer, investment adviser, or provider of investment supervisory services (as defined in section 3 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78c</ref>) or section 202 of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 80b–2</ref>)) or a major United States commercial bank that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is headquartered in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> holds for the account of others investment assets in a total amount considered by the Secretary of the Navy to qualify the firm as a major investment management firm.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2871(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 873</ref>, § 6975; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1087(a)(17)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–291; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(56)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1603</ref>; renumbered § 8475, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8476.</num>
<heading> Operation of Naval Academy dairy farm</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Discretion Regarding Continued Operation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary of the Navy may terminate or reduce the dairy or other operations conducted at the Naval Academy dairy farm located in Gambrills, Maryland.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding the termination or reduction of operations at the Naval Academy dairy farm under paragraph (1), the real property containing the dairy farm (consisting of approximately 875 acres)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may not be declared to be excess real property to the needs of the Navy or transferred or otherwise disposed of by the Navy or any Federal agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be maintained in its rural and agricultural nature.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lease Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), to the extent that the termination or reduction of operations at the Naval Academy dairy farm permit, the Secretary of the Navy may lease the real property containing the dairy farm, and any improvements and personal property thereon, to such persons and under such terms as the Secretary considers appropriate. In leasing any of the property, the Secretary may give a preference to persons who will continue dairy operations on the property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any lease of property at the Naval Academy dairy farm shall be subject to a condition that the lessee maintain the rural and agricultural nature of the leased property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lease Proceeds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All money received from a lease entered into under subsection (b) shall be retained by the Superintendent of the Naval Academy and shall be available to cover expenses related to the property described in subsection (a), including reimbursing nonappropriated fund instrumentalities of the Naval Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Other Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in <ref>section 8471 of this title</ref> shall be construed to require the Secretary of the Navy or the Superintendent of the Naval Academy to operate a dairy farm for the Naval Academy in Gambrills, Maryland, or any other location.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2871(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2014</ref>, § 6976; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2814</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 851</ref>; renumbered § 8476 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(c)(1), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8477.</num>
<heading> Grants for faculty research for scientific, literary, and educational purposes: acceptance; authorized grantees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Research Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may authorize the Superintendent of the Academy to accept qualifying research grants under this section. Any such grant may only be accepted if the work under the grant is to be carried out by a professor or instructor of the Academy for a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifying Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A qualifying research grant under this section is a grant that is awarded on a competitive basis by an entity referred to in subsection (c) for a research project with a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Entities From Which Grants May be Accepted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A grant may be accepted under this section only from a corporation, fund, foundation, educational institution, or similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific, literary, or educational purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration of Grant Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish an account for administering funds received as research grants under this section. The Superintendent shall use the funds in the account in accordance with applicable regulations and the terms and conditions of the grants received.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Related Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the Academy may be used to pay expenses incurred by the Academy in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, award of a qualifying research grant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1063(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2130</ref>, § 6977; renumbered § 8477, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8478.</num>
<heading> Mixed-funded athletic and recreational extracurricular programs: authority to manage appropriated funds in same manner as nonappropriated funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a Naval Academy mixed-funded athletic or recreational extracurricular program, the Secretary of the Navy may designate funds appropriated to the Department of the Navy and available for that program to be treated as nonappropriated funds and expended for that program in accordance with laws applicable to the expenditure of nonappropriated funds. Appropriated funds so designated shall be considered to be nonappropriated funds for all purposes and shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “Naval Academy mixed-funded athletic or recreational extracurricular program” means an athletic or recreational extracurricular program of the Naval Academy to which each of the following applies:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The program is not considered a morale, welfare, or recreation program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The program is supported through appropriated funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The program is supported by a nonappropriated fund instrumentality.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The program is not a private organization and is not operated by a private organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 544(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1906</ref>, § 6978; renumbered § 8478, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8479.</num>
<heading> Midshipmen: charges and fees for attendance; limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), no charge or fee for tuition, room, or board for attendance at the Naval Academy may be imposed unless the charge or fee is specifically authorized by a law enacted after <date date="1994-10-05">October 5, 1994</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibition specified in subsection (a) does not apply with respect to any item or service provided to midshipmen for which a charge or fee is imposed as of <date date="1994-10-05">October 5, 1994</date>. The Secretary of Defense shall notify Congress of any change made by the Naval Academy in the amount of a charge or fee authorized under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 545(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1908</ref>, § 6979; renumbered § 8479, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8480.</num>
<heading> Policy on sexual harassment and sexual violence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under guidance prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Navy shall direct the Superintendent of the Naval Academy to prescribe a policy on sexual harassment and sexual violence applicable to the midshipmen and other personnel of the Naval Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matters To Be Specified in Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The policy on sexual harassment and sexual violence prescribed under this section shall include specification of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Programs to promote awareness of the incidence of rape, acquaintance rape, and other sexual offenses of a criminal nature that involve midshipmen or other Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Procedures that a midshipman should follow in the case of an occurrence of sexual harassment or sexual violence, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the midshipman chooses to report an occurrence of sexual harassment or sexual violence, a specification of the person or persons to whom the alleged offense should be reported and the options for confidential reporting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a specification of any other person whom the victim should contact; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> procedures on the preservation of evidence potentially necessary for proof of criminal sexual assault.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Procedures for disciplinary action in cases of alleged criminal sexual assault involving a midshipman or other Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any other sanction authorized to be imposed in a substantiated case of sexual harassment or sexual violence involving a midshipman or other Academy personnel in rape, acquaintance rape, or any other criminal sexual offense, whether forcible or nonforcible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Required training on the policy for all midshipmen and other Academy personnel, including the specific training required for personnel who process allegations of sexual harassment or sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Assessment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, through the Secretary of the Navy, shall direct the Superintendent to conduct at the Academy during each Academy program year an assessment, to be administered by the Department of Defense, to determine the effectiveness of the policies, training, and procedures of the Academy with respect to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For the assessment at the Academy under paragraph (1) with respect to an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year, the Secretary of the Navy shall conduct a survey, to be administered by the Department of Defense, of Academy personnel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to measure—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual violence events, on or off the Academy reservation, that have been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual violence events, on or off the Academy reservation, that have not been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to assess the perceptions of Academy personnel of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the policies, training, and procedures on sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the enforcement of such policies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the incidence of sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other issues relating to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may postpone the conduct of an assessment under this subsection if the Secretary determines that conducting such assessment is not practicable due to a war or national emergency declared by the President or Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that an assessment postponed under subparagraph (A) is conducted as soon as practicable after the end of the period of war or national emergency concerned, or earlier if the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall notify Congress of a determination under subparagraph (A) not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary makes such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy shall direct the Superintendent of the Naval Academy to submit to the Secretary a report on sexual harassment and sexual violence involving midshipmen or other personnel at the Academy for each Academy program year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, for the Academy program year covered by the report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The number of sexual assaults, rapes, and other sexual offenses involving midshipmen or other Academy personnel that have been reported to Naval Academy officials during the program year and, of those reported cases, the number that have been substantiated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The policies, procedures, and processes implemented by the Secretary of the Navy and the leadership of the Naval Academy in response to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving midshipmen or other Academy personnel during the program year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A plan for the actions that are to be taken in the following Academy program year regarding prevention of and response to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving midshipmen or other Academy personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each report under paragraph (1) for an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year shall include the results of the survey conducted in that program year under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy shall transmit to the Secretary of Defense, and to the Board of Visitors of the Naval Academy, each report received by the Secretary under this subsection, together with the Secretary’s comments on the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall transmit each such report, together with the Secretary’s comments on the report, to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration of Request for Transfer of a Midshipman Who Is the Victim of a Sexual Assault or Related Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy shall provide for timely consideration of and action on a request submitted by a midshipman appointed to the United States Naval Academy who is the victim of an alleged sexual assault or other offense covered by section 920, 920c, or 930 of this title (article 120, 120c, or 130 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice) for transfer to another military service academy or to enroll in a Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program affiliated with another institution of higher education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Navy shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection, within guidelines provided by the Secretary of Defense that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide that the Superintendent of the United States Naval Academy shall ensure that any midshipman who has been appointed to the United States Naval Academy and who is a victim of an alleged sexual assault or other offense referred to in paragraph (1), is informed of the right to request a transfer pursuant to this section, and that any formal request submitted by a midshipman is processed as expeditiously as practicable through the chain of command for review and action by the Superintendent;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> direct the Superintendent of the United States Naval Academy, in coordination with the Superintendent of the military service academy to which the midshipman requests to transfer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to take action on a request for transfer under this subsection not later than 72 hours after receiving the formal request from the midshipman;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to approve such request for transfer unless there are exceptional circumstances that require denial of the request; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> upon approval of such request, to take all necessary and appropriate action to effectuate the transfer of the midshipman to the military service academy concerned as expeditiously as possible; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> direct the Superintendent of the United States Naval Academy, in coordination with the Secretary of the military department that sponsors the Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program at the institution of higher education to which the midshipman requests to transfer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to take action on a request for transfer under this subsection not later than 72 hours after receiving the formal request from the midshipman;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> subject to the midshipman’s acceptance for admission to the institution of higher education to which the midshipman wishes to transfer, to approve such request for transfer unless there are exceptional circumstances that require denial of the application; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to take all necessary and appropriate action to effectuate the midshipman’s enrollment in the institution of higher education to which the midshipman wishes to transfer and to process the midshipman for participation in the relevant Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program as expeditiously as possible.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Superintendent of the United States Naval Academy denies a request for transfer under this subsection, the midshipman may request review of the denial by the Secretary of the Navy, who shall take action on such request not later than 72 hours after receipt of the formal request for review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall ensure that all records of any request, determination, transfer, or other action under this subsection remain confidential, consistent with applicable law and regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A midshipman who transfers under this subsection may retain the midshipman’s appointment to the United States Naval Academy or may be appointed to the military service academy to which the midshipman transfers without regard to the limitations and requirements set forth in sections 7442, 8454, and 9442 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2201</ref>, § 6980; renumbered § 8480, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 555(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1389</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 552(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3632</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8481.</num>
<heading> Support of athletic and physical fitness programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracts and cooperative agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Navy may enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with the Naval Academy Athletic Association for the purpose of supporting the athletic and physical fitness programs of the Naval Academy. Notwithstanding <ref>section 3201(e) of this title</ref>, the Secretary may enter such contracts or cooperative agreements on a sole source basis pursuant to <ref>section 3204(a)(5) of this title</ref>. Notwithstanding chapter 63 of title 31, a cooperative agreement under this section may be used to acquire property or services for the direct benefit or use of the Naval Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leases</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may enter into leases, in accordance with <ref>section 2667 of this title</ref>, or licenses with the Association for the purpose of supporting the athletic and physical fitness programs of the Naval Academy. Any such lease or license shall be deemed to satisfy the conditions of <ref>section 2667(h)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Navy Personal Property by the Association</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may allow the Association to use, at no cost, personal property of the Department of the Navy to assist the Association in supporting the athletic and physical fitness programs of the Naval Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Support.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support received from the association</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary may accept from the Association funds, supplies, and services for the support of the athletic and physical fitness programs of the Naval Academy. For purposes of this section, employees or personnel of the Association may not be considered to be employees of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funds received from ncaa</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may accept funds from the National Collegiate Athletic Association to support the athletic and physical fitness programs of the Naval Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that contributions under this subsection do not reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Department of the Navy, any of its employees, or any member of the armed forces to carry out any responsibility or duty in a fair and objective manner, or compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the Department of the Navy, or any individual involved in such a program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention and Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 2260(d) of this title</ref>, funds received under this section may be retained for use in support of athletic and physical fitness programs of the Naval Academy and shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Trademarks and Service Marks.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Licensing, marketing, and sponsorship agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agreement under subsection (a)(1) may, consistent with sections 2260 (other than subsection (d)) and 8022(b)(3) of this title, authorize the Association to enter into licensing, marketing, and sponsorship agreements relating to trademarks and service marks identifying the Naval Academy, subject to the approval of the Department of the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No such licensing, marketing, or sponsorship agreement may be entered into if it would reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Department of the Navy, any of its employees, or any member of the armed forces to carry out any responsibility or duty in a fair and objective manner, or if the Secretary determines that the use of the trademark or service mark would compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the Department of the Navy, or any individual involved in such a program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service on Association Board of Control</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Association is a designated entity for which authorization under sections 1033(a) and 1589(a) of this title may be provided.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The authority provided in this section with respect to the Association is available only so long as the Association continues to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> qualify as a nonprofit organization under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and operates in accordance with this section, the laws of the State of Maryland, and the constitution and bylaws of the Association; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> operate exclusively to support the athletic and physical fitness programs of the Naval Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Association Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Association” means the Naval Academy Athletic Association.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 542(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1735</ref>, § 6981; renumbered § 8481 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(c)(1), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>