<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 967—</num>
<heading>UTILITIES AND SERVICES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9591.</num>
<heading> Utilities: proceeds from overseas operations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During actual or threatened hostilities, proceeds from operating a public utility in connection with operations of the Air Force or the Space Force in the field overseas are available for that utility until the close of the fiscal year following that in which they are received.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 578</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(e)(6)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3816</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9592.</num>
<heading> Radiograms and telegrams: forwarding charges due connecting commercial facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the operation of telegraph lines, cables, or radio stations, members of the Air Force may, in the discretion of the Secretary of the Air Force, collect forwarding charges due connecting commercial telegraph or radio companies for sending radiograms or telegrams over their lines. Under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, they may present a voucher to a disbursing official for payment of the forwarding charge.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 578</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1052</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–316, title I, § 105(e)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9593.</num>
<heading> Quarters: heat and light</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The heat and light necessary for the authorized quarters of members of the Air Force and members of the Space Force shall be furnished at the expense of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 578</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(e)(7)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3816</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9594.</num>
<heading> Department of the Air Force Military History Institute: fee for providing historical information to the public</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary of the Air Force may charge a person a fee for providing the person with information from the United States Department of the Air Force Military History Institute that is requested by that person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A fee may not be charged under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to a person for information that the person requests to carry out a duty as a member of the armed forces or an officer or employee of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for a release of information under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A fee charged for providing information under this section may not exceed the cost of providing the information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention of Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts received under subsection (a) for providing information in any fiscal year shall be credited to the appropriation or appropriations charged the costs of providing information to the public from the United States Department of the Air Force Military History Institute during that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “United States Department of the Air Force Military History Institute” means the archive for historical records and materials of the Air Force and the Space Force that the Secretary of the Air Force designates as the primary archive for such records and materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The terms “officer of the United States” and “employee of the United States” have the meanings given the terms “officer” and “employee”, respectively, in sections 2104 and 2105, respectively, of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1085(c)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–289; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(e)(8)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3816</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>