<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 203—</num>
<heading>GENERAL MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3062.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense is required by <ref>section 2202 of this title</ref> to prescribe regulations governing the performance within the Department of Defense of the procurement functions, and related functions, of the Department of Defense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1807(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4157</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(2)(A)</ref>, (j), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2132</ref>, 2143.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3063.</num>
<heading> Covered agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of any provision of law referring to this section, the agencies named in this section are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Department of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Department of the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Department of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1807(c)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3064.</num>
<heading> Applicability of chapter 137 legacy provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any provision of this part that is a chapter 137 legacy provision applies to the procurement by any of the agencies named in <ref>section 3063 of this title</ref>, for its use or otherwise, of all property (other than land) and all services for which payment is to be made from appropriated funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability to Contracts for Installation or Alteration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provisions of this part that are chapter 137 legacy provisions that apply to the procurement of property apply also to contracts for its installation or alteration.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1807(c)(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4157</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2132</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3065.</num>
<heading> Assignment and delegation of procurement functions and responsibilities: delegation within agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except to the extent expressly prohibited by another provision of law, the head of an agency may delegate, subject to his direction, to any other officer or official of that agency, any power under any provision of this part that is a chapter 137 legacy provision.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 132</ref>, § 2311; <ref>Pub. L. 85–800, § 11</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 967</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–653, § 1(g)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-10">Sept. 10, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–378, § 3</ref>, <date date="1968-07-05">July 5, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX</ref>, §§ 907(c), 909(f), <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1117</ref>, 1120; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VII, § 2726</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1194</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XII, § 1214</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–577, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title I, § 1503(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(49)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1548</ref>; renumbered § 3065 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1807(d)(1)</ref>, (2)(A)–(C), (3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4157</ref>, 4158.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3066.</num>
<heading> Assignment and delegation of procurement functions and responsibilities: procurements for or with other agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to <ref>section 3065 of this title</ref>, to facilitate the procurement of property and services covered by any provision of this part that is a chapter 137 legacy provision by each agency named in <ref>section 3063 of this title</ref> for any other agency, and to facilitate joint procurement by those agencies—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the head of an agency may delegate functions and assign responsibilities relating to procurement to any officer or employee within such agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the heads of two or more agencies may by agreement delegate procurement functions and assign procurement responsibilities from one agency to another of those agencies or to an officer or civilian employee of another of those agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the heads of two or more agencies may create joint or combined offices to exercise procurement functions and responsibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1807(d)(2)(A)</ref>, (D), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3067.</num>
<heading> Approval required for military department termination or reduction in participation in joint acquisition programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval of Terminations and Reductions of Joint Acquisition Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations that prohibit each military department participating in a joint acquisition program approved by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment from terminating or substantially reducing its participation in such program without the approval of the Under Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Content of Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The regulations shall include the following provisions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A requirement that, before any such termination or substantial reduction in participation is approved, the proposed termination or reduction be reviewed by the Joint Requirements Oversight Council of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A provision that authorizes the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment to require a military department whose participation in a joint acquisition program has been approved for termination or substantial reduction to continue to provide some or all of the funding necessary for the acquisition program to be continued in an efficient manner.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1807(d)(2)(B)</ref>, (E), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3068.</num>
<heading> Inapplicability of certain laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Laws Inapplicable to Agencies Named in Section</inline> 3063.—</heading>
<content>Sections 6101 and 6304 of title 41 do not apply to the procurement or sale of property or services by the agencies named in <ref>section 3063 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Laws Inapplicable to Procurement of Automatic Data Processing Equipment and Services for Certain Defense Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of subtitle III of title 40, the term “national security system”, with respect to a telecommunications and information system operated by the Department of Defense, has the meaning given that term by <ref>section 3552(b)(6) of title 44</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1807(e)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4158</ref>, 4159; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2132</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3069.</num>
<heading> Buy-to-budget acquisition: end items</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Acquire Additional End Items</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Using funds available to the Department of Defense for the acquisition of an end item, the head of an agency making the acquisition may acquire a higher quantity of the end item than the quantity specified for the end item in a law providing for the funding of that acquisition if that head of an agency makes each of the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The agency has an established requirement for the end item that is expected to remain substantially unchanged throughout the period of the acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> It is possible to acquire the higher quantity of the end item without additional funding because of production efficiencies or other cost reductions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The amount of the funds used for the acquisition of the higher quantity of the end item will not exceed the amount provided under that law for the acquisition of the end item.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The amount so provided is sufficient to ensure that each unit of the end item acquired within the higher quantity is fully funded as a complete end item.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section. The regulations shall include, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The level of approval within the Department of Defense that is required for a decision to acquire a higher quantity of an end item under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Authority (subject to subsection (a)) to acquire up to 10 percent more than the quantity of an end item approved in a justification and approval of the use of procedures other than competitive procedures for the acquisition of the end item under sections 3201 through 3205 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The head of an agency is not required to notify Congress in advance regarding a decision under the authority of this section to acquire a higher quantity of an end item than is specified in a law described in subsection (a), but, except as provided in paragraph (2), shall notify the congressional defense committees of the decision not later than 30 days after the date of the decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A notification is not required under paragraph (1) if the end item being acquired in a higher quantity is an end item under a tactical missile program or a munitions program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver by Other Law</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A provision of law may not be construed as prohibiting the acquisition of a higher quantity of an end item under this section unless that provision of law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specifically refers to this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specifically states that the acquisition of the higher quantity of the end item is prohibited notwithstanding the authority provided in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, a quantity of an end item shall be considered specified in a law if the quantity is specified either in a provision of that law or in any related representation that is set forth separately in a table, chart, or explanatory text included in a joint explanatory statement or governing committee report accompanying the law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “end item” means a production product assembled, completed, and ready for issue or deployment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “head of an agency” means the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Navy, and the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VIII, § 801(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2600</ref>, § 2308; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1043(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 852</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2296</ref>; renumbered § 3069 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1807(f)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3070.</num>
<heading> Limitation on acquisition of excess supplies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Two-Year Supply</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may not incur any obligation against a stock fund of the Department of Defense for the acquisition of any item of supply if that acquisition is likely to result in an on-hand inventory (excluding war reserves) of that item of supply in excess of two years of operating stocks, or in the case of ship maintenance, overhaul, and repair, in excess of five years of operating stocks.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of a procuring activity may authorize the acquisition of an item of supply in excess of the limitation contained in subsection (a) if that activity head determines in writing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the acquisition is necessary to achieve an economical order quantity and will not result in an on-hand inventory (excluding war reserves) in excess of three years of operating stocks and that the need for the item is unlikely to decline during the period for which the acquisition is made; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that the acquisition is necessary for purposes of maintaining the industrial base, to protect against identified risk of supply chain disruptions, or for other reasons of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title III, § 317(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1338</ref>, § 2213; renumbered § 3070, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1807(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4159</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 812</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1979</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3072.</num>
<heading> Comptroller General assessment of acquisition programs and initiatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the congressional defense committees an annual assessment of selected acquisition programs and initiatives of the Department of Defense by March 30th of each year from 2020 through 2029.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Analyses To Be Included</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The assessment required under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a macro analysis of how well acquisition programs and initiatives are performing and reasons for that performance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specific analyses of individual acquisition programs and initiatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> other issues as determined appropriate by the Comptroller General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition Programs and Efforts </inline><ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002115">1</ref><inline class="small-caps"> to Be Considered</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The assessment required under subsection (a) shall consider the following programs and initiatives:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Selected weapon systems, as determined appropriate by the Comptroller General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Selected information technology systems and initiatives, including defense business systems, networks, and software-intensive systems, as determined appropriate by the Comptroller General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Selected prototyping and rapid fielding activities and initiatives, as determined appropriate by the Comptroller General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 833(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1858</ref>, § 2229b; renumbered § 3072 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 813</ref>, title XVIII, § 1807(g)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3749</ref>, 4159; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 812(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 813(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1980</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>