<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 134—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS ADMINISTRATIVE PROVISIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS AUTHORITIES, PROHIBITIONS, AND LIMITATIONS ON THE USE OF APPROPRIATED FUNDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2241.</num>
<heading> Availability of appropriations for certain purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operation and Maintenance Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance of the active forces may be used for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Morale, welfare, and recreation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Modification of personal property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Design of vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Industrial mobilization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Military communications facilities on merchant vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Acquisition of services, special clothing, supplies, and equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Expenses for the Reserve Officers’ Training Corps and other units at educational institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Necessary Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense may be used for all necessary expenses, at the seat of the Government or elsewhere, in connection with communication and other services and supplies that may be necessary for the national defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Activities of the National Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated for operation and maintenance may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, be used by the Secretary for official reception, representation, and advertising activities and materials of the National Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve to further employer commitments to their employees who are members of a reserve component.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation of Vienna Document</inline> 2011.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated for operation and maintenance may be used by the Secretary of Defense for travel, transportation, and subsistence expenses for meetings and demonstrations hosted by the Department of Defense for the implementation of the Vienna Document 2011 on Confidence and Security-Building Measures.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 844</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 518</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1462</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1043</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 389</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2241a.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on use of funds for publicity or propaganda purposes within the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds available to the Department of Defense may not be obligated or expended for publicity or propaganda purposes within the United States not otherwise specifically authorized by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2241b.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on contracts providing payments for activities at sporting events to honor members of the armed forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Department of Defense may not enter into any contract or other agreement under which payments are to be made in exchange for activities by the contractor intended to honor, or giving the appearance of honoring, members of the armed forces (whether members of the regular components or the reserve components) at any form of sporting event.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in subsection (a) shall be construed as prohibiting the Department of Defense from taking actions to facilitate activities intended to honor members of the armed forces at sporting events that are provided on a pro bono basis or otherwise funded with non-Federal funds if such activities are provided and received in accordance with applicable rules and regulations regarding the acceptance of gifts by the military departments, the armed forces, and members of the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 792</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2242.</num>
<heading> Authority to use appropriated funds for certain investigations and security services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of each military department may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pay in advance for the expenses of conducting investigations in foreign countries incident to matters relating to the Department of Defense, to the extent such expenses are determined by the investigating officer to be necessary and in accord with local custom;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> pay expenses incurred in connection with the administration of occupied areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> pay expenses of military courts, boards, and commissions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> reimburse the Administrator of General Services for security guard services furnished by the Administrator to the Department of Defense for the protection of confidential files.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 844</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2243.</num>
<heading> Authority to use appropriated funds to support student meal programs in overseas defense dependents’ schools</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (b), amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense for the operation of overseas defense dependents’ schools may be used by the Secretary of Defense to enable an overseas meal program to provide students enrolled in such a school with meals at a price equal to the average price paid by students for equivalent meals under a comparable public school meal program in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided by subsection (a) may be used only if the Secretary of Defense determines that Federal payments and commodities provided under section 20 of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1769b</ref>) and section 20 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1789</ref>) to support an overseas meal program are insufficient to provide meals under that program at a price for students equal to the average price paid by students for equivalent meals under a comparable public school meal program in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determining Average Price</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In determining the average price paid by students in the United States for meals under a school meal program, the Secretary of Defense shall exclude free and reduced price meals provided pursuant to income guidelines.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Overseas Meal Program Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “overseas meal program” means a program administered by the Secretary of Defense to provide breakfasts or lunches to students attending overseas defense dependents’ schools.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Overseas Defense Dependents’ School Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “overseas defense dependents’ school” means the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A school established as part of the defense dependents’ education system provided for under the Defense Dependents’ Education Act of 1978 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 921</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An elementary or secondary school established pursuant to <ref>section 2164 of this title</ref> that is located in a territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 326(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1415</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–78, title VII, § 752(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1169</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 573(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 830</ref>, 831.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2244.</num>
<heading> Security investigations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense may not be used for the conduct of an investigation by the Department of Defense, or by any other Federal department or agency, for purposes of determining whether to grant a security clearance to an individual or a facility unless the Secretary of Defense determines both of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> That a current, complete investigation file is not available from any other department or agency of the Federal Government with respect to that individual or facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> That no other department or agency of the Federal Government is conducting an investigation with respect to that individual or facility that could be used as the basis for determining whether to grant the security clearance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of subsection (a)(1), a current investigation file is a file on an investigation that has been conducted within the past five years.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title IX, § 904(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1621</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1473</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2244a.</num>
<heading> Equipment scheduled for retirement or disposal: limitation on expenditures for modifications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Secretary of a military department may not carry out a modification of an aircraft, weapon, vessel, or other item of equipment that the Secretary plans to retire or otherwise dispose of within five years after the date on which the modification, if carried out, would be completed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for below-threshold modifications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibition in subsection (a) does not apply to a modification for which the cost is less than $100,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for transfer of reusable items of value</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The prohibition in subsection (a) does not apply to a modification in a case in which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the reusable items of value, as determined by the Secretary, installed on the item of equipment as part of such modification will, upon the retirement or disposal of the item to be modified, be removed from such item of equipment, refurbished, and installed on another item of equipment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost of such modification (including the cost of the removal and refurbishment of reusable items of value under subparagraph (A)) is less than $1,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for safety modifications</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibition in subsection (a) does not apply to a safety modification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned may waive the prohibition in subsection (a) in the case of any modification otherwise subject to that subsection if the Secretary determines that carrying out the modification is in the national security interest of the United States. Whenever the Secretary issues such a waiver, the Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees in writing.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title III, § 372(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2245.</num>
<heading> Use of aircraft for proficiency flying: limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An aircraft under the jurisdiction of a military department may not be used by a member of the armed forces for the purpose of proficiency flying except in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Such regulations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may not require proficiency flying by a member except to the extent required for the member to maintain flying proficiency in anticipation of the member’s assignment to combat operations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not permit proficiency flying in the case of a member who is assigned to a course of instruction of 90 days or more.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “proficiency flying” means flying performed under competent orders by a rated or designated member of the armed forces while serving in a non-aviation assignment or in an assignment in which skills would normally not be maintained in the performance of assigned duties.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1481(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1706</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1077</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 333</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2245a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 833(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2284</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2246.</num>
<heading> Authorization of certain support for military service academy foundations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (b) and pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Superintendent of a Service Academy may authorize a covered foundation to use, on an unreimbursed basis, facilities or equipment of such Service Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Use of facilities or equipment under subsection (a) may be provided only if such use—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is without any liability of the United States to the covered foundation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> does not affect the ability of any official or employee of the military department concerned, or any member of the armed forces, to carry out any responsibility or duty in a fair and objective manner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> does not compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the military department concerned, or any individual involved in such a program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> does not include the participation of any cadet or midshipman, other than participation in an honor guard at an event of the covered foundation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> complies with the Joint Ethics Regulation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> has been reviewed and approved by an attorney of the military department concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Briefing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any fiscal year during which the Superintendent of a Service Academy exercises the authority under subsection (a), the Secretary of the military department concerned shall provide a briefing not later than the last day of that fiscal year to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives regarding the number of events or activities of a covered foundation supported by such exercise during such fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered foundation” means a charitable, educational, or civic nonprofit organization under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, that the Secretary concerned determines operates exclusively to support, with respect to a Service Academy, any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Recruiting.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Parent or alumni development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Academic, leadership, or character development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Institutional development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Athletics.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Service Academy” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 347 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 551(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2591</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2247.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2491b]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2248.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1045(a)(5)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1612</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2249.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4652]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2249a.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 361]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2249b.</num>
<heading> Display of State, District of Columbia, commonwealth, and territorial flags by the armed forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Display of Flags by Armed Forces</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, whenever the official flags of all 50 States are displayed by the armed forces, such display shall include the flags of the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Position and Manner of Display</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The display of an official flag of a State, territory, or possession of the United States at an installation or other facility of the Department shall be governed by <ref>section 7 of title 4</ref> and any modification of section 7 under <ref>section 10 of title 4</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2656</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–225, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-08-12">Aug. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 588(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1768</ref>, 1769.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2249c.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 345]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2249d.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 346]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2249e.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 362]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS ADMINISTRATIVE AUTHORITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2251.</num>
<heading> Household furnishings and other property: personnel outside the United States or in Alaska or Hawaii</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of the military department concerned may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> purchase household furnishings and automobiles from members of the armed forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense on duty outside the United States or in Hawaii for resale at cost to incoming personnel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide household furnishings, without charge, in other than public quarters occupied by members of the armed forces or civilian employees of the Department of Defense who are on duty outside the United States or in Alaska or Hawaii.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided in subsection (a) may be used only when it is determined, under regulations approved by the Secretary of Defense, that the use of that authority would be advantageous to the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2252.</num>
<heading> Rewards: missing property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of each military department may pay a reward of not more than $500 in any case for information leading to the discovery of missing property under the jurisdiction of that Secretary or leading to the recovery of such property.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2253.</num>
<heading> Motor vehicles</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of each military department may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide for insurance of official motor vehicles in a foreign country when the laws of such country require such insurance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> purchase right-hand drive passenger sedans at a cost of not more than $30,000 each.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hire of Passenger Vehicles</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance of the active forces may be used for the hire of passenger motor vehicles.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 845</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VIII, § 805</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 814(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1491</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2254.</num>
<heading> Treatment of reports of aircraft accident investigations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever the Secretary of a military department conducts an accident investigation of an accident involving an aircraft under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, the records and report of the investigations shall be treated in accordance with this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, an accident investigation is any form of investigation of an aircraft accident other than an investigation (known as a “safety investigation”) that is conducted solely to determine the cause of the accident and to obtain information that may prevent the occurrence of similar accidents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Disclosure of Certain Accident Investigation Information</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned, upon request, shall publicly disclose unclassified tapes, scientific reports, and other factual information pertinent to an aircraft accident investigation, before the release of the final accident investigation report relating to the accident, if the Secretary concerned determines—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that such tapes, reports, or other information would be included within and releasable with the final accident investigation report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> that release of such tapes, reports, or other information—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> would not undermine the ability of accident or safety investigators to continue to conduct the investigation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> would not compromise national security.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A disclosure under paragraph (1) may not be made by or through officials with responsibility for, or who are conducting, a safety investigation with respect to the accident.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Opinions Regarding Causation of Accident</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Following a military aircraft accident—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if the evidence surrounding the accident is sufficient for the investigators who conduct the accident investigation to come to an opinion (or opinions) as to the cause or causes of the accident, the final report of the accident investigation shall set forth the opinion (or opinions) of the investigators as to the cause or causes of the accident; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the evidence surrounding the accident is not sufficient for those investigators to come to an opinion as to the cause or causes of the accident, the final report of the accident investigation shall include a description of those factors, if any, that, in the opinion of the investigators, substantially contributed to or caused the accident.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Information in Civil Proceedings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of any civil or criminal proceeding arising from an aircraft accident, any opinion of the accident investigators as to the cause of, or the factors contributing to, the accident set forth in the accident investigation report may not be considered as evidence in such proceeding, nor may such information be considered an admission of liability by the United States or by any person referred to in those conclusions or statements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each military department shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2254a.</num>
<heading> Data files of military flight operations quality assurance systems: exemption from disclosure under Freedom of Information Act</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority to Exempt Certain Data Files From Disclosure Under FOIA.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may exempt information contained in any data file of the military flight operations quality assurance system of a military department from disclosure under <ref>section 552(b)(3) of title 5</ref>, upon a written determination that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the information is sensitive information concerning military aircraft, units, or aircrew; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the public interest consideration in the disclosure of such information does not outweigh preventing the disclosure of such information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In this section, the term “data file” means a file of the military flight operations quality assurance (in this section referred to as “MFOQA”) system that contains information acquired or generated by the MFOQA system, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any data base containing raw MFOQA data; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any analysis or report generated by the MFOQA system or which is derived from MFOQA data.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Information that is exempt under paragraph (1) from disclosure under <ref>section 552(b)(3) of title 5</ref> shall be exempt from such disclosure even if such information is contained in a data file that is not exempt in its entirety from such disclosure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The provisions of paragraph (1) may not be superseded except by a provision of law which is enacted after the date of the enactment of this section and which specifically cites and repeals or modifies those provisions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section. Such regulations shall ensure consistent application of the authority in subsection (a) across the military departments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transparency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each determination of the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be made in writing and accompanied by a statement of the basis for the determination. All such determinations and statements of basis shall be available to the public, upon request.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1082(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1600</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title IX, § 901(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2255.</num>
<heading> Aircraft accident investigation boards: composition requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Membership of Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whenever the Secretary of a military department convenes an aircraft accident investigation board to conduct an accident investigation (as described in <ref>section 2254(a)(2) of this title</ref>) with respect to a Class A accident involving an aircraft under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, the Secretary shall select the membership of the board so that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a majority of the members (or in the case of a board consisting of a single member, the member) is selected from units other than the mishap unit or a unit subordinate to the mishap unit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a board consisting of more than one member, at least one member of the board is a member of the armed forces or an officer or an employee of the Department of Defense who possesses knowledge and expertise relevant to aircraft accident investigations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the military department concerned may waive the requirement of subsection (a)(1) in the case of an aircraft accident if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> it is not practicable to meet the requirement because of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the remote location of the aircraft accident;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an urgent need to promptly begin the investigation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a lack of available persons outside of the mishap unit who have adequate knowledge and expertise regarding the type of aircraft involved in the accident; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the objectivity and independence of the aircraft accident investigation board will not be compromised.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of an aircraft accident investigation board consisting of a single member, the member shall consult with a member of the armed forces or an officer or an employee of the Department of Defense who possesses knowledge and expertise relevant to aircraft accident investigations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Class A Accidents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 60 days after an aircraft accident involving an aircraft under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of a military department, the Secretary shall determine whether the aircraft accident should be designated as a Class A accident for purposes of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Class A accident” means an accident involving an aircraft that results in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the loss of life or permanent disability;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> damages to the aircraft, other property, or a combination of both, in an amount in excess of the amount specified by the Secretary of Defense for purposes of determining Class A accidents; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the destruction of the aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “mishap unit”, with respect to an aircraft accident investigation, means the unit of the armed forces (at the squadron or battalion level or equivalent) to which was assigned the flight crew of the aircraft that sustained the accident that is the subject of the investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2621</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1597</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2257.</num>
<heading> Use of recruiting materials for public relations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may use for public relations purposes of the Department of Defense any advertising materials developed for use for recruitment and retention of personnel for the armed forces. Any such use shall be under such conditions and subject to such restrictions as the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 574(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 624</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2259.</num>
<heading> Transit pass program: personnel in poor air quality areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To encourage Department of Defense personnel assigned to duty, or employed, in poor air quality areas to use means other than single-occupancy motor vehicles to commute to or from the location of their duty assignments, the Secretary of Defense shall exercise the authority provided in <ref>section 7905 of title 5</ref> to establish a program to provide a transit pass benefit under subsection (b)(2)(A) of that section for members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force who are assigned to duty, and to Department of Defense civilian officers and employees who are employed, in a poor air quality area.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Poor Air Quality Areas</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “poor air quality area” means an area—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that is subject to the national ambient air quality standards promulgated by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 7409</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that, as determined by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, is a nonattainment area with respect to any of those standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1082(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–285; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(1)(O)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2260.</num>
<heading> Licensing of intellectual property: retention of fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary concerned may license trademarks, service marks, certification marks, and collective marks owned or controlled by the Secretary concerned and may retain and expend fees received from such licensing in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designated Marks</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned shall designate the trademarks, service marks, certification marks, and collective marks regarding which the Secretary will exercise the authority to retain licensing fees under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Licenses for Qualifying Companies</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may license trademarks, service marks, certification marks, and collective marks owned or controlled by the Secretary relating to military designations and likenesses of military weapons systems to any qualifying company upon receipt of a request from the company.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), a qualifying company is any United States company that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a toy or hobby manufacturer; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is determined by the Secretary concerned to be qualified in accordance with such criteria as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The fee for a license under this subsection shall not exceed by more than a nominal amount the amount needed to recover all costs of the Department of Defense in processing the request for the license and supplying the license.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A license to a qualifying company under this subsection shall provide that the license may not be transferred, sold, or relicensed by the qualifying company.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A license under this subsection shall not be an exclusive license.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary concerned shall use fees retained under this section for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For payment of the following costs incurred by the Secretary:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Costs of securing trademark registrations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Costs of operating the licensing program under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For morale, welfare, and recreation activities under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, to the extent (if any) that the total amount of the licensing fees available under this section for a fiscal year exceed the total amount needed for such fiscal year under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Fees received in a fiscal year and retained under this section shall be available for obligation in such fiscal year and the following two fiscal years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The terms “trademark”, “service mark”, “certification mark”, and “collective mark” have the meanings given such terms in <ref>section 45 of the Act of July 5, 1946</ref> (commonly referred to as the Trademark Act of 1946; <ref>15 U.S.C. 1127</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Secretary concerned” has the meaning provided in <ref>section 101(a)(9) of this title</ref> and also includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense, with respect to matters concerning the Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Homeland Security, with respect to matters concerning the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Department of the Navy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1004(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2035</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VIII, § 882(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 263</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 881, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4559</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2261.</num>
<heading> Presentation of recognition items for recruitment and retention purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expenditures for Recognition Items</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, appropriated funds may be expended—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to procure recognition items of nominal or modest value for recruitment or retention purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to present such items—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to members of the armed forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to members of the families of members of the armed forces, and other individuals, recognized as providing support that substantially facilitates service in the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provision of Meals and Refreshments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of <ref>section 520c of this title</ref> and any regulation prescribed to implement that section, functions conducted for the purpose of presenting recognition items described in subsection (a) shall be treated as recruiting functions, and recipients of such items shall be treated as persons who are the objects of recruiting efforts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recognition Items of Nominal or Modest Value</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “recognition item of nominal or modest value” means a commemorative coin, medal, trophy, badge, flag, poster, painting, or other similar item that is valued at less than $50 per item and is designed to recognize or commemorate service in the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 589(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3279</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 594</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2262.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense conferences: collection of fees to cover Department of Defense costs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Collect Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may collect fees from any individual or commercial participant in a conference, seminar, exhibition, symposium, or similar meeting conducted by the Department of Defense (in this section referred to collectively as a “conference”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may provide for the collection of fees under this section directly or by contract. The fees may be collected in advance of a conference.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Collected Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts collected under subsection (a) with respect to a conference shall be credited to the appropriation or account from which the costs of the conference are paid and shall be available to pay the costs of the Department of Defense with respect to the conference or to reimburse the Department for costs incurred with respect to the conference.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Excess Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the event the total amount of fees collected under subsection (a) with respect to a conference exceeds the actual costs of the Department of Defense with respect to the conference, the amount of such excess shall be deposited into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2395</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2263.</num>
<heading> United States contributions to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization common-funded budgets</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total amount contributed by the Secretary of Defense in any fiscal year for the common-funded budgets of NATO may be an amount in excess of the maximum amount that would otherwise be applicable to those contributions in such fiscal year under the fiscal year 1998 baseline limitation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Common-funded budgets of nato</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “common-funded budgets of NATO” means the Military Budget, the Security Investment Program, and the Civil Budget of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (and any successor or additional account or program of NATO).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fiscal year 1998 baseline limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “fiscal year 1998 baseline limitation” means the maximum annual amount of Department of Defense contributions for common-funded budgets of NATO that is set forth as the annual limitation in section 3(2)(C)(ii) of the resolution of the Senate giving the advice and consent of the Senate to the ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and the Czech Republic (as defined in section 4(7) of that resolution), approved by the Senate on <date date="1998-04-30">April 30, 1998</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title X, § 1004(a)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4582</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2264.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement for assistance provided to nongovernmental entertainment-oriented media producers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be credited to the applicable appropriations account or fund from which the expenses described in subsection (b) were charged any amounts received by the Department of Defense as reimbursement for such expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Description of Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The expenses referred to in subsection (a) are any expenses—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> incurred by the Department of Defense as a result of providing assistance to a nongovernmental entertainment-oriented media producer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for which the Department of Defense requires reimbursement under <ref>section 9701 of title 31</ref> or any other provision of law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for which the Department of Defense received reimbursement after <date date="2014-12-19">December 19, 2014</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title VIII, § 859(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3461</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(29)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1595</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2265.</num>
<heading> Access to broadband internet access service for certain members of the armed forces</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of a military department may provide, to a member of the armed forces who resides in military unaccompanied housing (as defined in <ref>section 2871 of this title</ref>) within the United States, broadband internet access service, at no cost to such member.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VI, § 651(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>