<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 835—</num>
<heading>BANDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8286.</num>
<heading> United States Navy Band; officer in charge</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is a Navy band known as the United States Navy Band.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer of the Navy designated for limited duty under section 8139 or 8146 of this title who is serving in a grade above lieutenant may be detailed by the Secretary of the Navy as Officer in Charge of the United States Navy Band.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> While serving as Officer in Charge of the United States Navy Band, an officer shall hold the grade of captain if appointed to that grade by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Such an appointment may be made notwithstanding <ref>section 8146(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 388</ref>, § 6221; <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 14c(44)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(16)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2932</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 510(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1091</ref>; renumbered § 8286 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(b)(12), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8287.</num>
<heading> United States Marine Band; United States Marine Drum and Bugle Corps: composition; appointment and promotion of members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United States Marine Band</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The band of the Marine Corps shall be composed of one director, two assistant directors, and other personnel in such numbers and grades as the Secretary of the Navy determines to be necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United States Marine Drum and Bugle Corps</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The drum and bugle corps of the Marine Corps shall be composed of one commanding officer and other personnel in such numbers and grades as the Secretary of the Navy determines to be necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment and Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy shall prescribe regulations for the appointment and promotion of members of the Marine Band and members of the Marine Drum and Bugle Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The President may from time to time appoint members of the Marine Band and members of the Marine Drum and Bugle Corps to grades not above the grade of captain. The authority of the President to make appointments under this paragraph may be delegated only to the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, may from time to time appoint any member of the Marine Band or of the Marine Drum and Bugle Corps to a grade above the grade of captain.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless otherwise entitled to higher retired grade and retired pay, a member of the Marine Band or Marine Drum and Bugle Corps who holds, or has held, an appointment under this section is entitled, when retired, to be retired in, and with retired pay based on, the highest grade held under this section in which the Secretary of the Navy determines that such member served satisfactorily.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Revocation of Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Navy may revoke any appointment of a member of the Marine Band or Marine Drum and Bugle Corps. When a member’s appointment to a commissioned grade terminates under this subsection, such member is entitled, at the option of such member—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to be discharged from the Marine Corps; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to revert to the grade and status such member held at the time of appointment under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 388</ref>, § 6222; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(140)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 14c(45)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–197</ref>, <date date="1970-02-24">Feb. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 15</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(18)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2932</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 599(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2238</ref>; renumbered § 8287, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(12)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>