<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 907—</num>
<heading>THE AIR FORCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9061.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may prescribe regulations for the government of the Air Force.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 493</ref>, § 8061; renumbered § 9061, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9062.</num>
<heading> Policy; composition; aircraft authorization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> It is the intent of Congress to provide an Air Force that is capable, in conjunction with the other armed forces, of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> preserving the peace and security, and providing for the defense, of the United States, the Commonwealths and possessions, and any areas occupied by the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> supporting the national policies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> implementing the national objectives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> overcoming any nations responsible for aggressive acts that imperil the peace and security of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There is a United States Air Force within the Department of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In general, the Air Force includes aviation forces both combat and service not otherwise assigned. It shall be organized, trained, and equipped primarily for prompt and sustained offensive and defensive air operations. It is responsible for the preparation of the air forces necessary for the effective prosecution of war except as otherwise assigned and, in accordance with integrated joint mobilization plans, for the expansion of the peacetime components of the Air Force to meet the needs of war.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The Air Force consists of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Regular Air Force, the Air National Guard of the United States, the Air National Guard while in the service of the United States, and the Air Force Reserve;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all persons appointed or enlisted in, or conscripted into, the Air Force without component; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> all Air Force units and other Air Force organizations, with their installations and supporting and auxiliary combat, training, administrative, and logistic elements; and all members of the Air Force, including those not assigned to units; necessary to form the basis for a complete and immediate mobilization for the national defense in the event of a national emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (f) of this section, chapter 911 of this title, and the strength authorized by law pursuant to <ref>section 115 of this title</ref>, the authorized strength of the Air Force is 70 Regular Air Force groups and such separate Regular Air Force squadrons, reserve groups, and supporting and auxiliary regular and reserve units as required.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> There are authorized for the Air Force 24,000 serviceable aircraft or 225,000 airframe tons of serviceable aircraft, whichever the Secretary of the Air Force considers appropriate to carry out this section. This subsection does not apply to guided missiles.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Effective <date date="2011-10-01">October 1, 2011</date>, the Secretary of the Air Force shall maintain a total aircraft inventory of strategic airlift aircraft of not less than 301 aircraft. Effective on the date that is 45 days after the date on which the report under section 141(c)(3) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 is submitted to the congressional defense committees, the Secretary shall maintain a total aircraft inventory of strategic airlift aircraft of not less than 275 aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “strategic airlift aircraft” means an aircraft—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that has a cargo capacity of at least 150,000 pounds; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that is capable of transporting outsized cargo an unrefueled range of at least 2,400 nautical miles.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “outsized cargo” means any single item of equipment that exceeds 1,090 inches in length, 117 inches in width, or 105 inches in height.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(h)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title I, § 132(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3430</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During the period beginning on <date date="2017-10-01">October 1, 2017</date>, and ending on <date date="2026-10-01">October 1, 2026</date>, the Secretary of the Air Force shall maintain a total aircraft inventory of fighter aircraft of not less than 1,800 aircraft, and a total primary mission aircraft inventory (combat-coded) of not less than 1,145 fighter aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “fighter aircraft” means an aircraft that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is designated by a mission design series prefix of F– or A–;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is manned by one or two crewmembers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> executes single-role or multi-role missions, including air-to-air combat, air-to-ground attack, air interdiction, suppression or destruction of enemy air defenses, close air support, strike control and reconnaissance, combat search and rescue support, or airborne forward air control.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “primary mission aircraft inventory” means aircraft assigned to meet the primary aircraft authorization to a unit for the performance of its wartime mission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of the Air Force shall maintain a total aircraft inventory of air refueling tanker aircraft of not less than 466 aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Air Force may reduce the number of air refueling tanker aircraft in the total aircraft inventory of the Air Force below 466 only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary certifies to the congressional defense committees that such reduction is justified by the results of the mobility capability and requirements study conducted under section 144(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 (<ref>Public Law 115–91</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a period of 30 days has elapsed following the date on which the certification is made to the congressional defense committees under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “air refueling tanker aircraft” means an aircraft that has as its primary mission the refueling of other aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “total aircraft inventory” means aircraft authorized to a flying unit for operations or training.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> During the period beginning on the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 and ending on <date date="2027-09-30">September 30, 2027</date>, the Secretary of the Air Force may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> retire an F–22 aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reduce funding for unit personnel or weapon system sustainment activities for F–22 aircraft in a manner that presumes future congressional authority to divest such aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> keep an F–22 aircraft in a status considered excess to the requirements of the possessing command and awaiting disposition instructions (commonly referred to as “XJ” status); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> decrease the total aircraft inventory of F–22 aircraft below 184 aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The prohibition under paragraph (1) shall not apply to individual F–22 aircraft that the Secretary of the Air Force determines, on a case-by-case basis, to be no longer mission capable and uneconomical to repair because of aircraft accidents, mishaps, or excessive material degradation and non-airworthiness status of certain aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> During the period beginning on the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 and ending on <date date="2029-09-30">September 30, 2029</date>, the Secretary of the Air Force may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> retire more than 68 F–15E aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reduce funding for unit personnel or weapon system sustainment activities for retained F–15E aircraft in a manner that presumes future congressional authority to divest such aircraft; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> keep an F–15E aircraft (other than an aircraft identified for retirement under subparagraph (A)) in a status considered excess to the requirements of the possessing command and awaiting disposition instructions (commonly referred to as “XJ” status).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The prohibition under paragraph (1) shall not apply to individual F–15E aircraft that the Secretary of the Air Force determines, on a case-by-case basis, to be no longer mission capable and uneconomical to repair because of aircraft accidents, mishaps, or excessive material degradation and non-airworthiness status of certain aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> During the period beginning on the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 and ending on <date date="2029-09-30">September 30, 2029</date>, the Secretary of the Air Force may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> retire an RQ–4 aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reduce funding for unit personnel or weapon system sustainment activities for RQ–4 aircraft in a manner that presumes future congressional authority to divest such aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> keep an RQ–4 aircraft in a status considered excess to the requirements of the possessing command and awaiting disposition instructions (commonly referred to as “XJ” status); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> decrease the total aircraft inventory of RQ–4 aircraft below 10 aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The prohibition under paragraph (1) shall not apply to individual RQ–4 aircraft that the Secretary of the Air Force determines, on a case-by-case basis, to be no longer mission capable and uneconomical to repair because of aircraft accidents, mishaps, or excessive material degradation and non-airworthiness status of certain aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 493</ref>, § 8062; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 504(4)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2916</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title I, § 110(g)(10)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1004</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XIII, § 1314(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1176</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title I, § 132</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2112</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title I, § 139</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title I, § 131</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1320</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 141(a), 142(a), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1659</ref>, 1662; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title I, § 131(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1314</ref>; renumbered § 9062 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title I, § 141(a)</ref>, title VIII, §§ 806(c), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1666</ref>, 1833, 1840; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title I, § 132(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3430</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title I, § 131(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 141(a), 142(a), 143(a), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2452</ref>, 2453; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 131(a), 132, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 171</ref>, 172; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title I, § 141</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1808</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9062a.</num>
<heading> Annual report on Air Force tactical fighter aircraft force structure.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002178">1</ref></heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than <date date="2025-04-01">April 1, 2025</date>, and annually thereafter through 2029, the Secretary of the Air Force, in consultation with the Director of the Air National Guard and the Commander of the Air Force Reserve Command, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop a 10-year tactical fighter aircraft force structure, recapitalization, training, and sustainment plan for the active and reserve components of the Air Force; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The report required by subsection (a) shall address each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The appropriate mix of tactical fighter aircraft, and associated operational risk analyses, required for the Secretary of the Air Force to meet expected steady-state, global force management allocation plans and geographic combatant commander contingency operational plans tasked to the Air Force, using active and reserve component tactical fighter aircraft units.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The procurement, divestment, and unit activation, deactivation, or re-missioning plans or actions the Secretary plans to implement, fiscal year-by-fiscal year, unit-by-unit, for the 10-year period beginning on the date on which the report is submitted, for each active and reserve component tactical fighter aircraft unit existing as of such date of submittal, including the rationale and justification for any such plans or actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The actions the Secretary will take to ensure that required operational readiness rates are maintained during any planned recapitalization, modernization, or change of mission affecting tactical fighter aircraft units.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any plans of the Secretary to augment or supplant existing piloted tactical fighter aircraft capability or capacity with collaborative combat aircraft increment 1 or increment 2 capability or capacity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Any plans of the Secretary to augment or supplant existing piloted tactical fighter aircraft training events through the acquisition and fielding of common, joint, all-domain, high-fidelity synthetic simulation environments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form of Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form with accompanying graphs, tables, and charts, but may contain a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fighter Aircraft Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “fighter aircraft” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 9062(i)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title I, § 142</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1809</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9063.</num>
<heading> Designation: officers to perform certain professional functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Medical functions in the Air Force and the Space Force shall be performed by commissioned officers of the Air Force who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force and who are designated as medical officers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Dental functions in the Air Force and the Space Force shall be performed by commissioned officers of the Air Force who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary and who are designated as dental officers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Veterinary functions in the Air Force and the Space Force shall be performed by commissioned officers of the Air Force who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, and who are designated as veterinary officers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Medical service functions in the Air Force and the Space Force shall be performed by commissioned officers of the Air Force who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, and who are designated as medical service officers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Nursing functions in the Air Force and the Space Force shall be performed by commissioned officers of the Air Force who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary and who are designated as Air Force nurses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Biomedical science functions, including physician assistant functions and chiropractic functions, in the Air Force and the Space Force shall be performed by commissioned officers of the Air Force who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, and who are designated as biomedical science officers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Judge advocate functions in the Air Force and the Space Force shall be performed by commissioned officers of the Air Force who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, and who are designated as judge advocates.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Chaplain functions in the Air Force and the Space Force shall be performed by commissioned officers of the Air Force who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary and who are designated as chaplains.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Other functions in the Air Force and the Space Force requiring special training or experience shall be performed by members of the Air Force or the Space Force who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, and who are designated as being in named categories.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 494</ref>, § 8067; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(156)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1513</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 504(5)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2916</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title V, § 505(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2404</ref>; renumbered § 9067, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; renumbered § 9063, <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 952(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1561</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3809</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9064.</num>
<heading> Air Force nurses: Chief; appointment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Position of Chief</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a Chief of the Air Force Nurse Corps.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chief</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force shall appoint the Chief from the officers of the Regular Air Force designated as Air Force nurses whose regular grade is above lieutenant colonel and who are recommended by the Surgeon General. The Chief serves during the pleasure of the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2511</ref>, § 8069; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2004</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 504(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2531</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(nn)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2106</ref>; renumbered § 9069, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; renumbered § 9064 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 952(b)(1)</ref>, title XVII, § 1731(a)(61), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1561</ref>, 1815.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9065.</num>
<heading> Commands: territorial organization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise prescribed by law or by the Secretary of Defense, the Air Force shall be divided into such organizations as the Secretary of the Air Force may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For Air Force purposes, the United States, its possessions, and other places in which the Air Force is stationed or is operating, may be divided into such areas as directed by the Secretary. Officers of the Air Force may be assigned to command Air Force activities, installations, and personnel in those areas. In the discharge of the Air Force’s functions or other functions authorized by law, officers so assigned have the duties and powers prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 495</ref>, § 8074; <ref>Pub. L. 85–599, § 4(f)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-06">Aug. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 517</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–37, title III, § 306(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-11">June 11, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 129</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 523</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title IX, § 931(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3440</ref>; renumbered § 9074, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; renumbered § 9065, <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 952(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9066.</num>
<heading> Regular Air Force: composition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Regular Air Force is the component of the Air Force that consists of persons whose continuous service on active duty in both peace and war is contemplated by law, and of retired members of the Regular Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Regular Air Force includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the officers and enlisted members of the Regular Air Force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the professors, registrar, and cadets at the United States Air Force Academy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the retired officers and enlisted members of the Regular Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 496</ref>, § 8075; <ref>Pub. L. 85–600, § 1(13)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-06">Aug. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 523</ref>; renumbered § 9075, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; renumbered § 9066, <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 952(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9067.</num>
<heading> Assistant Surgeon General for Dental Services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is an Assistant Surgeon General for Dental Services in the Air Force who is appointed by the Secretary of the Air Force upon the recommendation of the Surgeon General from officers of the Air Force above the grade of lieutenant colonel who are designated as dental officers under <ref>section 9067(b) of this title</ref>. The Assistant Surgeon General for Dental Services serves at the pleasure of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–485, title VIII, § 805(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-20">Oct. 20, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1622</ref>, § 8081; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2004</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2179</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502</ref>(<i>oo</i>), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2106</ref>; renumbered § 9081 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(c), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>, 1840; renumbered § 9067, <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 952(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>