<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 41—</num>
<heading>SPECIAL APPOINTMENTS, ASSIGNMENTS, DETAILS, AND DUTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 711.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002047">1</ref></num>
<heading> Senior members of Military Staff Committee of United Nations: appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, may appoint an officer of the Army, an officer of the Navy or the Marine Corps, and an officer of the Air Force or the Space Force, as senior members of the Military Staff Committee of the United Nations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(f)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2103</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(19)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3823</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 711a.</num>
<heading> American National Red Cross: detail of commissioned officers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Commissioned officers of the Army, Navy, and Air Force may be detailed for duty with the American National Red Cross, by the Secretary of the military department concerned, as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> for duty with the Service to the Armed Forces Division—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> one or more officers of the Army Medical Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> one or more officers of the Medical Department of the Navy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> one or more officers selected from among medical officers, dental officers, veterinary officers, medical service officers, nurses, and medical specialists of the Air Force; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to be in charge of the first-aid department—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an officer of the Medical Corps of the Army;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an officer of the Medical Corps of the Navy; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a medical officer of the Air Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 4(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 759</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 90–329</ref>, <date date="1968-06-04">June 4, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(21)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2921</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 712.</num>
<heading> Foreign governments: detail to assist</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Upon the application of the country concerned, the President, whenever he considers it in the public interest, may detail members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force to assist in military matters—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any republic in North America, Central America, or South America;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Republic of Cuba, Haiti, or Santo Domingo; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> during a war or a declared national emergency, any other country that he considers it advisable to assist in the interest of national defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subject to the prior approval of the Secretary of the military department concerned, a member detailed under this section may accept any office from the country to which he is detailed. He is entitled to credit for all service while so detailed, as if serving with the armed forces of the United States. Arrangements may be made by the President, with countries to which such members are detailed to perform functions under this section, for reimbursement to the United States or other sharing of the cost of performing such functions.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–477</ref>, ch. V, § 502(k), <date date="1958-06-30">June 30, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 713.</num>
<heading> State Department: assignment or detail as couriers and building inspectors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Upon the request of the Secretary of State, the Secretary of a military department may assign or detail members of the armed forces under his jurisdiction for duty—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as inspectors of buildings owned or occupied abroad by the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as inspectors or supervisors of buildings under construction or repair abroad by or for the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> as couriers of the Department of State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may assign or detail a member for duty under subsection (a) with or without reimbursement from the Department of State. However, a member so assigned or detailed may be paid the traveling expenses authorized for officers of the Foreign Service of the United States. These expenses shall be paid from appropriations of the Department of State.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 33</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 714.</num>
<heading> Senior leaders of the Department of Defense and other specified persons: authority to provide protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection for Department Leadership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary and in accordance with guidelines approved by the Secretary and the Attorney General, may authorize qualified members of the armed forces and qualified civilian employees of the Department of Defense to provide physical protection and personal security to the following persons who, by nature of their positions, require continuous security and protection:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Deputy Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Secretaries of the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Members of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in addition to the Chairman and Vice Chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Commanders of combatant commands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002048">1</ref> <inline class="small-caps">Protection for Additional Personnel.—</inline></heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to provide</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary and in accordance with guidelines approved by the Secretary and the Attorney General, may authorize qualified members of the armed forces and qualified civilian employees of the Department of Defense to provide physical protection and personal security to individuals other than individuals described in paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (a) if the Secretary determines that such protection and security are necessary because—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there is a serious and credible threat to the safety of the individual for whom protection is to be provided; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compelling operational considerations make such protection essential to the conduct of official Department of Defense business.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Individuals authorized to receive physical protection and personal security under this subsection include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any official or employee of the Department of Defense or member of the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A former or retired official who faces serious and credible threats arising from duties performed while employed by the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A head of a foreign state, an official representative of a foreign government, or any other distinguished foreign visitor to the United States who is primarily conducting official business with the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any member of the immediate family of a person authorized to receive physical protection and personal security under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> An individual who has been designated by the President, and who has received the advice and consent of the Senate, to serve as Secretary of Defense, but who has not yet been appointed as Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary of Defense to authorize the provision of physical protection and personal security under this subsection may be delegated only to the Deputy Secretary of Defense or the Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for written determination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A determination of the Secretary of Defense whether to provide physical protection and personal security under this subsection shall be in writing, shall be based on a threat assessment by an appropriate law enforcement, security, or intelligence organization, and shall include the name and title of the officer, employee, or other individual affected, the reason for such determination, the duration of any authorized protection and security for such officer, employee, or individual, and the nature of any arrangements for such protection and security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration of protection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall require periodic reviews, not less than once every six months, of the duration of protection provided to individuals under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Submission to congress.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (D), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees an initial determination made under paragraph (4), or a determination to deny the renewal of protection and security, together with the justification for such determination, not later than 15 days after the date on which the determination is made. In the case of determination <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002049">2</ref> to continue protection and security, the Secretary shall make such submission not less than twice each year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form of report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A report submitted under subparagraph (A) may be made in classified form.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations and guidelines</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees the regulations and guidelines prescribed pursuant to paragraph (1) not less than 20 days before the date on which such regulations take effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subparagraph (A) does not apply to determinations made with respect to the following individuals:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> An individual described in paragraph (2)(C) who is otherwise sponsored by the Secretary of Defense, the Deputy Secretary of Defense, the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, or the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> An individual described in paragraph (2)(E).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Temporary protection</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may temporarily provide physical protection and personal security under this subsection to an individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pending the determination of the Secretary under paragraph (4) regarding such individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a period not to exceed 30 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the terms “qualified members of the armed forces” and “qualified civilian employees of the Department of Defense” refer collectively to members or employees who are assigned to investigative, law enforcement, or security duties of any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Army Criminal Investigation Command.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Naval Criminal Investigative Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Air Force Office of Special Investigations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Defense Criminal Investigative Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Pentagon Force Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Construction.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No additional law enforcement or arrest authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Other than the authority to provide protection and security under this section, nothing in this section may be construed to bestow any additional law enforcement or arrest authority upon the qualified members of the armed forces and qualified civilian employees of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Posse comitatus</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to abridge <ref>section 1385 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorities of other departments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed to preclude or limit, in any way, the express or implied powers of the Secretary of Defense or other Department of Defense officials, or the duties and authorities of the Secretary of State, the Director of the United States Secret Service, the Director of the United States Marshals Service, or any other Federal law enforcement agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may reimburse a former or retired official who faces serious and credible threats arising from duties performed while employed by the Department for security services and equipment procured at the personal expense of the official, not to exceed an aggregate of $15,000,000 in any fiscal year for all former and retired officials authorized by the Secretary of Defense for such reimbursement.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 952(c)(1)</ref>, (4)–(6), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2375</ref>, 2376; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 529A</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 522</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(a)(16), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1883</ref>, 2204.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 715.</num>
<heading> Attending Physician to the Congress: grade</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A general officer serving as Attending Physician to the Congress, while so serving, holds the grade of major general. A flag officer serving as Attending Physician to the Congress, while so serving, holds the grade of rear admiral (upper half).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 508(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1749</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 716.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers: transfers among the armed forces, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Public Health Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President, within authorized strengths and with the consent of the officer involved, may transfer any commissioned officer of a uniformed service from his uniformed service to, and appoint him in, another uniformed service. The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall jointly establish, by regulations approved by the President, policies and procedures for such transfers and appointments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An officer transferred under this section may not be assigned precedence or relative rank higher than that which he held on the day before the transfer.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–599, § 11(2)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-06">Aug. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 521</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 91–392, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-09-01">Sept. 1, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–215, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-25">Mar. 25, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 123</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(10)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title X, § 1007(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title III, § 304(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 703</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 717.</num>
<heading> Members of the armed forces: participation in international sports</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense, or the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, may permit members of the armed forces under his jurisdiction to train for, attend, and participate in any of the following sports competitions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Pan-American Games and the Olympic Games, and qualifying events and preparatory competition for those games.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Paralympic Games, if eligible to participate in those games, and qualifying events and preparatory competition for those games.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any other international competition in amateur sports, if the Secretary of State determines that the interests of the United States will be served by participation in that competition, and qualifying events and preparatory competition for that competition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to subsections (c) and (d), the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as the case may be, may spend such funds, and acquire and use such supplies, as he determines to be necessary to provide for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the training of members of the armed forces for the competitions covered by subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> their attendance at and participation in those competitions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the training of animals of the armed forces for, and their attendance at and participation in, those competitions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not more than $3,000,000, to be apportioned among the military departments as the Secretary of Defense prescribes, may be spent during each successive four-year period beginning on <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>, for the participation of members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force in the competitions covered by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not more than $100,000 may be spent during each successive four-year period beginning on <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>, for the participation of members of the Coast Guard in the competitions covered by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Appropriations available to the Department of Defense or to the Department of Homeland Security, as the case may be, may be used to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(17)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1442</ref>, § 716; renumbered § 717, <ref>Pub. L. 87–651, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 508</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–348, § 1(12)</ref>, <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1311</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 7</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(22)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2921</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XV, § 1534</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2632</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 561</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3266</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(1)(F)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 718.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title I, § 110(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1001</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 719.</num>
<heading> Department of Commerce: assignment or detail of members of the armed forces to National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of a military department may assign or detail members of the armed forces under his jurisdiction for duty in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, Department of Commerce, with reimbursement from the Department of Commerce. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a member so assigned or detailed may exercise the functions, and assume the title, of any position in that Administration without affecting his status as a member of an armed force, but he is not entitled to the compensation fixed for that position.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–683, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 960</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 511(23)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2921</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 720.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2103</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 721.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 502(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2276</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 722.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2103</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 723.</num>
<heading> Support of Federal authorities in response to civil disturbances: requirement for use of members of the Armed Forces and Federal law enforcement personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whenever a member of the armed forces (including the National Guard) or Federal law enforcement personnel provide support to Federal authorities to respond to a civil disturbance, each individual employed in the capacity of providing such support shall visibly display—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the individual’s name or other individual identifier that is unique to that individual; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the name of the armed force, Federal entity, or other organization by which such individual is employed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The requirement under subsection (a) shall not apply to individuals referred to in such subsection who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> do not wear a uniform or other distinguishing clothing or equipment in the regular performance of their official duties; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> are engaged in undercover operations in the regular performance of their official duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1064(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3860</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>