<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 87—</num>
<heading>DEFENSE ACQUISITION WORKFORCE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL AUTHORITIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1701.</num>
<heading> Management policies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policies and Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish policies and procedures for the effective management (including accession, education, training, and career development) of persons serving in acquisition positions in the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Uniform Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, acquisition workforce policies and procedures established in accordance with this chapter are uniform in their implementation throughout the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1638</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1701a.</num>
<heading> Management for acquisition workforce excellence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purpose of this chapter is to require the Department of Defense to develop and manage a highly skilled professional acquisition workforce—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in which excellence and contribution to mission is rewarded;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> which has the technical expertise and business skills to ensure the Department receives the best value for the expenditure of public resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> which serves as a model for performance management of employees of the Department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> which is managed in a manner that complements and reinforces the management of the defense acquisition system pursuant to chapter 205 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance Management</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In order to achieve the purpose set forth in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> use the full authorities provided in subsections (a) through (d) of <ref>section 9902 of title 5</ref>, including flexibilities related to performance management and hiring and to training of managers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require managers to develop performance plans for individual members of the acquisition workforce in order to give members an understanding of how their performance contributes to their organization’s mission and the success of the defense acquisition system (as defined in <ref>section 3001 of this title</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to the extent appropriate, use the lessons learned from the acquisition demonstration project carried out under <ref>section 1762 of this title</ref> related to contribution-based compensation and appraisal, and how those lessons may be applied within the General Schedule system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop and implement a career path, as described in <ref>section 1722(a) of this title</ref>, for each career field designated by the Secretary under <ref>section 1721(a) of this title</ref> as an acquisition workforce career field;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> direct continuing education and training;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> authorize a member of the acquisition workforce to participate in professional associations, consistent with the performance plan of such a member in order to provide the member with the opportunity to gain leadership and management skills;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> develop appropriate procedures for warnings and consequences during performance evaluations for members of the acquisition workforce who consistently fail to meet performance standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> take full advantage of the Defense Civilian Leadership Program established under section 1112 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 (<ref>Public Law 111–84</ref>; <ref>123 Stat. 2496</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 1580</ref> note prec.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> use the authorities for highly qualified experts under <ref>section 9903 of title 5</ref>, to hire experts who are skilled acquisition professionals to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> serve in leadership positions within the acquisition workforce to strengthen management and oversight;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide mentors to advise individuals within the acquisition workforce on their career paths and opportunities to advance and excel within the acquisition workforce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assist with the design of education and training courses and the training of individuals in the acquisition workforce;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> use the authorities for expedited security clearance processing pursuant to <ref>section 1564 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> ensure the participation in the public-private talent exchange program established under <ref>section 1599g of this title</ref> of up to 250 members of the acquisition workforce in each fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Professional Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall implement a certification program to provide for a professional certification requirement for all members of the acquisition workforce. Except as provided in paragraph (2), the certification requirement for any acquisition workforce career field shall be based on standards developed by a third-party accredited program based on nationally or internationally recognized standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the Secretary determines that, for a particular acquisition workforce career field, a third-party accredited program based on nationally or internationally recognized standards does not exist, the Secretary shall establish the certification requirement for that career field that conforms with the practices of national or international accrediting organizations. The Secretary shall determine the best approach for meeting the certification requirement for any such career field, including by implementing such certification requirement through entities outside the Department of Defense, and may design and implement such certification requirement without regard to <ref>section 1746 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Negotiations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any action taken by the Secretary under this section, or to implement this section, shall be subject to the requirements of chapter 71 of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any rules or regulations prescribed pursuant to this section shall be deemed an agency rule or regulation under <ref>section 7117(a)(2) of title 5</ref>, and shall not be deemed a Government-wide rule or regulation under section 7117(a)(1) of such title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 871(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4299</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(a)(1)</ref>–(3), (e)(1), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1515</ref>, 1517; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(31)</ref>, title XVIII, §§ 1808(d)(2), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3872</ref>, 4160, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 831(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2711</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1701b.</num>
<heading> Enhanced pay authority for certain acquisition and technology positions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may carry out a program using the pay authority specified in subsection (d) to fix the rate of basic pay for positions described in subsection (c) in order to assist the Office of the Secretary of Defense and the military departments in attracting and retaining high-quality acquisition and technology experts in positions responsible for managing and developing complex, high-cost, technological acquisition efforts of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The program may be carried out only with approval as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Approval of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, in the case of positions in the Office of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Approval of the service acquisition executive of the military department concerned, in the case of positions in a military department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The positions described in this subsection are positions that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require expertise of an extremely high level in a scientific, technical, professional, or acquisition management field; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> are critical to the successful accomplishment of an important acquisition or technology development mission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rate of Basic Pay</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The pay authority specified in this subsection is authority as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Authority to fix the rate of basic pay for a position at a rate not to exceed 150 percent of the rate of basic pay payable for level I of the Executive Schedule, upon the approval of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment or the service acquisition executive concerned, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Authority to fix the rate of basic pay for a position at a rate in excess of 150 percent of the rate of basic pay payable for level I of the Executive Schedule, upon the approval of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority in subsection (a) may be used only to the extent necessary to competitively recruit or retain individuals exceptionally well qualified for positions described in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of positions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The authority in subsection (a) may not be used at any one time with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> more than five positions, in total, in Department of Defense Field Activities and Defense Agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> more than five positions in the Office of the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> more than five positions in each military department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term of positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority in subsection (a) may be used only for positions having terms less than five years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1114(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3894</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 831(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2711</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1702.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment: authorities and responsibilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall carry out all powers, functions, and duties of the Secretary of Defense with respect to the acquisition workforce in the Department of Defense. The Under Secretary shall ensure that the policies of the Secretary of Defense established in accordance with this chapter are implemented throughout the Department of Defense. The Under Secretary shall prescribe policies and requirements for the educational programs of the defense acquisition university structure established under <ref>section 1746 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1638</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title VIII, § 815</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2088</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, (3)(A), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(11)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1544</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1703.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 831(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1549</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1704.</num>
<heading> Service acquisition executives: authorities and responsibilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of the military department concerned, the service acquisition executive for each military department shall carry out all powers, functions, and duties of the Secretary concerned with respect to the acquisition workforce within the military department concerned and shall ensure that the policies of the Secretary of Defense established in accordance with this chapter are implemented in that department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1639</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1705.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Account</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish an account to be known as the “Department of Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Account” (in this section referred to as the “Account”) to provide funds, in addition to other funds that may be available, for the recruitment, training, and retention of acquisition personnel of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The purpose of the Account is to ensure that the Department of Defense acquisition workforce has the capacity, in both personnel and skills, needed to properly perform its mission, provide appropriate oversight of contractor performance, and ensure that the Department receives the best value for the expenditure of public resources.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Management</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Account shall be managed by a senior official of the Department of Defense designated by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment for that purpose, from among persons with an extensive background in management relating to acquisition and personnel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Account shall consist of amounts appropriated to the Account by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisions of this subsection, amounts in the Account shall be available to the Secretary of Defense for expenditure, or for transfer to a military department or Defense Agency, for the recruitment, training, and retention of acquisition personnel of the Department of Defense for the purpose of the Account, including for the provision of training and retention incentives to the acquisition workforce of the Department and to develop acquisition tools and methodologies, and undertake research and development activities, leading to acquisition policies and practices that will improve the efficiency and effectiveness of defense acquisition efforts. In the case of temporary members of the acquisition workforce designated pursuant to subsection (g)(2), such funds shall be available only for the limited purpose of providing training in the performance of acquisition-related functions and duties.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Amounts in the Account also may be used to pay salaries of personnel at the Office of the Secretary of Defense, military departments, and Defense Agencies to manage the Account.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Amounts in the Account may be used to pay the expenses of the public-private talent exchange program established under <ref>section 1599g of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts in the Account may not be obligated for any purpose other than purposes described in paragraph (1) or otherwise in accordance with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, acting through the senior official designated to manage the Account, shall issue guidance for the administration of the Account. Such guidance shall include provisions—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> identifying areas of need in the acquisition workforce for which amounts in the Account may be used, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> changes to the types of skills needed in the acquisition workforce;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> incentives to retain in the acquisition workforce qualified, experienced acquisition workforce personnel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> incentives for attracting new, high-quality personnel to the acquisition workforce;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> describing the manner and timing for applications for amounts in the Account to be submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> describing the evaluation criteria to be used for approving or prioritizing applications for amounts in the Account in any fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> describing measurable objectives of performance for determining whether amounts in the Account are being used in compliance with this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> describing the amount from the Account that may be used to pay salaries of personnel at the Office of the Secretary of Defense, military departments, and Defense Agencies to manage the Account and the circumstances under which such amounts may be used for such purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on payments to or for contractors</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts in the Account shall not be available for payments to contractors or contractor employees, other than for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing advanced training to Department of Defense employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> developing acquisition tools and methodologies and performing research on acquisition policies and best practices that will improve the efficiency and effectiveness of defense acquisition efforts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> supporting human capital and talent management of the acquisition workforce, including benchmarking studies, assessments, and requirements planning.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on payment of base salary of current employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts in the Account may not be used to pay the base salary of any person who was an employee of the Department serving in a position in the acquisition workforce as of <date date="2008-01-28">January 28, 2008</date>, and who has continued in the employment of the Department since such time without a break in such employment of more than a year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration of availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated to the Account pursuant to subsection (d) shall remain available for expenditure for the fiscal year in which appropriated and the succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expedited Hiring Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of sections 3304, 5333, and 5753 of title 5, the Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designate any category of positions in the acquisition workforce as positions for which there exists a shortage of candidates or there is a critical hiring need; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> utilize the authorities in such sections to recruit and appoint qualified persons directly to positions so designated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition Workforce Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “acquisition workforce” means the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Personnel in positions designated under <ref>section 1721 of this title</ref> as acquisition positions for purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Other military personnel or civilian employees of the Department of Defense who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> contribute significantly to the acquisition process by virtue of their assigned duties; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> contribute significantly to the acquisition or development of systems relating to cybersecurity; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are designated as temporary members of the acquisition workforce by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, or by the senior acquisition executive of a military department, for the limited purpose of receiving training for the performance of acquisition-related functions and duties.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VIII, § 852(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 248</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 833, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 831, 832(a)–(g), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2414</ref>, 2415; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 804(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1486</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VIII, § 803(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1825</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 841(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 913</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 863(a)</ref>, (b), title X, § 1081(a)(5), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2302</ref>, 2303, 2417; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 842, 843(a)(1), title X, § 1051(a)(7), title XVI, § 1636, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1479</ref>, 1480, 1560, 1741; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 863(b)</ref>, title IX, § 902(13), title X, § 1010(a)(1), (2)(A), (b)–(d), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1522</ref>, 1544, 1576; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(22)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1920</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1706.</num>
<heading> Government performance of certain acquisition functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Goal</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>It shall be the goal of the Department of Defense and each of the military departments to ensure that, for each major defense acquisition program (as defined in <ref>section 4201 of this title</ref>), each acquisition program that is estimated by the Secretary of Defense to require an eventual total expenditure greater than the amount described in <ref>section 4201(a)(2) of this title</ref>, and any other acquisition program identified by the Secretary, each of the following positions is performed by a properly qualified member of the armed forces or full-time employee of the Department of Defense:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Program executive officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Deputy program executive officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Deputy program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Senior contracting official.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Chief developmental tester.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Program lead product support manager.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Program lead systems engineer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Program lead cost estimator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Program lead contracting officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Program lead business financial manager.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Program lead production, quality, and manufacturing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Program lead information technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Program lead software.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Plan of Action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop and implement a plan of action for recruiting, training, and ensuring appropriate career development of military and civilian personnel to achieve the objective established in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VIII, § 824(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1832</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 812</ref>, title XVIII, § 1846(i)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3749</ref>, 4252; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1846(j)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(15)(C)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2134</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(15)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2134</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1707.</num>
<heading> Cadre of intellectual property experts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cadre</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall establish a cadre of personnel who are experts in intellectual property matters. The purpose of the cadre is to ensure a consistent, strategic, and highly knowledgeable approach to acquiring or licensing intellectual property by providing expert advice, assistance, and resources to the acquisition workforce on intellectual property matters, including acquiring or licensing intellectual property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leadership Structure</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Under Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall establish an appropriate leadership structure and office within which the cadre shall be managed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall determine the appropriate official to whom members of the cadre shall report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The cadre of experts shall be assigned to a program office or an acquisition command within a military department to advise, assist, and provide resources to a program manager or program executive officer on intellectual property matters at various stages of the life cycle of a system. In performing such duties, the experts shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> interpret and provide counsel on laws, regulations, and policies relating to intellectual property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advise and assist in the development of an acquisition strategy, product support strategy, and intellectual property strategy for a system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> conduct or assist with financial analysis and valuation of intellectual property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> assist in the drafting of a solicitation, contract, or other transaction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> interact with or assist in interactions with contractors, including communications and negotiations with contractors on solicitations and awards; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> conduct or assist with mediation if technical data delivered pursuant to a contract is incomplete or does not comply with the terms of agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Administration.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In order to achieve the purpose set forth in subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall ensure the cadre has the appropriate number of staff and such staff possesses the necessary skills, knowledge, and experience to carry out the duties under subsection (b), including in relevant areas of law, contracting, acquisition, logistics, engineering, financial analysis, and valuation. The Under Secretary, in coordination with the Defense Acquisition University and in consultation with academia and industry, shall develop a career path, including development opportunities, exchanges, talent management programs, and training, for the cadre. The Under Secretary may use existing authorities to staff the cadre, including those in paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (6).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Civilian personnel from within the Office of the Secretary of Defense, Joint Staff, military departments, Defense Agencies, and combatant commands may be assigned to serve as members of the cadre, upon request of the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary may use the authorities for highly qualified experts under <ref>section 9903 of title 5</ref>, to hire experts as members of the cadre who are skilled professionals in intellectual property and related matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary may enter into a contract with a private-sector entity for specialized expertise to support the cadre. Such entity may be considered a covered Government support contractor, as defined in <ref>section 3775(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In establishing the cadre, the Under Secretary shall give preference to civilian employees of the Department of Defense, rather than members of the armed forces, to maintain continuity in the cadre.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary is authorized to use amounts in the Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund for the purpose of recruitment, training, and retention of the cadre, including paying salaries of newly hired members of the cadre for up to three years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1877</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ACQUISITION POSITIONS AND ACQUISITION WORKFORCE CAREER FIELDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1721.</num>
<heading> Designation of acquisition positions and acquisition workforce career fields</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall designate in regulations those positions in the Department of Defense that are acquisition positions for purposes of this chapter. The Secretary shall also designate in regulations those career fields in the Department of Defense that are acquisition workforce career fields for purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In designating the positions under subsection (a), the Secretary shall include, at a minimum, all acquisition-related positions in the following areas:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Program management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Systems planning, research, development, engineering, and testing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Procurement, including contracting.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Industrial property management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Logistics.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Quality control and assurance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Manufacturing and production.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Business, cost estimating, financial management, and auditing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Education, training, and career development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Construction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Security cooperation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Intellectual property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Other positions, as necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Management Headquarters Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary also shall designate as acquisition positions under subsection (a) those acquisition-related positions which are in management headquarters activities and in management headquarters support activities. For purposes of this subsection, the terms “management headquarters activities” and “management headquarters support activities” have the meanings given those terms in Department of Defense Directive 5100.73, entitled “Department of Defense Management Headquarters and Headquarters Support Activities”, dated <date date="1996-11-12">November 12, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1640</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(j)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title IX, § 912(f)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1862</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 802(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1451</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(d)</ref>, (f)(1), (2)(A), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1517</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1722.</num>
<heading> Career development</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Career Paths</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall ensure that an appropriate career path for civilian and military personnel who wish to pursue careers in acquisition is identified for each acquisition workforce career field in terms of the education, training, experience, and assignments necessary for career progression of civilians and members of the armed forces to the most senior acquisition positions. The Secretary shall make available published information on such career paths.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Preference for Military Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that no requirement or preference for a member of the armed forces is used in the consideration of persons for acquisition positions, except as provided in the policy established under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish a policy permitting a particular acquisition position to be specified as available only to members of the armed forces if a determination is made, under criteria specified in the policy, that a member of the armed forces is required for that position by law, is essential for performance of the duties of the position, or is necessary for another compelling reason.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Not later than December 15 of each year, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall submit to the Secretary a report that lists each acquisition position that is restricted to members of the armed forces under such policy and the recommendation of the Under Secretary as to whether such position should remain so restricted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Opportunities for Civilians To Qualify</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that civilian personnel are provided the opportunity to acquire the education, training, and experience necessary to qualify for senior acquisition positions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Best Qualified</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the policies established under this chapter are designed to provide for the selection of the best qualified individual for a position, consistent with other applicable law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(e)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1227</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignments Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish a policy on assigning military personnel to acquisition positions that provides for a balance between (A) the need for personnel to serve in career broadening positions, and (B) the need for requiring service in each such position for sufficient time to provide the stability necessary to effectively carry out the duties of the position and to allow for the establishment of responsibility and accountability for actions taken in the position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In implementing the policy established under paragraph (1), the Secretaries of the military departments shall provide, as appropriate, for longer lengths of assignments to acquisition positions than assignments to other positions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance Appraisals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each military department, acting through the service acquisition executive for that department, shall provide an opportunity for review and inclusion of any comments on any appraisal of the performance of a person serving in an acquisition position by a person serving in an acquisition position in the same acquisition career field.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Balanced Workforce Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the development of defense acquisition workforce policies under this chapter with respect to any civilian employees or applicants for employment, the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department (as applicable) shall, consistent with the merit system principles set out in paragraphs (1) and (2) of <ref>section 2301(b) of title 5</ref>, take into consideration the need to maintain a balanced workforce in which women and members of racial and ethnic minority groups are appropriately represented in Government service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1641</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, (e)(3), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>, 1227; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(e)(2)</ref>, title IX, § 902(15), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1517</ref>, 1544.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1722a.</num>
<heading> Special requirements for military personnel in the acquisition field</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Policy and Guidance Regarding Military Personnel in Acquisition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall require the Secretary of each military department (with respect to such military department), in collaboration with the Chief of Staff of the Army, the Chief of Naval Operations, the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, the Commandant of the Marine Corps, and the Chief of Space Operations (with respect to the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force, respectively), and the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment (with respect to the Office of the Secretary of Defense, the unified combatant commands, the Defense Agencies, and the Defense Field Activities) to establish policies and issue guidance to ensure the proper development, assignment, and employment of members of the armed forces in the acquisition field to achieve the objectives of this section as specified in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objectives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Policies established and guidance issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall ensure, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A single-track career path in the acquisition field that attracts the highest quality officers and enlisted personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A dual-track career path that attracts the highest quality officers and enlisted personnel and allows them to gain experience in and receive credit for a primary career in combat arms and a functional secondary career in the acquisition field in order to more closely align the military operational, requirements, and acquisition workforces of each armed force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A number of command positions and senior noncommissioned officer positions, including acquisition billets reserved for general officers and flag officers under subsection (c), sufficient to ensure that members of the armed forces have opportunities for promotion and advancement in the acquisition field.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A number of qualified, trained members of the armed forces eligible for and active in the acquisition field sufficient to ensure the optimum management of the acquisition functions of the Department of Defense and the appropriate use of military personnel in contingency contracting.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reservation of Acquisition Billets for General Officers and Flag Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish for each military department a sufficient number of billets coded or classified for acquisition personnel that are reserved for general officers and flag officers that are needed for the purpose of ensuring the optimum management of the acquisition functions of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that the policies established and guidance issued pursuant to subsection (a) by the Secretary of each military department reserve at least that minimum number of billets and fill the billets with qualified and trained general officers and flag officers who have significant acquisition experience.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a sufficient number of billets for acquisition personnel who are general officers or flag officers exist within the Office of the Secretary of Defense, the unified combatant commands, the Defense Agencies, and the Defense Field Activities to ensure the optimum management of the acquisition functions of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that the policies established and guidance issued pursuant to subsection (a) by the Secretary reserve within the Office of the Secretary of Defense, the unified combatant commands, the Defense Agencies, and the Defense Field Activities at least that minimum number of billets and fill the billets with qualified and trained general officers and flag officers who have significant acquisition experience.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that a portion of the billets referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) involve command of organizations primarily focused on contracting and are reserved for general officers and flag officers who have significant contracting experience.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Limitation on Preference for Military Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any designation or reservation of a position for a member of the armed forces as a result of a policy established or guidance issued pursuant to this section shall be deemed to meet the requirements for an exception under paragraph (2) of <ref>section 1722(b) of this title</ref> from the limitation in paragraph (1) of such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than January 1 of each year, the Secretary of each military department shall submit to the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment a report describing how the Secretary fulfilled the objectives of this section in the preceding calendar year. The report shall include information on the reservation of acquisition billets for general officers and flag officers within the department concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 834(a)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4535</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 842</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 914</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(16)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1544</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(27)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3825</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(23)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1920</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1722b.</num>
<heading> Special requirements for civilian employees in the acquisition field</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Policy and Guidance Regarding Civilian Personnel in Acquisition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall establish policies and issue guidance to ensure the proper development, assignment, and employment of civilian members of the acquisition workforce to achieve the objectives specified in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objectives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Policies established and guidance issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall ensure, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A career path in the acquisition field that attracts the highest quality civilian personnel, from either within or outside the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A deliberate workforce development strategy that increases attainment of key experiences that contribute to a highly qualified acquisition workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Sufficient opportunities for promotion and advancement in the acquisition field.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A sufficient number of qualified, trained members eligible for and active in the acquisition field to ensure adequate capacity, capability, and effective succession for acquisition functions, including contingency contracting, of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A deliberate workforce development strategy that ensures diversity in promotion, advancement, and experiential opportunities commensurate with the general workforce outlined in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Key Work Experiences</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out subsection (b)(2), the Secretary shall ensure that key work experiences, in the form of multidisciplinary experiences, are developed for each acquisition workforce career field.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 873(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4302</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1951</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1560</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(g)(1)</ref>, title IX, § 902(17), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1518</ref>, 1545.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1723.</num>
<heading> General education, training, and experience requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualification Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish education, training, and experience requirements for each acquisition position, based on the level of complexity of duties carried out in the position. In establishing such requirements, the Secretary shall ensure the availability and sufficiency of training in all areas of acquisition, including additional training courses with an emphasis on services contracting, market research strategies (including assessments of local contracting capabilities), long-term sustainment strategies, information technology, and rapid acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In establishing such requirements for positions other than critical acquisition positions designated pursuant to <ref>section 1731 of this title</ref>, the Secretary may state the requirements by categories of positions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall establish requirements for continuing education and periodic renewal of an individual’s certification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Career Path Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each career path, the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall establish requirements for the completion of course work and related on-the-job training and demonstration of qualifications in duties and tasks of the career path. The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary, shall also—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> direct individuals in the acquisition workforce to maintain the currency of their acquisition knowledge and generally enhance their knowledge of related acquisition management disciplines through academic programs and other self-developmental activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop key work experiences, including the creation of a program sponsored by the Department of Defense that facilitates the periodic interaction between individuals in the acquisition workforce and the end user in such end user’s environment to enhance the knowledge base of such workforce, for individuals in the acquisition workforce so that the individuals may gain in-depth knowledge and experience in the acquisition process and become seasoned, well-qualified members of the acquisition workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Credit for Training or Education</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not more than one year of a period of time spent pursuing a program of academic training or education in acquisition may be counted toward fulfilling any requirement established under this chapter for a certain period of experience.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1642</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1074(a)(9)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2659</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 873(b), 874(a), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4303</ref>, 4304; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(a)(4)</ref>, (h), (j)(8), title IX, § 902(18), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1515</ref>, 1518, 1520, 1545.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1724.</num>
<heading> Contracting positions: qualification requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracting Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall require that, in order to qualify to serve in an acquisition position as a contracting officer with authority to award or administer contracts for amounts above the simplified acquisition threshold referred to in <ref>section 3205 of this title</ref>, an employee of the Department of Defense or member of the armed forces (other than the Coast Guard) must, except as provided in subsections (c) and (d)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> have completed all contracting courses required for a contracting officer (A) in the case of an employee, serving in the position within the grade of the General Schedule in which the employee is serving, and (B) in the case of a member of the armed forces, in the member’s grade;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> have at least two years of experience in a contracting position;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have received a baccalaureate degree from an accredited educational institution authorized to grant baccalaureate degrees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> meet such additional requirements, based on the dollar value and complexity of the contracts awarded or administered in the position, as may be established by the Secretary of Defense for the position.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading> GS–1102 <inline class="small-caps">Series Positions and Similar Military Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall require that in order to qualify to serve in a position in the Department of Defense that is in the GS–1102 occupational series an employee or potential employee of the Department of Defense meet the requirement set forth in paragraph (3) of subsection (a). The Secretary may not require that in order to serve in such a position an employee or potential employee meet any of the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall require that in order for a member of the armed forces to be selected for an occupational specialty within the armed forces that (as determined by the Secretary) is similar to the GS–1102 occupational series a member of the armed forces meet the requirement set forth in paragraph (3) of subsection (a). The Secretary may not require that in order to be selected for such an occupational specialty a member meet any of the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The qualification requirements imposed by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to an employee of the Department of Defense or member of the armed forces who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> served as a contracting officer with authority to award or administer contracts in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold on or before <date date="2000-09-30">September 30, 2000</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> served, on or before <date date="2000-09-30">September 30, 2000</date>, in a position either as an employee in the GS–1102 series or as a member of the armed forces in a similar occupational specialty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is in the contingency contracting force; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is described in subsection (e)(1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may waive any or all of the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) with respect to an employee of the Department of Defense or member of the armed forces if the Secretary determines that the individual possesses significant potential for advancement to levels of greater responsibility and authority, based on demonstrated job performance and qualifying experience. With respect to each waiver granted under this subsection, the Secretary shall set forth in a written document the rationale for the decision of the Secretary to waive such requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Developmental Opportunities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish or continue one or more programs for the purpose of recruiting, selecting, appointing, educating, qualifying, and developing the careers of individuals to meet the requirement of subsection (a)(3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> appoint individuals to developmental positions in those programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> separate from the civil service after a three-year probationary period any individual appointed under this subsection who fails to meet the requirement described in subsection (a)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To qualify for any developmental program described in paragraph (1)(B), an individual shall have been awarded a baccalaureate degree, with a grade point average of at least 3.0 (or the equivalent), from an accredited institution of higher education authorized to grant baccalaureate degrees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contingency Contracting Force</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish qualification requirements for the contingency contracting force consisting of members of the armed forces whose mission is to deploy in support of contingency operations and other operations of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1642</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 97</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1074(a)(9)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2659</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title VIII, § 808(a)–(d)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–208; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VIII, § 824(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1183</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 831(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1549</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(14)</ref>, (h)(1), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2062</ref>, 2064; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1725.</num>
<heading> Senior Military Acquisition Advisors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Position.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish in the acquisition workforce a position to be known as “Senior Military Acquisition Advisor”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Senior Military Acquisition Advisor shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of position</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An officer who is appointed as a Senior Military Acquisition Advisor—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall serve as an advisor to, and provide senior level acquisition expertise to, the service acquisition executive of that officer’s military department in accordance with this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be assigned as an adjunct professor at the Defense Acquisition University.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuation on Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer who is appointed as a Senior Military Acquisition Advisor may continue on active duty while serving in such position without regard to any mandatory retirement date that would otherwise be applicable to that officer by reason of years of service or age. An officer who is continued on active duty pursuant to this section is not eligible for consideration for selection for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retired Grade</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Upon retirement, an officer who is a Senior Military Acquisition Advisor may, in the discretion of the President, be retired in the grade of brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the officer has served as a Senior Military Acquisition Advisor for a period of not less than three years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the officer’s service as a Senior Military Acquisition Advisor has been distinguished.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Selection and Tenure.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Selection of an officer for recommendation for appointment as a Senior Military Acquisition Advisor shall be made competitively, and shall be based upon demonstrated experience and expertise in acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers eligible</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Officers shall be selected for recommendation for appointment as Senior Military Acquisition Advisors from among officers in the acquisition workforce serving in critical acquisition positions who are serving in the grade of colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain, and who have at least 12 years of acquisition experience. An officer selected for recommendation for appointment as a Senior Military Acquisition Advisor shall have at least 30 years of active commissioned service at the time of appointment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The appointment of an officer as a Senior Military Acquisition Advisor shall be for a term of not longer than five years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on number and distribution</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There may not be more than 15 Senior Military Acquisition Advisors at any time, of whom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not more than five may be officers of the Army;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not more than five may be officers of the Navy and Marine Corps; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not more than five may be officers of the Air Force and Space Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number in each military department</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraph (1), the number of Senior Military Acquisition Advisors for each military department shall be as required and identified by the service acquisition executive of such military department and approved by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advice to Service Acquisition Executive</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer who is a Senior Military Acquisition Advisor shall have as the officer’s primary duty providing strategic, technical, and programmatic advice to the service acquisition executive of the officer’s military department on matters pertaining to the Defense Acquisition System, including matters pertaining to procurement, research and development, advanced technology, test and evaluation, production, program management, systems engineering, and lifecycle logistics.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 866(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2305</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(j)(9)</ref>, title IX, § 902(19), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1520</ref>, 1545; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(28)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3825</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>CRITICAL ACQUISITION POSITIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1731.</num>
<heading> Critical acquisition positions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Critical Acquisition Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall designate the acquisition positions in the Department of Defense that are critical acquisition positions. Such positions shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Any acquisition position which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of employees, is required to be filled by an employee in a senior position in the National Security Personnel System, as determined in accordance with guidelines prescribed by the Secretary, or in the Senior Executive Service; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of members of the armed forces, is required to be filled by a commissioned officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force who is serving in the grade of lieutenant colonel, or, in the case of the Navy, commander, or a higher grade.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Other selected acquisition positions not covered by subparagraph (A), including the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Program executive officer.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Program manager of a major defense acquisition program (as defined in <ref>section 4201 of this title</ref>) or of a significant nonmajor defense acquisition program (as defined in <ref>section 1737(a)(3) of this title</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Deputy program manager of a major defense acquisition program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any other acquisition position of significant responsibility in which the primary duties are supervisory or management duties.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall periodically publish a list of the positions designated under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Promotion Rate for Officers in the Acquisition Workforce</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the qualifications of commissioned officers in the acquisition workforce are such that those officers are expected, as a group, to be promoted at a rate not less than the rate for all line (or the equivalent) officers of the same armed force (both in the zone and below the zone) in the same grade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mobility Statements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense is authorized to require civilians in critical acquisition positions to sign mobility statements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall identify which categories of civilians in critical acquisition positions, as a condition of employment, shall be required to sign mobility statements. The Secretary shall make available published information on such identification of categories.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1646</ref>, § 1733; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(22)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2500</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–89, § 3(b)(3)(C)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 983</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1074(a)(9)(C)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2659</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 833(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1550</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VIII, § 812(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2013</ref>; renumbered § 1731 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(j)(2)</ref>–(4), (6)(A), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1519</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(AA)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1846(i)(4), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>, 4252.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1732.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(j)(5)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1519</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1733.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 1731]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1734.</num>
<heading> Career development</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Three-Year Assignment Period</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided under subsection (b) and paragraph (3), the Secretary of each military department, acting through the service acquisition executive for that department, shall provide that any person who is assigned to a critical acquisition position shall be assigned to the position for not fewer than three years. Except as provided in subsection (d), the Secretary concerned may not reassign a person from such an assignment before the end of the three-year period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person may not be assigned to a critical acquisition position unless the person executes a written agreement to remain on active duty (in the case of a member of the armed forces) or to remain in Federal service (in the case of an employee) in that position for at least three years. The service obligation contained in such a written agreement shall remain in effect unless and until waived by the Secretary concerned under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The assignment period requirement of the first sentence of paragraph (1) is waived for any individual serving as a deputy program manager if the individual is assigned to a critical acquisition position upon completion of the individual’s assignment as a deputy program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment Period for Program Managers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe in regulations—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a requirement that a program manager and a deputy program manager (except as provided in paragraph (3)) of a major defense acquisition program be assigned to the position at least until completion of the major milestone that occurs closest in time to the date on which the person has served in the position for four years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a requirement that, to the maximum extent practicable, a program manager who is the replacement for a reassigned program manager arrive at the assignment location before the reassigned program manager leaves.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Except as provided in subsection (d), the Secretary concerned may not reassign a program manager or deputy program manager from such an assignment until after such major milestone has occurred.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person may not be assigned to a critical acquisition position as a program manager or deputy program manager of a major defense acquisition program unless the person executes a written agreement to remain on active duty (in the case of a member of the armed forces) or to remain in Federal service (in the case of an employee) in that position at least until completion of the first major milestone that occurs closest in time to the date on which the person has served in the position for four years. The service obligation contained in such a written agreement shall remain in effect unless and until waived by the Secretary concerned under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The assignment period requirement under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) is waived for any individual serving as a deputy program manager if the individual is assigned to a critical acquisition position upon completion of the individual’s assignment as a deputy program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major Milestone Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall issue regulations defining what constitutes major milestones for purposes of this section. The service acquisition executive of each military department shall establish major milestones at the beginning of a major defense acquisition program consistent with such regulations and shall use such milestones to determine the assignment period for program managers and deputy program managers under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The regulations shall require that major milestones be clearly definable and measurable events that mark the completion of a significant phase in a major defense acquisition program and that such milestones be the same as the milestones contained in the baseline description established for the program pursuant to <ref>section 4214(a) of this title</ref>. The Secretary shall require that the major milestones as defined in the regulations be included in the Selected Acquisition Report required for such program under <ref>section 4351 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver of Assignment Period</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> With respect to a person assigned to a critical acquisition position, the Secretary concerned may waive the prohibition on reassignment of that person (in subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1)) and the service obligation in an agreement executed by that person (under subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2)), but only in exceptional circumstances in which a waiver is necessary for reasons permitted in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> With respect to each waiver granted under this subsection, the service acquisition executive (or his delegate) shall set forth in a written document the rationale for the decision to grant the waiver.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rotation Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish a policy encouraging the rotation of members of the acquisition workforce serving in critical acquisition positions to new assignments after completion of five years of service in such positions, or, in the case of a program manager, after completion of a major program milestone, whichever is longer. Such rotation policy shall be designed to ensure opportunities for career broadening assignments and an infusion of new ideas into critical acquisition positions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish a procedure under which the assignment of each person assigned to a critical acquisition position shall be reviewed on a case-by-case basis for the purpose of determining whether the Government and such person would be better served by a reassignment to a different position. Such a review shall be carried out with respect to each such person not later than five years after that person is assigned to a critical position.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Centralized Job Referral System</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations providing for the use of centralized lists to ensure that persons are selected for critical positions without regard to geographic location of applicants for such positions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exchange Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish, for purposes of broadening the experience of members of the acquisition workforce, a test program in which members of the acquisition workforce serving in a military department or Defense Agency are assigned or detailed to an acquisition position in another department or agency. Under the test program, the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, at least 5 percent of the members of the acquisition workforce in critical acquisition positions shall serve in such exchange assignments each year. The test program shall operate for not less than a period of three years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for Assignments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each military department, acting through the service acquisition executive for that department, is responsible for making assignments of civilian and military personnel of that military department who are members of the acquisition workforce to critical acquisition positions.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1646</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 812(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1074(a)(9)(D)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2659</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(e)(5)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1227</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 831(b)(4), 832(b)(3), 833(2), (3), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1550; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(j)(10)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1849(f)</ref>, formerly § 1849(m), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4264</ref>, renumbered § 1849(f) and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(5)(B), (6)(D), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2155</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1735.</num>
<heading> Education, training, and experience requirements for critical acquisition positions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualification Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In establishing the education, training, and experience requirements under <ref>section 1723 of this title</ref> for critical acquisition positions, the Secretary of Defense shall, at a minimum, include the requirements set forth in subsections (b) through (e).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Managers and Deputy Program Managers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before being assigned to a position as a program manager or deputy program manager of a major defense acquisition program or a significant nonmajor defense acquisition program, a person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> must have completed the program management course at the Defense Systems Management College or a management program at an accredited educational institution determined to be comparable by the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> must have executed a written agreement as required in section 1734(b)(2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a program manager of a major defense acquisition program, must have at least eight years of experience in acquisition, at least two years of which were performed in a systems program office or similar organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a program manager of a significant nonmajor defense acquisition program, must have at least six years of experience in acquisition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a deputy program manager of a major defense acquisition program, must have at least six years of experience in acquisition, at least two years of which were performed in a systems program office or similar organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a deputy program manager of a significant nonmajor defense acquisition program, must have at least four years of experience in acquisition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Executive Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before being assigned to a position as a program executive officer, a person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> must have completed the program management course at the Defense Systems Management College or a management program at an accredited educational institution in the private sector determined to be comparable by the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> must have at least 10 years experience in an acquisition position, at least four years of which were performed while assigned to a critical acquisition position; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> must have held a position as a program manager or a deputy program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General and Flag Officers and Civilians in Equivalent Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before a general or flag officer, or a civilian serving in a position equivalent in grade to the grade of such an officer, may be assigned to a critical acquisition position, the person must have at least 10 years experience in an acquisition position, at least four years of which were performed while assigned to a critical acquisition position.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senior Contracting Officials</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before a person may be assigned to a critical acquisition position as a senior contracting official, the person must have at least four years experience in contracting.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1648</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 812(d)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2451</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(20)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1545</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1736.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(e)(6)(A)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1227</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1737.</num>
<heading> Definitions and general provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “program manager” means, with respect to a defense acquisition program, the member of the acquisition workforce responsible for managing the program, regardless of the title given the member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “deputy program manager” means the person who has authority to act on behalf of the program manager in the absence of the program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “significant nonmajor defense acquisition program” means a Department of Defense acquisition program that is not a major defense acquisition program (as defined in <ref>section 4201 of this title</ref>) and that is estimated by the Secretary of Defense to require an eventual total expenditure for research, development, test, and evaluation of more than the dollar threshold set forth in <ref>section 3041(b)(1) of this title</ref> for such purposes for a major system or an eventual total expenditure for procurement of more than the dollar threshold set forth in <ref>section 3041(b)(1) of this title</ref> for such purpose for a major system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “program executive officer” has the meaning given such term in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “senior contracting official” means a director of contracting, or a principal deputy to a director of contracting, serving in the office of the Secretary of a military department, the headquarters of a military department, the head of a Defense Agency, a subordinate command headquarters, or in a major systems or logistics contracting activity in the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any civilian or military member of the acquisition workforce who does not meet the education, training, and experience requirements for a critical acquisition position established under this subchapter may not carry out the duties or exercise the authorities of that position, except for a period not to exceed six months, unless a waiver of the requirements is granted under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each military department (acting through the service acquisition executive for that department) or the Secretary of Defense (acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment) for Defense Agencies and other components of the Department of Defense may waive, on a case-by-case basis, the requirements established under this subchapter with respect to the assignment of an individual to a particular critical acquisition position. Such a waiver may be granted only if unusual circumstances justify the waiver or if the Secretary concerned (or official to whom the waiver authority is delegated) determines that the individual’s qualifications obviate the need for meeting the education, training, and experience requirements established under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1650</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(8)</ref>, (c), <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1472</ref>, 1475; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 831(b)(5), 832(b)(4), 833(2), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1550; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(j)(11)</ref>, title IX, § 902(21), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1520</ref>, 1545; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1806(e)(4), 1846(i)(4), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4156</ref>, 4252.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>EDUCATION AND TRAINING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1741.</num>
<heading> Policies and programs: establishment and implementation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policies and Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish policies and procedures for the establishment and implementation of the education and training programs authorized by this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding Levels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment each year shall recommend to the Secretary of Defense the funding levels to be requested in the defense budget to implement the education and training programs under this subchapter. The Secretary of Defense shall set forth separately the funding levels requested for such programs in the Department of Defense budget justification documents submitted in support of the President’s budget submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each military department, acting through the service acquisition executive for that department, shall establish and implement the education and training programs authorized by this subchapter. In carrying out such requirement, the Secretary concerned shall ensure that such programs are established and implemented throughout the military department concerned and, to the maximum extent practicable, uniformly with the programs of the other military departments.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1651</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(22)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1545</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1742.</num>
<heading> Internship, cooperative education, and scholarship programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall conduct the following education and training programs:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An intern program for purposes of providing highly qualified and talented individuals an opportunity for accelerated promotions, career broadening assignments, and specified training to prepare them for entry into acquisition positions in the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A cooperative education credit program under which the Secretary arranges, through cooperative arrangements entered into with one or more accredited institutions of higher education, for such institutions to grant undergraduate credit for work performed by students who are employed by the Department of Defense in acquisition positions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A scholarship program for the purpose of qualifying personnel for acquisition positions in the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scholarship Program Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each recipient of a scholarship under a program conducted under subsection (a)(3) shall be required to sign a written agreement that sets forth the terms and conditions of the scholarship. The agreement shall be in a form prescribed by the Secretary and shall include terms and conditions, including terms and conditions addressing reimbursement in the event that a recipient fails to fulfill the requirements of the agreement, that are comparable to those set forth as a condition for providing advanced education assistance under section 2005. The obligation to reimburse the United States under an agreement under this subsection is, for all purposes, a debt owing the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1651</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 834(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1550</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VIII, § 812(b)</ref>, title X, § 1084(f)(1), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2013</ref>, 2064; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(j)(12)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1520</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1743.</num>
<heading> Awards to recognize members of the acquisition workforce</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President of the Defense Acquisition University shall establish two programs to provide awards to recognize members of the acquisition workforce as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An award of not more than $5,000 to such members who use an iterative writing process to document a first-hand account of using independent judgment to overcome an obstacle the member faced while working within the defense acquisition system (as defined in <ref>section 3001 of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An award of not more than $5,000 to such members who make the best use of the flexibilities and authorities granted by the Federal Acquisition Regulation and Department of Defense Instruction 5000.02 (Operation of the Defense Acquisition System).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Number of Awards.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President of the Defense Acquisition University may make not more than five awards under subsection (a)(1) and one award under subsection (a)(2) each year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of the acquisition workforce may receive one award each year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Writing Award.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A member of the acquisition workforce desiring an award under subsection (a)(1) shall submit to the President of the Defense Acquisition University the first-hand account described in such subsection. Such first-hand account shall demonstrate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an original and engaging idea documenting the use of independent judgment to overcome an obstacle the recipient faced while working within the defense acquisition system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the use of an iterative writing process, including evidence of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> critical thinking;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> incorporation of feedback from diverse perspectives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> editing to achieve plain writing (as defined in section 3 of the Plain Writing Act of 2010 (<ref>5 U.S.C. 301</ref> note)).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Website</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President of the Defense Acquisition University shall establish and maintain a website to serve as a repository for submissions made under paragraph (1). Such website shall allow for public comments and discussion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Flexibility Award</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A member of the acquisition workforce desiring an award under subsection (a)(2) shall submit to the President of the Defense Acquisition University documentation that such member uses approaches to program management that emphasize innovation and local adaptation, including the use of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> simplified acquisition procedures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inherent flexibilities within the Federal Acquisition Regulation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> commercial contracting approaches;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> public-private partnership agreements and practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> cost-sharing arrangements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> innovative contractor incentive practices; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> other innovative implementations of acquisition flexibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall use funds from the Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Account to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 801(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2692</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1744.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 834(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1551</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1745.</num>
<heading> Additional education and training programs available to acquisition personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tuition Reimbursement and Training</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall provide for tuition reimbursement and training (including a full-time course of study leading to a degree) for acquisition personnel in the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For civilian personnel, the reimbursement and training shall be provided under <ref>section 4107(b) of title 5</ref> for the purposes described in that section. For purposes of such section 4107(b), there is deemed to be, until <date date="2010-09-30">September 30, 2010</date>, a shortage of qualified personnel to serve in acquisition positions in the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of members of the armed forces, the limitation in <ref>section 2007(a) of this title</ref> shall not apply to tuition reimbursement and training provided for under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repayment of Student Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may repay all or part of a student loan under <ref>section 5379 of title 5</ref> for an employee of the Department of Defense appointed to an acquisition position.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1653</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1503(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title IX, § 925(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 726</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1123], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–317.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1746.</num>
<heading> Defense Acquisition University</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense Acquisition University Structure</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall establish and maintain a defense acquisition university structure to provide for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the professional educational development and training of the acquisition workforce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> research and analysis of defense acquisition policy issues from an academic perspective.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civilian Faculty Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may employ as many civilians as professors, instructors, and lecturers in the defense acquisition university structure as the Secretary considers necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure the defense acquisition university structure includes relevant expert lecturers from extramural institutions (as defined in <ref>section 1746a(g) of this title</ref>), industry, or federally funded research and development centers to advance acquisition workforce competence regarding commercial business interests, acquisition process-related innovations, and other relevant leading practices of the private sector.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The compensation of persons employed under this subsection shall be as prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “defense acquisition university” includes the Defense Systems Management College.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Curriculum Development</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President of the Defense Acquisition University shall work with the relevant professional schools and degree-granting institutions of the Department of Defense and military departments, and with extramural institutions (as defined in <ref>section 1746a(g) of this title</ref>), to ensure that best practices are used in curriculum development to support acquisition workforce positions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Research and Development Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In engaging in research and development projects pursuant to subsection (a) of <ref>section 4001 of this title</ref> by a contract, cooperative agreement, or grant pursuant to subsection (b)(1) of such section, the Secretary may enter into such contract or cooperative agreement or award such grant through the Defense Acquisition University.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Defense Acquisition University shall be considered a Government-operated Federal laboratory for purposes of section 12 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 3710a</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">President Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall appoint the President of the Defense Acquisition University.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> When determining who to appoint under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall, in consultation with the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering and the service acquisition executives, prioritize highly qualified candidates who demonstrate a combination of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Leadership abilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Experience using leading practices to develop talent in the private sector.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Other qualifying factors, including experience with and an understanding of the defense acquisition system (as defined in <ref>section 3001 of this title</ref>), an understanding of emerging technologies and the defense applications of such technologies, experience partnering with States, national associations, and academia, and experience with learning technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term of the President of the Defense Acquisition University shall be not more than five years, unless the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment determines it necessary to extend the term for up to an additional five years. The preceding sentence does not apply to the President of the Defense Acquisition University serving on <date date="2025-01-01">January 1, 2025</date>, who shall serve a maximum term of three years beginning on the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 without an option for extension of such term.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1653</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1503(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 877(c)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4306</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title II, § 214(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(c)</ref>, title IX, § 902(23), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1516</ref>, 1545; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(32)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1841(e)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3872</ref>, 4244; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 832(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2712</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 831</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1984</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1746a.</num>
<heading> Acquisition workforce educational partnerships</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall establish a program within Defense Acquisition University to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> facilitate the engagement of relevant experts, including with the acquisition research activities established under <ref>section 4142 of this title</ref>, with the faculty of the Defense Acquisition University to assess and modify the curriculum of the Defense Acquisition University, as appropriate, to enhance the capabilities of the Defense Acquisition University to support educational, training, and research activities in support of acquisition missions of the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish a cross-discipline, peer mentoring program for academic advising and to address critical retention concerns with respect to the acquisition workforce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> partner with extramural institutions and military department functional leadership to offer training and on-the-job learning support to all members of the acquisition workforce addressing operational challenges that affect procurement decisionmaking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> support the partnerships between the Department of Defense and extramural institutions with missions relating to the training and continuous development of members of the acquisition workforce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> accelerate the adoption, appropriate design and customization, and use of flexible acquisition practices by the acquisition workforce by expanding the availability of training and on-the-job learning and guidance on such practices and incorporating such training into the curriculum of the Defense Acquisition University; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> support and enhance the capabilities of the faculty of the Defense Acquisition University, and the currency and applicability of the knowledge possessed by such faculty, by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> building partnerships between the faculty of the Defense Acquisition University and the director of, and individuals involved with, the activities established under <ref>section 4142 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> supporting the preparation and drafting of the reports required under subsection (f)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> instituting a program under which each member of the faculty of the Defense Acquisition University shall be detailed to an operational acquisition position in a military department or Defense Agency, or to an extramural institution, for not less than six months out of every five year period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senior Official</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 180 days after the enactment of this section, the President of the Defense Acquisition University shall designate a senior official to execute activities under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support From Other Department of Defense Organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may direct other elements of the Department of Defense to provide personnel, resources, and other support to the program established under this section, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment may use amounts available in the Defense Acquisition Workforce and Development Account (as established under <ref>section 1705 of this title</ref>) to carry out the requirements of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2022-09-30">September 30, 2022</date>, and annually thereafter, the President of the Defense Acquisition University shall submit to the Secretary of Defense and the congressional defense committees a report describing the activities conducted under this section during the one-year period ending on the date on which such report is submitted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption to Report Termination Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Section 1080(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 (<ref>Public Law 114–92</ref>; <ref>129 Stat. 1000</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 111</ref> note), as amended by section 1061(j) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<ref>Public Law 114–328</ref>; <ref>130 Stat. 2405</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 111</ref> note), does not apply with respect to the reports required to be submitted to Congress under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition workforce</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “acquisition workforce” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 1705(g) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extramural institutions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “extramural institutions” means participants in an activity established under <ref>section 4142 of this title</ref>, public sector organizations, and nonprofit credentialing organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 801(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1811</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1747.</num>
<heading> Acquisition fellowship program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish and carry out an acquisition fellowship program in accordance with this section in order to enhance the ability of the Department of Defense to recruit employees who are highly qualified in fields of acquisition.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of Fellowships</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may designate up to 25 prospective employees of the Department of Defense as acquisition fellows.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In order to be eligible for designation as an acquisition fellow, an employee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> must complete at least 2 years of Federal Government service as an employee in an acquisition position in the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> must be serving in an acquisition position in the Department of Defense that involves the performance of duties likely to result in significant restrictions under law on the employment activities of that employee after leaving Government service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Two-Year Period of Research and Teaching</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under the fellowship program, the Secretary of Defense shall pay designated acquisition fellows to engage in research or teaching for a 2-year period in a field related to Federal Government acquisition policy. Such research or teaching may be conducted in the defense acquisition university structure of the Department of Defense, any other institution of professional education of the Federal Government, or a nonprofit institution of higher education. Each fellow shall be paid at a rate equal to the rate of pay payable for the level of the position in which the fellow served in the Department of Defense before undertaking such research or teaching.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 841(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2468</ref>, § 2410h; renumbered § 1747, <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1062(a)(10)(A)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1748.</num>
<heading> Fulfillment standards for acquisition workforce training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall develop fulfillment standards, and implement and maintain a program, for purposes of the training requirements of sections 1723, 1724, and 1735 of this title. Such fulfillment standards shall consist of criteria for determining whether an individual has demonstrated competence in the areas that would be taught in the training courses required under those sections. If an individual meets the appropriate fulfillment standard, the applicable training requirement is fulfilled.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 874(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4304</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(24)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1545</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1749.</num>
<heading> Field training for acquisition and sustainment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary for Acquisition and Sustainment shall establish a training program that supports cross-functional personnel and contractors of the Department of Defense involved in any phase of the acquisition and sustainment lifecycle in making important decisions with respect to acquisition or sustainment, including requirements validation, the development of an acquisition strategy, awarding contracts, and ongoing management of performance and governance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The training program established under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> create deployable training teams to coach the cross-functional personnel and contractors described in subsection (a) and facilitate such personnel and contractors successfully completing a phase of an acquisition or sustainment effort with the same training team to the maximum extent possible;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, ensure that the same training team under paragraph (1) provides the support described under such paragraph with respect to a phase of an acquisition or sustainment effort until such phase is completed or otherwise ends;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide to the cross-functional personnel and contractors described in subsection (a) short, intermittent lessons on innovative acquisition and fielding procedures, flexible contracting frameworks, and business negotiation skills that are timed to align the topics of the lessons to relevant activities under a phase of an acquisition or sustainment effort;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> emphasizes— <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002079">1</ref></chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the acquisition of commercial products, commercial services, and commercially available off-the-shelf items (as such terms are defined in sections 103, 103a, and 104, respectively, of title 41);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> technology procured “as-a-service” or as a consumption-based solution (as defined in section 834 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<ref>10 U.S.C. 4571</ref> note)); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> using the middle tier acquisition pathways under <ref>section 3602 of this title</ref> and the pathways under <ref>section 3603 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> include a process for collecting feedback on the training program and performance of the training teams to improve the training program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training Team Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each training team created under the training program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> include <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002080">2</ref> at not less than one individual from the private sector or academia with expertise in conducting commercial transactions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has excellent facilitation skills and can coach the cross-functional personnel and contractors described in subsection (a) on applying the best practices to the formulation of acquisition and sustainment programs and contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall ensure that each member of the acquisition workforce who participates in the training program established under subsection (a) can meet up to 80 hours of a continuous education requirement established under <ref>section 1723 of this title</ref> by participating in the training program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>During fiscal year 2025, the Secretary of each military department shall carry out not less than one pilot program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> under which the military department shall receive support under the training program established under subsection (a) with respect to acquisition and sustainment efforts of high importance or urgency to the military department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> which the Under Secretary for Acquisition and Sustainment shall use to develop the training material and procedures for the training program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Under Secretary for Acquisition and Sustainment is authorized to use funds available for the Defense Acquisition University for civilian faculty members, contracts, and associated travel and expenses to carry out the training program established in (a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002081">3</ref> starting in fiscal year 2025, and for fiscal years 2027 through fiscal year 2031—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not less than 25 percent of civilian faculty members authorized under <ref>section 1746 of this title</ref> shall be detailed on a reimbursable basis to the training program established in (a) <sup>3</sup> for a minimum of half of their time; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not less than 25 percent of all contract or agreement obligations in support of Defense Acquisition University shall be reserved for the training program established in (a),<sup>3</sup> including the training of civilian faculty members to facilitate programs under the training program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than <date date="2026-11-01">November 1, 2026</date>, the Under Secretary for Acquisition and Sustainment shall provide a report to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives on the training program required under subsection (a), including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number and qualifications of civilian faculty members detailed to the training program under subsection (f)(1), including any training requirements they receive to facilitate programs under the training program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an identification of contractor or university support for the training program pursuant to subsection (f)(2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a budget for the training program that meets the requirements of subsection (f);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the status and success of the pilot program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any additional information or recommendations with respect to the training program that the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 832(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1984</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>GENERAL MANAGEMENT PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1761.</num>
<heading> Management information system</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to ensure that the military departments and Defense Agencies establish a management information system capable of providing standardized information to the Secretary on persons serving in acquisition positions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The management information system shall, at a minimum, provide for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The collection and retention of information concerning the qualifications, assignments, and tenure of persons in the acquisition workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any exceptions and waivers granted with respect to the application of qualification, assignment, and tenure policies, procedures, and practices to such persons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Relative promotion rates for military personnel in the acquisition workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1653</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(15)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2062</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1762.</num>
<heading> Demonstration project relating to certain acquisition personnel management policies and procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commencement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense is authorized to carry out a demonstration project, the purpose of which is to determine the feasibility or desirability of one or more proposals for improving the personnel management policies or procedures that apply with respect to the acquisition workforce of the Department of Defense and supporting personnel assigned to work directly with the acquisition workforce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms and Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, any demonstration project described in subsection (a) shall be subject to <ref>section 4703 of title 5</ref> and all other provisions of such title that apply with respect to any demonstration project under such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (3), in applying <ref>section 4703 of title 5</ref> with respect to a demonstration project described in subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> “180 days” in subsection (b)(4) of such section shall be deemed to read “120 days”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> “90 days” in subsection (b)(6) of such section shall be deemed to read “30 days”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> subsection (d)(1) of such section shall be disregarded.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (2) shall not apply with respect to a demonstration project unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for each organization or team participating in the demonstration project—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> at least one-third of the workforce participating in the demonstration project consists of members of the acquisition workforce; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> at least two-thirds of the workforce participating in the demonstration project consists of members of the acquisition workforce and supporting personnel assigned to work directly with the acquisition workforce; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the demonstration project commences before <date date="2007-10-01">October 1, 2007</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall exercise the authorities granted to the Office of Personnel Management under <ref>section 4703 of title 5</ref> for purposes of the demonstration project authorized under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Number of Participants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total number of persons who may participate at any one time in the demonstration project under this section may not exceed 130,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Reorganizations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The applicability of paragraph (2) of subsection (b) to an organization or team shall not terminate by reason that the organization or team, after having satisfied the conditions in paragraph (3) of such subsection when it began to participate in a demonstration project under this section, ceases to meet one or both of the conditions set forth in subparagraph (A) of such paragraph (3) as a result of a reorganization, restructuring, realignment, consolidation, or other organizational change.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessments</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall designate an independent organization to conduct two assessments of the acquisition workforce demonstration project described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each such assessment shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of the workforce included in the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An explanation of the flexibilities used in the project to appoint individuals to the acquisition workforce and whether those appointments are based on competitive procedures and recognize veteran’s preferences.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An explanation of the flexibilities used in the project to develop a performance appraisal system that recognizes excellence in performance and offers opportunities for improvement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The steps taken to ensure that such system is fair and transparent for all employees in the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> How the project allows the organization to better meet mission needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> An analysis of how the flexibilities in subparagraphs (B) and (C) are used, and what barriers have been encountered that inhibit their use.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> Whether there is a process for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> ensuring ongoing performance feedback and dialogue among supervisors, managers, and employees throughout the performance appraisal period; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> setting timetables for performance appraisals.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The project’s impact on career progression.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The project’s appropriateness or inappropriateness in light of the complexities of the workforce affected.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> The project’s sufficiency in terms of providing protections for diversity in promotion and retention of personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> The adequacy of the training, policy guidelines, and other preparations afforded in connection with using the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Whether there is a process for ensuring employee involvement in the development and improvement of the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The first assessment under this subsection shall be completed not later than <date date="2012-09-30">September 30, 2012</date>. The second and final assessment shall be completed not later than <date date="2016-09-30">September 30, 2016</date>. The Secretary shall submit to the covered congressional committees a copy of each assessment within 30 days after receipt by the Secretary of the assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Congressional Committees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “covered congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority to conduct a demonstration project under this section shall terminate on <date date="2031-12-31">December 31, 2031</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conversion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Within 6 months after the authority to conduct a demonstration project under this section is terminated as provided in subsection (g), employees in the project shall convert to the civilian personnel system created pursuant to <ref>section 9902 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 872(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4300</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 846</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 916</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 867(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2306</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 844(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(27)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1813</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 812</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1823</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 833</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1763.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 835(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1551</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1764.</num>
<heading> Authority to establish different minimum requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may prescribe a different minimum number of years of experience, different minimum education qualifications, and different tenure of service qualifications to be required for eligibility for appointment or advancement to an acquisition position referred to in subsection (b) than is required for such position under or pursuant to any provision of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any requirement prescribed under paragraph (1) for a position referred to in any paragraph of subsection (b) shall be applied uniformly to all positions referred to in such paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section applies to the following acquisition positions in the Department of Defense:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Contracting officer, except a position referred to in paragraph (6).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Program executive officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Senior contracting official.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Deputy program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A position in the contract contingency force of an armed force that is filled by a member of that armed force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “contract contingency force”, with respect to an armed force, has the meaning given such term in regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 835(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1551</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VIII, § 812(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2013</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1765.</num>
<heading> Competency development</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For each acquisition workforce career field, the Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish, for the civilian personnel in that career field, defined proficiency standards and technical and nontechnical competencies which shall be used in personnel qualification assessments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assign resources to accomplish such technical and nontechnical competencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1518</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1766.</num>
<heading> Joint reserve detachment of the Defense Innovation Unit</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments, may establish a joint reserve detachment (referred to in this section as the “Detachment”) composed of members of the reserve components described in subsection (b) to be assigned to each office of the Defense Innovation Unit to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> support engagement and collaboration with private-sector industry and the community surrounding the location of such office; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> accelerate the use and adoption of commercially-developed technologies for national security purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Secretary of a military department shall select for the Detachment, and make efforts to retain, members of the reserve components who possess relevant private-sector experience in the fields of business, acquisition, intelligence, engineering, technology transfer, science, mathematics, program management, logistics, cybersecurity, or such other fields as determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Detachment shall have the following duties:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Providing the Department of Defense with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> expertise on and analysis of commercially-developed technologies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> commercially-developed technologies to be used as alternatives for technologies in use by the Department; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> opportunities for greater engagement and collaboration between the Department and private-sector industry on innovative technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> On an ongoing basis—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> partnering with the military departments, the combatant commands, and other Department of Defense organizations to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identify and rapidly prototype commercially-developed technologies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> use alternative contracting mechanisms to procure such technologies;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> increasing awareness of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the work of the Defense Innovation Unit; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the technology requirements of the Department of Defense, as identified in the most recent—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> National Defense Strategy;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> National Defense Science and Technology Strategy as directed under section 218 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<ref>Public Law 115–232</ref>; <ref>132 Stat. 1679</ref>); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> relevant policy and guidance from the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> using the investment in research and development made by private-sector industry in assessing and developing dual-use technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Carrying out other activities as directed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joint Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Assignment to a Detachment shall not qualify as a joint duty assignment, as defined in <ref>section 668(b)(1) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, unless approved by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title II, § 213(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1256</ref>, § 2358b; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(37)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1842(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3872</ref>, 4244; renumbered § 1766, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1878A(a)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(q)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2149</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 211(d), 213(a), title XVII, § 1701(q)(1), (u)(3)(B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1587</ref>, 1588, 2148, 2152; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title IX, § 913(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 368</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>