<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1219—</num>
<heading>STANDARDS AND PROCEDURES FOR RETENTION AND PROMOTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12641.</num>
<heading> Standards and procedures: Secretary to prescribe</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall, by regulation, prescribe—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> standards and qualifications for the retention and promotion of members of the reserve components under his jurisdiction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> equitable procedures for the periodic determination of the compliance of each such Reserve with those standards and qualifications.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> If a Reserve fails to comply with the standards and qualifications prescribed under subsection (a), he shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if qualified, be transferred to an inactive reserve status;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if qualified, be retired without pay; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have his appointment or enlistment terminated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 79</ref>, § 1001; renumbered § 12641 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(h)(2)</ref>, (4)(A), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12642.</num>
<heading> Standards and qualifications: result of failure to comply with</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> To be retained in an active status, a reserve commissioned officer must, in any applicable yearly period, attain the number of points under <ref>section 12732(a)(2) of this title</ref> prescribed by the Secretary concerned, with the approval of the Secretary of Defense in the case of a Secretary of a military department, and must conform to such other standards and qualifications as the Secretary concerned may prescribe. The Secretary may not prescribe a minimum of more than 50 points under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to <ref>section 12645 of this title</ref>, a reserve commissioned officer who fails to attain the number of points, or to conform to the standards and qualifications, prescribed in subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be transferred to the Retired Reserve if he is qualified and applies therefor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if he is not qualified or does not apply for transfer to the Retired Reserve, be transferred to an inactive status, if he is qualified therefor; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if he is not transferred to the Retired Reserve or an inactive status, be discharged from his reserve appointment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to commissioned warrant officers or to adjutants general or assistant adjutants general of States, Puerto Rico, and the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(22)(A)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1443</ref>, § 1002; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; renumbered § 12642 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(h)(2), 1675(d)(1), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2996</ref>, 3018; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3440</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12643.</num>
<heading> Boards for appointment, promotion, and certain other purposes: composition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided in <ref>section 612(a)(3) of this title</ref> and except for boards that may be convened to select Reserves for appointment in the Regular Army, Regular Navy, Regular Air Force, or Regular Marine Corps, each board convened for the appointment, promotion, demotion, involuntary release from active duty, discharge, or retirement of Reserves shall include at least one member of the Reserves, with the exact number of Reserves determined by the Secretary concerned in his discretion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each member of a board convened for the selection for promotion, or for the demotion or discharge, of Reserves must be senior in rank to the persons under consideration by that board. However, a member serving in a legal advisory capacity may be junior in rank to any person, other than a judge advocate or law specialist, being considered by that board; and a member serving in a medical advisory capacity may be junior in rank to any person, other than a medical officer, being considered by that board.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 11</ref>, § 266; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 501(4)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2907</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 124</ref>; renumbered § 12643, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12644.</num>
<heading> Members physically not qualified for active duty: discharge or transfer to retired status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided by law, the Secretary concerned may provide for the honorable discharge or the transfer to a retired status of members of the reserve components under his jurisdiction who are found to be not physically qualified for active duty. However, no member of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States may be transferred under this subsection without the consent of the governor or other appropriate authority of the jurisdiction concerned.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 79</ref>, § 1004; <ref>Pub. L. 86–603, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-07">July 7, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 519</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1651</ref>; renumbered § 12644 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1661(a)(4), 1662(h)(2), (4)(B), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2980</ref>, 2996, 2997.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12645.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers: retention until completion of required service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b), a reserve commissioned officer who has not completed the period of service required of him by <ref>section 651 of this title</ref> or any other provision of law may not be discharged or transferred from an active status under chapter 843, 1407, 1409, or 1411 of this title or chapter 21 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002188">1</ref> of title 14. Unless, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, he is promoted to a higher reserve grade, he shall be retained in an active status in his reserve grade for the rest of his period of required service and shall be an additional number to the authorized strength of his grade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) does not prevent the discharge or transfer from an active status of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a commissioned warrant officer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an officer on the active-duty list or a reserve active-status list who is found not qualified for promotion to the grade of first lieutenant, in the case of an officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps, or lieutenant (junior grade), in the case of an officer of the Navy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an officer on the active-duty list or reserve active-status list who has failed of selection for promotion for the second time to the grade of captain, in the case of an officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps, or to the grade of lieutenant, in the case of an officer of the Navy; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an officer whose discharge or transfer from an active status is required by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(22)(B)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1444</ref>, § 1005; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–586, § 2</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1920</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 528(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2525</ref>; renumbered § 12645 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1627, 1662(h)(2), 1675(d)(2), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2962</ref>, 2996, 3018; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 495</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 544(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2523</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12646.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers: retention of after completing 18 or more, but less than 20, years of service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> If on the date prescribed for the discharge or transfer from an active status of a reserve commissioned officer he is entitled to be credited with at least 18, but less than 19, years of service computed under <ref>section 12732 of this title</ref>, he may not be discharged or transferred from an active status under chapter 843, 1407, or 1409 of this title or chapter 21 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002189">1</ref> of title 14, without his consent before the earlier of the following dates—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which he is entitled to be credited with 20 years of service computed under <ref>section 12732 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the third anniversary of the date on which he would otherwise be discharged or transferred from an active status.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> If on the date prescribed for the discharge or transfer from an active status of a reserve commissioned officer he is entitled to be credited with at least 19, but less than 20, years of service computed under <ref>section 12732 of this title</ref>, he may not be discharged or transferred from an active status under chapter 843, 1407, or 1409 of this title or chapter 21 <sup>1</sup> of title 14, without his consent before the earlier of the following dates—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which he is entitled to be credited with 20 years of service computed under <ref>section 12732 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the second anniversary of the date on which he would otherwise be discharged or transferred from an active status.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An officer who is retained in an active status under subsection (a) or (b) is an additional number to those otherwise authorized.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Subsections (a) and (b) do not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> officers who are discharged or transferred from an active status for physical disability, for cause, or because they have reached the age at which transfer from an active status or discharge is required by law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> commissioned warrant officers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A reserve commissioned officer on active duty (other than for training) or full-time National Guard duty (other than full-time National Guard duty for training only) who, on the date on which the officer would otherwise be removed from an active status under section 8373, 14513, or 14514 of this title or section 740 <sup>1</sup> of title 14, is within two years of qualifying for retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title may, in the discretion of the Secretary concerned and subject to paragraph (2), be retained on that duty for a period of not more than two years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An officer may be retained on active duty or full-time National Guard duty under paragraph (1) only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at the end of the period for which the officer is retained the officer will be qualified for retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the officer will not, before the end of that period, reach the age at which transfer from an active status or discharge is required by this title or title 14.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An officer who is retained on active duty or full-time National Guard duty under this section may not be removed from an active status while on that duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(22)(B)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1444</ref>, § 1006; amended <ref>Pub. L. 86–559, § 1(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-30">June 30, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 264</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–651, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–130, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1967-11-08">Nov. 8, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 374</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–586, § 3</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1920</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1015</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(30)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2922</ref>; renumbered § 12646 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(h)(2), 1675(d)(3), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2996</ref>, 3018; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12647.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers: retention in active status while assigned to Selective Service System or serving as United States property and fiscal officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding chapters 843, 1407, and 1409 of this title, a reserve commissioned officer, other than a commissioned warrant officer, who is assigned to the Selective Service System or who is a property and fiscal officer appointed, designated, or detailed under <ref>section 708 of title 32</ref>, may be retained in an active status in that assignment or position until he becomes 62 years of age.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(22)(B)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1445</ref>, § 1007; amended <ref>Pub. L. 86–559, § 1(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-30">June 30, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 265</ref>; renumbered § 12647 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(h)(2), 1675(d)(4), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2996</ref>, 3018; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 514(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>