<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 551—</num>
<heading>MISSILE DEFENSE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ORGANIZATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5501.</num>
<heading> National missile defense policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to research, develop, test, procure, deploy, and sustain, with funding subject to the annual authorization of appropriations for National Missile Defense, systems that provide effective, layered missile defense capabilities to defeat increasingly complex missile threats in all phases of flight; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to rely on nuclear deterrence to address more sophisticated and larger quantity near-peer intercontinental missile threats to the homeland of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2187</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5502.</num>
<heading> Missile defense agency <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002150">1</ref></heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment of Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Missile Defense Agency shall be a general or flag officer appointed for a six-year term.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deputy Director</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is a Deputy Director of the Missile Defense Agency, who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Defense from among the general officers on active duty in the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force, or from among the flag officers on active duty in the Navy. In selecting an individual to serve as the Deputy Director, the Secretary of Defense shall select an individual who serves in a different armed force than the armed force in which the Director serves.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Deputy Director shall be appointed for a term of not fewer than two, and not more than four years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Deputy Director shall be under the authority, direction, and control of the Director of the Missile Defense Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The Deputy Director shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> carry out such responsibilities as may be assigned by the Director; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serve as acting director during periods of absence by the Director, or at such times as the office of the Director is vacant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of Changes to Non-standard Acquisition and Requirements Processes and Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may not make any changes to the missile defense non-standard acquisition and requirements processes and responsibilities unless, with respect to those proposed changes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary, without delegation, has taken each of the actions specified in paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a period of 120 days has elapsed following the date on which the Secretary submits the report under subparagraph (C) of such paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary proposes to make changes to the missile defense non-standard acquisition and requirements processes and responsibilities, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consult with the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy, the Secretaries of the military departments, the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, the Commander of the United States Strategic Command, the Commander of the United States Northern Command, and the Director of the Missile Defense Agency, regarding the changes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> certify to the congressional defense committees that the Secretary has coordinated the changes with, and received the views of, the individuals referred to in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> submit to the congressional defense committees a report that contains—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of the changes, the rationale for the changes, and the views of the individuals referred to in subparagraph (A) with respect to the changes;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a certification that the changes will not impair the missile defense capabilities of the United States nor degrade the unique special acquisition authorities of the Missile Defense Agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> with respect to any such changes to Department of Defense Directive 5134.09, or successor directive issued in accordance with this subsection, a final draft of the proposed modified directive, both in an electronic format and in a hard copy format; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> with respect to any such changes to Department of Defense Directive 5134.09, or successor directive issued in accordance with this subsection, provide to such committees a briefing on the proposed modified directive described in subparagraph (C)(iii).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “non-standard acquisition and requirements processes and responsibilities” means the processes and responsibilities described in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the memorandum of the Secretary of Defense titled “Missile Defense Program Direction” signed on <date date="2002-01-02">January 2, 2002</date>, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this subsection or as modified in accordance with this subsection, or any successor memorandum issued in accordance with this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Department of Defense Directive 5134.09, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this subsection (without regard to any modifications described in Directive-type Memorandum 20–002 of the Deputy Secretary of Defense, or any amendments or extensions thereto made before the date of such enactment), or as modified in accordance with this subsection, or any successor directive issued in accordance with this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> United States Strategic Command Instruction 538–3 titled “MD Warfighter Involvement Process”, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this subsection or as modified in accordance with this subsection, or any successor instruction issued in accordance with this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2187</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>BUDGET AND ACQUISITION MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5511.</num>
<heading> Ballistic missile defense programs: program elements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Elements Specified by President</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department of Defense budget for any fiscal year (as submitted with the budget of the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>), the amount requested for activities of the Missile Defense Agency shall be set forth in accordance with such program elements as the President may specify.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Separate Program Elements for Programs Entering Engineering and Manufacturing Development</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that each ballistic missile defense program that enters engineering and manufacturing development is assigned a separate, dedicated program element.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “engineering and manufacturing development” means the period in the course of an acquisition program during which the primary objectives are to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> translate the most promising design approach into a stable, interoperable, producible, supportable, and cost-effective design;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> validate the manufacturing or production process; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> demonstrate system capabilities through testing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Management and Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount requested for a fiscal year for any program element specified for that fiscal year pursuant to subsection (a) shall include requests for the amounts necessary for the management and support of the programs, projects, and activities contained in that program element.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5512.</num>
<heading> Ballistic missile defense programs: display of amounts for research, development, test, and evaluation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any amount in the budget submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> for any fiscal year for research, development, test, and evaluation for the integration of a ballistic missile defense element into the overall ballistic missile defense architecture shall be set forth under the account of the Department of Defense for Defense-wide research, development, test, and evaluation and, within that account, under the subaccount (or other budget activity level) for the Missile Defense Agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall establish criteria for the transfer of responsibility for a ballistic missile defense program from the Director of the Missile Defense Agency to the Secretary of a military department. The criteria established for such a transfer shall, at a minimum, address the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The technical maturity of the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The availability of facilities for production.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The commitment of the Secretary of the military department concerned to procurement funding for that program, as shown by funding through the future-years defense program and other defense planning documents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall submit the criteria established, and any modifications to those criteria, to the congressional defense committees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of Transfer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before responsibility for a ballistic missile defense program is transferred from the Director of the Missile Defense Agency to the Secretary of a military department, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees notice in writing of the Secretary’s intent to make that transfer. The Secretary shall include with such notice a certification that the program has met the criteria established under subsection (b) for such a transfer. The transfer may then be carried out after the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date of such notice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conforming Budget and Planning Transfers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When a ballistic missile defense program is transferred from the Missile Defense Agency to the Secretary of a military department in accordance with this section, the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that all appropriate conforming changes are made to proposed or projected funding allocations in the future-years defense program under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref> and other Department of Defense program, budget, and planning documents.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Follow-on Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, before a ballistic missile defense program is transferred from the Director of the Missile Defense Agency to the Secretary of a military department, roles and responsibilities for research, development, test, and evaluation related to system improvements for that program are clearly delineated.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2190</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5513.</num>
<heading> Unfunded priorities of the missile defense agency:<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002151">1</ref> annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 10 days after the date on which the budget of the President for a fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the Director of the Missile Defense Agency shall submit to the Secretary of Defense and the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and to the congressional defense committees, a report on the unfunded priorities of the Missile Defense Agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Elements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report under subsection (a) shall specify, for each unfunded priority covered by such report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A summary description of such priority, including the objectives to be achieved if such priority is funded (whether in whole or in part).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The additional amount of funds recommended in connection with the objectives under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Account information with respect to such priority, including the following (as applicable):</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Line Item Number (LIN) for applicable procurement accounts.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Program Element (PE) number for applicable research, development, test, and evaluation accounts.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Sub-activity group (SAG) for applicable operation and maintenance accounts.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prioritization of priorities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each report under subsection (a) shall present the unfunded priorities covered by such report in order of urgency of priority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unfunded Priority Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “unfunded priority”, in the case of a fiscal year, means a program, activity, or mission requirement of the Missile Defense Agency that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is not funded in the budget of the President for the fiscal year as submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is necessary to fulfill a requirement associated with an operational or contingency plan of a combatant command or other validated requirement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> would have been recommended for funding through the budget referred to in paragraph (1) by the Director of the Missile Defense Agency in connection with the budget if additional resources had been available for the budget to fund the program, activity, or mission requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2190</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5514.</num>
<heading> Acquisition accountability on the missile defense system</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Baselines Required</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In accordance with paragraph (2), the Director of the Missile Defense Agency shall establish and maintain an acquisition baseline for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each program element of the missile defense system, as specified in section 223 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002152">1</ref> of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> each designated major subprogram of such program elements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Director shall establish an acquisition baseline required by paragraph (1) before the date on which the program element or major subprogram enters—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> engineering and manufacturing development (or its equivalent); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> production and deployment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Except as provided by subsection (c), the Director may not adjust or revise an acquisition baseline established under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of Baselines</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each acquisition baseline required by subsection (a) for a program element or major subprogram shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A comprehensive schedule, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> research and development milestones;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> acquisition milestones, including design reviews and key decision points;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> key test events, including ground, flight, and cybersecurity tests and ballistic missile defense system tests;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> delivery and fielding schedules;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> quantities of assets planned for acquisition and delivery in total and by fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> planned contract award dates.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A detailed technical description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the capability to be developed, including hardware and software;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> system requirements, including performance requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> how the proposed capability satisfies a capability requirement or performance attribute identified through—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the missile defense warfighter involvement process, as governed by United States Strategic Command Instruction 538–03, or such successor document; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> processes and products approved by the Joint Chiefs of Staff or Joint Requirements Oversight Council;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> key knowledge points that must be achieved to permit continuation of the program and to inform production and deployment decisions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> how the Director plans to improve the capability over time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A cost estimate, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a life-cycle cost estimate that separately identifies the costs regarding research and development, procurement, military construction, operations and sustainment, and disposal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> program acquisition unit costs for the program element;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> average procurement unit costs and program acquisition costs for the program element;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an identification of when the document regarding the program joint cost analysis requirements description is scheduled to be approved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an explanation for why a program joint cost analysis requirements description has not been prepared and approved, and, if a program joint cost analysis requirements description is not applicable, the rationale for such inapplicability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A test baseline summarizing the comprehensive test program for the program element or major subprogram outlined in the integrated master test plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception to Limitation on Revision</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director may adjust or revise an acquisition baseline established under this section if the Director submits to the congressional defense committees notification of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a justification for such adjustment or revision;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the specific adjustments or revisions made to the acquisition baseline, including to the elements described in subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the effective date of the adjusted or revised acquisition baseline.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operations and Sustainment Cost Estimates</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall ensure that each life-cycle cost estimate included in an acquisition baseline pursuant to subsection (b)(3)(A) includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all of the operations and sustainment costs for which the Director is responsible;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the operations and sustainment functions and costs for which a military department is responsible;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amount of operations and sustainment costs (dollar value and base year) for which the military department or other element of the Department of Defense is responsible; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a citation to the source (such as a joint cost estimate or one or more military department estimates) that captures the operations and sustainment costs for which a military department or other element of the Department of Defense is responsible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date the source was prepared; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if and when the source was independently verified by the Office for Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2191</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5515.</num>
<heading> Missile defense and defeat programs: major force program and budget assessment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Major Force Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a unified major force program for missile defense and defeat programs pursuant to <ref>section 222(b) of this title</ref> to prioritize missile defense and defeat programs in accordance with the requirements of the Department of Defense and national security.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget Assessment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall include with the defense budget materials for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2030 a report on the budget for missile defense and defeat programs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report on the budget for missile defense and defeat programs of the Department under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> An overview of the budget, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a comparison between that budget, the previous budget, the most recent and prior future-years defense program submitted to Congress under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref> (such comparison shall exclude the responsibility for research and development of the continuing improvement of such missile defense and defeat program), and the amounts appropriated for such missile defense and defeat programs during the previous fiscal year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the specific identification, as a budgetary line item, for the funding under such programs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An assessment of the budget, including significant changes, priorities, challenges, and risks.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any additional matters the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each report under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “budget”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the budget for that fiscal year that is submitted to Congress by the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “defense budget materials”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the materials submitted to Congress by the Secretary of Defense in support of the budget for that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “missile defense and defeat programs” means active and passive ballistic missile defense programs, cruise missile defense programs for the homeland, and missile defeat programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2193</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>MISSILE DEFENSE CAPABILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5531.</num>
<heading> Technical authority for integrated air and missile defense activities and programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Missile Defense Agency is the technical authority of the Department of Defense for integrated air and missile defense activities and programs, including joint engineering and integration efforts for such activities and programs, including with respect to defining and controlling the interfaces of such activities and programs and the allocation of technical requirements for such activities and programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detailees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In carrying out the technical authority under paragraph (1),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002153">1</ref> the Director may seek to have staff detailed to the Missile Defense Agency from the Joint Functional Component Command for Integrated Missile Defense and the Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization in a number the Director determines necessary in accordance with subparagraph (B).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002154">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In detailing staff under subparagraph (A) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002155">3</ref> to carry out the technical authority under paragraph (1), <sup>1</sup> the total number of staff, including detailees, of the Missile Defense Agency who carry out such authority may not exceed the number that is twice the number of such staff carrying out such authority as of <date date="2016-01-01">January 1, 2016</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2194</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5532.</num>
<heading> Hypersonic defense capability development</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive Agent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Missile Defense Agency shall serve as the executive agent for the Department of Defense for the development of a capability by the United States to counter hypersonic boost-glide vehicle capabilities and conventional prompt strike capabilities that may be employed against the United States, the allies of the United States, and the deployed forces of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out subsection (a), the Director shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> develop architectures for a hypersonic defense capability, from detecting threats to intercepting such threats, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> involves systems of the military departments and the Defense Agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes both kinetic and nonkinetic options for such interception; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not later than <date date="2017-09-30">September 30, 2017</date>, establish a program of record to develop a hypersonic defense capability.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2194</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5533.</num>
<heading> Required testing of ground-based midcourse defense element of ballistic missile defense system</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Testing Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (c), not less frequently than once each fiscal year, the Director of the Missile Defense Agency shall administer a flight test of the ground-based midcourse defense element of the ballistic missile defense system. Beginning not later than five years after the date on which the next generation interceptor achieves initial operational capability, the Director shall ensure that such flight tests include the next generation interceptor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall ensure that each test carried out under subsection (a) provides for one or more of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The validation of technical improvements made to increase system performance and reliability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The evaluation of the operational effectiveness of the ground-based midcourse defense element of the ballistic missile defense system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The use of threat-representative targets and critical engagement conditions, including the use of threat-representative countermeasures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The evaluation of new configurations of interceptors before they are fielded.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The satisfaction of the “fly before buy” acquisition approach for new interceptor components or software.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The evaluation of the interoperability of the ground-based midcourse defense element with other elements of the ballistic missile defense systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director may forgo a test under subsection (a) in a fiscal year under one or more of the following conditions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Such a test would jeopardize national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Insufficient time considerations between post-test analysis and subsequent pre-test design.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Insufficient funding.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An interceptor is unavailable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A target is unavailable or is insufficiently representative of threats.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The test range or necessary test assets are unavailable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Inclement weather.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Any other condition the Director considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 45 days after forgoing a test for a condition or conditions under subsection (c)(8), the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall submit to the congressional defense committees a certification setting forth the condition or conditions that caused the test to be forgone under such subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 45 days after forgoing a test for any condition specified in subsection (c), the Director shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report setting forth the rationale for forgoing the test and a plan to restore an intercept flight test in the Integrated Master Test Plan of the Missile Defense Agency. In the case of a test forgone for a condition or conditions under subsection (c)(8), the report required by this subsection is in addition to the certification required by subsection (d).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2195</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5534.</num>
<heading> Integration and interoperability of air and missile defense capabilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interoperability of Missile Defense Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and the chairman of the Missile Defense Executive Board (pursuant to section 1681(c) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<ref>Public Law 115–232</ref>), acting through the Missile Defense Executive Board, shall ensure the interoperability and integration of the covered air and missile defense capabilities of the United States, including by carrying out operational testing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Demonstration</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided by paragraph (2), the Director of the Missile Defense Agency and the Secretary of the Army shall jointly ensure that not less than one intercept or flight test is carried out each year that demonstrates interoperability and integration among the covered air and missile defense capabilities of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Director and the Secretary may waive the requirement in paragraph (1) with respect to an intercept or flight test carried out during the year covered by the waiver if the chairman of the Missile Defense Executive Board—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determines that such waiver is necessary for such year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submits to the congressional defense committees notification of such waiver, including an explanation for how such waiver will not negatively affect demonstrating the interoperability and integration among the covered air and missile defense capabilities of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Covered Air and Missile Defense Capabilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “covered air and missile defense capabilities” means Patriot air and missile defense batteries and associated interceptors and systems, Aegis ships and associated ballistic missile interceptors (including Aegis Ashore capability), AN/TPY–2 radars, or terminal high altitude area defense batteries and interceptors.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2196</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5535.</num>
<heading> Development of requirements to support integrated air and missile defense capabilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Consistent with the memorandum of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff of <date date="2014-01-27">January 27, 2014</date>, regarding joint integrated air and missile defense, the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff shall oversee the development of warfighter requirements for persistent and survivable capabilities to detect, identify, determine the status, track, and support engagement of strategically important mobile or relocatable assets in all phases of conflict in order to achieve the objective of preventing the effective employment of such assets, including through offensive actions against such assets prior to their use.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose of Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirements developed pursuant to subsection (a) shall be used and updated, as appropriate, for the purpose of informing applicable acquisition programs and systems-of-systems architecture planning that are funded through the Military Intelligence Program, the National Intelligence Program, and non-intelligence programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supporting Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Vice Chairman shall also oversee the development of the enabling framework for intelligence support for integrated air and missile defense, including concepts for the integrated operation of multiple systems, and, as appropriate, the development of requirements for capabilities to be acquired to achieve such integrated operations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2196</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5536.</num>
<heading> Testing and assessment of missile defense systems prior to production and deployment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Successful Testing Required Prior to Final Production or Operational Deployment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may not make a final production decision for, or operationally deploy, a covered system unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary ensures that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sufficient and operationally realistic testing of the covered system is conducted to assess the performance of the covered system in order to inform a final production decision or an operational deployment decision; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the results of such testing have demonstrated a high probability that the covered system—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> will work in an operationally effective manner; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has the ability to accomplish the intended mission of the covered system; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Director of Operational Test and Evaluation has carried out subsection (b) with respect to such covered system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment by Director of Operational Test and Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director of Operational Test and Evaluation shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide to the Secretary the assessment of the Director, based on the available test data, of the sufficiency, adequacy, and results of the testing of each covered system, including an assessment of whether the covered system will be sufficiently effective, suitable, and survivable when needed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit to the congressional defense committees a written summary of such assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter, modify, or otherwise affect a determination of the Secretary with respect to the participation of the Missile Defense Agency in the Joint Capabilities Integration Development System or the acquisition reporting process under the Department of Defense Directive 5000 series, or to diminish the authority of the Secretary of Defense to deploy a missile defense system at the date on which the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered System</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “covered system” means a new or substantially upgraded interceptor or weapon system of the ballistic missile defense system.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2197</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5537.</num>
<heading> Limitation on Missile Defense Agency production of satellites and ground systems associated with operation of such satellites</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Production of Satellites and Ground Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Missile Defense Agency may not authorize or obligate funding for a program of record for the production of satellites or ground systems associated with the operation of such satellites.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prototype Satellites</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director, with the concurrence of the Space Acquisition Council established by <ref>section 9021 of this title</ref>, may authorize the production of one or more prototype satellites, consistent with the requirements of the Missile Defense Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Space Acquisition Council concurs with the Director with respect to authorizing the production of a prototype satellite under paragraph (1), the chair of the Council shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report explaining the reasons for such concurrence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Director may not obligate funds for the production of a prototype satellite under paragraph (1) before the date on which the Space Acquisition Council submits the report for such prototype satellite under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2197</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>MISSILE DEFENSE INFORMATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5551.</num>
<heading> Prohibitions relating to missile defense information and systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain “Hit-to-kill” Technology and Telemetry Data</inline>.—</heading>
<content>None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of Defense may be used to provide the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China with “hit-to-kill” technology and telemetry data for missile defense interceptors or target vehicles.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Sensitive Missile Defense Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of Defense may be used to provide the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information relating to velocity at burnout of missile defense interceptors or targets of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> classified or otherwise controlled missile defense information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibitions in subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to the United States providing to the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China information regarding ballistic missile early warning.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Integration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of Defense may be obligated or expended to integrate a missile defense system of the Russian Federation or a missile defense system of the People’s Republic of China into any missile defense system of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1641, 1649(a), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2182</ref>, 2198.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5552.</num>
<heading> Biannual briefing on missile defense and related activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On or about June 1 and December 1 of each year, the officials specified in subsection (b) shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing on matters relating to missile defense policies, operations, technology development, and other similar topics as requested by such committees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officials Specified</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The officials specified in this subsection are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Space Policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Director of the Missile Defense Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Director for Strategy, Plans, and Policy of the Joint Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An official specified in subsection (b) may delegate the authority to provide a briefing required by subsection (a) to a member of the Senior Executive Service who reports to the official.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirement to provide a briefing under subsection (a) shall terminate on <date date="2028-01-01">January 1, 2028</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2198</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5553.</num>
<heading> Provision of information on flight testing of ground-based midcourse national missile defense system</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information to Be Furnished to Congressional Committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Missile Defense Agency shall provide to the congressional defense committees information on the results of each flight test of the ground-based midcourse national missile defense system.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Information provided under subsection (a) on the results of a flight test shall include the following matters:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A thorough discussion of the content and objectives of the test.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For each such test objective, a statement regarding whether or not the objective was achieved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For any such test objective not achieved—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a thorough discussion describing the reasons that the objective was not achieved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a discussion of any plans for future tests to achieve that objective.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2199</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>