<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 33A—</num>
<heading>APPOINTMENT, PROMOTION, AND INVOLUNTARY SEPARATION AND RETIREMENT FOR MEMBERS ON THE WARRANT OFFICER ACTIVE-DUTY LIST</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 571.</num>
<heading> Warrant officers: grades</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The regular warrant officer grades in the armed forces corresponding to the pay grades prescribed for warrant officers by <ref>section 201(b) of title 37</ref> are as follows:<p class="indent0 firstIndent0" role="listItem">Warrant officer grade:</p>
<p class="indent0" role="listItem">Chief warrant officer, W–5.</p>
<p class="indent0">Chief warrant officer, W–4.</p>
<p class="indent0">Chief warrant officer, W–3.</p>
<p class="indent0">Chief warrant officer, W–2.</p>
<p class="indent0">Warrant officer, W–1.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Appointments in the grade of regular warrant officer, W–1, shall be made by warrant, except that with respect to an armed force under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of a military department, the Secretary concerned may provide by regulation that appointments in that grade in that armed force shall be made by commission. Appointments in regular chief warrant officer grades shall be made by commission by the President, and appointments (whether by warrant or commission) in the grade of regular warrant officer, W–1, shall be made by the President, except that appointments in that grade in the Coast Guard shall be made by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An appointment may not be made in any of the armed forces in the regular warrant officer grade of chief warrant officer, W–5, if the appointment would result in more than 5 percent of the warrant officers of that armed force on active duty being in the grade of chief warrant officer, W–5. In computing the limitation prescribed in the preceding sentence, there shall be excluded warrant officers described in <ref>section 582 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1493</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 541(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 572.</num>
<heading> Warrant officers: original appointment; service credit</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For the purposes of promotion, persons originally appointed in regular or reserve warrant officer grades shall be credited with such service as the Secretary concerned may prescribe. However, such a person may not be credited with a period of service greater than the period of active service performed in the grade, or pay grade corresponding to the grade, in which so appointed, or in any higher grade or pay grade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall credit a person who is receiving an original appointment as a warrant officer in the regular component of an armed force under the jurisdiction of such Secretary concerned, and who has advanced education or training or special experience, with constructive service for such education, training, or experience, as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For special training or experience in a particular warrant officer field designated by the Secretary concerned, if such training or experience is directly related to the operational needs of the armed force concerned, as determined by such Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For advanced education in a warrant officer field designated by the Secretary concerned, if such education is directly related to the operational needs of the armed force concerned, as determined by such Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1493</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 507(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2558</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 573.</num>
<heading> Convening of selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever the Secretary concerned determines that the needs of the service so require, he shall convene a selection board to recommend for promotion to the next higher warrant officer grade warrant officers on the warrant officer active-duty list who are in the grade of chief warrant officer, W–2, chief warrant officer, W–3, or chief warrant officer, W–4.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Warrant officers serving on the warrant officer active-duty list in the grade of warrant officer, W–1, shall be promoted to the grade of chief warrant officer, W–2, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned. Such regulations shall require that an officer have served not less than 18 months on active duty in the grade of warrant officer, W–1, before promotion to the grade of warrant officer, W–2.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A selection board shall consist of five or more officers who are on the active-duty list of the same armed force as the warrant officers under consideration by the board. At least five members of a selection board must be serving in a permanent grade above major or lieutenant commander. The Secretary concerned may appoint warrant officers, senior in grade to those under consideration, as additional members of the selection board. If warrant officers are appointed members of the selection board and if competitive categories have been established by the Secretary under <ref>section 574(b) of this title</ref>, at least one must be appointed from each warrant officer competitive category under consideration by the board, unless there is an insufficient number of warrant officers in the competitive category concerned who are senior in grade to those under consideration and qualified, as determined by the Secretary concerned, to be appointed as additional members of the board. The members of a selection board shall represent the diverse population of the armed force concerned to the extent practicable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may convene selection boards to recommend regular warrant officers for continuation on active duty under <ref>section 580 of this title</ref> and for retirement under <ref>section 581 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> When reserve warrant officers of one of the armed forces are to be considered by a selection board convened under subsection (a), the membership of the board shall, if practicable, include at least one reserve officer of that armed force, with the exact number of reserve officers to be determined by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> No officer may serve on two consecutive boards under this section, if the second board considers any warrant officer who was considered by the first board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall prescribe all other matters relating to the functions and duties of the boards, including the number of members constituting a quorum, and instructions concerning notice of convening of boards and communications with boards.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1493</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 541(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1503(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 503(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3564</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 574.</num>
<heading> Warrant officer active-duty lists; competitive categories; number to be recommended for promotion; promotion zones</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall maintain for each armed force under the jurisdiction of that Secretary a single list of all warrant officers (other than warrant officers described in <ref>section 582 of this title</ref>) who are on active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may establish competitive categories for promotion. Warrant officers in the same competitive category shall compete among themselves for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Before convening a selection board under <ref>section 573 of this title</ref>, the Secretary concerned shall determine for each grade (or grade and competitive category) to be considered by the board the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The maximum number of warrant officers to be recommended for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A promotion zone for warrant officers on the warrant officer active-duty list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The position of a warrant officer on the warrant officer active-duty list shall be determined as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Warrant officers shall be carried in the order of seniority of the grade in which they are serving on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Warrant officers serving in the same grade shall be carried in the order of their rank in that grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A warrant officer on the warrant officer active-duty list who receives a temporary appointment or a temporary assignment in a grade other than a warrant officer grade or chief warrant officer grade shall retain his position on the warrant officer active-duty list while so serving.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A chief warrant officer may not be considered for promotion to the next higher grade under this chapter until the officer has completed two years of service on active duty in the grade in which the officer is serving.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1494</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(3)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 541(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2512</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 575.</num>
<heading> Recommendations for promotion by selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A selection board convened under <ref>section 573(a) of this title</ref> shall recommend for promotion to the next higher grade those warrant officers considered by the board whom the board, giving due consideration to the needs of the armed force concerned for warrant officers with particular skills, considers best qualified for promotion within each grade (or grade and competitive category) considered by the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a selection board to consider warrant officers for selection for promotion to the grade of chief warrant officer, W–3, chief warrant officer, W–4, or chief warrant officer, W–5, the Secretary concerned shall establish the number of warrant officers that the selection board may recommend from among warrant officers being considered from below the promotion zone within each grade (or grade and competitive category). The number of warrant officers recommended for promotion from below the promotion zone does not increase the maximum number of warrant officers which the board is authorized under <ref>section 574 of this title</ref> to recommend for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The number of officers recommended for promotion from below the promotion zone may not exceed 10 percent of the total number recommended, except that the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy, may authorize such percentage to be increased to not more than 15 percent. If the number determined under this subsection with respect to a promotion zone within a grade (or grade and competitive category) is less than one, the board may recommend one such officer for promotion from below the zone within that grade (or grade and competitive category).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A selection board convened under <ref>section 573(a) of this title</ref> may not recommend a warrant officer for promotion unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the officer receives the recommendation of a majority of the members of the board; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a majority of the members of the board find that the officer is fully qualified for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Each time a selection board is convened under <ref>section 573(a) of this title</ref> to consider warrant officers in a competitive category for promotion to the next higher grade, each warrant officer in the promotion zone, and each warrant officer above the promotion zone, for the grade and competitive category under consideration (except for a warrant officer precluded from consideration under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned under <ref>section 577 of this title</ref>) shall be considered for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In selecting the warrant officers to be recommended for promotion, a selection board shall, when authorized by the Secretary concerned, recommend warrant officers of particular merit, pursuant to guidelines and procedures prescribed by the Secretary concerned, from among those warrant officers selected for promotion, to be placed higher on the promotion list contained in the report of such board under <ref>section 576(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A selection board may recommend that a warrant officer be placed higher on a promotion list under paragraph (1) only if the warrant officer receives the recommendation of at least a majority of the members of the board, unless the Secretary concerned establishes an alternative requirement. Any such alternate requirement shall be furnished to the board as part of the guidelines furnished to the board under <ref>section 576 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the warrant officers recommended to be placed higher on a promotion list under paragraph (1), the board shall recommend the order in which those warrant officers should be placed on the list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon the request of a warrant officer, the Secretary concerned may exclude the warrant officer from consideration for promotion under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned may approve a request of a warrant officer under paragraph (1) only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the basis for the request is to allow the officer to complete—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an assignment in support of career progression;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> advanced education;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an assignment such Secretary determines is of significant value to the Armed Force concerned; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a career progression requirement delayed by an assignment or education;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such Secretary determines that such exclusion from consideration is in the best interest of the Armed Force concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the officer has not previously failed of selection for promotion to the grade for which the officer requests exclusion from consideration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1495</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 501(a), 541(b)(3), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2748</ref>, 2764; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 506(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 591</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 508(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2559</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 576.</num>
<heading> Information to be furnished to selection boards; selection procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall furnish to each selection board convened under <ref>section 573 of this title</ref> the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The maximum number of warrant officers that may be recommended for promotion from those serving in any grade (or grade and competitive category) to be considered, as determined in accordance with <ref>section 574 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The names and pertinent records of all officers in each grade (or grade and competitive category) to be considered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Such information or guidelines relating to the needs of the armed force concerned for warrant officers having particular skills, including guidelines or information relating to the need for either a minimum number or a maximum number of officers with particular skills within a grade or competitive category, as the Secretary concerned determines to be relevant in relation to the requirements of that armed force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> From each promotion zone for a grade (or grade and competitive category), the selection board shall recommend for promotion to the next higher warrant officer grade those warrant officers whom it considers best qualified for promotion, but no more than the number specified by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The names of warrant officers selected for promotion under this section shall be arranged in the report of such board in the following order of priority:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Warrant officers recommended under <ref>section 575(e) of this title</ref> to be placed higher on the promotion list, in the order in which the board determines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Warrant officers otherwise recommended for promotion, in the order of seniority on the warrant officer active-duty list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary concerned may prescribe, the selection board shall report the names of those warrant officers considered by it whose records establish, in its opinion, their unfitness or unsatisfactory performance. A regular warrant officer whose name is so reported shall be considered, under regulations provided by the Secretary concerned, for retirement or separation under <ref>section 1166 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The report of the selection board shall be submitted to the Secretary concerned. The Secretary may approve or disapprove all or part of the report.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon receipt of the report of a selection board submitted to him under subsection (e), the Secretary concerned shall review the report to determine whether the board has acted contrary to law or regulation or to guidelines furnished the board under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If, on the basis of a review of the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned determines that the board acted contrary to law or regulation or to guidelines furnished the board under this section, the Secretary shall return the report, together with a written explanation of the basis for such determination, to the board for further proceedings. Upon receipt of a report returned by the Secretary concerned under this paragraph, the selection board (or a subsequent selection board convened under <ref>section 573 of this title</ref> for the same grade and competitive category) shall conduct such proceedings as may be necessary in order to revise the report to be consistent with law, regulation, and such guidelines and shall resubmit the report, as revised, to the Secretary in accordance with subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1496</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 501(b), 541(b)(4), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2748</ref>, 2764; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 508(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 577.</num>
<heading> Promotions: effect of failure of selection for</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A warrant officer who has been considered for promotion by a selection board convened under <ref>section 573 of this title</ref>, but not selected, shall be considered for promotion by each subsequent selection board that considers officers in his grade (or grade and competitive category) until he is retired or separated or he is selected for promotion. However, the Secretary concerned may, by regulation, preclude from consideration by a selection board by which he would otherwise be eligible to be considered, a warrant officer who has an established separation date that is within 90 days after the date on which the board is convened or an approved retirement date.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1497</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1868</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 578.</num>
<heading> Promotions: how made; effective date</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When the report of a selection board convened under this chapter is approved by the Secretary concerned, the Secretary shall place the names of the warrant officers approved for promotion on a single promotion list for each grade (or grade and competitive category), in the order set forth in <ref>section 576(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Promotions of warrant officers on the warrant officer promotion list shall be made when, in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary concerned, additional warrant officers in that grade (or grade and competitive category), are needed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A regular warrant officer who is promoted is appointed in the regular grade to which promoted, and a reserve warrant officer who is promoted is appointed in the reserve grade to which promoted. The date of appointment in that grade and date of rank shall be prescribed by the Secretary concerned. A warrant officer is entitled to the pay and allowances for the grade to which appointed from the date specified in the appointment order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Promotions shall be made in the order in which the names of warrant officers appear on the promotion list and after warrant officers previously selected for promotion in the applicable grade (or grade and competitive category) have been promoted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A warrant officer who is appointed to a higher grade under this section is considered to have accepted such appointment on the date on which the appointment is made unless the officer expressly declines the appointment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> A warrant officer who has served continuously as an officer since subscribing to the oath of office prescribed in <ref>section 3331 of title 5</ref> is not required to take a new oath upon appointment to a higher grade under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (d), and subject to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, in the case of a warrant officer who is selected for promotion by a selection board convened under this chapter, and prior to the placement of the warrant officer’s name on the applicable promotion list as approved for transfer to a new component within the same or a different armed force, the Secretary concerned may place the warrant officer’s name on a corresponding promotion list of the new component without regard to the warrant officer’s competitive category. A warrant officer’s promotion under this subsection shall be made pursuant to <ref>section 12242 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1497</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(4)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 501(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2748</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 508(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2560</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 240</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 579.</num>
<heading> Removal from a promotion list</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The name of a warrant officer recommended for promotion by a selection board convened under this chapter may be removed from the report of the selection board by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may remove the name of a warrant officer who is on a promotion list as a result of being recommended for promotion by a selection board convened under this chapter at any time before the promotion is effective.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An officer whose name is removed from the list of officers recommended for promotion by a selection board continues to be eligible for consideration for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If the next selection board that considers the warrant officer for promotion under this chapter selects the warrant officer for promotion and the warrant officer is promoted, the Secretary concerned may, upon his promotion, grant him the same effective date for pay and allowances and the same date of rank, and the same position on the warrant officer active-duty list as the warrant officer would have had if his name had not been so removed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If the next selection board does not select the warrant officer for promotion, or if his name is again removed under subsection (a) from the list of officers recommended for promotion by the selection board or under subsection (b) from the warrant officer promotion list, he shall be treated for all purposes as if he has twice failed of selection for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 580.</num>
<heading> Regular warrant officers twice failing of selection for promotion: involuntary retirement or separation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Unless retired or separated sooner under some other provision of law, a regular chief warrant officer who has twice failed of selection for promotion to the next higher regular warrant officer grade shall be retired under paragraph (2) or (3) or separated from active duty under paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a warrant officer described in paragraph (1) has more than 20 years of creditable active service on (A) the date on which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board under <ref>section 576(e) of this title</ref>, or (B) the date on which his name was removed from the recommended list under <ref>section 579 of this title</ref>, whichever applies, the warrant officer shall be retired. The date of such retirement shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the applicable date under the preceding sentence, except as provided by <ref>section 8301 of title 5</ref>. A warrant officer retired under this paragraph shall receive retired pay computed under <ref>section 1401 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If a warrant officer described in paragraph (1) has at least 18 but not more than 20 years of creditable active service on (A) the date on which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board under <ref>section 576(e) of this title</ref>, or (B) the date on which his name was removed from the recommended list under <ref>section 579 of this title</ref>, whichever applies, the warrant officer shall be retired not later than the date determined under the next sentence unless he is selected for promotion to the next higher regular warrant officer grade before that date. The date of the retirement of a warrant officer under the preceding sentence shall be on a date specified by the Secretary concerned, but not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the date upon which he completes 20 years of active service, except as provided by <ref>section 8301 of title 5</ref>. A warrant officer retired under this paragraph shall receive retired pay computed under <ref>section 1401 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If a warrant officer described in paragraph (1) has less than 18 years of creditable active service on (i) the date on which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board under <ref>section 576(e) of this title</ref>, or (ii) the date on which his name was removed from the recommended list under <ref>section 579 of this title</ref>, whichever applies, the warrant officer shall be separated (except as provided in subparagraph (C)). The date of such separation shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the applicable date under the preceding sentence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A warrant officer separated under this paragraph shall receive separation pay computed under <ref>section 1174 of this title</ref>, or severance pay computed under section 286a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002038">1</ref> of title 14, as appropriate, except in a case in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> upon his request and in the discretion of the Secretary concerned, he is enlisted in the grade prescribed by the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> he is serving on active duty in a grade above chief warrant officer, W–5, and he elects, with the consent of the Secretary concerned, to remain on active duty in that status.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> If on the date on which a warrant officer is to be separated under subparagraph (A) the warrant officer has at least 18 years of creditable active service, the warrant officer shall be retained on active duty until retired under paragraph (3) in the same manner as if the warrant officer had had at least 18 years of service on the applicable date under subparagraph (A) or (B) of that paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A warrant officer who is subject to retirement or discharge under this subsection is not eligible for further consideration for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “creditable active service” means active service that could be credited to a warrant officer under section 511 of the Career Compensation Act of 1949, as amended (<ref>70 Stat. 114</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may defer, for not more than four months, the retirement or separation under this section of a warrant officer if, because of unavoidable circumstances, evaluation of his physical condition and determination of his entitlement to retirement or separation for physical disability require hospitalization or medical observation that cannot be completed before the date on which he would otherwise be required to retire or be separated under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may defer, until such date as he prescribes, the retirement under subsection (a) of a warrant officer who is serving on active duty in a grade above chief warrant officer, W–5, and who elects to continue to so serve.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If a warrant officer who also holds a grade above chief warrant officer, W–5, is retired or separated under subsection (a), his commission in the higher grade shall be terminated on the date on which he is so retired or separated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A regular warrant officer subject to discharge or retirement under this section may, subject to the needs of the service, be continued on active duty if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a warrant officer in the grade of chief warrant officer, W–2, or chief warrant officer, W–3, the warrant officer is selected for continuation on active duty by a selection board convened under <ref>section 573(c) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a warrant officer in the grade of chief warrant officer, W–4, the warrant officer is selected for continuation on active duty by the Secretary concerned under such procedures as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A warrant officer who is selected for continuation on active duty under this subsection but declines to continue on active duty shall be discharged, retired, or retained on active duty, as appropriate, in accordance with this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A warrant officer in the grade of chief warrant officer, W–4, who is retained on active duty pursuant to procedures prescribed under paragraph (1)(B) is eligible for further consideration for promotion while remaining on active duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Each warrant officer who is continued on active duty under this subsection, not subsequently promoted or continued on active duty, and not on a list of warrant officers recommended for continuation or for promotion to the next higher regular grade shall, unless sooner retired or discharged under another provision of law—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be discharged upon the expiration of his period of continued service; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if he is eligible for retirement under any provision of law, be retired under that law on the first day of the first month following the month in which he completes his period of continued service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), a warrant officer who would otherwise be discharged under such subparagraph and who is within two years of qualifying for retirement under <ref>section 1293 of this title</ref> shall, unless he is sooner retired or discharged under some other provision of law, be retained on active duty until he is qualified for retirement under that section and then be retired.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The retirement or discharge of a warrant officer pursuant to this subsection shall be considered to be an involuntary retirement or discharge for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Continuation of a warrant officer on active duty under this subsection pursuant to the action of a selection board convened under <ref>section 573(c) of this title</ref> is subject to the approval of the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy, shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> A warrant officer subject to discharge or retirement under this section, but against whom any action has been commenced with a view to trying the officer by court-martial, may be continued on active duty, without prejudice to such action, until the completion of such action.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1498</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1645</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 541(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2179</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 541</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4218</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 580a.</num>
<heading> Enhanced authority for selective early discharges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary of a military department, during the period beginning on <date date="2015-10-01">October 1, 2015</date>, and ending on <date date="2019-10-01">October 1, 2019</date>, to take the action set forth in subsection (b) with respect to regular warrant officers of an armed force under the jurisdiction of that Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of a military department may, with respect to regular warrant officers of an armed force, when authorized to do so under subsection (a), convene selection boards under <ref>section 573(c) of this title</ref> to consider for discharge regular warrant officers on the warrant officer active-duty list—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who have served at least one year of active duty in the grade currently held;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whose names are not on a list of warrant officers recommended for promotion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> who are not eligible to be retired under any provision of law and are not within two years of becoming so eligible.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of an action under subsection (b), the Secretary of the military department concerned may submit to a selection board convened pursuant to that subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the names of all regular warrant officers described in that subsection in a particular grade and competitive category; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the names of all regular warrant officers described in that subsection in a particular grade and competitive category who also are in particular year groups or specialties, or both, within that competitive category.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall specify the total number of warrant officers to be recommended for discharge by a selection board convened pursuant to subsection (b). That number may not be more than 30 percent of the number of officers considered—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in each grade in each competitive category; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in each grade, year group, or specialty (or combination thereof) in each competitive category.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A warrant officer who is recommended for discharge by a selection board convened pursuant to subsection (b) and whose discharge is approved by the Secretary concerned shall be discharged on a date specified by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Selection of warrant officers for discharge under this subsection shall be based on the needs of the service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The discharge of any warrant officer pursuant to this section shall be considered involuntary for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> This section applies to the Secretary of Homeland Security in the same manner and to the same extent as it applies to the Secretary of Defense. The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall take the action set forth in subsection (b) with respect to regular warrant officers of the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1644</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 541(g)</ref>, title X, § 1070(a)(3), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2767</ref>, 2855; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 806</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 581.</num>
<heading> Selective retirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A regular warrant officer who holds a warrant officer grade above warrant officer, W–1, and whose name is not on a list of warrant officers recommended for promotion and who is eligible to retire under any provision of law may be considered for retirement by a selection board convened under <ref>section 573(c) of this title</ref>. The Secretary concerned shall specify the maximum number of warrant officers that such a board may recommend for retirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A warrant officer who is recommended for retirement under this section and whose retirement is approved by the Secretary concerned shall be retired, under any provision of law under which he is eligible to retire, on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for retirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The retirement of a warrant officer pursuant to this section shall be considered to be an involuntary retirement for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such regulations shall require that when the Secretary concerned submits a list of regular warrant officers to a selection board convened under <ref>section 573(c) of this title</ref> to consider regular warrant officers for selection for retirement under this section, the list shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of each warrant officer on the active-duty list in the same grade or same grade and competitive category whose position on the active-duty list is between that of the most junior regular warrant officer in that grade whose name is submitted to the board and that of the most senior regular warrant officer in that grade whose name is submitted to the board; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to a group of warrant officers designated under subparagraph (A) who are in a particular grade and competitive category, only those warrant officers in that grade and competitive category who are also in a particular year group or specialty, or any combination thereof determined by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Such regulations shall establish procedures to exclude from consideration by the board any warrant officer who has been approved for voluntary retirement, or who is to be mandatorily retired under any other provision of law, during the fiscal year in which the board is convened or during the following fiscal year. An officer not considered by a selection board convened under <ref>section 573(c) of this title</ref> under such regulations because the officer has been approved for voluntary retirement shall be retired on the date approved for the retirement of such officer as of the convening date of such selection board unless the Secretary concerned approves a modification of such date in order to prevent a personal hardship for the officer or for other humanitarian reasons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may defer for not more than three months the retirement of an officer otherwise approved for early retirement under this section in order to prevent a personal hardship to the officer or for other humanitarian reasons. Any such deferral shall be made on a case-by-case basis considering the circumstances of the case of the particular officer concerned. The authority of the Secretary to grant such a deferral may not be delegated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An officer recommended for early retirement under this section, if approved for deferral under paragraph (1), shall be retired on the date requested by the officer, and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the tenth calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1500</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(5)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 541(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 295</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 501, 502(a), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 582.</num>
<heading> Warrant officer active-duty list: exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Warrant officers in the following categories are not subject to this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Reserve warrant officers—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on active duty as authorized under section 115(a)(1)(B) or 115(b)(1) of this title, or excluded from counting for active duty end strengths under <ref>section 115(i) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on full-time National Guard duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Retired warrant officers on active duty (other than retired warrant officers who were recalled to active duty before <date date="1992-02-01">February 1, 1992</date>, and have served continuously on active duty since that date).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Students enrolled in the Army Physician’s Assistant Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1500</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 501(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2748</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(c)(5)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IV, § 416(i)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 583.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “promotion zone” means a promotion eligibility category consisting of officers on a warrant officer active-duty list in the same grade (or the same grade and competitive category) who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of grades below chief warrant officer, W–5, have neither (i) failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade, nor (ii) been removed from a list of warrant officers recommended for promotion to that grade (other than after having been placed on that list after a selection from below the promotion zone); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are senior to the warrant officer designated by the Secretary concerned to be the junior warrant officer in the promotion zone eligible for promotion to the next higher grade.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “warrant officers above the promotion zone” means a group of officers on a warrant officer active-duty list in the same grade (or the same grade and competitive category) who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are in the same grade as warrant officers in the promotion zone; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> are senior to the senior warrant officer in the promotion zone.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “warrant officers below the promotion zone” means a group of officers on a warrant officer active-duty list in the same grade (or the same grade and competitive category) who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are in the same grade as warrant officers in the promotion zone; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> are junior to the junior warrant officer in the promotion zone.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The active-duty list referred to in <ref>section 573(b) of this title</ref> includes the active-duty promotion list established by section 41a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002039">1</ref> of title 14.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1501</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 541(f)(7)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2767</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>