<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1207—</num>
<heading>WARRANT OFFICERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12241.</num>
<heading> Warrant officers: grades; appointment, how made; term</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The permanent reserve warrant officer grades in each armed force are those prescribed for regular warrant officers by <ref>section 571(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Appointments in permanent reserve warrant officer grades shall be made in the same manner as is prescribed for regular warrant officer grades by <ref>section 571(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Appointments as Reserves in permanent warrant officer grades are for an indefinite term and are held during the pleasure of the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 26</ref>, § 597; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 531(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 633</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1131(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1505</ref>; renumbered § 12241, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2991</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12242.</num>
<heading> Warrant officers: promotion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The promotion of permanent reserve warrant officers not on the warrant officer active-duty list to permanent reserve warrant officer grades shall be governed by such regulations as the Secretary concerned may prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 26</ref>, § 598; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1131(3)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1505</ref>; renumbered § 12242, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12243.</num>
<heading> Warrant officers: suspension of laws for promotion or mandatory retirement or separation during war or emergency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In time of war, or of emergency declared after <date date="1954-05-29">May 29, 1954</date>, by Congress or the President, the President may suspend the operation of any provision of law relating to promotion, or mandatory retirement or separation, of permanent reserve warrant officers of any armed force.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 26</ref>, § 599; renumbered § 12243, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12244.</num>
<heading> Warrant officers: discharge or retirement for years of service or for age</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each reserve warrant officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps who is in an active status and has reached the maximum years of service or age prescribed by the Secretary concerned shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be transferred to the Retired Reserve if the warrant officer is qualified for such transfer and does not request (in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned) not to be transferred to the Retired Reserve; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be discharged if the warrant officer is not qualified for transfer to the Retired Reserve or has requested (in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned) not to be so transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 517(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>