<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 809—</num>
<heading>BUREAUS; OFFICE OF THE JUDGE ADVOCATE GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8071.</num>
<heading> Bureaus: names; location</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are in the executive part of the Department of the Navy the following bureaus:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Bureau of Medicine and Surgery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Bureau of Naval Personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 285</ref>, § 5131; <ref>Pub. L. 86–174</ref>, §§ 1(1), 2(1), <date date="1959-08-18">Aug. 18, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 395</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 35(1)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1120</ref>; renumbered § 8071, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8072.</num>
<heading> Bureaus: distribution of business; orders; records; expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided by law, the business of the executive part of the Department of the Navy shall be distributed among the bureaus as the Secretary of the Navy considers expedient and proper.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each bureau shall perform its duties under the authority of the Secretary, and its orders are considered as coming from the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Under the Secretary, each bureau has custody and charge of its records and accounts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Each bureau shall furnish to the Secretary estimates for its specific, general, and contingent expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 285</ref>, § 5132; renumbered § 8072, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8075.</num>
<heading> Bureau Chiefs: succession to duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When there is a vacancy in the office of chief of a bureau, or during the absence or disability of the chief of a bureau, the deputy chief of that bureau, unless otherwise directed by the President, shall perform the duties of the chief until a successor is appointed or the absence or disability ceases.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When subsection (a) cannot be complied with because of the absence or disability of the deputy chief of the bureau, the heads of the major divisions of the bureau, in the order directed by the Secretary of the Navy, shall perform the duties of the chief, unless otherwise directed by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 286</ref>, § 5135; renumbered § 8075, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8077.</num>
<heading> Surgeon General: appointment; duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Surgeon General of the Navy shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, for a term of four years, from officers on the active-duty list of the Navy in any corps of the Navy Medical Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Surgeon General serves as the Chief of the Bureau of Medicine and Surgery and serves as the principal advisor to the Secretary of the Navy and the Chief of Naval Operations on all health and medical matters of the Navy and the Marine Corps, including strategic planning and policy development relating to such matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Surgeon General serves as the chief medical advisor of the Navy and the Marine Corps to the Director of the Defense Health Agency on matters pertaining to military health readiness requirements and safety of members of the Navy and the Marine Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Surgeon General, acting under the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of the Navy, shall recruit, organize, train, and equip, medical personnel of the Navy and the Marine Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 286</ref>, § 5137; <ref>Pub. L. 89–288, § 4</ref>, <date date="1965-10-22">Oct. 22, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1050</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 503(10)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2912</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 506(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VII, § 702(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2195</ref>; renumbered § 8077, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8078.</num>
<heading> Bureau of Medicine and Surgery: Dental Corps; Chief; functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An officer of the Dental Corps shall be detailed as Chief of the Dental Corps.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Chief of the Dental Corps is entitled to the same privileges of retirement as provided for chiefs of bureaus in section 5133 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002168">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> All matters relating to dentistry shall be referred to the Chief of the Dental Corps.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The Chief of the Dental Corps shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish professional standards and policies for dental practice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> initiate and recommend action pertaining to complements, strength, appointments, advancement, training assignment, and transfer of dental personnel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> serve as the advisor for the Bureau on all matters relating directly to dentistry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 286</ref>, § 5138; <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 14c(17)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title III, § 342</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 593(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(aa)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2105</ref>; renumbered § 8078, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8079.</num>
<heading> Appointment of chiropractors in the Medical Service Corps</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Chiropractors who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy may be appointed as commissioned officers in the Medical Service Corps of the Navy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title V, § 505(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2404</ref>, § 5139; renumbered § 8079, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8081.</num>
<heading> Chief of Naval Personnel; Deputy Chief of Naval Personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Chief of Naval Personnel shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, for a term of four years, from officers on the active-duty list in the line of the Navy not below the grade of commander.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An officer on the active-duty list in the line of the Navy not below the grade of commander may be detailed as Deputy Chief of Naval Personnel.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 287</ref>, § 5141; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 503(11)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2912</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(bb)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2105</ref>; renumbered § 8081, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8082.</num>
<heading> Chaplain Corps and Chief of Chaplains</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Chaplain Corps is a staff corps of the Navy and shall be organized in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There is in the executive part of the Department of the Navy the office of the Chief of Chaplains of the Navy. The Chief of Chaplains shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from officers of the Chaplain Corps in the grade of commander or above who are serving on active duty and who have served on active duty in the Chaplain Corps for at least eight years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An officer appointed as the Chief of Chaplains shall be appointed for a term of four years. However, the President may terminate or extend the appointment at any time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chief of Chaplains shall perform such duties as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy and by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chief of Chaplains shall, with respect to all duties pertaining to the procurement, distribution, and support of personnel of the Chaplain Corps, report to and be supported by the Chief of Naval Personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Chief of Chaplains, while so serving, holds the grade of rear admiral (upper half).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–343, § 11(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-08">Sept. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1130</ref>, § 5142; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 504(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(cc)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2105</ref>; renumbered § 8082 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 510(b)</ref>, title VIII, § 807(a)(2), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1751</ref>, 1834.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8082a.</num>
<heading> Deputy Chief of Chaplains</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy may detail as the Deputy Chief of Chaplains an officer of the Chaplain Corps in the grade of commander or above who is on active duty and who has served on active duty in the Chaplain Corps for at least eight years.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–343, § 11(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-08">Sept. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1130</ref>, § 5142a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 504(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1725</ref>; renumbered § 8082a, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8083.</num>
<heading> Office of Navy Reserve: appointment of Chief</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Office: Chief of Navy Reserve</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is in the executive part of the Department of the Navy, on the staff of the Chief of Naval Operations, an Office of the Navy Reserve, which is headed by a Chief of Navy Reserve. The Chief of Navy Reserve—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is the principal adviser on Navy Reserve matters to the Chief of Naval Operations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is the commander of the Navy Reserve Force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint the Chief of Navy Reserve from flag officers of the Navy (as defined in section 8001(1)) who have had at least 10 years of commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may not recommend an officer to the President for appointment as Chief of Navy Reserve unless the officer—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is recommended by the Secretary of the Navy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is determined by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, in accordance with criteria and as a result of a process established by the Chairman, to have significant joint duty experience.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An officer on active duty for service as the Chief of Navy Reserve shall be counted for purposes of the grade limitations under sections 525 and 526 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Until <date date="2006-12-31">December 31, 2006</date>, the Secretary of Defense may waive subparagraph (B) of paragraph (2) with respect to the appointment of an officer as Chief of Navy Reserve if the Secretary of the Navy requests the waiver and, in the judgment of the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the officer is qualified for service in the position; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the waiver is necessary for the good of the service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any such waiver shall be made on a case-by-case basis.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term; Reappointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of Navy Reserve is appointed for a term determined by the Chief of Naval Operations, normally four years, but may be removed for cause at any time. An officer serving as Chief of Navy Reserve may be reappointed for one additional term of up to four years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of Navy Reserve is the official within the executive part of the Department of the Navy who, subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of the Navy and the Chief of Naval Operations, is responsible for preparation, justification, and execution of the personnel, operation and maintenance, and construction budgets for the Navy Reserve. As such, the Chief of Navy Reserve is the director and functional manager of appropriations made for the Navy Reserve in those areas.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of Navy Reserve shall submit to the Secretary of Defense, through the Secretary of the Navy, an annual report on the state of the Navy Reserve and the ability of the Navy Reserve to meet its missions. The report shall be prepared in conjunction with the Chief of Naval Operations and may be submitted in classified and unclassified versions.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XII, § 1212(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2691</ref>, § 5143; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 554(c)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 507(b), title X, § 1087(a)(18)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–103, 1654A–291; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 536(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(F)</ref>, (2), (3)(A), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>, 3234; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1061(26)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1584</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(dd)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2105</ref>; renumbered § 8083 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(a)(2), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>, 1840; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title X, § 1061</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2064</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8084.</num>
<heading> Office of Marine Forces Reserve: appointment of Commander</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Office; Commander, Marine Forces Reserve</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is in the executive part of the Department of the Navy an Office of the Marine Forces Reserve, which is headed by the Commander, Marine Forces Reserve. The Commander, Marine Forces Reserve, is the principal adviser to the Commandant on Marine Forces Reserve matters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint the Commander, Marine Forces Reserve, from general officers of the Marine Corps Reserve who have had at least 10 years of commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may not recommend an officer to the President for appointment as Commander, Marine Forces Reserve, unless the officer—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is recommended by the Secretary of the Navy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is determined by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, in accordance with criteria and as a result of a process established by the Chairman, to have significant joint duty experience.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An officer on active duty for service as the Commander, Marine Forces Reserve, shall be counted for purposes of the grade limitations under sections 525 and 526 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Until <date date="2006-12-31">December 31, 2006</date>, the Secretary of Defense may waive subparagraph (B) of paragraph (2) with respect to the appointment of an officer as Commander, Marine Forces Reserve, if the Secretary of the Navy requests the waiver and, in the judgment of the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the officer is qualified for service in the position; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the waiver is necessary for the good of the service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any such waiver shall be made on a case-by-case basis.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term; Reappointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commander, Marine Forces Reserve, is appointed for a term determined by the Commandant of the Marine Corps, normally four years, but may be removed for cause at any time. An officer serving as Commander, Marine Forces Reserve, may be reappointed for one additional term of up to four years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commander, Marine Forces Reserve, shall submit to the Secretary of Defense, through the Secretary of the Navy, an annual report on the state of the Marine Corps Reserve and the ability of the Marine Corps Reserve to meet its missions. The report shall be prepared in conjunction with the Commandant of the Marine Corps and may be submitted in classified and unclassified versions.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XII, § 1212(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2692</ref>, § 5144; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 554(d)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 507(c), title X, § 1087(a)(19)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–103, 1654A–291; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 536(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(ee)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(29)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1562</ref>; renumbered § 8084 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(a)(2), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>, 1840; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 514(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1349</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8088.</num>
<heading> Judge Advocate General’s Corps: Office of the Judge Advocate General; Judge Advocate General; appointment, term, emoluments, duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Judge Advocate General’s Corps is a Staff Corps of the Navy, and shall be organized in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There is in the executive part of the Department of the Navy the Office of the Judge Advocate General of the Navy. The Judge Advocate General shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, for a term of four years. He shall be appointed from judge advocates of the Navy or the Marine Corps who are members of the bar of a Federal court or the highest court of a State and who have had at least eight years of experience in legal duties as commissioned officers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Navy, in selecting an officer for recommendation to the President for appointment as the Judge Advocate General, shall ensure that the officer selected is recommended by a board of officers that, insofar as practicable, is subject to the procedures applicable to selection boards convened under chapter 36 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The Judge Advocate General of the Navy, under the direction of the Secretary of the Navy, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> perform duties relating to legal matters arising in the Department of the Navy as may be assigned to him;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> perform the functions and duties and exercise the powers prescribed for the Judge Advocate General in chapter 47 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> receive, revise, and have recorded the proceedings of boards for the examination of officers of the naval service for promotion and retirement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> perform such other duties as may be assigned to him.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> No officer or employee of the Department of Defense may interfere with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the ability of the Judge Advocate General to give independent legal advice to the Secretary of the Navy or the Chief of Naval Operations; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the ability of judge advocates of the Navy assigned or attached to, or performing duty with, military units to give independent legal advice to commanders.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 289</ref>, § 5148; <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 14c(20)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–179, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="1967-12-08">Dec. 8, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 546</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title III, § 343</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 504(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2750</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 574(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1922</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 508(b)</ref>, title X, § 1057(a)(2), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3229</ref>, 3440; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 543(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(ff)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2105</ref>; renumbered § 8088, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8089.</num>
<heading> Office of the Judge Advocate General: Deputy Judge Advocate General; Assistant Judge Advocates General</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is a Deputy Judge Advocate General of the Navy who is appointed by the President from among judge advocates of the Navy and Marine Corps who have the qualifications prescribed for the Judge Advocate General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Navy, in selecting an officer for recommendation to the President for appointment as the Deputy Judge Advocate General, shall ensure that the officer selected is recommended by a board of officers that, insofar as practicable, is subject to the procedures applicable to selection boards convened under chapter 36 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary of the Navy elects to convene a selection board under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> to consider eligible officers for selection to appointment as Deputy Judge Advocate General, the Secretary may, in connection with such consideration for selection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> treat any section in chapter 36 of this title referring to promotion to the next higher grade as if such section referred to promotion to a higher grade; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> waive <ref>section 619(a)(2) of this title</ref> if the Secretary determines that the needs of the Navy require the waiver.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An officer of the Judge Advocate General’s Corps who has the qualifications prescribed for the Judge Advocate General in <ref>section 8088(b) of this title</ref> may be detailed as Assistant Judge Advocate General of the Navy. An officer who is retired while serving as Assistant Judge Advocate General of the Navy under this subsection or who, after serving at least twelve months as Assistant Judge Advocate General of the Navy, is retired after completion of that service while serving in a lower rank or grade, may, in the discretion of the President, be retired with the rank and grade of rear admiral (lower half).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A judge advocate of the Marine Corps who has the qualifications prescribed for the Judge Advocate General in <ref>section 8088(b) of this title</ref> may be detailed as Assistant Judge Advocate General of the Navy. An officer who is retired while serving as Assistant Judge Advocate General of the Navy under this subsection or who, after serving at least twelve months as Assistant Judge Advocate General of the Navy, is retired after completion of that service while serving in a lower rank or grade, may, in the discretion of the President, be retired with the rank and grade of brigadier general.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> When there is a vacancy in the Office of the Judge Advocate General, or during the absence or disability of the Judge Advocate General, the Deputy Judge Advocate General shall perform the duties of the Judge Advocate General until a successor is appointed or the absence or disability ceases.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> When subsection (d) cannot be complied with because of the absence or disability of the Deputy Judge Advocate General, the Assistant Judge Advocates General, in the order directed by the Secretary of the Navy, shall perform the duties of the Judge Advocate General.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 290</ref>, § 5149; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 33(a)(28)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 14c(21)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 36</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–179, § 2(2)</ref>, <date date="1967-12-08">Dec. 8, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 546</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–623, § 2(9)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 503(13)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2912</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V, § 508(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3867</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 504(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2751</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(gg)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 508(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1375</ref>; renumbered § 8089 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(a)(2), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8090.</num>
<heading> Staff corps of the Navy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The staff corps of the Navy are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Medical Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Dental Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Judge Advocate General’s Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Chaplain Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Supply Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Civil Engineer Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the Nurse Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the Medical Service Corps; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> such other staff corps as may be established by the Secretary of the Navy under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy may establish staff corps of the Navy in addition to the staff corps specified in subsection (a). The Secretary may designate commissioned officers in, and may assign members to, any such staff corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy may provide for the appointment of the chief of any staff corps established under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title III, § 351</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2902</ref>, § 5155; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 129</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; renumbered § 5150, <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 514(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1054</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIII, § 1343(a)(23)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3994</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(7)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 274</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(22)(A)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1473</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 504(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2531</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1714</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(hh)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2105</ref>; renumbered § 8090, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title IX, § 923</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2039</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>