<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 102—</num>
<heading>JUNIOR RESERVE OFFICERS’ TRAINING CORPS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2031.</num>
<heading> Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of each military department shall establish and maintain a Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps, organized into units, at public and private secondary educational institutions, including Job Corps centers as defined in section 147 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 3197</ref>), which apply for a unit and meet the standards and criteria prescribed pursuant to this section. The Secretary of Defense shall promulgate regulations prescribing the standards and criteria to be followed by the military departments in selecting the institutions at which units are to be established and maintained.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> It is a purpose of the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps to instill in students in United States secondary educational institutions the values of citizenship, service to the United States (including an introduction to service opportunities in military, national, and public service), and personal responsibility and a sense of accomplishment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> No unit may be established or maintained at an institution unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the number of physically fit students in such unit who are in a grade above the 7th grade and physically co-located with the 9th grade participating unit and are citizens or nationals of the United States, or aliens lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence, is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an educational institution with fewer than 1,000 enrolled students, the lesser of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 10 percent of the number of such students who are in a grade above the 7th grade and physically co-located with the 9th grade participating unit; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 50; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an educational institution with 1,000 or more enrolled students—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 50; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a number, determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned, that is higher than 50 and not more than 100;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the institution has adequate facilities for classroom instruction, storage of arms and other equipment which may be furnished in support of the unit, and adequate drill areas at or in the immediate vicinity of the institution, as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the institution provides a course of military instruction of not less than three academic years’ duration and which may include instruction or activities in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, as prescribed by the Secretary of the military department concerned, or is a Job Corps center as defined in section 147 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 3197</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the institution agrees to limit membership in the unit to students who maintain acceptable standards of academic achievement and conduct, as prescribed by the Secretary of the military department concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the unit meets such other requirements as the Secretary of the military department concerned prescribes in the memorandum of understanding required under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe in regulations a memorandum of understanding to be signed by the Secretary of the military department concerned and each institution operating a unit under this section. The memorandum shall be standardized to the extent practicable and include the following elements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A requirement that an institution notify the Secretary of the military department concerned of allegations of misconduct (including sexual misconduct and harassment) against an instructor who is receiving retired or other pay, not later than 48 hours after such institution learns of such allegations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A process by which the Secretary of the military department concerned certifies an instructor, including the conduct of appropriate background checks by such Secretary and the institution concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A process by which the Secretary of the military department concerned shall conduct oversight of instructors certified by such Secretary, including a requirement that such certification shall expire after not more than five years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Processes by which such institution’s program will be inspected by the military department concerned prior to establishment of a new unit, or not less often than once every four years in the case of units existing as of <date date="2024-01-01">January 1, 2024</date>, staggered as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> A requirement that each institution certifies it—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has created a process for students to report violations of their rights under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1681</ref> et seq.), as applicable, and title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000d</ref> et seq.), including the rights of students to not be subject to discrimination or subject to retaliation for reporting a violation of those laws, if such laws apply to the public or private institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has implemented policies ensuring students and instructors are notified of those rights, as well as the process for reporting violations of those rights, including information on available mandatory reporters, if such laws apply to the institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> has implemented annual training to inform students of methods to prevent, respond to, and report sexual assault and harassment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> agrees to report all allegations of violations described in this subparagraph to the military department concerned and, if subject to the jurisdiction of the Department of Education, the Office of Civil Rights of the Department of Education not less often than annually;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> has developed processes to ensure that each student enrolled in a unit under this section has done so voluntarily; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> agrees to provide the data necessary to compile the report under subsection (j).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the military department concerned shall, to support the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> detail officers and noncommissioned officers of an armed force under his jurisdiction to institutions having units of the Corps as administrators and instructors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide necessary text materials, equipment, and uniforms and, to the extent considered appropriate by the Secretary concerned, such additional resources (including transportation and billeting) as may be available to support activities of the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establish minimum acceptable standards for performance and achievement for qualified units; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> maintain a prioritized waiting list that includes all secondary educational institutions that have made a request for a unit under this section and have not yet been approved by the Secretary concerned, and prescribe regulations describing the factors to be considered in assigning priority, including the length of time an institution has been waiting for a unit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Instead of, or in addition to, detailing officers and noncommissioned officers on active duty under subsection (c)(1), the Secretary of the military department concerned may authorize qualified institutions to employ, as administrators and instructors in the program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> retired officers and noncommissioned officers whose qualifications are approved by the Secretary and the institution concerned and who request such employment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> officers and noncommissioned officers who are separated with an honorable discharge within the past 5 years with at least 8 years of service and are approved by the Secretary and the institution concerned and who request such employment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> officers and noncommissioned officers who are active participating members of the selected reserve at the time of application, for purposes of <ref>section 101(d) of this title</ref>, and have not yet reached retirement eligibility and are approved by the Secretary and the institution concerned and who request such employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Employment under this subsection shall be subject to the following conditions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall pay to the institution an amount equal to one-half of the Department’s prescribed JROTC Standardized Instructor Pay Scale amount paid to the member by the institution for any period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned may pay to the institution more than one-half of the amount paid to the member by the institution if (as determined by the Secretary)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the institution is in an educationally and economically deprived area; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that such action is in the national interest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Payments by the Secretary concerned under this subsection shall be made from funds appropriated for that purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may require successful applicants to transfer to the Individual Ready Reserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned to be in the national interest and agreed upon by the institution concerned, the institution may reimburse a Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps instructor for moving expenses incurred by the instructor to accept employment at the institution in a position that the Secretary concerned determines is hard-to-fill for geographic or economic reasons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> As a condition on providing reimbursement under paragraph (1), the institution shall require the instructor to execute a written agreement to serve a minimum of two years of employment at the institution in the hard-to-fill position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any reimbursement provided to an instructor under paragraph (1) is in addition to the minimum instructor pay otherwise payable to the instructor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall reimburse an institution providing reimbursement to an instructor under paragraph (1) in an amount equal to the amount of the reimbursement paid by the institution under that paragraph. Any reimbursement provided by the Secretary concerned shall be provided from funds appropriated for that purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The provision of reimbursement under paragraph (1) or (4) shall be subject to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for purposes of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each public secondary educational institution that maintains a unit under this section shall permit membership in the unit to homeschooled students residing in the area served by the institution who are qualified for membership in the unit (but for lack of enrollment in the institution).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A student who is a member of a unit pursuant to this subsection shall count toward the satisfaction by the institution concerned of the requirement in subsection (b)(1) relating to the minimum number of student members in the unit necessary for the continuing maintenance of the unit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> No unit may be established or maintained at an educational institution that is owned, operated, or controlled by a person that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is the People’s Republic of China;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is a member of the Chinese Communist Party;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is a member of the People’s Liberation Army;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is identified by the Secretary of Defense under section 1260H(a) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<ref>10 U.S.C. 113</ref> note) as a Chinese military company;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> is included in the Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List published by the Department of the Treasury; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> is owned by or controlled by or is an agency or instrumentality of any person described in paragraphs (1) through (5).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may suspend or place on probation a unit of the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps that fails to comply with the provisions of the memorandum of understanding required pursuant to subsection (b) or any other requirement of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A unit may be placed on probation under paragraph (1) for a period of up to three years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A unit may be suspended under paragraph (1) if, after the three-year probationary period, such unit remains out of compliance with the requirements of this section and the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that such suspension is necessary to mitigate program deficiencies or to protect the safety of program participants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish and support not fewer than 3,400, and not more than 4,000, units of the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The requirement under paragraph (1) shall not apply—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the Secretary fails to receive an adequate number of requests for Junior Reserve Officer’s Training Corps units by public and private secondary educational institutions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> during a time of national emergency when the Secretaries of the military departments determine that funding must be allocated elsewhere.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than <date date="2024-03-31">March 31, 2024</date>, and annually thereafter through <date date="2029-03-31">March 31, 2029</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on allegations of sexual misconduct, sexual harassment, and sex discrimination in Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps programs during the preceding year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report required under paragraph (1) shall set forth the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The number of reported allegations of violations under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1681</ref> et seq.) in school-affiliated Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps programs, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of such reported allegations that were investigated;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the outcome of those investigations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the number of such reported allegations by State, the District of Columbia, or overseas location where these reports occurred.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The number of reports that the Department of Defense or armed forces have received during the reporting period involving allegations of acts of violence, including sexual abuse or harassment, by instructors against students in Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps programs, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the offense involved;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the armed force involved;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the number of instructors and number of allegations each instructor received;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the number of reports of sexual misconduct and harassment that have been investigated;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the number of reports or investigations that have led to the removal of an instructor from a Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the number of such reported allegations by State, the District of Columbia, or overseas location where these reports occurred.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any steps the Department of Defense has taken to mitigate sexual misconduct and harassment in Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps programs during the preceding year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form and may not be designated as controlled unclassified information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall annually report to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives regarding compliance with this subsection by the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps programs, including an up-to-date report on the Secretary’s monitoring of such compliance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 88–647, title I, § 101(1)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1063</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 16</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 3(4)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 220</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–165</ref>, <date date="1973-11-29">Nov. 29, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 660</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–361, title VIII, § 807</ref>, <date date="1976-07-14">July 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 933</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–358</ref>, <date date="1978-09-08">Sept. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title IV, § 422</ref>, title XIV, § 1405(32), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2520</ref>, 2624; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(i)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title V, § 533(a)</ref>–(e)(1), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2411</ref>, 2412; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1182(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 537</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1107</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 540</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2211</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VI, § 635</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 155</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 511, 512(a), 513, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1348</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3587</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 512(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 551–553(a), 554, 555(a), 556, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 269–272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 542–545(a), title XVII, § 1701(a)(25), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1892</ref>, 1893, 2204.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2032.</num>
<heading> Responsibility of the Secretaries of the military departments to maximize enrollment and enhance efficiency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each military department, in establishing, maintaining, transferring, and terminating Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps units under <ref>section 2031 of this title</ref>, shall do so in a coordinated manner that is designed to maximize enrollment in the Corps and to enhance administrative efficiency in the management of the Corps.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration of New School Openings and Consolidations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of a military department shall take into consideration—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> openings of new schools;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consolidations of schools; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the desirability of continuing the opportunity for participation in the Corps by participants whose continued participation would otherwise be adversely affected by new school openings and consolidations of schools.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 546(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2033.</num>
<heading> Instructor qualifications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In order for a retired officer or noncommissioned officer to be employed as an instructor in the program, the officer must be certified by the Secretary of the military department concerned as a qualified instructor in leadership, wellness and fitness, civics, and other courses related to the content of the program, according to the qualifications set forth in subsection (b)(2) or (c)(2), as appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Senior Military Instructors.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Role</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Senior military instructors shall be retired officers of the armed forces and shall serve as instructional leaders who oversee the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifications</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A senior military instructor shall have the following qualifications:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Professional military qualification, as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Award of a baccalaureate degree from an institution of higher learning.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Completion of secondary education teaching certification requirements for the program as established by the Secretary of the military department concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Award of an advanced certification by the Secretary of the military department concerned in core content areas based on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> accumulated points for professional activities, services to the profession, awards, and recognitions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> professional development to meet content knowledge and instructional skills; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> performance evaluation of competencies and standards within the program through site visits and inspections.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Non-Senior Military Instructors.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Role</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Non-senior military instructors shall be retired noncommissioned officers of the armed forces and shall serve as instructional leaders and teach independently of, but share program responsibilities with, senior military instructors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifications</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A non-senior military instructor shall demonstrate a depth of experience, proficiency, and expertise in coaching, mentoring, and practical arts in executing the program, and shall have the following qualifications:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Professional military qualification, as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Award of an associates degree from an institution of higher learning within five years of employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Completion of secondary education teaching certification requirements for the program as established by the Secretary of the military department concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Award of an advanced certification by the Secretary of the military department concerned in core content areas based on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> accumulated points for professional activities, services to the profession, awards, and recognitions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> professional development to meet content knowledge and instructional skills; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> performance evaluation of competencies and standards within the program through site visits and inspections.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 539(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2034.</num>
<heading> Educational institutions not maintaining units of Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps: issuance of arms, tentage, and equipment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of a military department may issue arms, tentage, and equipment to an educational institution at which no unit of the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps is maintained if the educational institution—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> offers a course in military training prescribed by that Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has a student body of at least 50 students who are in a grade above the eighth grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 552(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1741</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2035.</num>
<heading> Flexibility in authorities for management of programs and units</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Convert Otherwise Closing Units to National Defense Cadet Corps Program Units</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of a military department is notified by a local educational agency of the intent of the agency to close its Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps, the Secretary shall offer the agency the option of converting the unit to a National Defense Cadet Corps (NDCC) program unit in lieu of closing the unit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Flexibility in Administration of Instructors.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretaries of the military departments may, without regard to any other provision of this chapter, undertake initiatives designed to promote flexibility in the hiring and compensation of instructors for the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program under the jurisdiction of such Secretaries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The initiatives undertaken pursuant to this subsection may provide for one or more of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Termination of the requirement for a waiver as a condition of the hiring of well-qualified non-commissioned officers with a bachelor’s degree for senior instructor positions within the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Specification of a single instructor as the minimum number of instructors required to found and operate a Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps unit.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Authority for Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps instructors to undertake school duties, in addition to Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps duties, at small schools.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Authority for the payment of instructor compensation for a limited number of Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps instructors on a 10-month per year basis rather than a 12-month per year basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Such other actions as the Secretaries of the military departments consider appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Flexibility in Allocation and Use of Travel Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretaries of the military departments shall take appropriate actions to provide so-called regional directors of the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps programs located at remote rural schools enhanced discretion in the allocation and use of funds for travel in connection with Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standardization of Program Data</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall take appropriate actions to standardize the data collected and maintained on the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps programs in order to facilitate and enhance the collection and analysis of such data. Such actions shall include a requirement for the use of the National Center for Education Statistics (NCES) identification code for each school with a unit under a Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program in order to facilitate identification of such schools and their units under the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps programs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 557(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1773</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2036.</num>
<heading> Grants to support science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, may carry out a program to make grants to eligible entities to assist such entities in providing education in covered subjects to students in the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out a program under subsection (a), the Secretary may coordinate with the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Science Foundation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The heads of such other Federal, State, and local government entities the Secretary of Defense determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Activities funded with grants under this section may include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Training and other support for instructors to teach courses in covered subjects to students.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The acquisition of materials, hardware, and software necessary for the instruction of covered subjects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Activities that improve the quality of educational materials, training opportunities, and curricula available to students and instructors in covered subjects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Development of travel opportunities, demonstrations, mentoring programs, and informal education in covered subjects for students and instructors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Students’ pursuit of certifications in covered subjects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preference</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In making any grants under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to eligible entities that are eligible for assistance under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6311</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Evaluations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out a program under this section, the Secretary shall establish outcome-based metrics and internal and external assessments to evaluate the merits and benefits of the activities funded with grants under this section with respect to the needs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out a program under this section, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, make use of the authorities under chapter 111 and sections 2601 and 2605 of this title, and other authorities the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “eligible entity” means a local education agency that hosts a unit of the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered subjects” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> science;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> engineering;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> mathematics;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> computer science;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> computational thinking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> artificial intelligence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> machine learning;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> data science;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> quantum information sciences;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> cybersecurity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> robotics;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> health sciences; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> other subjects determined by the Secretary of Defense to be related to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 513(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3587</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 511</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1682</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>