<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 21—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE INTELLIGENCE MATTERS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 421.</num>
<heading> Funds for foreign cryptologic support</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may use appropriated funds available to the Department of Defense for intelligence and communications purposes to pay for the expenses of arrangements with foreign countries for cryptologic support.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may use funds other than appropriated funds to pay for the expenses of arrangements with foreign countries for cryptologic support without regard for the provisions of law relating to the expenditure of United States Government funds, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> no such funds may be expended, in whole or in part, by or for the benefit of the Department of Defense for a purpose for which Congress had previously denied funds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> proceeds from the sale of cryptologic items may be used only to purchase replacement items similar to the items that are sold; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the authority provided by this subsection may not be used to acquire items or services for the principal benefit of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Any funds expended under the authority of subsection (a) shall be reported to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives pursuant to the provisions of title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.). Funds expended under the authority of subsection (b) shall be reported pursuant to procedures jointly agreed upon by such committees and the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–450, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1977</ref>, § 140a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1063</ref>; renumbered § 128 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a)(3), 110(d)(5), <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 994</ref>, 1002; renumbered § 421, <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 9(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–453, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1604</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3508</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 422.</num>
<heading> Use of funds for certain incidental purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Counterintelligence Official Reception and Representation Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may use funds available to the Department of Defense for counterintelligence programs to pay the expenses of hosting foreign officials in the United States under the auspices of the Department of Defense for consultation on counterintelligence matters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Promotional Items for Recruitment Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may use funds available for an intelligence element of the Department of Defense to purchase promotional items of nominal value for use in the recruitment of individuals for employment by that element.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–569, title IV, § 401(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3195</ref>, § 140a; renumbered § 422, <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 9(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 287</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–108, title V, § 501(a)</ref>–(b)(2), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1404</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 423.</num>
<heading> Authority to use proceeds from counterintelligence operations of the military departments or the Defense Intelligence Agency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may authorize, without regard to the provisions of <ref>section 3302 of title 31</ref>, use of proceeds from counterintelligence operations conducted by components of the military departments or the Defense Intelligence Agency to offset necessary and reasonable expenses, not otherwise prohibited by law, incurred in such operations, and to make exceptional performance awards to personnel involved in such operations, if use of appropriated funds to meet such expenses or to make such awards would not be practicable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> As soon as the net proceeds from such counterintelligence operations are no longer necessary for the conduct of those operations, such proceeds shall be deposited into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish policies and procedures to govern acquisition, use, management, and disposition of proceeds from counterintelligence operations conducted by components of the military departments or the Defense Intelligence Agency, including effective internal systems of accounting and administrative controls.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–569, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3196</ref>, § 140b; renumbered § 423 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 9(a)(3)</ref>, (b)(3), <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title IX, § 921(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 424.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of organizational and personnel information: exemption for specified intelligence agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemption From Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as required by the President or as provided in subsection (c), no provision of law shall be construed to require the disclosure of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the organization or any function of an organization of the Department of Defense named in subsection (b); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of persons employed by or assigned or detailed to any such organization or the name, official title, occupational series, grade, or salary of any such person.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section applies to the following organizations of the Department of Defense:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Defense Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The National Reconnaissance Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provision of Information to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) does not apply with respect to the provision of information to Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2683</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(5)(A)</ref>, (B)(i), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1569</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 425.</num>
<heading> Prohibition of unauthorized use of name, initials, or seal: specified intelligence agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except with the written permission of both the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence, no person may knowingly use, in connection with any merchandise, retail product, impersonation, solicitation, or commercial activity in a manner reasonably calculated to convey the impression that such use is approved, endorsed, or authorized by the Secretary and the Director, any of the following (or any colorable imitation thereof):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The words “Defense Intelligence Agency”, the initials “DIA”, or the seal of the Defense Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The words “National Reconnaissance Office”, the initials “NRO”, or the seal of the National Reconnaissance Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The words “National Imagery and Mapping Agency”, the initials “NIMA”, or the seal of the National Imagery and Mapping Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The words “Defense Mapping Agency”, the initials “DMA”, or the seal of the Defense Mapping Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The words “National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency”, the initials “NGA,” or the seal of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Enjoin Violations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever it appears to the Attorney General that any person is engaged or is about to engage in an act or practice which constitutes or will constitute conduct prohibited by subsection (a), the Attorney General may initiate a civil proceeding in a district court of the United States to enjoin such act or practice. Such court shall proceed as soon as practicable to the hearing and determination of such action and may, at any time before final determination, enter such restraining orders or prohibitions, or take such other actions as is warranted, to prevent injury to the United States or to any person or class of persons for whose protection the action is brought.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–107, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1997-11-20">Nov. 20, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2262</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 932(a)(6), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(c)(10)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2475</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 426.</num>
<heading> Integration of Department of Defense intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance capabilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">ISR Integration Council</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security shall establish an Intelligence, Surveillance, and Reconnaissance Integration Council—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to assist the Secretary of Defense in carrying out the responsibilities of the Secretary under section 105(a) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3038(a)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to assist the Under Secretary with respect to matters relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> integration of intelligence and counterintelligence capabilities and activities under <ref>section 137(b) of this title</ref> of the military departments, intelligence agencies of the Department of Defense, and relevant combatant commands; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> coordination of related developmental activities of such departments, agencies, and combatant commands; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to otherwise provide a means to facilitate such integration and coordination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Council shall be composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Under Secretary, who shall chair the Council;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the directors of the intelligence agencies of the Department of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the senior intelligence officers of the armed forces and the regional and functional combatant commands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Director for Intelligence of the Joint Chiefs of Staff; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Director for Operations of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary shall invite the participation of the Director of National Intelligence (or a representative of the Director) in the proceedings of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary may designate additional participants to attend the proceedings of the Council, as the Under Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Briefings on the Intelligence and Counterintelligence Requirements of the Combatant Commands</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff shall provide to the congressional defense committees and the congressional intelligence committees a briefing on the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The intelligence and counterintelligence requirements, by specific intelligence capability type, of each of the relevant combatant commands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For the year preceding the year in which the briefing is provided, the fulfillment rate for each of the relevant combatant commands of the validated intelligence and counterintelligence requirements, by specific intelligence capability type, of such combatant command.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A risk analysis identifying the critical gaps and shortfalls in efforts to address operational and strategic requirements of the Department of Defense that would result from the failure to fulfill the validated intelligence and counterintelligence requirements of the relevant combatant commands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A mitigation plan to balance and offset the gaps and shortfalls identified under subparagraph (C), including with respect to spaceborne, airborne, ground, maritime, and cyber intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance capabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> For the year preceding the year in which the briefing is provided—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of intelligence and counterintelligence requests of each commander of a relevant combatant command determined by the Joint Chiefs of Staff to be a validated requirement, and the total of capacity of such requests provided to each such commander;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to such validated requirements—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the quantity of intelligence and counterintelligence capabilities or activities, by specific intelligence capability type, that the Joint Chiefs of Staff requested each military department to provide; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the total of capacity of such requests so provided by each such military department; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> a qualitative assessment of the alignment of intelligence and counterintelligence capabilities and activities with the program of analysis for each combat support agency and intelligence center of a military service that is part of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Defense Intelligence Enterprise; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the intelligence community.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security shall provide to the congressional defense committees and the congressional intelligence committees a briefing on short-, mid-, and long-term strategies to address the validated intelligence and counterintelligence requirements of the relevant combatant commands, including with respect to spaceborne, airborne, ground, maritime, and cyber intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The briefings required by paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be provided at the same time that the President’s budget is submitted pursuant to <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref> for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2025.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “congressional intelligence committees” has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Defense Intelligence Enterprise” means the organizations, infrastructure, and measures, including policies, processes, procedures, and products, of the intelligence, counterintelligence, and security components of each of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Department of Defense.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Joint Staff.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The combatant commands.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The military departments.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Other elements of the Department of Defense that perform national intelligence, defense intelligence, intelligence-related, counterintelligence, or security functions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The term “fulfillment rate” means the percentage of combatant command intelligence and counterintelligence requirements satisfied by available, acquired, or realigned intelligence and counterintelligence capabilities or activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The term “intelligence community” has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 923(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1575</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)(7)</ref>, (8), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title IX, § 922(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4331</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVI, § 1625(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1621(e)(1)(A)(vii), 1622, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1733</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 427.</num>
<heading> Conflict Records Research Center</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Center Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish a center to be known as the “Conflict Records Research Center” (in this section referred to as the “Center”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes of the Center shall be the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To establish a digital research database, including translations, and to facilitate research and analysis of records captured from countries, organizations, and individuals, now or once hostile to the United States, with rigid adherence to academic freedom and integrity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Consistent with the protection of national security information, personally identifiable information, and intelligence sources and methods, to make a significant portion of these records available to researchers as quickly and responsibly as possible while taking into account the integrity of the academic process and risks to innocents or third parties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To conduct and disseminate research and analysis to increase the understanding of factors related to international relations, counterterrorism, and conventional and unconventional warfare and, ultimately, enhance national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To collaborate with members of academic and broad national security communities, both domestic and international, on research, conferences, seminars, and other information exchanges to identify topics of importance for the leadership of the United States Government and the scholarly community.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Concurrence of the Director of National Intelligence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall seek the concurrence of the Director of National Intelligence to the extent the efforts and activities of the Center involve the entities referred to in subsection (b)(4).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support From Other United States Government Departments or Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of any non-Department of Defense department or agency of the United States Government may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide to the Secretary of Defense services, including personnel support, to support the operations of the Center; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transfer funds to the Secretary of Defense to support the operations of the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Gifts and Donations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary of Defense may accept from any source specified in paragraph (2) any gift or donation for purposes of defraying the costs or enhancing the operations of the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The sources specified in this paragraph are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The government of a State or a political subdivision of a State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The government of a foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A foundation or other charitable organization, including a foundation or charitable organization that is organized or operates under the laws of a foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any source in the private sector of the United States or a foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may not accept a gift or donation under this subsection if acceptance of the gift or donation would compromise or appear to compromise—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the ability of the Department of Defense, any employee of the Department, or any member of the armed forces to carry out the responsibility or duty of the Department in a fair and objective manner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the integrity of any program of the Department or of any person involved in such a program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall provide written guidance setting forth the criteria to be used in determining the applicability of paragraph (3) to any proposed gift or donation under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crediting of Funds Transferred or Accepted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds transferred to or accepted by the Secretary of Defense under this section shall be credited to appropriations available to the Department of Defense for the Center, and shall be available for the same purposes, and subject to the same conditions and limitations, as the appropriations with which merged. Any funds so transferred or accepted shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “captured record” means a document, audio file, video file, or other material captured during combat operations from countries, organizations, or individuals, now or once hostile to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “gift or donation” means any gift or donation of funds, materials (including research materials), real or personal property, or services (including lecture services and faculty services).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 867</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 428.</num>
<heading> Defense industrial security</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for Defense Industrial Security</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall be responsible for the protection of classified information disclosed to contractors of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consistency With Executive Orders and Directives</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall carry out the responsibility assigned under subsection (a) in a manner consistent with Executive Order 12829 (or any successor order to such executive order) and consistent with policies relating to the National Industrial Security Program (or any successor to such program).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance of Industrial Security Functions for Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may perform industrial security functions for other agencies of the Federal government upon request or upon designation of the Department of Defense as executive agent for the National Industrial Security Program (or any successor to such program).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations and Policy Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe, and from time to time revise, such regulations and policy guidance as are necessary to ensure the protection of classified information disclosed to contractors of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Dedication of Resources</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that sufficient resources are provided to staff, train, and support such personnel as are necessary to fully protect classified information disclosed to contractors of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 845(a)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4541</ref>, § 438; renumbered § 428, <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 429.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for Defense intelligence elements: accounts for transfers; transfer authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accounts for Appropriations for Defense Intelligence Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may transfer appropriations of the Department of Defense which are available for the activities of Defense intelligence elements to an account or accounts established for receipt of such transfers. Each such account may also receive transfers from the Director of National Intelligence if made pursuant to section 102A of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3024</ref>) and transfers and reimbursements arising from transactions, as authorized by law, between a Defense intelligence element and another entity. Appropriation balances in each such account may be transferred back to the account or accounts from which such appropriations originated as appropriation refunds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recordation of Transfers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Transfers made pursuant to subsection (a) shall be recorded as expenditure transfers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds transferred pursuant to subsection (a) shall remain available for the same time period and for the same purpose as the appropriation from which transferred, and shall remain subject to the same limitations provided in the law making the appropriation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligation and Expenditure of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless otherwise specifically authorized by law, funds transferred pursuant to subsection (a) shall only be obligated and expended in accordance with chapter 15 of title 31 and all other applicable provisions of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense Intelligence Element Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Defense intelligence element” means any of the Department of Defense agencies, offices, and elements included within the definition of “intelligence community” under section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–87, title IV, § 433(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-01-03">Jan. 3, 2012</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1894</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(5)</ref>, (f)(6), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3508</ref>, 3510.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 429a.</num>
<heading> Expenditure of funds for Department of Defense intelligence and counterintelligence activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary of Defense may expend amounts made available for the Military Intelligence Program for intelligence and counterintelligence activities for any purpose the Secretary determines to be proper with regard to intelligence and counterintelligence objects of a confidential, extraordinary, or emergency nature. Such a determination is final and conclusive upon the accounting officers of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may not expend more than five percent of the amounts described in subsection (a) for any fiscal year for objects described in that subsection unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary notifies the congressional defense committees and the congressional intelligence committees of the intent to expend the amounts and purpose of the expenditure; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 30 days have elapsed from the date on which the Secretary provides the notice described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each expenditure of funds under this section, the Secretary shall certify that such expenditure was made for an object of a confidential, extraordinary, or emergency nature.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than December 31 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees and the congressional intelligence committees a report on expenditures made under this section during the fiscal year preceding the year in which the report is submitted. Each such report shall include, for each expenditure under this section during the fiscal year covered by the report, a description, the purpose, the program element, and the certification required under section (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Delegations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may not delegate the authority under this section with respect to any expenditure in excess of $200,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication of Section </inline>127.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided by subsection (a) shall be the exclusive authority available to the Secretary of Defense to expend amounts made available for the Military Intelligence Program for intelligence and counterintelligence objects of a confidential, extraordinary, or emergency nature.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Intelligence Committees Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “congressional intelligence committees” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1614(a)</ref>–(e)(1), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2168</ref>, 2169.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 430.</num>
<heading> Tactical Exploitation of National Capabilities Executive Agent</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security shall designate a civilian employee of the Department or a member of the armed forces to serve as the Tactical Exploitation of National Capabilities Executive Agent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Executive Agent designated under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> report directly to the Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> work with the combatant commands, military departments, and the intelligence community (as defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</ref>) to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop methods to increase warfighter effectiveness through the exploitation of national capabilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promote cross-domain integration of such capabilities into military operations, training, intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3631</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(e)(1)(A)(viii)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1733</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3871</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 430a.</num>
<heading> Executive agent for management and oversight of alternative compensatory control measures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive Agent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall designate a senior official from among the personnel of the Department of Defense to act as the Department of Defense executive agent for the management and oversight of alternative compensatory control measures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Roles, Responsibilities, and Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe the roles, responsibilities, and authorities of the executive agent designated under subsection (a). Such roles, responsibilities, and authorities shall include the development of an annual management and oversight plan for Department-wide accountability and reporting to the congressional defense committees.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1083(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1003</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 430b.</num>
<heading> Executive agent for open-source intelligence tools</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2016-04-01">April 1, 2016</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall designate a senior official of the Department of Defense to serve as the executive agent for the Department for open-source intelligence tools.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Roles, Responsibilities, and Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num> (1)</num>
<content> Not later than <date date="2016-07-01">July 1, 2016</date>, in accordance with Directive 5101.1, the Secretary shall prescribe the roles, responsibilities, and authorities of the executive agent designated under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The roles and responsibilities of the executive agent designated under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Developing and maintaining a comprehensive list of open-source intelligence tools and technical standards.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Establishing priorities for the development, acquisition, and integration of open-source intelligence tools into the intelligence enterprise, and other command and control systems as needed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Certifying all open-source intelligence tools with respect to compliance with the standards required by the framework and guidance for the Intelligence Community Information Technology Enterprise, the Defense Intelligence Information Enterprise, and the Joint Information Environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Assessing and making recommendations regarding the protection of privacy in the acquisition, analysis, and dissemination of open-source information available around the world.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Performing such other assessments or analyses as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support Within Department of Defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In accordance with Directive 5101.1, the Secretary shall ensure that the military departments, the Defense Agencies, and other elements of the Department of Defense provide the executive agent designated under subsection (a) with the appropriate support and resources needed to perform the roles, responsibilities, and authorities of the executive agent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Directive 5101.1” means Department of Defense Directive 5101.1, or any successor directive relating to the responsibilities of an executive agent of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “executive agent” has the meaning given the term “DoD Executive Agent” in Directive 5101.1.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “open-source intelligence tools” means tools for the systematic collection, processing, and analysis of publicly available information for known or anticipated intelligence requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1631(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 430c.</num>
<heading> Senior intelligence oversight official <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002033">1</ref></heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, or a designee of the Secretary determined by regulations prescribed by the Secretary, shall designate a civilian employee of the Department of Defense in the Senior Executive Service to serve as the Senior Intelligence Oversight Official.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Senior Intelligence Oversight Official shall conduct independent oversight of all intelligence, counterintelligence, and intelligence-related activities of the Department of Defense and shall have such other related responsibilities as may be determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Senior Intelligence Oversight Official shall have—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> access to all information necessary to carry out the responsibilities and functions of the Senior Intelligence Oversight Official, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> direct access to the Secretary of Defense and the Deputy Secretary of Defense, as circumstances require in the determination of the Senior Intelligence Oversight Official.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title IX, § 921(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2036</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 430d.</num>
<heading> Cyber intelligence capability</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2026-10-01">October 1, 2026</date>, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, shall ensure that the Department of Defense has a dedicated cyber intelligence capability in support of the military cyber operations requirements for the warfighting missions of the United States Cyber Command, the other combatant commands, the military departments, the Defense Agencies, the Joint Staff, and the Office of the Secretary of Defense with respect to foundational, scientific and technical, and all-source intelligence on cyber technology development, capabilities, concepts of operation, operations, and plans and intentions of cyber threat actors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonduplication</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary may not unnecessarily duplicate intelligence activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Resources</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure the defense budget materials submitted for each fiscal year beginning with fiscal year 2027 include a request for funds necessary to carry out subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall carry out subsection (a) using funds made available for the United States Cyber Command under the Military Intelligence Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The National Security Agency may not provide information technology services for the dedicated cyber intelligence capability under subsection (a) unless such services are provided under the Military Intelligence Program or the Information Systems Security Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense Budget Materials Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “defense budget materials”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the materials submitted to Congress by the Secretary of Defense in support of the budget for that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1612(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>INTELLIGENCE COMMERCIAL ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 431.</num>
<heading> Authority to engage in commercial activities as security for intelligence collection activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, subject to the provisions of this subchapter, may authorize the conduct of those commercial activities necessary to provide security for authorized intelligence collection activities abroad undertaken by the Department of Defense. No commercial activity may be initiated pursuant to this subchapter after <date date="2028-12-31">December 31, 2028</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interagency Coordination and Support</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any such activity shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be pre-coordinated with the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency using procedures mutually agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense and the Director; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> where appropriate, be supported by the Director; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the extent the activity takes place within the United States, be coordinated with, and (where appropriate) be supported by, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “commercial activities” means activities that are conducted in a manner consistent with prevailing commercial practices and includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the acquisition, use, sale, storage and disposal of goods and services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> entering into employment contracts and leases and other agreements for real and personal property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> depositing funds into and withdrawing funds from domestic and foreign commercial business or financial institutions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> acquiring licenses, registrations, permits, and insurance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> establishing corporations, partnerships, and other legal entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “intelligence collection activities” means the collection of foreign intelligence and counterintelligence information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–88, title V, § 504(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 437</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–93, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1996-01-06">Jan. 6, 1996</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 973</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–272, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1998-10-20">Oct. 20, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2404</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1077], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–282; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1053</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2649</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IX, § 921</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2029</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title IX, § 931</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2362</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 931(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 932(a)(7), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(c)(10)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title IX, § 921</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4330</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XVI, § 1623</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3632</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVI, § 1622</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 685</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2166</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 432.</num>
<heading> Use, disposition, and auditing of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds generated by a commercial activity authorized pursuant to this subchapter may be used to offset necessary and reasonable expenses arising from that activity. Use of such funds for that purpose shall be kept to the minimum necessary to conduct the activity concerned in a secure manner. Any funds generated by the activity in excess of those required for that purpose shall be deposited, as often as may be practicable, into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Audits</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall assign an organization within the Department of Defense to have auditing responsibility with respect to activities authorized under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> That organization shall audit the use and disposition of funds generated by any commercial activity authorized under this subchapter not less often than annually. The results of all such audits shall be reported to the congressional defense committees and the congressional intelligence committees (as defined in <ref>section 437(c) of this title</ref>) by not later than December 31 of each year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–88, title V, § 504(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 438</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title IX, § 921(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 827</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVI, § 1623</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1732</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 433.</num>
<heading> Relationship with other Federal laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided by subsection (b), a commercial activity conducted pursuant to this subchapter shall be carried out in accordance with applicable Federal law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Waivers When Necessary to Maintain Security</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of Defense determines, in connection with a commercial activity authorized pursuant to <ref>section 431 of this title</ref>, that compliance with certain Federal laws or regulations pertaining to the management and administration of Federal agencies would create an unacceptable risk of compromise of an authorized intelligence activity, the Secretary may, to the extent necessary to prevent such compromise, waive compliance with such laws or regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any determination and waiver by the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall be made in writing and shall include a specification of the laws and regulations for which compliance by the commercial activity concerned is not required consistent with this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary under paragraph (1) may be delegated only to the Deputy Secretary of Defense, an Under Secretary of Defense, an Assistant Secretary of Defense, or a Secretary of a military department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Laws and Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section, Federal laws and regulations pertaining to the management and administration of Federal agencies are only those Federal laws and regulations pertaining to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The receipt and use of appropriated and nonappropriated funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The acquisition or management of property or services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Information disclosure, retention, and management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The employment of personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Payments for travel and housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The establishment of legal entities or government instrumentalities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Foreign trade or financial transaction restrictions that would reveal the commercial activity as an activity of the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–88, title V, § 504(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 438</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 434.</num>
<heading> Reservation of defenses and immunities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The submission to judicial proceedings in a State or other legal jurisdiction, in connection with a commercial activity undertaken pursuant to this subchapter, shall not constitute a waiver of the defenses and immunities of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–88, title V, § 504(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 435.</num>
<heading> Limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lawful Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subchapter authorizes the conduct of any intelligence activity that is not otherwise authorized by law or Executive order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Domestic Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Personnel conducting commercial activity authorized by this subchapter may only engage in those activities in the United States to the extent necessary to support intelligence activities abroad.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Providing Goods and Services to the Department of Defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Commercial activity may not be undertaken within the United States for the purpose of providing goods and services to the Department of Defense, other than as may be necessary to provide security for the activities subject to this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to United States Persons</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In carrying out a commercial activity authorized under this subchapter, the Secretary of Defense may not permit an entity engaged in such activity to employ a United States person in an operational, managerial, or supervisory position, and may not assign or detail a United States person to perform operational, managerial, or supervisory duties for such an entity, unless that person is informed in advance of the intelligence security purpose of that activity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “United States person” means an individual who is a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–88, title V, § 504(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 436.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to implement the authority provided in this subchapter. Such regulations shall be consistent with this subchapter and shall at a minimum—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specify all elements of the Department of Defense who are authorized to engage in commercial activities pursuant to this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require the personal approval of the Secretary or Deputy Secretary of Defense for all sensitive activities to be authorized pursuant to this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> specify all officials who are authorized to grant waivers of laws or regulations pursuant to <ref>section 433(b) of this title</ref>, or to approve the establishment or conduct of commercial activities pursuant to this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> designate a single office within the Department of Defense to be responsible for the oversight of all activities authorized under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> require that each commercial activity proposed to be authorized under this subchapter be subject to appropriate legal review before the activity is authorized; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide for appropriate internal audit controls and oversight for such activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–88, title V, § 504(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 439</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title IX, § 921(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 827</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 437.</num>
<heading> Congressional oversight</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proposed Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Copies of regulations proposed to be prescribed under <ref>section 436 of this title</ref> (including any proposed revision to such regulations) shall be submitted to congressional defense committees and the congressional intelligence committees not less than 30 days before they take effect.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Current Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that congressional defense committees and the congressional intelligence committees are kept fully and currently informed of actions taken pursuant to this subchapter, including any significant anticipated activity to be authorized pursuant to this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Intelligence Committees Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “congressional intelligence committees” has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–88, title V, § 504(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 440</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–306, title VIII, § 811(b)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2423</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2061</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1061(5)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1583</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title IX, § 921(c)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 827</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>