<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 36—</num>
<heading>PROMOTION, SEPARATION, AND INVOLUNTARY RETIREMENT OF OFFICERS ON THE ACTIVE-DUTY LIST</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>SELECTION BOARDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 611.</num>
<heading> Convening of selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whenever the needs of the service require, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall convene selection boards to recommend for promotion to the next higher permanent grade, under subchapter II of this chapter, officers on the active-duty list in each permanent grade from first lieutenant through brigadier general in the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force and from lieutenant (junior grade) through rear admiral (lower half) in the Navy. The preceding sentence does not require the convening of a selection board in the case of officers in the permanent grade of first lieutenant or, in the case of the Navy, lieutenant (junior grade) when the Secretary concerned recommends for promotion to the next higher grade under <ref>section 624(a)(3) of this title</ref> all such officers whom the Secretary finds to be fully qualified for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whenever the needs of the service require, the Secretary of the military department concerned may convene selection boards to recommend officers for continuation on active duty under <ref>section 637 of this title</ref> or for early retirement under <ref>section 638 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The convening of selection boards under subsections (a) and (b) shall be under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2851</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 505(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 521(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1881</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 612.</num>
<heading> Composition of selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Members of selection boards shall be appointed by the Secretary of the military department concerned in accordance with this section. A selection board shall consist of five or more officers of the same armed force as the officers under consideration by the board. Each member of a selection board (except as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4)) shall be an officer on the active-duty list. Each member of a selection board must be serving in a grade higher than the grade of the officers under consideration by the board, except that no member of a board may be serving in a grade below major or lieutenant commander. The members of a selection board shall represent the diverse population of the armed force concerned to the extent practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a selection board shall include at least one officer from each competitive category of officers to be considered by the board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A selection board need not include an officer from a competitive category to be considered by the board when there are no officers of that competitive category on the active-duty list in a grade higher than the grade of the officers to be considered by the board and eligible to serve on the board. However, in such a case the Secretary of the military department concerned, in his discretion, may appoint as a member of the board an officer of that competitive category who is not on the active-duty list from among officers of the same armed force as the officers under consideration by the board who hold a higher grade than the grade of the officers under consideration and who are retired officers, reserve officers serving on active duty but not on the active-duty list, or members of the Ready Reserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> When reserve officers of an armed force are to be considered by a selection board, the membership of the board shall include at least one reserve officer of that armed force on active duty (whether or not on the active-duty list). The actual number of reserve officers shall be determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned, in the Secretary’s discretion. Notwithstanding the first sentence of this paragraph, in the case of a board which is considering officers in the grade of colonel or brigadier general or, in the case of officers of the Navy, captain or rear admiral (lower half), no reserve officer need be included if there are no reserve officers of that armed force on active duty in the next higher grade who are eligible to serve on the board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), if qualified officers on the active-duty list are not available in sufficient number to comprise a selection board, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall complete the membership of the board by appointing as members of the board officers who are members of the same armed force and hold a grade higher than the grade of the officers under consideration by the board and who are retired officers, reserve officers serving on active duty but not on the active-duty list, or members of the Ready Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A retired general or flag officer who is on active duty for the purpose of serving on a selection board shall not, while so serving, be counted against any limitation on the number of general and flag officers who may be on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> No officer may be a member of two successive selection boards convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> for the consideration of officers of the same competitive category and grade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> that will consider an officer described in paragraph (2) shall include at least one officer designated by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff who is a joint qualified officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) applies with respect to an officer who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is serving on, or has served on, the Joint Staff; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is a joint qualified officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may waive the requirement in paragraph (1) in the case of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any selection board of the Marine Corps or the Space Force; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any selection board that is considering officers in specialties identified in paragraph (2) or (3) of <ref>section 619a(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2851</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 125</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1030</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 504(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–101; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 522(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4214</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 503(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 521(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1881</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 613.</num>
<heading> Oath of members of selection boards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each member of a selection board shall swear that he will perform his duties as a member of the board without prejudice or partiality and having in view both the special fitness of officers and the efficiency of his armed force.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 613a.</num>
<heading> Nondisclosure of board proceedings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The proceedings of a selection board convened under section 573, 611, 628, or 20211 of this title may not be disclosed to any person not a member of the board, except as authorized or required to process the report of the board. This prohibition is a statutory exemption from disclosure, as described in <ref>section 552(b)(3) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibited Uses of Board Discussions, Deliberations, Notes, and Records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The discussions and deliberations of a selection board described in subsection (a) and any written or documentary record of such discussions and deliberations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are immune from legal process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not be admitted as evidence; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may not be used for any purpose in any action, suit, or judicial or administrative proceeding without the consent of the Secretary of the military department concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section applies to all selection boards convened under section 573, 611, 628, or 20211 of this title, regardless of the date on which the board was convened.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 547(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2215</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4207</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 668</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 614.</num>
<heading> Notice of convening of selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> At least 30 days before a selection board is convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> to recommend officers in a grade for promotion to the next higher grade, the Secretary concerned (1) shall notify in writing the officers eligible for consideration for promotion of the date on which the board is to convene and the name and date of rank of the junior officer, and of the senior officer, in the promotion zone as of the date of the notification, or (2) shall issue a general written notice to the armed force concerned regarding the convening of the board which shall include the convening date of the board and the name and date of rank of the junior officer, and of the senior officer, in the promotion zone as of the date of the notification.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An officer eligible for consideration by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> may send a written communication to the board, to arrive not later than 10 calendar days before the date the board convenes, calling attention to any matter concerning himself that the officer considers important to his case. The selection board shall give consideration to any timely communication under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2852</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 504(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3227</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 615.</num>
<heading> Information furnished to selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations governing information furnished to selection boards convened under section 611(a) or 20211 of this title. Those regulations shall apply uniformly among the military departments. Any regulations prescribed by the Secretary of a military department to supplement those regulations may not take effect without the approval of the Secretary of Defense in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> No information concerning a particular eligible officer may be furnished to a selection board except for the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Information that is in the officer’s official military personnel file and that is provided to the selection board in accordance with the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Other information that is determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned, after review by that Secretary in accordance with standards and procedures set out in the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to paragraph (1), to be substantiated, relevant information that could reasonably and materially affect the deliberations of the selection board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Subject to such limitations as may be prescribed in those regulations, information communicated to the board by the officer in accordance with this section, <ref>section 614(b) of this title</ref> (including any comment on information referred to in subparagraph (A) regarding that officer), or other applicable law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A factual summary of the information described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) that, in accordance with the regulations prescribed pursuant to paragraph (1), is prepared by administrative personnel for the purpose of facilitating the work of the selection board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of an eligible officer considered for promotion to a grade specified in subparagraph (B), any credible information of an adverse nature, including any substantiated adverse finding or conclusion from an officially documented investigation or inquiry, shall be furnished to the selection board in accordance with standards and procedures set out in the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A grade specified in this subparagraph is as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In the case of a regular officer or an officer in the Space Force, a grade above captain or, in the case of the Navy, lieutenant.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> In the case of a reserve officer, a grade above lieutenant colonel or, in the case of the Navy, commander.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The standards and procedures referred to in subparagraph (A) shall require the furnishing to the selection board, and to each individual member of the board, the information described in that subparagraph with regard to an officer in a grade specified in subparagraph (B) at each stage or phase of the selection board, concurrent with the screening, rating, assessment, evaluation, discussion, or other consideration by the board or member of the official military personnel file of the officer, or of the officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> With respect to the consideration of an officer for promotion to a grade at or below major general or in the case of the Navy, rear admiral, the requirements in subparagraphs (A) and (C) may be met through the convening and actions of a special selection review board with respect to the officer under <ref>section 628a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Information provided to a selection board in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) shall be made available to all members of the board and shall be made a part of the record of the board. Communication of such information shall be in a written form or in the form of an audio or video recording. If a communication is in the form of an audio or video recording, a written transcription of the recording shall also be made a part of the record of the selection board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) do not apply to the furnishing of appropriate administrative processing information to the selection board by administrative staff designated to assist the board, but only to the extent that oral communications are necessary to facilitate the work of the board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Information furnished to a selection board that is described in subparagraph (B), (C), or (D) of paragraph (2), or in paragraph (3), may not be furnished to a later selection board unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the information has been properly placed in the official military personnel file of the officer concerned; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the information is provided to the later selection board in accordance with paragraph (2) or (3), as applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Before information described in paragraph (2)(B) or (3) regarding an eligible officer is furnished to a selection board, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall ensure—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that such information is made available to such officer; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that the officer is afforded a reasonable opportunity to submit comments on that information to the selection board.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If an officer cannot be given access to the information referred to in subparagraph (A) because of its classification status, the officer shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be furnished with an appropriate summary of the information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the military department concerned shall furnish each selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the maximum number, as determined in accordance with <ref>section 622 of this title</ref>, of officers in each competitive category under consideration that the board may recommend for promotion to the next higher grade;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the names of all officers in each competitive category to be considered by the board for promotion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the pertinent records (as determined by the Secretary) of each officer whose name is furnished to the board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> information or guidelines relating to the needs of the armed force concerned for officers having particular skills, including guidelines or information relating to the need for either a minimum number or a maximum number of officers with particular skills within a competitive category;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> guidelines, based upon guidelines received by the Secretary from the Secretary of Defense under subsection (c), for the purpose of ensuring that the board gives appropriate consideration to the performance of officers who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> such other information and guidelines as may be necessary to enable the board to properly perform its functions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, with the advice and assistance of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, shall furnish to the Secretaries of the military departments guidelines for the purpose of ensuring that each selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> gives appropriate consideration to the performance of officers who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Information or guidelines furnished to a selection board under subsection (b) may not be modified, withdrawn, or supplemented after the board submits the report to the Secretary of the military department concerned pursuant to <ref>section 617(a) of this title</ref>, except that, in the case of a report returned to a board pursuant to <ref>section 618(a)(2) of this title</ref> for further proceedings because of a determination by the Secretary of the military department concerned that the board acted contrary to law, regulation, or guidelines, the Secretary may modify, withdraw, or supplement such information or guidelines as part of a written explanation to the board as provided in that section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary of each military department, under uniform regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, shall include in guidelines furnished to a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> that is considering officers in a health-professions competitive category for promotion to a grade below colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain, a direction that the board give consideration to an officer’s clinical proficiency and skill as a health professional to at least as great an extent as the board gives to the officer’s administrative and management skills.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2852</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title IV, § 402(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1030</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1965</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 519</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1444</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 504(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1355</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(7)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3227</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 522(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4215</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1344</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 505(c)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 668</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 616.</num>
<heading> Recommendations for promotion by selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> shall recommend for promotion to the next higher grade those officers considered by the board whom the board, giving due consideration to the needs of the armed force concerned for officers with particular skills (as noted in the guidelines or information furnished the board under <ref>section 615(b) of this title</ref>), considers best qualified for promotion within each competitive category considered by the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the military department concerned shall establish the number of officers such a selection board may recommend for promotion from among officers being considered from below the promotion zone in any competitive category. Such number may not exceed the number equal to 10 percent of the maximum number of officers that the board is authorized to recommend for promotion in such competitive category, except that the Secretary of Defense may authorize a greater number, not to exceed 15 percent of the total number of officers that the board is authorized to recommend for promotion, if the Secretary of Defense determines that the needs of the service so require. If the number determined under this subsection is less than one, the board may recommend one such officer. The number of officers recommended for promotion from below the promotion zone does not increase the maximum number of officers which the board is authorized under <ref>section 615 of this title</ref> to recommend for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> may not recommend an officer for promotion unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the officer receives the recommendation of a majority of the members of the board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a majority of the members of the board finds that the officer is fully qualified for promotion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a majority of the members of the board, after consideration by all members of the board of any adverse information about the officer that is provided to the board under <ref>section 615 of this title</ref>, finds that the officer is among the officers best qualified for promotion to meet the needs of the armed force concerned consistent with the requirement of exemplary conduct set forth in section 7233, 8167, or 9233 of this title, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), the number of officers recommended for promotion by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> may not exceed the number equal to 95 percent of the number of officers included in the promotion zone established under <ref>section 623 of this title</ref> for consideration by the board, except, the Secretary concerned may authorize a greater number of officers so recommended that is less than 100 percent of the number of officers so included, for medical and dental officers recommended for promotion to major or lieutenant commander, if the Secretary concerned determines that such greater number is necessary to maintain or improve medical readiness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> During the period beginning on <date date="2025-01-01">January 1, 2025</date>, and ending on <date date="2030-12-31">December 31, 2030</date>, the number of officers recommended for promotion by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> may not equal or exceed 100 percent of the number of officers included in the promotion zone established under <ref>section 623 of this title</ref> for consideration by the board, for nurse officers recommended for promotion to major or lieutenant commander, if the Secretary concerned determines that such greater number is necessary to maintain or improve medical readiness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided by law, an officer on the active-duty list may not be promoted to a higher grade under this chapter unless he is considered and recommended for promotion to that grade by a selection board convened under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The recommendations of a selection board may be disclosed only in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. Those recommendations may not be disclosed to a person not a member of the board (or a member of the administrative staff designated by the Secretary concerned to assist the board) until the written report of the recommendations of the board, required by <ref>section 617 of this title</ref>, is signed by each member of the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary convening a selection board under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref>, and an officer or other official exercising authority over any member of a selection board, may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> censure, reprimand, or admonish the selection board or any member of the board with respect to the recommendations of the board or the exercise of any lawful function within the authorized discretion of the board; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> attempt to coerce or, by any unauthorized means, influence any action of a selection board or any member of a selection board in the formulation of the board’s recommendations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In selecting the officers to be recommended for promotion, a selection board shall, when authorized by the Secretary of the military department concerned, recommend officers of particular merit, pursuant to guidelines and procedures prescribed by the Secretary, from among those officers selected for promotion, to be placed higher on the promotion list established by the Secretary under <ref>section 624(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An officer may be recommended to be placed higher on a promotion list under paragraph (1) only if the officer receives the recommendation of at least a majority of the members of the board, unless the Secretary concerned establishes an alternative requirement. Any such alternative requirement shall be furnished to the board as part of the guidelines furnished to the board under <ref>section 615 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the officers recommended to be placed higher on a promotion list under paragraph (1), the board shall recommend, pursuant to guidelines and procedures prescribed by the Secretary concerned, the order in which those officers should be placed on the list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2852</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1966</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 504(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(8)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 512(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2184</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1742</ref>, 1840; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1344</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3565</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 617.</num>
<heading> Reports of selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> shall submit to the Secretary of the military department concerned a written report, signed by each member of the board, containing a list of the names of the officers it recommends for promotion and certifying (1) that the board has carefully considered the record of each officer whose name was furnished to it under <ref>section 615 of this title</ref>, and (2) that, in the opinion of a majority of the members of the board, the officers recommended for promotion by the board are best qualified for promotion to meet the needs of the armed force concerned (as noted in the guidelines or information furnished the board under <ref>section 615(b) of this title</ref>) among those officers whose names were furnished to the selection board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> shall include in its report to the Secretary concerned the name of any regular or reserve officer before it for consideration for promotion whose record, in the opinion of a majority of the members of the board, indicates that the officer should be required under chapter 60 or 1411 of this title to show cause for his retention on active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> shall include in its report to the Secretary concerned the name of any officer considered and not recommended for promotion by the board who submitted to the board a request not to be selected for promotion or who otherwise directly caused his nonselection through written communication to the Board under <ref>section 614(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> shall, when authorized under <ref>section 616(h) of this title</ref>, include in its report to the Secretary concerned the names of those officers recommended by the board to be placed higher on the promotion list and the order in which the board recommends that those officers should be placed on the list.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2853</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title V, § 501(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1966</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(8)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1623</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2961</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2003</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 590</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 504(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1742</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(18)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3871</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 618.</num>
<heading> Action on reports of selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon receipt of the report of a selection board submitted to him under <ref>section 617(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall review the report to determine whether the board has acted contrary to law or regulation or to guidelines furnished the board under <ref>section 615(b) of this title</ref>. Following such review, unless the Secretary concerned makes a determination as described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall submit the report as required by subsection (b) or (c), as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If, on the basis of a review of the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the board acted contrary to law or regulation or to guidelines furnished the board under <ref>section 615(b) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall return the report, together with a written explanation of the basis for such determination, to the board for further proceedings. Upon receipt of a report returned by the Secretary concerned under this paragraph, the selection board (or a subsequent selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> for the same grade and competitive category) shall conduct such proceedings as may be necessary in order to revise the report to be consistent with law, regulation, and such guidelines and shall resubmit the report, as revised, to the Secretary in accordance with <ref>section 617 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> After completing the requirements of subsection (a), the Secretary concerned, in the case of the report of a selection board that considered officers who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers, shall submit the report to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Chairman, in accordance with guidelines furnished to the Chairman by the Secretary of Defense, shall review the report for the purpose of determining if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the selection board acted consistent with the guidelines of the Secretary of Defense under <ref>section 615(c) of this title</ref> to ensure that selection boards give appropriate consideration to the performance of officers who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the selection board otherwise gave appropriate consideration to the performance of officers who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> After reviewing the report, the Chairman shall return the report, with his determinations and comments, to the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> If the Chairman determines that the board acted contrary to the guidelines of the Secretary of Defense under <ref>section 615(c) of this title</ref> or otherwise failed to give appropriate consideration to the performance of officers who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers, the Secretary concerned may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> return the report, together with the Chairman’s determinations and comments, to the selection board (or a subsequent selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> for the same grade and competitive category) for further proceedings in accordance with subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> convene a special selection board in the manner provided for under <ref>section 628 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> take other appropriate action to satisfy the concerns of the Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> If, after completion of all actions taken under paragraph (4), the Secretary concerned and the Chairman remain in disagreement with respect to the report of a selection board, the Secretary concerned shall indicate such disagreement, and the reasons for such disagreement, as part of his transmittal of the report of the selection board to the Secretary of Defense under subsection (c). Such transmittal shall include any comments submitted by the Chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> After his final review of the report of a selection board, the Secretary concerned shall submit the report, with his recommendations thereon, to the Secretary of Defense for transmittal to the President for his approval or disapproval. The Secretary of Defense shall, before transmitting the report of a selection board to the President, take appropriate action to resolve any disagreement between the Secretary concerned and the Chairman transmitted to him under subsection (b)(5). If the authority of the President under this paragraph to approve or disapprove the report of a selection board is delegated to the Secretary of Defense, it may not be redelegated except to an official in the Office of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the report of a selection board names an officer as having a record which indicates that the officer should be required to show cause for his retention on active duty, the Secretary concerned may provide for the review of the record of that officer as provided for under regulations prescribed under <ref>section 1181 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the name of an officer recommended for promotion by a selection board may be removed from the report of the selection board only by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of an officer recommended by a selection board for promotion to a grade below brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half), the name of the officer may also be removed from the report of the selection board by the Secretary of Defense or the Deputy Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The names of the officers recommended for promotion in the report of a selection board shall be disseminated to the armed force concerned as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of officers recommended for promotion to a grade below brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half), such names may be disseminated upon, or at any time after, the transmittal of the report to the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of officers recommended for promotion to a grade above colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain, such names may be disseminated upon, or at any time after, the approval of the report by the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In the case of officers whose names have not been sooner disseminated, such names shall be promptly disseminated upon confirmation by the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A list of names of officers disseminated under paragraph (1) may not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any name removed by the President from the report of the selection board containing that name, if dissemination is under the authority of subparagraph (B) of such paragraph; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the name of any officer whose promotion the Senate failed to confirm, if dissemination is under the authority of subparagraph (C) of such paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(f)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 547(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2216</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of a military department or the Secretary of Defense makes a recommendation under this section that the name of an officer be removed from a report of a selection board and the recommendation is accompanied by information that was not presented to that selection board, that information shall be made available to that officer. The officer shall then be afforded a reasonable opportunity to submit comments on that information to the officials making the recommendation and the officials reviewing the recommendation. If an eligible officer cannot be given access to such information because of its classification status, the officer shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be provided with an appropriate summary of the information.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2853</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 524(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2524</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title IV, § 402(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1030</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title V, § 501(d)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1966</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 504(c)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(8)</ref>, (9), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 503(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–100; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 513(a), 547(a)(2), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2184</ref>, 2216; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 522(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>PROMOTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 619.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for consideration for promotion: time-in-grade and other requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time-in-Grade Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An officer who is on the active-duty list of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps and holds a permanent appointment in the grade of second lieutenant or first lieutenant or is on the active-duty list of the Navy and holds a permanent appointment in the grade of ensign or lieutenant (junior grade) may not be promoted to the next higher permanent grade until he has completed the following period of service in the grade in which he holds a permanent appointment:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Eighteen months, in the case of an officer holding a permanent appointment in the grade of second lieutenant or ensign.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Two years, in the case of an officer holding a permanent appointment in the grade of first lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade), except that the minimum period of service in effect under this subparagraph before <date date="2008-10-01">October 1, 2008</date>, shall be eighteen months.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (5), an officer who is on the active-duty list of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps and holds a permanent appointment in a grade above first lieutenant or is on the active-duty list of the Navy and holds a permanent appointment in a grade above lieutenant (junior grade) may not be considered for selection for promotion to the next higher permanent grade until he has completed the following period of service in the grade in which he holds a permanent appointment:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Three years, in the case of an officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps holding a permanent appointment in the grade of captain, major, or lieutenant colonel or of an officer of the Navy holding a permanent appointment in the grade of lieutenant, lieutenant commander, or commander.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> One year, in the case of an officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps holding a permanent appointment in the grade of colonel or brigadier general or of an officer of the Navy holding a permanent appointment in the grade of captain or rear admiral (lower half).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> When the needs of the service require, the Secretary of the military department concerned may prescribe a longer period of service in grade for eligibility for promotion, in the case of officers to whom paragraph (1) applies, or for eligibility for consideration for promotion, in the case of officers to whom paragraph (2) applies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> When the needs of the service require, the Secretary of the military department concerned may prescribe a shorter period of service in grade, but not less than two years, for eligibility for consideration for promotion, in the case of officers designated for limited duty to whom paragraph (2) applies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the military department concerned may waive paragraph (2) to the extent necessary to assure that officers described in subparagraph (A) of such paragraph have at least two opportunities for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade as officers below the promotion zone.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In computing service in grade for purposes of this section, service in a grade held as a result of assignment to a position is counted as service in the grade in which the officer would have served except for such assignment or appointment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continued Eligibility for Consideration for Promotion of Officers Who Have Previously Failed of Selection</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), an officer who has failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade remains eligible for consideration for promotion to that grade as long as he continues on active duty in other than a retired status and is not promoted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) does not apply to a regular officer who is ineligible for consideration for promotion under <ref>section 631(c) of this title</ref> or to a reserve officer who has failed of selection for promotion to the grade of captain or, in the case of an officer of the Navy, lieutenant for the second time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers To Be Considered by Promotion Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each time a selection board is convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> for consideration of officers in a competitive category for promotion to the next higher grade, each officer in the promotion zone (except as provided under paragraph (2)), and each officer above the promotion zone, for the grade and competitive category under consideration shall be considered for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the military department concerned—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may, in accordance with standards and procedures prescribed by the Secretary of Defense in regulations which shall apply uniformly among the military departments, limit the officers to be considered by a selection board from below the promotion zone to those officers who are determined to be exceptionally well qualified for promotion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may, by regulation, prescribe a period of time, not to exceed one year, from the time an officer is placed on the active-duty list during which the officer shall be ineligible for consideration for promotion; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> may, by regulation, preclude from consideration by a selection board by which he would otherwise be eligible to be considered, an officer who has an established separation date that is within 90 days after the date the board is convened or an approved retirement date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretaries of the military departments to preclude from consideration by selection boards for promotion to the grade of brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) officers in the grade of colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have been considered and not selected for promotion to the grade of brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) by at least two selection boards; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are determined, in accordance with standards and procedures prescribed pursuant to subparagraph (B), as not being exceptionally well qualified for promotion.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary of Defense authorizes the Secretaries of the military departments to have the authority described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall prescribe by regulation the standards and procedures for the exercise of such authority. Those regulations shall apply uniformly among the military departments and shall include the following provisions:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A requirement that the Secretary of a military department may exercise such authority in the case of a particular selection board only if the Secretary of Defense approves the exercise of that authority for that board.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A requirement that an officer may be precluded from consideration by a selection board under this paragraph only upon the recommendation of a preselection board of officers convened by the Secretary of the military department concerned and composed of at least three officers all of whom are serving in a grade higher than the grade of such officer.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A requirement that such a preselection board may not recommend that an officer be precluded from such consideration unless the Secretary concerned has given the officer advance written notice of the convening of such board and of the military records that will be considered by the board and has given the officer a reasonable period before the convening of the board in which to submit comments to the board.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> A requirement that the Secretary convening such a preselection board shall provide general guidance to the board in accordance with standards and procedures prescribed by the Secretary of Defense in those regulations.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> A requirement that the preselection board may recommend that an officer be precluded from consideration by a selection board only on the basis of the general guidance provided by the Secretary of the military department concerned, information in the officer’s official military personnel records that has been described in the notice provided the officer as required pursuant to clause (iii), and any communication to the board received from that officer before the board convenes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certain Officers Not To Be Considered</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> may not consider for promotion to the next higher grade any of the following officers:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer whose name is on a promotion list for that grade as a result of his selection for promotion to that grade by an earlier selection board convened under that section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An officer who is recommended for promotion to that grade in the report of an earlier selection board convened under that section, in the case of such a report that has not yet been approved by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An officer of the Marine Corps who is an officer designated for limited duty and who holds a grade above major.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An officer in the grade of first lieutenant or, in the case of the Navy, lieutenant (junior grade) who is on an approved all-fully-qualified-officers list under <ref>section 624(a)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An officer in the grade of captain or, in the case of the Navy, lieutenant who is not a citizen of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> An officer excluded under subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Allow Officers To Opt Out of Selection Board Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department may provide that an officer under the jurisdiction of the Secretary may, upon the officer’s request and with the approval of the Secretary, be excluded from consideration by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> to consider officers for promotion to the next higher grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned may only approve a request under paragraph (1) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the basis for the request is to allow an officer to complete a broadening assignment, advanced education, another assignment of significant value to the Department, training, or a career progression requirement delayed by the assignment, education, or training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines the exclusion from consideration is in the best interest of the military department concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the officer has not previously failed of selection for promotion to the grade for which the officer requests the exclusion from consideration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2854</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V</ref>, §§ 525(a), (b), 529(a), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2524</ref>, 2525, 2526; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1032</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XIII</ref>, §§ 1305(a), 1314(b)(4), <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1173</ref>, 1175; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title V, § 515(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1970</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 504(d)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 931(b)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1734</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1070(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2857</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 504, 505(c)(1)(A), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1085</ref>, 1087; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 501(a)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1873</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2179</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1742</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(E)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1680</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 668</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 503(b), 505(a)(1), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1868</ref>, 1869.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 619a.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for consideration for promotion: designation as joint qualified officer required before promotion to general or flag grade; exceptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Rule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer on the active-duty list of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force may not be appointed to the grade of brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) unless the officer has been designated as a joint qualified officer in accordance with <ref>section 661 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense may waive subsection (a) in the following circumstances:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When necessary for the good of the service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of an officer whose proposed selection for promotion is based primarily upon scientific and technical qualifications for which joint requirements do not exist.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a medical officer, dental officer, veterinary officer, medical service officer, nurse, or biomedical science officer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a chaplain; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a judge advocate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In the case of an officer selected by a promotion board for appointment to the grade of brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) while serving in a joint duty assignment if the officer’s total consecutive service in joint duty assignments is not less than two years and the officer has successfully completed a program of education described in subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 2155 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In the case of an officer who served in a joint duty assignment that began before <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, if the officer served in that assignment for a period of sufficient duration (which may not be less than 12 months) for the officer’s service to have been considered a full tour of duty under the policies and regulations in effect on <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver To Be Individual</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A waiver may be granted under subsection (b) only on a case-by-case basis in the case of an individual officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Rule for Good-of-the-Service Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a waiver under subsection (b)(1), the Secretary shall provide that the first duty assignment as a general or flag officer of the officer for whom the waiver is granted shall be in a joint duty assignment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Delegation of Waiver Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary of Defense to grant a waiver under subsection (b) (other than under paragraph (1) of that subsection) may be delegated only to the Deputy Secretary of Defense, an Under Secretary of Defense, or an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. The regulations shall specifically identify for purposes of subsection (b)(2) those categories of officers for which selection for promotion to brigadier general or, in the case of the Navy, rear admiral (lower half) is based primarily upon scientific and technical qualifications for which joint requirements do not exist.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation for General and Flag Officers Previously Receiving Joint Duty Assignment Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A general officer or flag officer who before <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, received a waiver of subsection (a) under the authority of this subsection (as in effect before that date) may not be appointed to the grade of lieutenant general or vice admiral until the officer completes a full tour of duty in a joint duty assignment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1732</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 508</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 591</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 525(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 533</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 521(a), (b)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4444</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(F)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 620.</num>
<heading> Active-duty lists</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the military department concerned shall maintain a single list of all officers (other than officers described in <ref>section 641 of this title</ref>) who are on active duty for each armed force under his jurisdiction (other than the Coast Guard when it is operating as a service in the Navy).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Officers shall be carried on the active-duty list of the armed force of which they are members in the order of seniority of the grade in which they are serving on active duty. Officers serving in the same grade shall be carried in the order of their rank in that grade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An officer whose position on the active-duty list results from service under a temporary appointment or in a grade held by reason of assignment to a position has, when that appointment or assignment ends, the grade and position on the active-duty list that he would have held if he had not received that appointment or assignment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the military department concerned, a reserve officer who is ordered to active duty (whether voluntarily or involuntarily) during a war or national emergency and who would otherwise be placed on the active-duty list may be excluded from that list as determined by the Secretary concerned. Exclusion of an officer from the active-duty list as the result of action by the Secretary concerned under the preceding sentence shall expire not later than 24 months after the date on which the officer enters active duty under an order to active duty covered by that sentence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2855</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1624</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2961</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 495</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 621.</num>
<heading> Competitive categories for promotion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of each military department shall establish competitive categories for promotion. Each officer whose name appears on an active-duty list shall be carried in a competitive category of officers. Officers in the same competitive category shall compete among themselves for promotion.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2856</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 622.</num>
<heading> Numbers to be recommended for promotion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before convening a selection board under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> for any grade and competitive category, the Secretary of the military department concerned, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, shall determine (1) the number of positions needed to accomplish mission objectives which require officers of such competitive category in the grade to which the board will recommend officers for promotion, (2) the estimated number of officers needed to fill vacancies in such positions during the period in which it is anticipated that officers selected for promotion will be promoted, and (3) the number of officers authorized by the Secretary of the military department concerned to serve on active duty in the grade and competitive category under consideration. Based on such determinations, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall determine the maximum number of officers in such competitive category which the selection board may recommend for promotion.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2856</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 623.</num>
<heading> Establishment of promotion zones</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Before convening a selection board under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> to consider officers for promotion to any grade above first lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade), the Secretary of the military department concerned shall establish a promotion zone for officers serving in each grade and competitive category to be considered by the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall determine the number of officers in the promotion zone for officers serving in any grade and competitive category from among officers who are eligible for promotion in that grade and competitive category. Such determination shall be made on the basis of an estimate of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of officers needed in that competitive category in the next higher grade in each of the next five years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of officers to be serving in that competitive category in the next higher grade in each of the next five years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of a promotion zone for officers to be promoted to a grade to which <ref>section 523 of this title</ref> is applicable, the number of officers authorized for such grade under such section to be on active duty on the last day of each of the next five fiscal years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the number of officers that should be placed in that promotion zone in each of the next five years to provide to officers in those years relatively similar opportunity for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2856</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 624.</num>
<heading> Promotions: how made</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When the report of a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> is approved by the President, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall place the names of all officers approved for promotion within a competitive category on a single list for that competitive category, to be known as a promotion list, in the order of the seniority of such officers on the active-duty list or based on particular merit, as determined by the promotion board. A promotion list is considered to be established under this section as of the date of the approval of the report of the selection board under the preceding sentence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (d), officers on a promotion list for a competitive category shall be promoted to the next higher grade when additional officers in that grade and competitive category are needed. Promotions shall be made in the order in which the names of officers appear on the promotion list and after officers previously selected for promotion in that competitive category have been promoted. Officers to be promoted to the grade of first lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade) shall be promoted in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (d), officers on the active-duty list in the grade of first lieutenant or, in the case of the Navy, lieutenant (junior grade) who are on an approved all-fully-qualified-officers list shall be promoted to the next higher grade in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An all-fully-qualified-officers list shall be considered to be approved for purposes of subparagraph (A) when the list is approved by the President. When so approved, such a list shall be treated in the same manner as a promotion list under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department may make a recommendation to the President for approval of an all-fully-qualified-officers list only when the Secretary determines that all officers on the list are needed in the next higher grade to accomplish mission objectives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this paragraph, an all-fully-qualified-officers list is a list of all officers on the active-duty list in a grade who the Secretary of the military department concerned determines—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are fully qualified for promotion to the next higher grade; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> would be eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> upon the convening of such a board.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that one or more officers or former officers were not placed on an all-fully-qualified-list under this paragraph because of administrative error, the Secretary may prepare a supplemental all-fully-qualified-officers list containing the names of any such officers for approval in accordance with this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A regular officer who is promoted under this section is appointed in the regular grade to which promoted and a reserve officer who is promoted under this section is appointed in the reserve grade to which promoted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The date of rank of an officer appointed to a higher grade under this section is determined under <ref>section 741(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Appointments under this section shall be made by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, except that appointments under this section in the grade of first lieutenant or captain, in the case of officers of the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force, or lieutenant (junior grade) or lieutenant, in the case of officers of the Navy, shall be made by the President alone.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the appointment of an officer under this section may be delayed if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sworn charges against the officer have been received by an officer exercising general court-martial jurisdiction over the officer and such charges have not been disposed of;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an investigation is being conducted to determine whether disciplinary action of any kind should be brought against the officer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a board of officers has been convened under chapter 60 of this title to review the record of the officer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a criminal proceeding in a Federal or State court is pending against the officer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> substantiated adverse information about the officer that is material to the decision to appoint the officer is under review by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary concerned; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that credible information of an adverse nature, including a substantiated adverse finding or conclusion described in <ref>section 615(a)(3)(A) of this title</ref>, with respect to the officer will result in the convening of a special selection review board under <ref>section 628a of this title</ref> to review the officer and recommend whether the recommendation for promotion of the officer should be sustained.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">If no disciplinary action is taken against the officer, if the charges against the officer are withdrawn or dismissed, if the officer is not ordered removed from active duty by the Secretary concerned under chapter 60 of this title, if the officer is acquitted of the charges brought against him, or if, after a review of substantiated adverse information about the officer regarding the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 7233, 8167, or 9233 of this title, as applicable, the officer is determined to be among the officers best qualified for promotion, as the case may be, then unless action to delay an appointment has also been taken under paragraph (2) the officer shall be retained on the promotion list (including an approved all-fully-qualified-officers list, if applicable) and shall, upon promotion to the next higher grade, have the same date of rank, the same effective date for the pay and allowances of the grade to which promoted, and the same position on the active-duty list as he would have had if no delay had intervened, unless the Secretary concerned determines that the officer was unqualified for promotion for any part of the delay. If the Secretary makes such a determination, the Secretary may adjust such date of rank, effective date of pay and allowances, and position on the active-duty list as the Secretary considers appropriate under the circumstances.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the appointment of an officer under this section may also be delayed in any case in which there is cause to believe that the officer has not met the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 7233, 8167, or 9233 of this title, as applicable, or is mentally, physically, morally, or professionally unqualified to perform the duties of the grade for which he was selected for promotion. If it is later determined by a civilian official of the Department of Defense (not below the level of Secretary of a military department) that the officer is qualified for promotion to such grade and, after a review of adverse information regarding the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 7233, 8167, or 9233 of this title, as applicable, the officer is determined to be among the officers best qualified for promotion to such grade, the officer shall be retained on the promotion list (including an approved all-fully-qualified-officers list, if applicable) and shall, upon such promotion, have the same date of rank, the same effective date for pay and allowances in the higher grade to which appointed, and the same position on the active-duty list as he would have had if no delay had intervened, unless the Secretary concerned determines that the officer was unqualified for promotion for any part of the delay. If the Secretary makes such a determination, the Secretary may adjust such date of rank, effective date of pay and allowances, and position on the active-duty list as the Secretary considers appropriate under the circumstances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of an officer whose promotion is delayed pursuant to paragraph (1)(F) and whose recommendation for promotion is sustained, authorities for the promotion of the officer are specified in <ref>section 628a(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the appointment of an officer may not be delayed under this subsection unless the officer has been given written notice of the grounds for the delay, unless it is impracticable to give such written notice before the effective date of the appointment, in which case such written notice shall be given as soon as practicable. An officer whose promotion has been delayed under this subsection shall be afforded an opportunity to make a written statement to the Secretary concerned in response to the action taken. Any such statement shall be given careful consideration by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of an officer whose promotion is delayed pursuant to paragraph (1)(F), requirements applicable to notice and opportunity for response to such delay are specified in <ref>section 628a(c)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An appointment of an officer may not be delayed under this subsection for more than six months after the date on which the officer would otherwise have been appointed unless the Secretary concerned specifies a further period of delay. An officer’s appointment may not be delayed more than 90 days after final action has been taken in any criminal case against such officer in a Federal or State court, more than 90 days after final action has been taken in any court-martial case against such officer, or more than 18 months after the date on which such officer would otherwise have been appointed, whichever is later.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a)(2), in the case of an officer who is selected for promotion by a selection board convened under this chapter, and prior to the placement of the officer’s name on the applicable promotion list as approved for transfer to the reserve active-status list of the same or a different armed force, the Secretary concerned may place the officer’s name on a corresponding promotion list on the reserve active-status list without regard to the officer’s competitive category. An officer’s promotion under this subsection shall be made pursuant to <ref>section 14308 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a)(3), in the case of an officer who is placed on an all-fully-qualified-officers list, and is subsequently approved for transfer to the reserve active-status list, the Secretary concerned may place the officer’s name on an appropriate all-fully-qualified-officers list on the reserve active-status list. An officer’s promotion under this subsection shall be made pursuant to <ref>section 14308 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2857</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(d)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(8)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 526</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2525</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 505(a)(1)</ref>, (c)(2)(A), (d)(1), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1085</ref>, 1087, 1088; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1062(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2649</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2181</ref>, 2183; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1063(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 322</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 504(c)</ref>, title VIII, § 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1742</ref>, 1840; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 505(a)(3)</ref>, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(G), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3568</ref>, 3821; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 503(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 625.</num>
<heading> Authority to vacate promotions to grades of brigadier general and rear admiral (lower half)</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President may vacate the promotion to the grade of brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) of an officer who has served less than 18 months in that grade after promotion to that grade under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps whose promotion is vacated under this section holds the regular grade of colonel, if he is a regular officer, or the reserve grade of colonel, if he is a reserve officer. An officer of the Navy whose promotion is vacated under this section holds the regular grade of captain, if he is a regular officer, or the reserve grade of captain, if he is a reserve officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The position on the active-duty list of an officer whose promotion is vacated under this section is the position he would have held had he not been promoted to the grade of brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2858</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, (4)(A), <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, (4)(A), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(H)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 668</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 626.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of promotions; oath of office</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An officer who is appointed to a higher grade under <ref>section 624 of this title</ref> is considered to have accepted such appointment on the date on which the appointment is made unless he expressly declines the appointment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An officer who has served continuously since he subscribed to the oath of office prescribed in <ref>section 3331 of title 5</ref> is not required to take a new oath upon appointment to a higher grade under <ref>section 624 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2858</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>FAILURE OF SELECTION FOR PROMOTION AND RETIREMENT FOR YEARS OF SERVICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 627.</num>
<heading> Failure of selection for promotion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An officer in a grade below the grade of colonel or, in the case of an officer of the Navy, captain who is in or above the promotion zone established for his grade and competitive category under <ref>section 623 of this title</ref> and is considered but not selected for promotion by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> shall be considered to have failed of selection for promotion.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2859</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 628.</num>
<heading> Special selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Persons Not Considered by Promotion Boards Due to Administrative Error</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that because of administrative error a person who should have been considered for selection for promotion from in or above the promotion zone by a promotion board was not so considered, the Secretary shall convene a special selection board under this subsection to determine whether that person (whether or not then on active duty) should be recommended for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A special selection board convened under paragraph (1) shall consider the record of the person whose name was referred to it for consideration as that record would have appeared to the board that should have considered him. That record shall be compared with a sampling of the records of those officers of the same competitive category who were recommended for promotion, and those officers who were not recommended for promotion, by the board that should have considered him.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If a special selection board convened under paragraph (1) does not recommend for promotion a person whose name was referred to it for consideration for selection for appointment to a grade other than a general officer or flag officer grade, the person shall be considered to have failed of selection for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Persons Considered by Promotion Boards in Unfair Manner</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary of the military department concerned determines, in the case of a person who was considered for selection for promotion by a promotion board but was not selected, that there was material unfairness with respect to that person, the Secretary may convene a special selection board under this subsection to determine whether that person (whether or not then on active duty) should be recommended for promotion. In order to determine that there was material unfairness, the Secretary must determine that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the action of the promotion board that considered the person was contrary to law in a matter material to the decision of the board or involved material error of fact or material administrative error; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the board did not have before it for its consideration material information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A special selection board convened under paragraph (1) shall consider the record of the person whose name was referred to it for consideration as that record, if corrected, would have appeared to the board that considered him. That record shall be compared with the records of a sampling of those officers of the same competitive category who were recommended for promotion, and those officers who were not recommended for promotion, by the board that considered him.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If a special selection board convened under paragraph (1) does not recommend for promotion a person whose name was referred to it for consideration, the person incurs no additional failure of selection for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports of Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each special selection board convened under this section shall submit to the Secretary of the military department concerned a written report, signed by each member of the board, containing the name of each person it recommends for promotion and certifying that the board has carefully considered the record of each person whose name was referred to it.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The provisions of sections 617(b) and 618 of this title apply to the report and proceedings of a special selection board convened under this section in the same manner as they apply to the report and proceedings of a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref>. However, in the case of a board convened under this section to consider a warrant officer or former warrant officer, the provisions of sections 576(d), 576(f), and 613a of this title (rather than the provisions of sections 617(b) and 618 of this title) apply to the report and proceedings of the board in the same manner as they apply to the report and proceedings of a selection board convened under <ref>section 573 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment of Persons Selected by Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the report of a special selection board convened under this section, as approved by the President, recommends for promotion to the next higher grade a person whose name was referred to it for consideration, that person shall, as soon as practicable, be appointed to that grade in accordance with subsections (b), (c), and (d) of <ref>section 624 of this title</ref>. However, in the case of a board convened under this section to consider a warrant officer or former warrant officer, if the report of that board, as approved by the Secretary concerned, recommends that warrant officer or former warrant officer for promotion to the next higher grade, that person shall, as soon as practicable, be appointed to the next higher grade in accordance with provisions of <ref>section 578(c) of this title</ref> (rather than subsections (b), (c), and (d) of <ref>section 624 of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person who is appointed to the next higher grade as the result of the recommendation of a special selection board convened under this section shall, upon that appointment, have the same date of rank, the same effective date for the pay and allowances of that grade, and the same position on the active-duty list as he would have had if he had been recommended for promotion to that grade by the board which should have considered, or which did consider, him. In the case of a person who is not on the active-duty list when appointed to the next higher grade, placement of that person on the active-duty list pursuant to the preceding sentence shall be only for purposes of determination of eligibility of that person for consideration for promotion by any subsequent special selection board under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deceased Persons</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a person whose name is being considered for referral to a special selection board under this section dies before the completion of proceedings under this section with respect to that person, this section shall be applied to that person posthumously.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Convening of Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A board convened under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be convened under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be composed in accordance with <ref>section 612 of this title</ref> or, in the case of board to consider a warrant officer or former warrant officer, in accordance with <ref>section 573 of this title</ref> and regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the military department concerned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be subject to the provisions of <ref>section 613 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Judicial Review</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A court of the United States may review a determination by the Secretary of a military department under subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1) not to convene a special selection board in the case of any person. In any such case, the court may set aside the Secretary’s determination only if the court finds the determination to be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> arbitrary or capricious;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not based on substantial evidence;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a result of material error of fact or material administrative error; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> otherwise contrary to law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If a court sets aside a determination by the Secretary of a military department not to convene a special selection board under this section, it shall remand the case to the Secretary concerned, who shall provide for consideration by such a board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A court of the United States may review the action of a special selection board convened under this section or an action of the Secretary of the military department concerned on the report of such a board. In any such case, a court may set aside the action only if the court finds that the action was—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> arbitrary or capricious;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not based on substantial evidence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a result of material error of fact or material administrative error; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> otherwise contrary to law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If, six months after receiving a complete application for consideration by a special selection board under this section in any case, the Secretary concerned has not convened such a board and has not denied consideration by such a board in that case, the Secretary shall be deemed for the purposes of this subsection to have denied the consideration of the case by such a board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If, six months after the convening of a special selection board under this section in any case, the Secretary concerned has not taken final action on the report of the board, the Secretary shall be deemed for the purposes of this subsection to have denied relief in such case.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed under subsection (j), the Secretary of a military department may waive the applicability of subparagraph (A) or (B) in a case if the Secretary determines that a longer period for consideration of the case is warranted. Such a waiver may be for an additional period of not more than six months. The Secretary concerned may not delegate authority to make a determination under this subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations of Other Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No official or court of the United States may, with respect to a claim based to any extent on the failure of a person to be selected for promotion by a promotion board—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consider the claim unless the person has first been referred by the Secretary concerned to a special selection board convened under this section and acted upon by that board and the report of the board has been approved by the President; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> except as provided in subsection (g), grant any relief on the claim unless the person has been selected for promotion by a special selection board convened under this section to consider the person for recommendation for promotion and the report of the board has been approved by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Existing Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section limits—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the jurisdiction of any court of the United States under any provision of law to determine the validity of any law, regulation, or policy relating to selection boards; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the authority of the Secretary of a military department to correct a military record under <ref>section 1552 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of each military department shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Regulations under this subsection may not apply to subsection (g), other than to paragraph (3)(C) of that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may prescribe in the regulations under paragraph (1) the circumstances under which consideration by a special selection board may be provided for under this section, including the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The circumstances under which consideration of a person’s case by a special selection board is contingent upon application by or for that person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any time limits applicable to the filing of an application for such consideration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Regulations prescribed by the Secretary of a military department under this subsection may not take effect until approved by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Promotion Board Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “promotion board” means a selection board convened by the Secretary of a military department under section 573(a) or 611(a) of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2859</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 527(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2525</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1131(4)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1506</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(10)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 501(a)</ref>–(e), <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2000–2002</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1087(a)(2)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–290; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 503(b), 505(c)(3)(A), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1083</ref>, 1088; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 514(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2185</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 503(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4208</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 502(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 807</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 628a.</num>
<heading> Special selection review boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that a person recommended by a promotion board for promotion to a grade at or below the grade of major general or rear admiral in the Navy is the subject of credible information of an adverse nature, including any substantiated adverse finding or conclusion described in <ref>section 615(a)(3)(A) of this title</ref>, that was not furnished to the promotion board during its consideration of the person for promotion as otherwise required by such section, the Secretary shall convene a special selection review board under this section to review the person and recommend whether the recommendation for promotion of the person should be sustained.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent a Secretary concerned from deferring consideration of adverse information concerning an officer subject to this section until the next regularly scheduled promotion board applicable to such officer, in lieu of furnishing such adverse information to a special selection review board under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If a person and the recommendation for promotion of the person is subject to review under this section by a special selection review board convened under this section, the name of the person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall not be disseminated or publicly released on the list of officers recommended for promotion by the promotion board recommending the promotion of the person; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall not be forwarded for appointment or nomination to the Secretary of Defense, the President, or the Senate, as applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Convening</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any special selection review board convened under this section shall be convened in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 628(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any special selection review board convened under this section may review such number of persons, and recommendations for promotion of such persons, as the Secretary of the military department concerned shall specify in convening such special selection review board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information Considered</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In reviewing a person and recommending whether the recommendation for promotion of the person should be sustained under this section, a special selection review board convened under this section shall be furnished and consider the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The record and information concerning the person furnished in accordance with <ref>section 615(a)(2) of this title</ref> to the promotion board that recommended the person for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any credible information of an adverse nature on the person, including any substantiated adverse finding or conclusion from an officially documented investigation or inquiry described in <ref>section 615(a)(3)(A) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The furnishing of information to a special selection review board under paragraph (1)(B) shall be governed by the standards and procedures referred to in paragraph (3)(C) of <ref>section 615(a) of this title</ref> applicable to the furnishing of information described in paragraph (3)(A) of such section to selection boards in accordance with that section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Before information on a person described in paragraph (1)(B) is furnished to a special selection review board for purposes of this section, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such information is made available to the person; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> subject to subparagraphs (C) and (D), the person is afforded a reasonable opportunity to submit comments on such information to the special selection review board before its review of the person and the recommendation for promotion of the person under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If information on a person described in paragraph (1)(B) is not made available to the person as otherwise required by subparagraph (A)(i) due to the classification status of such information, the person shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be furnished a summary of such information appropriate to the person’s authorization for access to classified information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> An opportunity to submit comments on information is not required for a person under subparagraph (A)(ii) if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> such information was made available to the person in connection with the furnishing of such information under <ref>section 615(a) of this title</ref> to the promotion board that recommended the promotion of the person subject to review under this section; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the person submitted comments on such information to that promotion board.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The comments on information of a person described in clause (i)(II) shall be furnished to the special selection review board.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> A person may waive either or both of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The right to submit comments to a special selection review board under subparagraph (A)(ii).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The furnishing of comments to a special selection review board under subparagraph (C)(ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In considering the record and information on a person under this section, the special selection review board shall compare such record and information with an appropriate sampling of the records of those officers of the same competitive category who were recommended for promotion by the promotion board that recommended the person for promotion, and an appropriate sampling of the records of those officers who were considered by and not recommended for promotion by that promotion board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Records and information shall be presented to a special selection review board for purposes of paragraph (1) in a manner that does not indicate or disclose the person or persons for whom the special selection review board was convened.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In considering whether the recommendation for promotion of a person should be sustained under this section, a special selection review board shall, to the greatest extent practicable, apply standards used by the promotion board that recommended the person for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The recommendation for promotion of a person may be sustained under this section only if the special selection review board determines that the person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ranks in the upper half of an order of merit created by the special selection review board or ranks on an order of merit created by the special selection review board as better qualified for promotion than the sample officer highest on the order of merit list who was considered by and not recommended for promotion by the promotion board concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is comparable in qualification for promotion to those sample officers who were recommended for promotion by that promotion board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A recommendation for promotion of a person may be sustained under this section only by a vote of a majority of the members of the special selection review board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> If a special selection review board does not sustain a recommendation for promotion of a person under this section, the person shall be considered to have failed of selection for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each special selection review board convened under this section shall submit to the Secretary of the military department concerned a written report, signed by each member of the board, containing the name of each person whose recommendation for promotion it recommends for sustainment and certifying that the board has carefully considered the record and information of each person whose name was referred to it.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The provisions of sections 617(b) and 618 of this title apply to the report and proceedings of a special selection review board convened under this section in the same manner as they apply to the report and proceedings of a promotion board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref>. However, in the case of an officer on the Space Force officer list, the provisions of sections 618, 20215, and 20216 of this title apply to the report and proceedings of a special selection review board convened under this section in the same manner as they apply to the report and proceedings of a promotion board convened under <ref>section 20211 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment of Persons</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the report of a special selection review board convened under this section recommends the sustainment of the recommendation for promotion to the next higher grade of a person whose name was referred to it for review under this section, and the President approves the report, the person shall, as soon as practicable, be appointed to that grade in accordance with subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 624 of this title</ref>. However, if the report of a special selection review board convened under this section recommends the sustainment of the recommendation for promotion to the next higher grade of an officer on the Space Force officer list who was referred to it for review under this section, and the President approves the report, the officer shall, as soon as practicable, be appointed to the grade in accordance with subsections (b) and (c) of <ref>section 20252 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person who is appointed to the next higher grade as described in paragraph (1) shall, upon that appointment, have the same date of rank, the same effective date for the pay and allowances of that grade, and the same position on the active-duty list as the person would have had pursuant to the original recommendation for promotion of the promotion board concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Such regulations shall apply uniformly across the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any regulation prescribed by the Secretary of a military department to supplement the regulations prescribed pursuant to paragraph (1) may not take effect without the approval of the Secretary of Defense, in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Promotion Board Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “promotion board” means a selection board convened by the Secretary of a military department under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 505(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3565</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 521</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 507(a)</ref>, title XVII, § 1722(b)(5), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 242</ref>, 668; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(a)(15), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1870</ref>, 2203.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 629.</num>
<heading> Removal from a list of officers recommended for promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal by President</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may remove the name of any officer from a list of officers recommended for promotion by a selection board convened under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal Due to Senate Not Giving Advice and Consent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, after consideration of a list of officers approved for promotion by the President to a grade for which appointment is required by <ref>section 624(c) of this title</ref> to be made by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, the Senate does not give its advice and consent to the appointment of an officer whose name is on the list, that officer’s name shall be removed from the list.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal After</inline> 18 <inline class="small-caps">Months</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If an officer whose name is on a list of officers approved for promotion under <ref>section 624(a) of this title</ref> to a grade for which appointment is required by <ref>section 624(c) of this title</ref> to be made by and with the advice and consent of the Senate is not appointed to that grade under such section during the officer’s promotion eligibility period, the officer’s name shall be removed from the list unless as of the end of such period the Senate has given its advice and consent to the appointment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Before the end of the promotion eligibility period with respect to an officer under paragraph (1), the President may extend that period for purposes of paragraph (1) by an additional 12 months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) does not apply when the military department concerned is not able to obtain and provide to the Senate the information the Senate requires to give its advice and consent to the appointment concerned because that information is under the control of a department or agency of the Federal Government other than the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “promotion eligibility period” means, with respect to an officer whose name is on a list of officers approved for promotion under <ref>section 624(a) of this title</ref> to a grade for which appointment is required by <ref>section 624(c) of this title</ref> to be made by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, the period beginning on the date on which the list is so approved and ending on the first day of the eighteenth month following the month during which the list is so approved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative Removal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, if an officer on the active-duty list is discharged or dropped from the rolls or transferred to a retired status after having been recommended for promotion to a higher grade under this chapter, but before being promoted, the officer’s name shall be administratively removed from the list of officers recommended for promotion by a selection board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continued Eligibility for Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer whose name is removed from a list under subsection (a), (b), or (c) continues to be eligible for consideration for promotion. If he is recommended for promotion by the next selection board convened for his grade and competitive category and he is promoted, the Secretary of the military department concerned may, upon such promotion, grant him the same date of rank, the same effective date for the pay and allowances of the grade to which promoted, and the same position on the active-duty list as he would have had if his name had not been so removed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If such an officer who is in a grade below the grade of colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain is not recommended for promotion by the next selection board convened for his grade and competitive category, or if his name is again removed from the list of officers recommended for promotion, or if the Senate again does not give its advice and consent to his promotion, he shall be considered for all purposes to have twice failed of selection for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2860</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 515(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2185</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1063(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 321</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4208</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2107</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 630.</num>
<heading> Discharge of commissioned officers with less than six years of active commissioned service or found not qualified for promotion for first lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade)</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the military department concerned, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> may discharge any officer on the active-duty list who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has less than six years of active commissioned service; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is serving in the grade of second lieutenant or ensign and has been found not qualified for promotion to the grade of first lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall, unless the officer has been promoted, discharge any officer described in paragraph (1)(B) at the end of the 18-month period beginning on the date on which the officer is first found not qualified for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2861</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(11)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 505(d)(2)</ref>, (4)(A), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1088</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 505(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1457</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 503(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 95</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 631.</num>
<heading> Effect of failure of selection for promotion: first lieutenants and lieutenants (junior grade)</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except an officer of the Navy and Marine Corps who is an officer designated for limited duty (to whom section 8146(e) or 8372 of this title applies), each officer of the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force on the active-duty list who holds the grade of first lieutenant and has failed of selection for promotion to the grade of captain for the second time, and each officer of the Navy on the active-duty list who holds the grade of lieutenant (junior grade) and has failed of selection for promotion to the grade of lieutenant for the second time, whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the next higher grade shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be discharged on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary of the military department concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if he is eligible for retirement under any provision of law, be retired under that law on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if on the date on which he is to be discharged under paragraph (1) he is within two years of qualifying for retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title, be retained on active duty until he is qualified for retirement and then be retired under that section, unless he is sooner retired or discharged under another provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The retirement or discharge of an officer pursuant to this section shall be considered to be an involuntary retirement or discharge for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An officer who is subject to discharge under subsection (a)(1) is not eligible for further consideration for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this chapter, an officer of the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force who holds the grade of first lieutenant, and an officer of the Navy who holds the grade of lieutenant (junior grade), shall be treated as having failed of selection for promotion if the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the officer would be eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> if such a board were convened but is not fully qualified for promotion when recommending for promotion under <ref>section 624(a)(3) of this title</ref> all fully qualified officers of the officer’s armed force in such grade who would be eligible for such consideration.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2861</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 525(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2525</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 505(a)(2)</ref>, (d)(3), (4)(B), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1086</ref>, 1088; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 505(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1457</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(I)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 505(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 632.</num>
<heading> Effect of failure of selection for promotion: captains and majors of the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force and lieutenants and lieutenant commanders of the Navy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except an officer of the Navy and Marine Corps who is an officer designated for limited duty (to whom section 8146(e) or 8372 of this title applies) and except as provided under <ref>section 637(a) of this title</ref>, each officer of the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force on the active-duty list who holds the grade of captain or major, and each officer of the Navy on the active-duty list who holds the grade of lieutenant or lieutenant commander, who has failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade for the second time and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the next higher grade shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> except as provided in paragraph (3) and in subsection (c), be discharged on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if he is eligible for retirement under any provision of law, be retired under that law on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if on the date on which he is to be discharged under paragraph (1) he is within two years of qualifying for retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title, be retained on active duty until he is qualified for retirement and then retired under that section, unless he is sooner retired or discharged under another provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The retirement or discharge of an officer pursuant to this section shall be considered to be an involuntary retirement or discharge for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If an officer is subject to discharge under subsection (a)(1) and, as of the date on which the officer is to be discharged under that subsection, the officer has not completed the officer’s active duty service obligation, the officer shall be retained on active duty until completion of such active duty service obligation, and then be discharged under subsection (a)(1), unless sooner retired or discharged under another provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may waive the applicability of paragraph (1) to any officer if the Secretary determines that completion of the active duty service obligation of that officer is not in the best interest of the service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2862</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 505(d)(3)</ref>, (4)(C), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1088</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1457</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2061</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(J)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 508(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 505(b)(2), 507, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1869</ref>, 1871.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 633.</num>
<heading> Retirement for years of service: regular and Space Force lieutenant colonels; regular Navy commanders</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading> 28 <inline class="small-caps">Years of Active Commissioned Service</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b) and as provided under section 637(b) or 637a of this title, each officer of the Regular Army, Regular Air Force, or Regular Marine Corps who holds the regular grade of lieutenant colonel, and each officer of the Regular Navy who holds the regular grade of commander, who is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the regular grade of colonel or captain, respectively, shall, if not earlier retired, be retired on the first day of the month after the month in which he completes 28 years of active commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided under section 637(b) or 637a of this title, each officer of the Space Force who holds the grade of lieutenant colonel who is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the grade of colonel shall, if not earlier retired, be retired on the first day of the month after the month in which the officer completes 28 years of active commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) does not apply to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer of the Navy or Marine Corps who is an officer designated for limited duty to whom section 8146(e) or 8372 of this title applies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An officer of the Navy or Marine Corps who is a permanent professor at the United States Naval Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2862</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 529(b)</ref>, title XIV, § 1405(12), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2526</ref>, 2622; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2403</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 561(e)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1667</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2004</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 509(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3229</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 505(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(4)(D)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(b)(6)(A)</ref>, (E)(i), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 669</ref>, 670.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 634.</num>
<heading> Retirement for years of service: regular and Space Force colonels; regular Navy captains</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading> 30 <inline class="small-caps">Years of Active Commissioned Service</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b) and as provided under section 637(b) or 637a of this title, each officer of the Regular Army, Regular Air Force, or Regular Marine Corps who holds the regular grade of colonel, and each officer of the Regular Navy who holds the regular grade of captain, who is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the regular grade of brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half), respectively, shall, if not earlier retired, be retired on the first day of the month after the month in which he completes 30 years of active commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided under section 637(b) or 637a of this title, each officer of the Space Force who holds the grade of colonel who is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the grade of brigadier general shall, if not earlier retired, be retired on the first day of the month after the month in which the officer completes 30 years of active commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) does not apply to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer of the Navy who is designated for limited duty to whom <ref>section 8372(a)(4) of this title</ref> applies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An officer of the Navy or Marine Corps who is a permanent professor at the United States Naval Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2862</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(13)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title V, § 504(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2403</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 561(e)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1667</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 504(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2004</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 509(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3229</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 505(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(4)(E)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(b)(6)(B)</ref>, (E)(ii), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 669</ref>, 670.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 635.</num>
<heading> Retirement for years of service: regular and Space Force brigadier generals; regular Navy rear admirals (lower half)</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided under section 637(b) or 637a of this title, each officer of the Regular Army, Regular Air Force, or Regular Marine Corps who holds the regular grade of brigadier general, and each officer of the Regular Navy who holds the regular grade of rear admiral (lower half), who is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the regular grade of major general or rear admiral, respectively, shall, if not earlier retired, be retired on the first day of the first month beginning after the date of the fifth anniversary of his appointment to that grade or on the first day of the month after the month in which he completes 30 years of active commissioned service, whichever is later.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Space Force</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided under section 637(b) or 637a of this title, each officer of the Space Force who holds the grade of brigadier general who is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the grade of major general shall, if not earlier retired, be retired as specified in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2863</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, (5)(A), <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>, 1106; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(13)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, (5)(A), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 505(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(4)(F)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(b)(6)(C)</ref>, (E)(iii), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 669</ref>, 670.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 636.</num>
<heading> Retirement for years of service: regular and Space Force officers in grades above brigadier general; regular Navy officers in grades above rear admiral (lower half)</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major Generals and Rear Admirals Serving in Grade</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b) or (c) and under section 637(b) or 637a of this title, each officer of the Regular Army, Regular Air Force, or Regular Marine Corps who holds the regular grade of major general, and each officer of the Regular Navy who holds the regular grade of rear admiral, shall, if not earlier retired, be retired on the first day of the first month beginning after the date of the fifth anniversary of his appointment to that grade or on the first day of the month after the month in which he completes 35 years of active commissioned service, whichever is later.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b) or (c) and under section 637(b) or 637a of this title, each officer of the Space Force who holds the grade of major general shall, if not earlier retired, be retired as specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lieutenant Generals and Vice Admirals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the administration of subsection (a) in the case of an officer who is serving in the grade of lieutenant general or vice admiral, the number of years of active commissioned service applicable to the officer is 38 years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Generals and Admirals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the administration of subsection (a) in the case of an officer who is serving in the grade of general or admiral, the number of years of active commissioned service applicable to the officer is 40 years.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2863</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(14)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1726</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 505(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(4)(G)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(b)(6)(D)</ref>, (E)(iv), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 669</ref>, 670.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>CONTINUATION ON ACTIVE DUTY AND SELECTIVE EARLY RETIREMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 637.</num>
<heading> Selection of regular officers for continuation on active duty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer subject to discharge or retirement in accordance with <ref>section 632 of this title</ref> may, subject to the needs of the service, be continued on active duty if he is selected for continuation on active duty by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An officer who holds the regular grade of captain in the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force, or the regular grade of lieutenant in the Navy, and who is subject to discharge or retirement in accordance with <ref>section 632 of this title</ref> may not be continued on active duty under this subsection for a period which extends beyond the last day of the month in which he completes 20 years of active commissioned service unless he is promoted to the regular grade of major or lieutenant commander, respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An officer who holds the regular grade of major or lieutenant commander who is subject to discharge or retirement in accordance with <ref>section 632 of this title</ref> may not be continued on active duty under this subsection for a period which extends beyond the last day of the month in which he completes 24 years of active commissioned service unless he is promoted to the regular grade of lieutenant colonel or commander, respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An officer who is selected for continuation on active duty under this subsection but declines to continue on active duty shall be discharged, retired, or retained on active duty, as appropriate, in accordance with <ref>section 632 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Each officer who is continued on active duty under this subsection, is not subsequently promoted or continued on active duty, and is not on a list of officers recommended for continuation or for promotion to the next higher regular grade shall, unless sooner retired or discharged under another provision of law—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be discharged upon the expiration of his period of continued service; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if he is eligible for retirement under any provision of law, be retired under that law on the first day of the first month following the month in which he completes his period of continued service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of clause (A), any officer who would otherwise be discharged under such clause and is within two years of qualifying for retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title, shall unless he is sooner retired or discharged under some other provision of law, be retained on active duty until he is qualified for retirement under that section and then be retired.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The retirement or discharge of an officer pursuant to this subsection shall be considered to be an involuntary retirement or discharge for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer subject to retirement under section 633 or 634 of this title may, subject to the needs of the service, have his retirement deferred and be continued on active duty if he is selected for continuation on active duty by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An officer subject to retirement under section 635 or 636 of this title who is serving in the grade of brigadier general, rear admiral (lower half), major general, or rear admiral may, subject to the needs of the service, have his retirement deferred and be continued on active duty by the Secretary concerned. An officer subject to retirement under section 635 or 636 of this title who is serving in a grade above major general or rear admiral may have his retirement deferred and be continued on active duty by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any deferral of retirement and continuation on active duty under this subsection shall be for a period not to exceed five years, except as provided under section 1251 or 1253 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Continuation of an officer on active duty under this section pursuant to the action of a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> is subject to the approval of the Secretary of the military department concerned. The period of the continuation on active duty of an officer under this section may be reduced by the Secretary concerned in the case of any officer as provided in <ref>section 638a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, a period of continuation on active duty under this section expires or is completed on the earlier of (1) the date originally established for the termination of such period, or (2) the date established for the termination of such period by any shortening of such period under <ref>section 638a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2863</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(e)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 127</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(15)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 521(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1561</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 95</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(K)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 637a.</num>
<heading> Continuation on active duty: officers in certain military specialties and career tracks</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the military department concerned may authorize an officer in a grade above grade O–2 to remain on active duty after the date otherwise provided for the separation or retirement of the officer in section 632, 633, 634, 635, or 636 of this title, as applicable, if the officer has a military occupational specialty, rating, or specialty code in a military specialty designated pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Military Specialties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Secretary of a military department shall designate the military specialties in which a military occupational specialty, rating, or specialty code, as applicable, assigned to members of the armed forces under the jurisdiction of such Secretary authorizes the members to be eligible for continuation on active duty as provided in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration of Continuation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer continued on active duty pursuant to this section shall, if not earlier retired, be retired on the first day of the month after the month in which the officer completes 40 years of active service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretaries of the military departments shall carry out this section in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. The regulations shall specify the criteria to be used by the Secretaries of the military departments in designating military specialties for purposes of subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 505(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2107</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 506</ref>, title X, § 1081(a)(8), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1743</ref>, 1983; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1345</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 638.</num>
<heading> Selective early retirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A regular officer on the active-duty list of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force may be considered for selective early retirement by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> if the officer is described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (D) as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An officer holding the regular grade of lieutenant colonel or commander who has failed of selection for promotion to the grade of colonel or, in the case of an officer of the Navy, captain two or more times and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An officer holding the regular grade of colonel or, in the case of an officer of the Navy, captain who has served at least four years of active duty in that grade and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An officer holding the regular grade of brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) who has served at least three and one-half years of active duty in that grade and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> An officer holding the regular grade of major general or rear admiral who has served at least three and one-half years of active duty in that grade.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the military department concerned shall specify the number of officers described in paragraphs (1)(A) and (1)(B) which a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> may recommend for early retirement. Such number may not be more than 30 percent of the number of officers considered in each grade in each competitive category.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A regular officer on the active-duty list of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force may also be considered for early retirement under the circumstances prescribed in <ref>section 638a of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An officer in a grade below brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) who is recommended for early retirement under this section or <ref>section 638a of this title</ref> and whose early retirement is approved by the Secretary concerned shall be retired, under any provision of law under which he is eligible to retire, on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If an officer described in subparagraph (A) is not eligible for retirement under any provision of law, the officer shall be retained on active duty until the officer is qualified for retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title, and then be retired under that section, unless the officer is sooner retired or discharged under some other provision of law, with such retirement under that section occurring not later than the later of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The first day of the month beginning after the month in which the officer becomes qualified for retirement under that section.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An officer who holds the regular grade of brigadier general, major general, rear admiral (lower half), or rear admiral who is recommended for early retirement under this section and whose early retirement is approved by the Secretary concerned shall be retired, under any provision of law under which he is eligible to retire, on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the tenth calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approved the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may defer for not more than three months the retirement of an officer otherwise approved for early retirement under this section or <ref>section 638a of this title</ref> in order to prevent a personal hardship to the officer or for other humanitarian reasons. Any such deferral shall be made on a case-by-case basis considering the circumstances of the case of the particular officer concerned. The authority of the Secretary to grant such a deferral may not be delegated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An officer recommended for early retirement under paragraph (1)(A) or <ref>section 638a of this title</ref>, if approved for deferral under subparagraph (A), shall be retired on the date requested by the officer, and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the tenth calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may defer the retirement of an officer otherwise approved for early retirement under paragraph (1)(B), but in no case later than the first day of the tenth calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> An officer recommended for early retirement under paragraph (2), if approved for deferral under subparagraph (A), shall be retired on the date requested by the officer, and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the thirteenth calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> So long as an officer in a grade below brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) holds the same grade, he may not be considered for early retirement under this section more than once in any five-year period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The retirement of an officer pursuant to this section shall be considered to be an involuntary retirement for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Such regulations shall require that when the Secretary of the military department concerned submits a list of officers to a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> to consider officers for selection for early retirement under this section, such list (except as provided in subparagraph (B)) shall include each officer on the active-duty list in the same grade and competitive category whose position on the active-duty list is between that of the most junior officer in that grade and competitive category whose name is submitted to the board and that of the most senior officer in that grade and competitive category whose name is submitted to the board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A list under subparagraph (A) may not include an officer in that grade and competitive category (i) who has been approved for voluntary retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title, or (ii) who is to be involuntarily retired under any provision of law during the fiscal year in which the selection board is convened or during the following fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An officer not considered by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> by reason of subparagraph (B) shall be retired on the date approved for the retirement of that officer as of the convening date of such selection board unless the Secretary concerned approves a modification of such date in order to prevent a personal hardship for the officer or for other humanitarian reasons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2864</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(f)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 127</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1967</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 521(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1561</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1355</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1646</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 504(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 295</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3354</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(L)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 638a.</num>
<heading> Modification to rules for continuation on active duty; enhanced authority for selective early retirement and early discharges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary of a military department to take any of the actions set forth in subsection (b) with respect to officers of an armed force under the jurisdiction of that Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any authority provided to the Secretary of a military department under paragraph (1) shall expire on the date specified by the Secretary of Defense, but such expiration date may not be later than <date date="2025-12-31">December 31, 2025</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Actions which the Secretary of a military department may take with respect to officers of an armed force when authorized to do so under subsection (a) are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Shortening the period of the continuation on active duty established under <ref>section 637 of this title</ref> for a regular officer who is serving on active duty pursuant to a selection under that section for continuation on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Providing that regular officers on the active-duty list may be considered for early retirement by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> in the case of officers described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (C) as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Officers in the regular grade of lieutenant colonel or commander who have failed of selection for promotion at least one time and whose names are not on a list of officers recommended for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Officers in the regular grade of colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain who have served on active duty in that grade for at least two years and whose names are not on a list of officers recommended for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Officers, other than those described in subparagraphs (A) and (B), holding a regular grade below the grade of colonel, or in the case of the Navy, captain, who are eligible for retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title, or who after two additional years or less of active service would be eligible for retirement under one of those sections and whose names are not on a list of officers recommended for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Convening selection boards under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> to consider for discharge regular officers on the active-duty list in a grade below lieutenant colonel or commander—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> who have served at least one year of active duty in the grade currently held;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whose names are not on a list of officers recommended for promotion; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> who are not eligible to be retired under any provision of law (other than by reason of eligibility pursuant to section 4403 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1993) and are not within two years of becoming so eligible.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Convening selection boards under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> to consider for early retirement or discharge regular officers on the active-duty list in a grade below lieutenant colonel or commander—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> who have served at least one year of active duty in the grade currently held; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whose names are not on a list of officers recommended for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of an action under subsection (b)(2), the total number of officers described in that subsection that a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> pursuant to the authority of that subsection may recommend for early retirement may not be more than 30 percent of the number of officers considered in each grade in each competitive category.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of an action authorized under subsection (b)(2), the Secretary of Defense may also authorize the Secretary of the military department concerned when convening a selection board under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> to consider regular officers on the active-duty list for early retirement to include within the officers to be considered by the board reserve officers on the active-duty list on the same basis as regular officers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of an action under subsection (b)(2), the Secretary of the military department concerned may submit to a selection board convened pursuant to that subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the names of all eligible officers described in that subsection in a particular grade and competitive category; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the names of all eligible officers described in that subsection in a particular grade and competitive category who are also in particular year groups, specialties, or retirement categories, or any combination thereof, within that competitive category.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In the case of an action under subsection (b)(2), the Secretary of Defense may also authorize the Secretary of the military department concerned to waive the five-year period specified in <ref>section 638(c) of this title</ref> if the Secretary of Defense determines that it is necessary for the Secretary of that military department to have such authority in order to meet mission needs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of an action under subsection (b)(3), the Secretary of the military department concerned may submit to a selection board convened pursuant to that subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the names of all officers described in that subsection in a particular grade and competitive category; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the names of all officers described in that subsection in a particular grade and competitive category who also are in particular year groups or specialties, or both, within that competitive category.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The total number of officers to be recommended for discharge by a selection board convened pursuant to subsection (b)(3) may not be more than 30 percent of the number of officers considered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An officer who is recommended for discharge by a selection board convened pursuant to the authority of subsection (b)(3) and whose discharge is approved by the Secretary concerned shall be discharged on a date specified by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Selection of officers for discharge under this subsection shall be based on the needs of the service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of action under subsection (b)(4), the Secretary of the military department concerned shall specify the total number of officers described in that subsection that a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> pursuant to the authority of that subsection may recommend for early retirement or discharge. Officers who are eligible, or are within two years of becoming eligible, to be retired under any provision of law (other than by reason of eligibility pursuant to section 4403 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1993 (<ref>Public Law 102–484</ref>)), if selected by the board, shall be retired or retained until becoming eligible to retire under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title, and those officers who are otherwise ineligible to retire under any provision of law shall, if selected by the board, be discharged.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of action under subsection (b)(4), the Secretary of the military department concerned may submit to a selection board convened pursuant to that subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the names of all eligible officers described in that subsection, whether or not they are eligible to be retired under any provision of law, in a particular grade and competitive category; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the names of all eligible officers described in that subsection in a particular grade and competitive category, whether or not they are eligible to be retired under any provision of law, who are also in particular year groups, specialties, or retirement categories, or any combination thereof, with that competitive category.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The number of officers specified under paragraph (1) may not be more than 30 percent of the number of officers considered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An officer who is recommended for discharge by a selection board convened pursuant to the authority of subsection (b)(4) and whose discharge is approved by the Secretary concerned shall be discharged on a date specified by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Selection of officers for discharge under this subsection shall be based on the needs of the service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The discharge or retirement of an officer pursuant to this section shall be considered to be involuntary for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 521(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1559</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 503(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1355</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title V, § 503</ref>, title LXIV, § 4403(g)(2), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2402</ref>, 2703; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 561(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1667</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 561(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2025</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 571(c)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–134; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VI, § 623(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1714</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 750</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3355</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 807</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 506, 508(b), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2108</ref>, 2109; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1373</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 638b.</num>
<heading> Voluntary retirement incentive</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incentive for Voluntary Retirement for Certain Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary of a military department to provide a voluntary retirement incentive payment in accordance with this section to an officer of the armed forces under that Secretary’s jurisdiction who is specified in subsection (c) as being eligible for such a payment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any authority provided the Secretary of a military department under this section shall expire as specified by the Secretary of Defense, but not later than <date date="2018-12-31">December 31, 2018</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The total number of officers who may be provided a voluntary retirement incentive payment under this section may not exceed 675 officers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), an officer of the armed forces is eligible for a voluntary retirement incentive payment under this section if the officer—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has served on active duty for more than 20 years, but not more than 29 years, on the approved date of retirement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> meets the minimum length of commissioned service requirement for voluntary retirement as a commissioned officer in accordance with section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title, as applicable to that officer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> on the approved date of retirement, has 12 months or more remaining on active-duty service before reaching the maximum retirement years of active service for the member’s grade as specified in section 633 or 634 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> on the approved date of retirement, has 12 months or more remaining on active-duty service before reaching the maximum retirement age under any other provision of law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> meets any additional requirements for such eligibility as is specified by the Secretary concerned, including any requirement relating to years of service, skill rating, military specialty or competitive category, grade, any remaining period of obligated service, or any combination thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The following officers are not eligible for a voluntary retirement incentive payment under this section:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An officer being evaluated for disability under chapter 61 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An officer projected to be retired under section 1201 or 1204 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An officer projected to be discharged with disability severance pay under <ref>section 1212 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A member transferred to the temporary disability retired list under section 1202 or 1205 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> An officer subject to pending disciplinary action or subject to administrative separation or mandatory discharge under any other provision of law or regulation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount of Payment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of the voluntary retirement incentive payment paid an officer under this section shall be an amount determined by the Secretary concerned, but not to exceed an amount equal to 12 times the amount of the officer’s monthly basic pay at the time of the officer’s retirement. The amount may be paid in a lump sum at the time of retirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repayment for Members Who Return to Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member of the armed forces who, after having received all or part of a voluntary retirement incentive under this section, returns to active duty shall have deducted from each payment of basic pay, in such schedule of monthly installments as the Secretary concerned shall specify, until the total amount deducted from such basic pay equals the total amount of voluntary retirement incentive received.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Members who are involuntarily recalled to active duty or full-time National Guard duty under any provision of law shall not be subject to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive, in whole or in part, repayment required under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that recovery would be against equity and good conscience or would be contrary to the best interest of the United States. The authority in this paragraph may be delegated only to the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness and the Principal Deputy Under Secretary of Defense of Personnel and Readiness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 504(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1389</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 639.</num>
<heading> Continuation on active duty to complete disciplinary action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When any action has been commenced against an officer with a view to trying such officer by court-martial and such officer is to be separated or retired in accordance with this chapter, the Secretary of the military department concerned may delay the separation or retirement of the officer, without prejudice to such action, until the completion of the action.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2866</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 640.</num>
<heading> Deferment of retirement or separation for medical reasons</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the evaluation of the physical condition of an officer and determination of the officer’s entitlement to retirement or separation for physical disability require hospitalization or medical observation and that such hospitalization or medical observation cannot be completed with confidence in a manner consistent with the member’s well being before the date on which the officer would otherwise be required to retire or be separated under this title, the Secretary may defer the retirement or separation of the officer under this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A deferral of retirement or separation under subsection (a) may not extend for more than 30 days after completion of the evaluation requiring hospitalization or medical observation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2866</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>ADDITIONAL PROVISIONS RELATING TO PROMOTION, SEPARATION, AND RETIREMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 641.</num>
<heading> Applicability of chapter</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Officers in the following categories are not subject to this chapter (other than section 640 and, in the case of warrant officers, section 628):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Reserve officers—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on active duty authorized under section 115(a)(1)(B) or 115(b)(1) of this title, or excluded from counting for active duty end strengths under <ref>section 115(i) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on active duty under section 7038, 8083, 8084, 9038, 10211, 10301 through 10305, 10502, 10505, 10506(a), 10506(b), 10507, or 12402 of this title or <ref>section 708 of title 32</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> on full-time National Guard duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The director of admissions, dean, and permanent professors at the United States Military Academy, the registrar, dean, and permanent professors at the United States Air Force Academy, and permanent professors of the Navy (as defined in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Warrant officers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Retired officers on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Students at the Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2866</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title IV, § 414(a)(5)</ref>, title V, § 527(b), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2519</ref>, 2525; <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 531(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1671(c)(5)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3014</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(c)(6)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XII, § 1212(e)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2694</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 521], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–108; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1092</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IV, § 416(j)</ref>, title V, § 501(d), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1869</ref>, 1874; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VI, § 621(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2255</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 508(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 97</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VI, § 618(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1426</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 642.</num>
<heading> Entitlement of officers discharged or retired under this chapter to separation pay or retired pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An officer who is discharged under this chapter is entitled, if eligible therefor, to separation pay under <ref>section 1174 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An officer who is retired under this chapter is entitled to retired pay computed under chapter 71 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2867</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 643.</num>
<heading> Chaplains: discharge or retirement upon loss of professional qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, a commissioned officer on the active-duty list of the Army, Navy, or Air Force who is appointed or designated as a chaplain may, if he fails to maintain the qualifications needed to perform his professional function, be discharged or, if eligible for retirement, may be retired.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2867</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 644.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2961</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 645.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “promotion zone” means a promotion eligibility category consisting of the officers on an active-duty list in the same grade and competitive category—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of officers in grades below colonel, for officers of the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force, or captain, for officers of the Navy, have neither (I) failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade, nor (II) been removed from a list of officers recommended for promotion to that grade (other than after having been placed on that list after a selection from below the promotion zone); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of officers in the grade of colonel or brigadier general, for officers of the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force, or captain or rear admiral (lower half), for officers of the Navy, have neither (I) not been recommended for promotion to the next higher grade when considered in the promotion zone, nor (II) been removed from a list of officers recommended for promotion to that grade (other than after having been placed on that list after a selection from below the promotion zone); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are senior to the officer designated by the Secretary of the military department concerned to be the junior officer in the promotion zone eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “officers above the promotion zone” means a group of officers on an active-duty list in the same grade and competitive category who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are in the same grade as those officers in the promotion zone for that competitive category; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> are senior to the senior officer in the promotion zone for that competitive category.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “officers below the promotion zone” means a group of officers on the active-duty list in the same grade and competitive category who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are in the same grade as the officers in the promotion zone for that competitive category; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> are junior to the junior officer in the promotion zone for that competitive category.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2867</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 533(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2528</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 521(e)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1881</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 646.</num>
<heading> Consideration of performance as a member of the Joint Staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, shall ensure that officer personnel policies of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force concerning promotion, retention, and assignment give appropriate consideration to the performance of an officer as a member of the Joint Staff.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIII, § 1301(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2612</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 647.</num>
<heading> Force shaping authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary concerned may, solely for the purpose of restructuring an armed force under the jurisdiction of that Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> discharge an officer described in subsection (b); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transfer such an officer from the active-duty list of that armed force to the reserve active-status list of a reserve component.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The authority under this section may be exercised in the case of an officer (other than an officer of the Space Force) who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has completed not more than six years of service as a commissioned officer in the armed forces; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has completed more than six years of service as a commissioned officer in the armed forces, but has not completed a minimum service obligation applicable to that member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “minimum service obligation” means the initial period of required active duty service together with any additional period of required active duty service incurred during the initial period of required active duty service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment of Transferred Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer of the Regular Army, Regular Air Force, Regular Navy, or Regular Marine Corps who is transferred to a reserve active-status list under this section shall be discharged from the regular component concerned and appointed as a reserve commissioned officer under <ref>section 12203 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations for the exercise of the Secretary’s authority under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Space Force</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For a similar provision with respect to officers of the Space Force, see <ref>section 20405 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 501(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1873</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 503(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 95</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(4)(H)</ref>, (16), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3822</ref>, 3823; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1718(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 658</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>ALTERNATIVE PROMOTION AUTHORITY FOR OFFICERS IN DESIGNATED COMPETITIVE CATEGORIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 649a.</num>
<heading> Officers in designated competitive categories</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Designate Competitive Categories of Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Secretary of a military department may designate one or more competitive categories for promotion of officers under <ref>section 621 of this title</ref> that are under the jurisdiction of such Secretary as a competitive category of officers whose promotion, retirement, and continuation on active duty shall be subject to the provisions of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Exercise of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of a military department may not designate a competitive category of officers for purposes of this subchapter until 60 days after the date on which the Secretary submits to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the designation of the competitive category. The report on the designation of a competitive category shall set forth the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A detailed description of officer requirements for officers within the competitive category.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An explanation of the number of opportunities for consideration for promotion to each particular grade, and an estimate of promotion timing, within the competitive category.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An estimate of the size of the promotion zone for each grade within the competitive category.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A description of any other matters the Secretary considered in determining to designate the competitive category for purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1744</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649b.</num>
<heading> Selection for promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in this section, the selection for promotion of officers in any competitive category of officers designated for purposes of this subchapter shall be governed by the provisions of subchapter I of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Recommendation for Promotion of Officers Below Promotion Zone</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 616(b) of this title</ref> shall not apply to the selection for promotion of officers described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendation for Officers To Be Excluded From Future Consideration for Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In making recommendations pursuant to <ref>section 616 of this title</ref> for purposes of the administration of this subchapter, a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(a) of this title</ref> may recommend that an officer considered by the board be excluded from future consideration for promotion under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1744</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649c.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for consideration for promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided by this section, eligibility for promotion of officers in any competitive category of officers designated for purposes of this subchapter shall be governed by the provisions of <ref>section 619 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of Certain Time-in-grade Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraphs (2) through (4) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002040">1</ref> of <ref>section 619(a) of this title</ref> shall not apply to the promotion of officers described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to Officers Above and Below Promotion Zone</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following provisions of <ref>section 619(c) of this title</ref> shall not apply to the promotion of officers described in subsection (a):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The reference in paragraph (1) of that section to an officer above the promotion zone.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (2)(A) of that section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of Requirement Relating to Opportunities for Consideration for Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 645(1)(A)(i)(I) of this title</ref> shall not apply to the promotion of officers described in subsection (a) to the extent that such section is inconsistent with a number of opportunities for promotion specified pursuant to <ref>section 649d of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ineligibility of Certain Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following officers are not eligible for promotion under this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer described in <ref>section 619(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An officer not included within the promotion zone.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An officer who has failed of promotion to a higher grade the maximum number of times specified for opportunities for promotion for such grade within the competitive category concerned pursuant to <ref>section 649d of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An officer recommended by a selection board to be removed from consideration for promotion in accordance with <ref>section 649b(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1745</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3573</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649d.</num>
<heading> Opportunities for consideration for promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specification of Number of Opportunities for Consideration for Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In designating a competitive category of officers pursuant to <ref>section 649a of this title</ref>, the Secretary of a military department shall specify the number of opportunities for consideration for promotion to be afforded officers of the armed force concerned within the category for promotion to each grade above the grade of first lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade), as applicable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limited Authority of Secretary of Military Department to Modify Number of Opportunities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may modify the number of opportunities for consideration for promotion to be afforded officers of an armed force within a competitive category for promotion to a particular grade, as previously specified by the Secretary pursuant subsection (a) or this subsection, not more frequently than once every five years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Discretionary Authority of Secretary of Defense to Modify Number of Opportunities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may modify the number of opportunities for consideration for promotion to be afforded officers of an armed force within a competitive category for promotion to a particular grade, as previously specified or modified pursuant to any provision of this section, at the discretion of the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Number of Opportunities Specified</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The number of opportunities for consideration for promotion to be afforded officers of an armed force within a competitive category for promotion to a particular grade, as specified or modified pursuant to any provision of this section, may not exceed five opportunities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Certain Reduction in Number of Opportunities Specified</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, by reason of a reduction in the number of opportunities for consideration for promotion under this section, an officer would no longer have one or more opportunities for consideration for promotion that were available to the officer before the reduction, the officer shall be afforded one additional opportunity for consideration for promotion after the reduction.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1745</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649e.</num>
<heading> Promotions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sections 620 through 626 of this title shall apply in promotions of officers in competitive categories of officers designated for purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649f.</num>
<heading> Failure of selection for promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in this section, sections 627 through 632 of this title shall apply to promotions of officers in competitive categories of officers designated for purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of Failure of Selection for Promotion to Officers Above Promotion Zone</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The reference in <ref>section 627 of this title</ref> to an officer above the promotion zone shall not apply in the promotion of officers described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Selection Board Matters</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The reference in <ref>section 628(a)(1) of this title</ref> to a person above the promotion zone shall not apply in the promotion of officers described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Failure of Selection</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the administration of this subchapter pursuant to subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an officer described in subsection (a) shall not be deemed to have failed twice of selection for promotion for purposes of <ref>section 629(e)(2) of this title</ref> until the officer has failed selection of promotion to the next higher grade the maximum number of times specified for opportunities for promotion to such grade within the competitive category concerned pursuant to <ref>section 649d of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any reference in section 631(a) or 632(a) of this title to an officer who has failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade for the second time shall be deemed to refer instead to an officer described in subsection (a) who has failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade for the maximum number of times specified for opportunities for promotion to such grade within the competitive category concerned pursuant to such section 649d.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649g.</num>
<heading> Retirement: retirement for years of service; selective early retirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retirement for Years of Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Sections 633 through 636 of this title shall apply to the retirement of officers in competitive categories of officers designated for purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selective Early Retirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Sections 638 and 638a of this title shall apply to the retirement of officers described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1747</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649h.</num>
<heading> Continuation on active duty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer subject to discharge or retirement pursuant to this subchapter may, subject to the needs of the service, be continued on active duty if the officer is selected for continuation on active duty in accordance with this section by a selection board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Identification of Positions for Officers Continued on Active Duty.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Officers may be selected for continuation on active duty pursuant to this section only for assignment to positions identified by the Secretary of the military department concerned for which vacancies exist or are anticipated to exist.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before convening a selection board pursuant to <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> for purposes of selection of officers for continuation on active duty pursuant to this section, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall specify for purposes of the board the positions identified by the Secretary to which officers selected for continuation on active duty may be assigned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendation for Continuation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A selection board may recommend an officer for continuation on active duty pursuant to this section only if the board determines that the officer is qualified for assignment to one or more positions identified pursuant to subsection (b) on the basis of skills, knowledge, and behavior required of an officer to perform successfully in such position or positions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval of Secretary of Military Department</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Continuation of an officer on active duty under this section pursuant to the action of a selection board is subject to the approval of the Secretary of the military department concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonacceptance of Continuation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer who is selected for continuation on active duty pursuant to this section, but who declines to continue on active duty, shall be discharged or retired, as appropriate, in accordance with <ref>section 632 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Period of Continuation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer continued on active duty pursuant to this section shall remain on active duty, and serve in the position to which assigned (or in another position to which assigned with the approval of the Secretary of the military department concerned), for a total of not more than three years after the date of assignment to the position to which first so assigned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional continuation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer whose continued service pursuant to this section would otherwise expire pursuant to paragraph (1) may be continued on active duty if selected for continuation on active duty in accordance with this section before the date of expiration pursuant to that paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Expiration of Continuation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each officer continued on active duty pursuant to this subsection who is not selected for continuation on active duty pursuant to subsection (f)(2) at the completion of the officer’s term of continued service shall, unless sooner discharged or retired under another provision of law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be discharged upon the expiration of the term of continued service; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if eligible for retirement under another other provision of law, be retired under that law on the first day of the first month following the month in which the officer completes the term of continued service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Discharge or Retirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The discharge or retirement of an officer pursuant to this section shall be considered to be an involuntary discharge or retirement for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1747</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649i.</num>
<heading> Continuation on active duty: officers in certain military specialties and career tracks</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to continuation on active duty provided for in <ref>section 649h of this title</ref>, an officer to whom <ref>section 637a of this title</ref> applies may be continued on active duty in accordance with the provisions of such section 637a.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649j.</num>
<heading> Other administrative authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following provisions of this title shall apply to officers in competitive categories of officers designated for purposes of this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Section 638b, relating to voluntary retirement incentives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Section 639, relating to continuation on active duty to complete disciplinary action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Section 640, relating to deferment of retirement or separation for medical reasons.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1748</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(18)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1813</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 649k.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations regarding the administration of this subchapter. The elements of such regulations shall include mechanisms to clarify the manner in which provisions of other subchapters of this chapter shall be used in the administration of this subchapter in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>