<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 303—</num>
<heading>RESEARCH AND ENGINEERING ACTIVITIES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4061.</num>
<heading> Defense Research and Development Rapid Innovation Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Established</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish a competitive, merit-based program to enable and assist small businesses to accelerate the commercialization of various technologies, including critical technologies developed pursuant to phase II Small Business Innovation Research Program projects, phase II Small Business Technology Transfer Program projects, technologies developed by the defense laboratories, capabilities developed through competitively awarded prototype agreements and other innovative technologies (including dual use technologies).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The purpose of this program is to stimulate innovative technologies and reduce acquisition or lifecycle costs, address technical risks, improve the timeliness and thoroughness of test and evaluation outcomes, support the integration of such products, and rapidly insert such products directly in support of primarily major defense acquisition programs, but also other defense acquisition programs that meet critical national security needs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall issue guidelines for the operation of the program. At a minimum such guidance shall provide for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The issuance of one or more broad agency announcements or the use of any other competitive or merit-based processes by the Department of Defense for candidate proposals in support of primarily major defense acquisition programs, but also other defense acquisition programs as described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The review of candidate proposals by the Department of Defense and by each Office of Small Business Programs of each military department and the merit-based selection of the most promising cost-effective proposals for funding through contracts, cooperative agreements, and other transactions for the purposes of carrying out the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The total amount of funding provided to any project under the program from funding provided under subsection (d) shall not exceed $6,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> No project shall receive more than a total of two years of funding under the program from funding provided under subsection (d), unless the Secretary, or the Secretary’s designee, approves funding for any additional year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Mechanisms to facilitate transition of follow-on or current projects carried out under the program into defense acquisition programs, through the use of the authorities of <ref>section 4004 of this title</ref> or such other authorities as may be appropriate to conduct further testing, low rate production, or full rate production of technologies developed under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Projects are selected using merit-based selection procedures and the selection of projects is not subject to undue influence by Congress or other Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> A preference under the program for funding small business concerns.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment Pursuant to Certain Congressional Rules</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be interpreted to require or enable any official of the Department of Defense to provide funding under this section to any earmark as defined pursuant to House Rule XXI, clause 9, or any congressionally directed spending item as defined pursuant to Senate Rule XLIV, paragraph 5.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose and to the limitation under paragraph (2), the amounts authorized to be appropriated for research, development, test, and evaluation for a fiscal year may be used for such fiscal year for the program established under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> During any fiscal year, the total amount of awards in an amount greater than $6,000,000 made under the program established under subsection (a) may not exceed 25 percent of the amount made available to carry out such program during such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may transfer funds available for the program to the research, development, test, and evaluation accounts of a military department, defense agency, or the unified combatant command for special operations forces pursuant to a proposal, or any part of a proposal, that the Secretary determines would directly support the purposes of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The transfer authority provided in this subsection is in addition to any other transfer authority available to the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title II, § 224(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1683</ref>, § 2359a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 878(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1530</ref>; renumbered § 4061 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1842(b), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4244</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(d)(8)</ref>, (q)(1), (u)(3)(B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2136</ref>, 2148, 2152; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VIII, § 860</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 346</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4062.</num>
<heading> Defense Acquisition Challenge Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Required</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, shall carry out a program to provide opportunities for the increased introduction of innovative and cost-saving technology in acquisition programs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The program, to be known as the Defense Acquisition Challenge Program (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Challenge Program”), shall provide any person or activity within or outside the Department of Defense with the opportunity to propose alternatives, to be known as challenge proposals, at the component, subsystem, system, or system-of-systems level of an existing Department of Defense acquisition program, or to address any broader functional challenge to Department of Defense missions that may not fall within an acquisition program, that would result in improvements in performance, affordability, manufacturability, or operational capability of that acquisition program or function.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Panels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Under Secretary shall establish one or more panels of highly qualified scientists and engineers (hereinafter in this section referred to as “Panels”) to provide preliminary evaluations of challenge proposals under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preliminary Evaluation by Panels</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under procedures prescribed by the Under Secretary, a person or activity within or outside the Department of Defense may submit challenge proposals to a Panel, through the unsolicited proposal process or in response to a broad agency announcement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary shall establish procedures pursuant to which appropriate officials of the Department of Defense may identify proposals submitted through the unsolicited proposal process as challenge proposals. The procedures shall provide for the expeditious referral of such proposals to a Panel for preliminary evaluation under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary shall issue on an annual basis not less than one such broad agency announcement inviting interested parties to submit challenge proposals. Such announcements may also identify particular technology areas and acquisition programs or functions that will be given priority in the evaluation of challenge proposals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Under Secretary shall establish procedures for the prompt issuance of a solicitation for challenge proposals addressing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any acquisition program for which, since the last such announcement, the Secretary concerned has determined under <ref>section 4374 of this title</ref> that the program’s acquisition unit cost or procurement unit cost has increased by a percentage equal to or greater than the critical cost growth threshold for the program (in this section referred to as a “critical cost growth threshold breach”);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any design, engineering, manufacturing, or technology integration issues, in accordance with the assessment required by <ref>section 4375(b) of this title</ref>, that have contributed significantly to the cost growth of such program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any functional challenges of importance to Department of Defense missions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A solicitation under this paragraph may be included in a broad agency announcement issued pursuant to paragraph (3) as long as the broad agency announcement is released in an expeditious manner following the determination of the Secretary concerned that a critical cost growth threshold breach has occurred with respect to a major defense acquisition program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Under procedures established by the Under Secretary, a Panel shall carry out a preliminary evaluation of each challenge proposal submitted in response to a broad agency announcement, or submitted through the unsolicited proposal process and identified as a challenge proposal in accordance with paragraph (2), to determine each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Whether the challenge proposal has merit.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Whether the challenge proposal is likely to result in improvements in performance, affordability, manufacturability, or operational capability at the component, subsystem, system, or system-of-systems level of an acquisition program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Whether the challenge proposal could be implemented in the acquisition program rapidly, at an acceptable cost, and without unacceptable disruption to the acquisition program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Whether the challenge proposal is likely to result in improvements to any functional challenges of importance to Department of Defense missions, and whether the proposal could be implemented rapidly, at an acceptable cost, and without unacceptable disruption to such missions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The Under Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may establish procedures to ensure that the Challenge Program does not become an avenue for the repetitive submission of proposals that have been previously reviewed and found not to have merit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may establish procedures to ensure that the Challenge Program establishes appropriate priorities for proposals from businesses that are not major contractors with the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> If a Panel determines that a challenge proposal satisfies each of the criteria specified in paragraph (5), the person or activity submitting that challenge proposal shall be provided an opportunity to submit such challenge proposal for a full review and evaluation under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Full Review and Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under procedures prescribed by the Under Secretary, for each challenge proposal submitted for a full review and evaluation as provided in subsection (c)(7), the office carrying out the acquisition program to which the proposal relates shall, in consultation with the prime system contractor carrying out such program, conduct a full review and evaluation of the proposal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The full review and evaluation shall, independent of the determination of a Panel under subsection (c)(5), determine each of the matters specified in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of such subsection. The full review and evaluation shall also include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an assessment of the cost of adopting the challenge proposal and implementing it in the acquisition program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consideration of any intellectual property issues associated with the challenge proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action Upon Favorable Full Review and Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under procedures prescribed by the Under Secretary, each challenge proposal determined under a full review and evaluation to satisfy each of the criteria specified in subsection (c)(5) with respect to an acquisition program shall be considered by the office carrying out the applicable acquisition program and the prime system contractor for incorporation into the acquisition program as a new technology insertion at the component, subsystem, system, or system-of-systems level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary shall encourage the adoption of each challenge proposal referred to in paragraph (1) by providing suitable incentives to the office carrying out the acquisition program and the prime system contractor carrying out such program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of a challenge proposal submitted in response to a solicitation issued as a result of a critical cost growth threshold breach that is determined under full review and evaluation to satisfy each of the criteria specified in subsection (c)(5), the Under Secretary shall establish guidelines for covering the costs of the challenge proposal. If appropriate, such guidelines shall not be restricted to funding provided by the Defense Acquisition Challenge Program, but shall also consider alternative funding sources, such as the acquisition program with respect to which the breach occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action Upon Unfavorable Full Review and Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under procedures prescribed by the Under Secretary, if a challenge proposal is determined by a Panel to satisfy each of the criteria specified in subsection (c)(5), but is not determined under a full review and evaluation to satisfy such criteria, the following provisions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The office carrying out the full review and evaluation shall provide to the Panel that conducted the preliminary evaluation a statement containing a summary of the rationale for the unfavorable evaluation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the Panel disagrees with the rationale provided under paragraph (1), the Panel may return the challenge proposal to the office for further consideration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access to Technical Resources</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under procedures established by the Under Secretary, the technical resources of the laboratories, research, development, and engineering centers, test and evaluation activities, and other elements of the Department may be called upon to support the activities of the Challenge Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds available to carry out this program may be used to compensate such laboratories, centers, activities, and elements for technical assistance provided to a Panel pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conflicts of Interest and Confidentiality</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out each preliminary evaluation under subsection (c) and full review under subsection (d), the Under Secretary shall ensure the elimination of conflicts of interest and that the identity of any person or activity submitting a challenge proposal is not disclosed outside the Federal Government, prior to contract award, without the consent of the person or activity. For purposes of the proceeding sentence, the term “Federal Government” includes both employees of the Federal Government and employees of Federal Government contractors providing advisory and assistance services as described in part 37 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds made available for the Challenge Program may be used only for activities authorized by this section, and not for implementation of challenge proposals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Use of Certain Procedures as Use of Competitive Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The use of general solicitation competitive procedures established under subsection (c) shall be considered to be the use of competitive procedures for purposes of sections 3201 through 3205 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">System Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “system”—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the organization of hardware, software, material, facilities, personnel, data, and services needed to perform a designated function with specified results (such as the gathering of specified data, its processing, and its delivery to users); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a combination of two or more interrelated pieces (or sets) of equipment arranged in a functional package to perform an operational function or to satisfy a requirement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> includes a major system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program for Programs Other Than Major Defense Acquisition Programs.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall carry out a pilot program to expand the use of the authority provided in this section to provide opportunities for the introduction of innovative and cost-saving approaches to programs other than major defense acquisition programs through the submission, review, and implementation, where appropriate, of qualifying proposals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifying proposals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this subsection, a qualifying proposal is an offer to supply a nondevelopmental item that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is evaluated as achieving a level of performance that is at least equal to the level of performance of an item being procured under a covered acquisition program and as providing savings in excess of 15 percent after considering all costs to the Government of implementing such proposal; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is evaluated as achieving a level of performance that is significantly better than the level of performance of an item being procured under a covered acquisition program without any increase in cost to the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Under Secretary shall adopt modifications as may be needed to the procedures applicable to the Challenge Program to provide for Department of Defense review of, and action on, qualifying proposals. Such procedures shall include, at a minimum, the issuance of a broad agency announcement inviting interested parties to submit qualifying proposals in areas of interest to the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nondevelopmental item</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “nondevelopmental item” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 110 of title 41</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered acquisition program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “covered acquisition program” means any acquisition program of the Department of Defense other than a major defense acquisition program, but does not include any contract awarded under an exception to competitive acquisition authorized by the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 631</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Level of performance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “level of performance”, with respect to a nondevelopmental item, means the extent to which the item demonstrates required item functional characteristics.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority to carry out the pilot program under this subsection shall terminate on <date date="2021-01-07">January 7, 2021</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title II, § 243(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2495</ref>, § 2359b; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title II, § 213(b)</ref>, (d)–(g), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2121–2123</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 821, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4531</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 827</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1951</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1091(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 876</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 828</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2281</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(56)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1549</ref>; renumbered § 4062 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1842(b), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4244</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(d)(9)</ref>, (q)(1), (u)(3)(B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2137</ref>, 2148, 2152.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4063 to 4065.</num>
<heading> Omitted]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4066.</num>
<heading> Global Research Watch Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall carry out a Global Research Watch program in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Goals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The goals of the program are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To monitor and analyze the basic and applied research activities and capabilities of foreign nations and private sector persons in areas of military interest, including allies and competitors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To provide standards for comparison and comparative analysis of research capabilities of foreign nations and private sector persons in relation to the research capabilities of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To assist Congress and Department of Defense officials in making investment decisions for research in technical areas where the United States may not be the global leader.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To identify areas where significant opportunities for cooperative research may exist.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To coordinate and promote the international cooperative research and analysis activities of each of the armed forces and Defense Agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> To establish and maintain an electronic database on international research capabilities, comparative assessments of capabilities, cooperative research opportunities, and ongoing cooperative programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Focus of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The program shall be focused on research and technologies at a technical maturity level equivalent to Department of Defense basic and applied research programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary shall coordinate the program with the international cooperation and analysis activities of the military departments and Defense Agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretaries of the military departments and the directors of the Defense Agencies shall provide the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering such assistance as the Under Secretary may require for purposes of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Funds available to a military department for a fiscal year for monitoring or analyzing the research activities and capabilities of foreign nations may not be obligated or expended until the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering certifies to the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics that the Secretary of such military department has provided the assistance required under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The limitation in subparagraph (A) shall not be construed to alter or effect the availability to a military department of funds for intelligence activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Classification of Database Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Information in electronic databases of the Global Research Watch program shall be maintained in unclassified form and, as determined necessary by the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, in classified form in such databases.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirement to carry out the program under this section shall terminate on <date date="2035-09-30">September 30, 2035</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title II, § 231(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1421</ref>, § 2365; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title II, § 232</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2134</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title IX, § 901(j)(3)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4324</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1950</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title II, § 266</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1301</ref>; renumbered § 4066, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1842(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4244</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(q)(1)</ref>, (u)(3)(B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2148</ref>, 2152; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4067.</num>
<heading> Technology protection features activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out activities to develop and incorporate technology protection features in a designated system to increase ally and partner military capability or improve coalition interoperability.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cost-sharing</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any contract for the design or development of a system resulting from activities under subsection (a) for the purpose of enhancing or enabling the exportability of the system, either for the development of program protection strategies for the system or the design and incorporation of exportability features into the system, shall include a cost-sharing provision that requires the contractor to bear half of the cost of such activities, or such other portion of such cost as the Secretary considers appropriate upon showing of good cause.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any contract for the design or development of an exportability feature of a system resulting from activities under subsection (a) for the purpose of enhancing or enabling the exportability of the system shall include a cost-sharing provision that requires the contractor to bear half of the cost of such activities, or such other portion of such cost as the Secretary considers appropriate upon showing of good cause.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may deem the portion of the costs of the contractor described in paragraph (1) or (2) with respect to a designated system or exportability feature as allowable independent research and development costs under the regulations issued under <ref>section 3762 of this title</ref> if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a designated system, the designated system receives Milestone B approval; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that doing so would further the purposes of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “designated system” means any system (including a major system, as defined in <ref>section 3041 of title 10</ref>, United States Code) that the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment designates for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “independent research and development costs” has the meaning given the term in section 31.205-18 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Milestone B approval” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 4172(e)(7) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “technology protection features” means the technical modifications necessary to protect critical program information, including anti-tamper technologies and other systems engineering activities intended to prevent or delay exploitation of critical technologies in a designated system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title II, § 223(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1682</ref>, § 2357; renumbered § 4067 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1841(c), 1842(b), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4243</ref>, 4244, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 831(a)</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(D), (3)(B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1832</ref>, 2151, 2152; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>PERSONNEL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4091.</num>
<heading> Authorities for certain positions at science and technology reinvention laboratories</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority to Make Direct Appointments.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Candidates for scientific and engineering positions at science and technology reinvention laboratories</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The director of any Science and Technology Reinvention Laboratory (hereinafter in this section referred to as an “STRL”) may appoint qualified candidates possessing a bachelor’s or advanced degree to positions described in paragraph (1) of subsection (b) as an employee in a laboratory described in that paragraph without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 of title 5 (other than sections 3303 and 3328 of such title).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Veteran candidates for similar positions at research and engineering facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The director of any STRL may appoint qualified veteran candidates to positions described in paragraph (2) of subsection (b) as an employee at a laboratory, agency, or organization specified in that paragraph without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Students enrolled in scientific and engineering programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The director of any STRL may appoint qualified candidates enrolled in a program of undergraduate or graduate instruction leading to a bachelor’s or an advanced degree in a scientific, technical, engineering or mathematical course of study at an institution of higher education (as that term is defined in sections 101 and 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>, 1002)) to positions described in paragraph (3) of subsection (b) as an employee in a laboratory described in that paragraph without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 of title 5 (other than sections 3303 and 3328 of such title).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Noncompetitive conversion of appointments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to any student appointed by the director of an STRL under paragraph (3) to a temporary or term appointment, upon graduation from the applicable institution of higher education (as defined in such paragraph), the director may noncompetitively convert such student to another temporary appointment or to a term or permanent appointment within the STRL without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 of title 5 (other than sections 3303 and 3328 of such title), provided the student meets all eligibility and Office of Personnel Management qualification requirements for the position.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Covered Positions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Candidates for scientific and engineering positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The positions described in this paragraph are scientific and engineering positions that may be temporary, term, or permanent in any laboratory designated by <ref>section 4121(b) of this title</ref> as a Department of Defense science and technology reinvention laboratory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified veteran candidates</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The positions described in this paragraph are scientific, technical, engineering, and mathematics positions, including technicians, in the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any laboratory referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any other Department of Defense research and engineering agency or organization designated by the Secretary for purposes of subsection (a)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Candidates enrolled in scientific and engineering programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The positions described in this paragraph are scientific and engineering positions that may be temporary or term in any laboratory designated by <ref>section 4121(b) of this title</ref> as a Department of Defense science and technology reinvention laboratory.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Number of Appointments Allowable in a Fiscal Year</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The authority under subsection (a) may not, in any fiscal year and with respect to any laboratory, agency, or organization described in subsection (b), be exercised with respect to a number of candidates greater than the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a laboratory described in subsection (b)(1), with respect to appointment authority under subsection (a)(1), the number equal to 11 percent of the total number of scientific and engineering positions in such laboratory that are filled as of the close of the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a laboratory, agency, or organization described in subsection (b)(2), with respect to appointment authority under subsection (a)(2), the number equal to 3 percent of the total number of scientific, technical, engineering, mathematics, and technician positions in such laboratory, agency, or organization that are filled as of the close of the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of a laboratory described in subsection (b)(3), with respect to appointment authority under subsection (a)(3), the number equal to 10 percent of the total number of scientific and engineering positions in such laboratory that are filled as of the close of the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Senior Scientific Technical Managers.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is hereby established in each STRL, each facility of the Major Range and Test Facility Base, and the Defense Test Resource Management Center a category of senior professional scientific and technical positions, the incumbents of which shall be designated as “senior scientific technical managers” and which shall be positions classified above GS–15 of the General Schedule, notwithstanding <ref>section 5108(a) of title 5</ref>. The primary functions of such positions shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to engage in research and development in the physical, biological, medical, or engineering sciences, or another field closely related to the mission of such STRL, of such facility of the Major Range and Test Facility Base, or the Defense Test Resource Management Center; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to carry out technical supervisory responsibilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointments</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The laboratory positions described in paragraph (1) may be filled, and shall be managed, by the director of the STRL involved, under criteria established pursuant to <ref>section 4121(a) of this title</ref>, relating to personnel demonstration projects at laboratories of the Department of Defense, except that the director of the laboratory involved shall determine the number of such positions at such laboratory, not to exceed 2 percent of the number of scientists and engineers employed at such laboratory as of the close of the last fiscal year before the fiscal year in which any appointments subject to that numerical limitation are made.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The test and evaluation positions described in paragraph (1) may be filled, and shall be managed, by the director of the Major Range and Test Facility Base, in the case of a position at a facility of the Major Range and Test Facility Base, and the director of the Defense Test Resource Management Center, in the case of a position at such center, under criteria established pursuant to <ref>section 4121(a) of this title</ref>, relating to personnel demonstration projects at laboratories of the Department of Defense, except that the director involved shall determine the number of such positions at each facility of the Major Range and Test Facility Base and the Defense Test Resource Management Center, not to exceed two percent of the number of scientists and engineers, but at least one position, employed at the Major Range and Test Facility Base or the Defense Test Resource Management Center, as the case may be, as of the close of the last fiscal year before the fiscal year in which any appointments subject to those numerical limitations are made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exclusion From Personnel Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The director of an STRL shall manage the workforce strength, structure, positions, and compensation of such STRL—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> without regard to any limitation on appointments, positions, or funding with respect to such STRL, subject to subparagraph (B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in a manner consistent with the budget available with respect to such STRL.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to Senior Executive Service positions (as defined in <ref>section 3132(a) of title 5</ref>) or scientific and professional positions authorized under section 3104 of such title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Defense Test Resource Management Center” means the Department of Defense Test Resource Management Center established under <ref>section 4173 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “employee” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2105 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Major Range and Test Facility Base” means the test and evaluation facilities and resources that are designated by the Secretary of Defense as facilities and resources comprising the Major Range and Test Facility Base.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “veteran” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 101 of title 38</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XI, § 1122(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2453</ref>, § 2358a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XI, § 1111</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1636</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2012</ref>; renumbered § 4091, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1843(a)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1843(b)(2), 1845(c)(5), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4245</ref>, 4247; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 212(a), 215(d)(13), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1588</ref>, 1595; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XI, § 1103</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 427</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4092.</num>
<heading> Personnel management authority to attract experts in science, engineering, and certain other disciplines</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Programs Authorized.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Laboratories of the military departments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may carry out a program of personnel management authority provided in subsection (b) in order to facilitate recruitment of eminent experts in science or engineering for such laboratories of the military departments as the Secretary shall designate for purposes of the program for research and development projects of such laboratories.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">DARPA</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency may carry out a program of personnel management authority provided in subsection (b) in order to facilitate recruitment of eminent experts in science or engineering for research and development projects and to enhance the administration and management of the Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">DOTE</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Office of Operational Test and Evaluation may carry out a program of personnel management authority provided in subsection (b) in order to facilitate recruitment of eminent experts in science or engineering to support operational test and evaluation missions of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Strategic capabilities office</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Strategic Capabilities Office may carry out a program of personnel management authority provided in subsection (b) in order to facilitate recruitment of eminent experts in science or engineering for the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">DIU</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Defense Innovation Unit may carry out a program of personnel management authority provided in subsection (b) in order to facilitate recruitment of eminent experts in science or engineering for the Unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joint artificial intelligence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The official designated under section 238(b) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<ref>Public Law 115–232</ref>) may carry out a program of personnel management authority provided in subsection (b) in order to facilitate recruitment of eminent experts in science or engineering to support the activities of such official under section 238 of such Act. The authority to carry out the program under this paragraph shall terminate on <date date="2024-12-31">December 31, 2024</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">NGA</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency may carry out a program of personnel management authority provided in subsection (b) in order to facilitate recruitment of eminent experts in science or engineering for research and development projects and to enhance the administration and management of the Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">SDA</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Space Development Agency may carry out a program of personnel management authority provided in subsection (b) in order to facilitate recruitment of eminent experts in science or engineering for research and development projects and to enhance the administration and management of the Agency. The authority to carry out the program under this paragraph shall terminate on <date date="2030-12-31">December 31, 2030</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United states cyber command</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commander of United States Cyber Command may carry out a program of personnel management authority provided in subsection (b) in order to facilitate the recruitment of eminent experts in computer science, data science, engineering, mathematics, and computer network exploitation within the headquarters of United States Cyber Command and the Cyber National Mission Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Office of the under secretary of defense for research and engineering</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering may carry out a program of personnel management authority provided in subsection (b) in order to facilitate recruitment of eminent experts in science or engineering for the Office of the Under Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Office of strategic capital</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Office of Strategic Capital may carry out a program of personnel management authority provided in subsection (b) in order to facilitate recruitment of eminent experts in finance and investment for the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel Management Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under a program under subsection (a), the official responsible for administration of the program may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> without regard to any provision of title 5 governing the appointment of employees in the civil service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of the laboratories of the military departments designated pursuant to subsection (a)(1), appoint scientists and engineers to a total of not more than 40 scientific and engineering positions in such laboratories;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, appoint individuals to a total of not more than 140 positions in the Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of the Office of Operational Test and Evaluation, appoint scientists and engineers to a total of not more than 10 scientific and engineering positions in the Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in the case of the Strategic Capabilities Office, appoint scientists and engineers to a total of not more than 20 scientific and engineering positions in the Office, of which not more than 5 such positions may be positions of administration or management of the Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> in the case of the Defense Innovation Unit, appoint scientists and engineers to a total of not more than 35 scientific and engineering positions in the Unit, of which not more than 5 such positions may be positions of administration or management of the Unit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> in the case of the office of the official designated under section 238(b) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<ref>Public Law 115–232</ref>), appoint scientists and engineers to a total of not more than 5 scientific and engineering positions in support of the activities of such official under section 238 of such Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> in the case of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, appoint individuals to a total of not more than 7 positions in the Agency, of which not more than 2 such positions may be positions of administration or management in the Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> in the case of the Space Development Agency, appoint individuals to a total of not more than 25 positions in the Agency, of which not more than 5 such positions may be positions of administration or management of the Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> in the case of United States Cyber Command, appoint computer scientists, data scientists, engineers, mathematicians, and computer network exploitation specialists to a total of not more than 10 scientific and engineering positions in the Command;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> in the case of the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, appoint scientists and engineers to a total of not more than 10 scientific and engineering positions in the Office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> in the case of the Office of Strategic Capital, appoint individuals to a total of not more than 30 positions in the Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> notwithstanding any provision of title 5 governing the rates of pay or classification of employees in the executive branch, prescribe the rates of basic pay for positions to which employees are appointed under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of employees appointed pursuant to subparagraphs (B), (D), (E), (H), and (K) of paragraph (1), at a rate to be determined by the head of the organization concerned up to 150 percent of the total annual compensation payable to the Vice President under <ref>section 104 of title 3</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of employees appointed pursuant to paragraph (1)(G), to any of 2 positions of administration or management designated by the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency for purposes of this subparagraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of any other employee appointed pursuant to paragraph (1), at rates not in excess of the maximum rate of basic pay authorized for senior-level positions under <ref>section 5376 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> pay any employee appointed under paragraph (1), other than an employee appointed to a position designated as described in paragraph (2)(A), payments in addition to basic pay within the limit applicable to the employee under subsection (d); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> during any fiscal year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pay up to 15 individuals newly appointed pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) the travel, transportation, and relocation expenses and services described under sections 5724, 5724a, and 5724c of title 5; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> pay up to 15 individuals previously appointed pursuant to such paragraph, upon separation, the travel, transportation, and relocation expenses and services described under such sections (as applicable).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Term of Appointment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the service of an employee under an appointment under subsection (b)(1) may not exceed four years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extension</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The official responsible for the administration of a program under subsection (a) may, in the case of a particular employee under the program, extend the period to which service is limited under paragraph (1) by up to two years if the official determines that such action is necessary to promote the efficiency of a laboratory of a military department, the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, the Office of Operational Test and Evaluation, the Strategic Capabilities Office, the Defense Innovation Unit, the activities under section 238 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<ref>Public Law 115–232</ref>), the Space Development Agency, or the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum Amount of Additional Payments Payable</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section or <ref>section 5307 of title 5</ref>, no additional payments may be paid to an employee under subsection (b)(3) in any calendar year if, or to the extent that, the employee’s total annual compensation in such calendar year will exceed the maximum amount of total annual compensation payable at the salary set in accordance with <ref>section 104 of title 3</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XI, § 1121(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2451</ref>, § 1599h; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XI, § 1111</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2011</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title II, § 212</ref>, title XI, § 1101, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1255</ref>, 1595; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. W, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVI, § 1602</ref>, title XVII, § 1708(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4042</ref>, 4085; renumbered § 4092, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1843(a)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(21)</ref>, title XI, § 1107, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1920</ref>, 1951; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. X, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 976</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 212(a), 213, title XI, § 1109, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2466</ref>, 2471, 2819; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title II, § 213</ref>, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(33), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 183</ref>, 685; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title II, § 216</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1825</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4093.</num>
<heading> Science, Mathematics, and Research for Transformation (SMART) Defense Education Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program to provide financial assistance for education in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology skills and disciplines that, as determined by the Secretary, are critical to the national security functions of the Department of Defense and are needed in the Department of Defense workforce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Financial Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under the program under this section, the Secretary of Defense may award a scholarship or fellowship in accordance with this section to a person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a citizen of the United States or, subject to subsection (g), a country the government of which is a party to The Technical Cooperation Program (TTCP) memorandum of understanding of <date date="1995-10-24">October 24, 1995</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is pursuing an associates degree, undergraduate degree, or advanced degree in a critical skill or discipline described in subsection (a) at an accredited institution of higher education; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> enters into a service agreement with the Secretary of Defense as described in subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The amount of the financial assistance provided under a scholarship or fellowship awarded to a person under this subsection shall be an amount determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Financial assistance provided under a scholarship or fellowship awarded under this section may be paid directly to the recipient of such scholarship or fellowship or to an administering entity for disbursement of the funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service Agreement for Recipients of Financial Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To receive financial assistance under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an employee of the Department of Defense, the employee shall enter into a written agreement to continue in the employment of the department for the period of obligated service determined under paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a person not an employee of the Department of Defense, the person shall enter into a written agreement to accept and continue employment for the period of obligated service determined under paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> with the Department, including by serving on active duty in the Armed Forces; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> with a public or private entity or organization outside of the Department if the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is unable to find an appropriate position for the person within the Department; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> determines that employment of the person with such entity or organization for the purpose of such obligated service would provide a benefit to the Department.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this subsection, the period of obligated service for a recipient of financial assistance under this section shall be the period determined by the Secretary of Defense as being appropriate to obtain adequate service in exchange for such financial assistance. The period of service required of a recipient may not be less than the total period of pursuit of a degree that is covered by such financial assistance. The period of obligated service is in addition to any other period for which the recipient is obligated to serve in the civil service of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An agreement entered into under this subsection by a person pursuing an academic degree shall include any terms and conditions that the Secretary of Defense determines necessary to protect the interests of the United States or otherwise appropriate for carrying out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment of Program Participants</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may, without regard to any provision of title 5 governing appointment of employees to competitive service positions within the Department of Defense, appoint to a position in the Department of Defense in the excepted service an individual who has successfully completed an academic program for which a scholarship or fellowship under this section was awarded and who, under the terms of the agreement for such scholarship or fellowship, at the time of such appointment, owes a service commitment to the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may, upon satisfactory completion of 2 years of substantially continuous service by an incumbent who was appointed to an excepted service position under the authority of paragraph (1), convert the appointment of such individual, without competition, to a career or career conditional appointment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may establish arrangements so that participants may participate in a paid internship for an appropriate period with an industry sponsor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Refund for Period of Unserved Obligated Service</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A participant in the program under this section who is not an employee of the Department of Defense and who voluntarily fails to complete the educational program for which financial assistance has been provided under this section, or fails to maintain satisfactory academic progress as determined in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, shall refund to the United States an appropriate amount, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A participant in the program under this section who is an employee of the Department of Defense and who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> voluntarily fails to complete the educational program for which financial assistance has been provided, or fails to maintain satisfactory academic progress as determined in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> before completion of the period of obligated service required of such participant—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> voluntarily terminates such participant’s employment with the Department; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is removed from such participant’s employment with the Department on the basis of misconduct,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall refund the United States an appropriate amount, as determined by the Secretary.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An obligation to reimburse the United States imposed under paragraph (1) is for all purposes a debt owed to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive, in whole or in part, a refund required under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that recovery would be against equity and good conscience or would be contrary to the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A discharge in bankruptcy under title 11 that is entered less than five years after the termination of an agreement under this section does not discharge the person signing such agreement from a debt arising under such agreement or under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall coordinate the provision of financial assistance under the authority of this section with the provision of financial assistance under the other authorities provided in this chapter in order to maximize the benefits derived by the Department of Defense from the exercise of all such authorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into partnerships with minority institutions of higher education and appropriate public and private sector organizations to diversify the participants in the program under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In coordination with the efforts under paragraph (2), the Secretary of Defense shall additionally establish a program, which shall be known as the “Ronald V. Dellums Memorial Fellowship in STEM”, to provide financial assistance under this section to at least 30 students from communities that are underrepresented in the Department of Defense STEM workforce, not fewer of 50 percent of whom shall attend historically Black colleges and universities and minority-serving institutions. As part of such program, the Secretary shall establish an internship program that provides each student who is awarded a fellowship under this paragraph with an internship in an organization or element of the Department of Defense, and to the extent practicable, each such student shall be paired with a mid-level or a senior-level official of the relevant organization or element of the Department of Defense who shall serve as a mentor during the internship.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Participation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not award scholarships or fellowships under this section to more than five individuals described in paragraph (2) per year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An individual described in this paragraph is an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has not previously been awarded a scholarship or fellowship under the program under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not a citizen of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is a citizen of a country the government of which is a party to The Technical Cooperation Program (TTCP) memorandum of understanding of <date date="1995-10-24">October 24, 1995</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Institution of Higher Education Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XI, § 1104(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3449</ref>, § 2192a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title X, § 1061(a)(5), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4612</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XI, § 1102(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2484</ref>, 2485; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XI, § 1105(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 886</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3327</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 767</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 242</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3488</ref>; renumbered § 4093, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1843(a)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title X, § 1083</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2800</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4094.</num>
<heading> Enhanced pay authority for certain research and technology positions in science and technology reinvention laboratories</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may carry out a program using the pay authority specified in subsection (d) to fix the rate of basic pay for positions described in subsection (c) in order to assist the military departments in attracting and retaining high quality acquisition and technology experts in positions responsible for managing and performing complex, high-cost research and technology development efforts in the science and technology reinvention laboratories of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The program may be carried out in a military department only with the approval of the service acquisition executive of the military department concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The positions described in this subsection are positions in the science and technology reinvention laboratories of the Department of Defense that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require expertise of an extremely high level in a scientific, technical, professional, or acquisition management field; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> are critical to the successful accomplishment of an important research or technology development mission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rate of Basic Pay</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The pay authority specified in this subsection is authority as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Authority to fix the rate of basic pay for a position at a rate not to exceed 150 percent of the rate of basic pay payable for level I of the Executive Schedule, upon the approval of the service acquisition executive concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Authority to fix the rate of basic pay for a position at a rate in excess of 150 percent of the rate of basic pay payable for level I of the Executive Schedule, upon the approval of the Secretary of the military department concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority in subsection (a) may be used only to the extent necessary to competitively recruit or retain individuals exceptionally well qualified for positions described in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority in subsection (a) may not be used with respect to more than five positions in each military department at any one time, unless the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, in concurrence with the Secretaries of the military departments concerned, authorizes the transfer of positions from one military department to another.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term of positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority in subsection (a) may be used only for positions having a term of less than five years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Science and Technology Reinvention Laboratories of the Department of Defense Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “science and technology reinvention laboratories of the Department of Defense” means the laboratories designated as science and technology reinvention laboratories by <ref>section 4121(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XI, § 1106(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2817</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT CENTERS AND FACILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4121.</num>
<heading> Science and technology reinvention laboratories: authority and designation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may carry out personnel demonstration projects at Department of Defense laboratories designated by the Secretary as Department of Defense science and technology reinvention laboratories.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Each personnel demonstration project carried out under the authority of paragraph (1) shall be generally similar in nature to the China Lake demonstration project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of subparagraph (A), the China Lake demonstration project is the demonstration project that is authorized by section 6 of the Civil Service Miscellaneous Amendments Act of 1983 (<ref>Public Law 98–224</ref>) to be continued at the Naval Weapons Center, China Lake, California, and at the Naval Ocean Systems Center, San Diego, California.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary carries out a demonstration project at a laboratory pursuant to paragraph (1), <ref>section 4703 of title 5</ref> shall apply to the demonstration project, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subsection (d) of such section 4703 shall not apply to the demonstration project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the authority of the Secretary to carry out the demonstration project is that which is provided in paragraph (1) rather than the authority which is provided in such section 4703; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary shall exercise the authorities granted to the Office of Personnel Management under such section 4703 through the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering (who shall place an emphasis in the exercise of such authorities on enhancing efficient operations of the laboratory and who may, in exercising such authorities, request administrative support from science and technology reinvention laboratories to review, research, and adjudicate personnel demonstration project proposals).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The employees of a laboratory covered by a personnel demonstration project carried out under this section shall be exempt from, and may not be counted for the purposes of, any constraint or limitation in a statute or regulation in terms of supervisory ratios or maximum number of employees in any specific category or categories of employment that may otherwise be applicable to the employees. The employees shall be managed by the director of the laboratory subject to the supervision of the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The limitations in <ref>section 5373 of title 5</ref> do not apply to the authority of the Secretary under this subsection to prescribe salary schedules and other related benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Laboratories</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each of the following is hereby designated as a Department of Defense science and technology reinvention laboratory as described in subsection (a):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Air Force Research Laboratory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Joint Warfare Analysis Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Army Research Institute for the Behavioral and Social Sciences.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Combat Capabilities Development Command Armaments Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Combat Capabilities Development Command Army Research Laboratory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Combat Capabilities Development Command Aviation and Missile Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Combat Capabilities Development Command Chemical Biological Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The Combat Capabilities Development Command Command, Control, Communications, Computers, Cyber, Intelligence, Surveillance, and Reconnaissance Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The Combat Capabilities Development Command Ground Vehicle Systems Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The Combat Capabilities Development Command Soldier Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The Engineer Research and Development Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The Medical Research and Development Command.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> The Technical Center, US Army Space and Missile Defense Command.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> The Naval Air Systems Command Warfare Centers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> The Naval Facilities Engineering Command Engineering and Expeditionary Warfare Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> The Naval Information Warfare Centers, Atlantic and Pacific.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> The Naval Medical Research Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> The Naval Research Laboratory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> The Naval Sea Systems Command Warfare Centers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> The Office of Naval Research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conversion Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall implement procedures to convert the civilian personnel of each Department of Defense science and technology reinvention laboratory, as so designated by subsection (b), to the personnel system under an appropriate demonstration project (as referred to in subsection (a)). Any conversion under this subsection—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall not adversely affect any employee with respect to pay or any other term or condition of employment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be consistent with <ref>section 4703(f) of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be completed within 18 months after designation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall not apply to prevailing rate employees (as defined by <ref>section 5342(a)(2) of title 5</ref>) or senior executives (as defined by section 3132(a)(3) of such title).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The science and technology reinvention laboratories, as so designated by subsection (a), may not implement any personnel system, other than a personnel system under an appropriate demonstration project (as referred to subsection (a)), without prior congressional authorization.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title II, § 215(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1591</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4123.</num>
<heading> Mechanisms to provide funds for defense laboratories for research and development of technologies for military missions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mechanisms to Provide Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall establish mechanisms under which the director of a defense laboratory may use an amount of funds equal to not less than two percent and not more than four percent of all funds available to the defense laboratory for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To fund innovative basic and applied research that is conducted at the defense laboratory and supports military missions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To fund development programs that support the transition of technologies developed by the defense laboratory into operational use.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To fund workforce development activities that improve the capacity of the defense laboratory to recruit and retain personnel with necessary scientific and engineering expertise that support military missions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> To fund the repair or minor military construction of the laboratory infrastructure and equipment, in accordance with subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The mechanisms established under paragraph (1) shall provide that funding shall be used under paragraph (1) at the discretion of the director of a defense laboratory in consultation with the science and technology executive of the military department concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The science and technology executive of a military department may develop policies and guidance to leverage funding and promote cross-laboratory collaboration, including with laboratories of other military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> After consultation with the science and technology executive of the military department concerned, the director of a defense laboratory may charge customer activities a fixed percentage fee, in addition to normal costs of performance, in order to obtain funds to carry out activities authorized by this subsection. The fixed fee may not exceed four percent of costs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds for Infrastructure Projects</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds shall be available in accordance with subsection (a)(1)(D) only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary notifies the congressional defense committees of the total cost of the project before the date on which the Secretary uses the mechanism under such subsection for such project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary ensures that the project complies with the applicable cost limitations in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>section 2805(d) of this title</ref>, with respect to revitalization and recapitalization projects; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 2811 of this title</ref>, with respect to repair projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Release and Dissemination of Information on Contributions From Use of Authority to Military Missions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collection of information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish and maintain mechanisms for the continuous collection of information on achievements, best practices identified, lessons learned, and challenges arising in the exercise of the authority in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Release of information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall establish and maintain mechanisms as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Mechanisms for the release to the public of information on achievements and best practices described in paragraph (1) in unclassified form.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Mechanisms for dissemination to appropriate civilian and military officials of information on achievements and best practices described in paragraph (1) in classified form.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title II, § 220(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1332</ref>, § 2363; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title II, § 250</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1702</ref>; renumbered § 4123, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1843(b)(1)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4124.</num>
<heading> Centers for Science, Technology, and Engineering Partnership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall designate each science and technology reinvention laboratory as a Center for Science, Technology, and Engineering Partnership (in this section referred to as “Centers”) in the recognized core competencies of the designee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish a policy to encourage the Secretary of each military department to reengineer management and business processes and adopt best-business and personnel practices at the Centers of the Secretary concerned in connection with the capability requirements of the Centers, so as to serve as recognized leaders in such capabilities throughout the Department of Defense and in the national technology and industrial base.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense, acting through the directors of the Centers, may conduct one or more pilot programs, consistent with applicable requirements of law, to test any practices referred to in paragraph (2) that the Directors determine could—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improve the efficiency and effectiveness of operations at Centers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improve the support provided by the Centers for the elements of the Department of Defense who use the services of the Centers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> enhance capabilities by reducing the cost and improving the performance and efficiency of executing laboratory missions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public-private Partnerships</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To achieve one or more objectives set forth in paragraph (2), the Secretary may authorize and establish incentives for the Director of a Center to enter into public-private cooperative arrangements (in this section referred to as a “public-private partnership”) to provide for any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> For employees of the Center, academia, private industry, State and local governments, or other entities outside the Department of Defense to perform (under contract, subcontract, or otherwise) work related to the capabilities of the Center, including any work that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> involves one or more capabilities of the Center; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may be applicable to both the Department and commercial entities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For private industry or other entities outside the Department of Defense to use for either Government or commercial purposes any capabilities of the Center that are not fully used for Department of Defense activities for any period determined to be consistent with the needs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The objectives for exercising the authority provided in paragraph (1) are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To maximize the use of the capacity of a Center.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To reduce or eliminate the cost of ownership of a Center by the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To reduce the cost of science, technology, and engineering activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> To leverage private sector investment in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such efforts as research and equipment recapitalization for a Center; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the promotion of the undertaking of commercial business ventures based on the capabilities of a Center, as determined by the director of the Center.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> To foster cooperation and technology transfer between the armed forces, academia, private industry, and State and local governments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> To increase access by a Center to a skilled technical workforce that can contribute to the effective and efficient execution of the missions of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> To increase the ability of a Center to access and use non-Department of Defense methods to develop and innovate and access capabilities that contribute to the effective and efficient execution of the missions of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Public-private partnerships entered into under paragraph (1) may be used for purposes relating to technology transfer and other authorities described in subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The authorities described in this subparagraph are provisions of law that provide for cooperation and partnership by the Department of Defense with academia, private industry, and State and local governments, including the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Sections 3371 through 3375 of title 5.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Sections 2194, 2563, 4001, 4021, 4831, and 4062 of this title.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content><ref>Section 209 of title 35</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Sections 8, 12, and 23 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 3706</ref>, 3710a, and 3715).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Private Sector Use of Excess Capacity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any capability of a Center made available to the private sector may be used to perform research and testing activities in order to make more efficient and economical use of Government-owned capabilities and encourage the creation and preservation of jobs to ensure the availability of a workforce with the necessary research and technical skills to meet the needs of the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crediting of Amounts for Performance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts received by a Center for work performed under a public-private partnership may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be credited to the appropriation or fund, including a working-capital or revolving fund, that incurs the cost of performing the work; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be used by the Director of the Center as the Director considers appropriate and consistent with section 219 of the Duncan Hunter National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009 (<ref>Public Law 110–417</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2358</ref> note).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002130">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Excess Capacities to Private-sector Partners</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Capacities of a Center may be made available for use by a private-sector entity under this section only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the use of the capacities will not have a significant adverse effect on the performance of the Center or the ability of the Center to achieve the mission of the Center, as determined by the Director of the Center; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the private-sector entity agrees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to reimburse the Department of Defense when required in accordance with the guidance of the Department for the direct and indirect costs (including any rental costs) that are attributable to the use of the capabilities by the private-sector entity, as determined by the Secretary of the military departments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to hold harmless and indemnify the United States from—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any claim for damages or injury to any person or property arising out of the use of the capabilities, except under the circumstances described in <ref>section 2563(c)(3) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any liability or claim for damages or injury to any person or property arising out of a decision by the Secretary to suspend or terminate that use of capabilities during a war or national emergency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Partnership Intermediaries to Promote Defense Research and Education</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to the approval of the Secretary or the head of the another department or agency of the Federal Government concerned, the Director of a Center may enter into a contract, memorandum of understanding or other transaction with a partnership intermediary that provides for the partnership intermediary to perform services for the Department of Defense that increase the likelihood of success in the conduct of cooperative or joint activities of the Center with industry or academic institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “partnership intermediary” means an agency of a State or local government, or a nonprofit entity owned in whole or in part by, chartered by, funded in whole or in part by, or operated in whole or in part by or on behalf of a State or local government, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assists, counsels, advises, evaluates, or otherwise cooperates with industry or academic institutions that need or can make demonstrably productive use of technology-related assistance from a Center;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> facilitates technology transfer from industry or academic institutions to a Center; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assists and facilitates workforce development in critical technology areas for technology transition activities to fulfill unmet needs of a Center.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction of Provision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize a change, otherwise prohibited by law, from the performance of work at a Center by personnel of the Department of Defense to performance by a contractor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “capabilities”, with respect to a Center for Science, Technology, and Engineering Partnership, means the facilities, equipment, personnel, intellectual property, and other assets that support the core competencies of the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “national technology and industrial base” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 4801 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “science and technology reinvention laboratory” means a science and technology reinvention laboratory designated under <ref>section 4121(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 764</ref>, § 2368; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1690</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(45)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1814</ref>; renumbered § 4124 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1843(b)(1)</ref>, (d), as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(4)(A)</ref>, (C), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1844(b)(1), (c), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4245</ref>, 4246, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title II, § 215(d)(12)</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(u)(5)(B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1594</ref>, 2154; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4125.</num>
<heading> Functions of Defense research facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions of Defense Research Facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that Defense research facilities are assigned broad mission requirements rather than specific hardware needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that appropriate personnel of such facilities are assigned to serve as consultants on component and support system standardization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that the managers of such facilities have broad latitude to choose research and development projects based on awareness of activities throughout the technology domain, including within the Federal Government, the Department of Defense, public and private research institutions and universities, and the global commercial marketplace;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> that technology position and issue papers prepared by Defense research facilities are readily available to all components of the Department of Defense and to contractors who submit bids or proposals for Department of Defense contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> that, in order to promote increased consideration of technological issues early in the development process, any technological assessment made by a Defense research facility shall be provided to the Defense Technical Information Center repository to support acquisition decisions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> that, in light of Defense research facilities being funded by the public, Defense research facilities are broadly authorized and encouraged to support national technological development goals and support technological missions of other departments and agencies of the Federal Government, when such support is determined by the Secretary of Defense to be in the best interests of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “Defense research facility” means a Department of Defense facility which performs or contracts for the performance of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> basic research; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> applied research known as exploratory development.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1843(b)(2)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4126.</num>
<heading> Use of federally funded research and development centers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Use of Centers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense may not place work with a federally funded research and development center unless such work is within the purpose, mission, and general scope of effort of such center as established in the sponsoring agreement of the Department of Defense with such center.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception for Applied Scientific Research</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply to a federally funded research and development center that performs applied scientific research under laboratory conditions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Creation of New Centers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The head of an agency may not obligate or expend amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense for purposes of operating a federally funded research center that was not in existence before <date date="1986-06-02">June 2, 1986</date>, until—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the head of the agency submits to Congress a report with respect to such center that describes the purpose, mission, and general scope of effort of the center; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a period of 60 days beginning on the date such report is received by Congress has elapsed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “head of an agency” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 3004 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identification to Congress of FFRDC Workload Effort</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After the close of a fiscal year, and not later than January 1 of the next year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report setting forth the actual obligations and the actual man-years of effort expended at each federally funded research and development center during that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title X, § 912(a)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–82</ref>, 1783–146, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title X, § 912(a)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–82</ref>, 3341–146, § 2367; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IX</ref>, formerly title IV, § 912(a)(1), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3925</ref>, renumbered title IX, <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 273</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title II, § 256(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1330</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2645</ref>; renumbered § 4126, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1843(b)(1)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1844(b)(1), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4245</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4127.</num>
<heading> Defense Innovation Unit</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established in the Department of Defense a Defense Innovation Unit (referred to in this section as the “Unit”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director and Deputy Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a Director of the Unit who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Defense from among persons with substantial experience in innovation and commercial technology, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Director</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director is the head of the Unit. The Director—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall serve as a principal staff assistant to the Secretary of Defense on matters within the responsibility of the Unit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall report directly to the Secretary without intervening authority; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may communicate views on matters within the responsibility of the Unit directly to the Secretary without obtaining the approval or concurrence of any other official within the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Unit shall have the following responsibilities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Seek out, identify, and support development of and experimentation with commercial technologies that have the potential to be implemented within the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Accelerate the adoption or integration of commercial technologies within the Department of Defense to transform military capacity and capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Serve as the principal liaison between the Department of Defense and individuals and entities in the national security innovation base, including entrepreneurs, startups, commercial technology companies, and venture capital sources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Carry out programs, projects, and other activities to strengthen the national security innovation base.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Coordinate and harmonize the activities of other organizations and elements of the Department of Defense on matters relating to commercial technologies, dual use technologies, and the innovation of such technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Coordinate and advise efforts among elements of the Department of Defense on matters relating to the development, procurement, and fielding of nontraditional capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Coordinate with the Joint Staff and the commanders of the combatant commands to identify operational challenges that have the potential to be addressed through the use of nontraditional capabilities, including dual-use technologies, that are being developed and financed in the commercial sector.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> Using funds made available to the Unit—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> select projects to be carried out by one or more of the service-level innovation organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> allocate funds to service-level innovation organizations to carry out such projects; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> monitor the execution of such projects by the service-level innovation organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Serve as the principal liaison between the Department of Defense, nontraditional defense contractors, investors in nontraditional defense companies, and departments and agencies of the Federal Government pursing <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002131">1</ref> nontraditional capabilities similar to those pursued by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> Lead engagement with industry, academia, and other nongovernment entities to develop—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> domestic capacity with respect to innovative, commercial, and dual-use technologies and the use of nontraditional defense contractors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the capacity of international allies and partners of the United States with respect to such technologies and the use of such contractors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Carry out such other activities as the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Support for Multi-stakeholder Partnerships.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Director shall identify and support multi-stakeholder research and innovation partnerships that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have the potential to generate technologies, processes, products, or other solutions that address national defense or security needs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have as an objective the technology transfer or commercialization of the work product generated by the partnership, which may include work product that incorporates Government-developed intellectual property licensed to the partnership in accordance with paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Support provided by the Director to a multi-stakeholder research and innovation partnership under this subsection may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing funding or other resources to the partnership;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> participating in the partnership;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> providing technical and technological advice and guidance to the partnership;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> suggesting and introducing other participants for inclusion in the partnership;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> providing the partnership with insight into desired solutions for defense and security needs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> such other forms of support as the Director determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To the extent the Director determines appropriate, the Director shall seek to actively inform potential participants in multi-stakeholder research and innovation partnerships of the availability of Government-developed intellectual property that may be licensed to the partnership.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> On an annual basis, the Director shall submit to the Secretary of Defense and the congressional defense committees a report on the activities, advances, outcomes, and work product of the multi-stakeholder research and innovation partnerships supported under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “multi-stakeholder research and innovation partnership” means a partnership composed of any combination of two or more of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Universities, colleges, or other institutions of higher education with research and innovation capability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Non-profit organizations that provide policy, research, outreach, operations, organizational, management, testing, evaluation, technology transfer, legal, financial, or advocacy expertise.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> For-profit commercial enterprises that may be publicly or privately owned, early stage or mature, and incorporated or operating by another ownership structure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Departments or agencies of the Federal Government with expertise, operations, or resources related to the objectives of the multi-stakeholder research and innovation partnership.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “nontraditional capability” means a solution to an operational challenge that can significantly leverage commercial innovation or external capital with minimal dependencies on fielded systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “nontraditional defense contractor” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 3014 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title IX, § 913(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 365</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(43)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4128.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002132">1</ref></num>
<heading> Laboratory Quality Enhancement Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Required</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, shall carry out a program under which the Secretary shall establish the panels described in subsection (b) and direct such panels—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to review and make recommendations to the Secretary with respect to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> existing policies and practices affecting the science and technology reinvention laboratories to improve the mission effectiveness of such laboratories;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> new initiatives proposed by the science and technology reinvention laboratories; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> new interpretations of existing provisions of law that would enhance the ability of a director of a science and technology reinvention laboratory to manage the laboratory and discharge the mission of the laboratory;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to support implementation of current and future initiatives affecting the science and technology reinvention laboratories; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to conduct assessments or data analysis on the effectiveness of the authorities granted to the science and technology reinvention laboratories and such other issues as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The program carried out pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be known as the “Laboratory Quality Enhancement Program”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Panels</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The panels described in this subsection are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A panel on personnel, workforce development, and talent management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A panel on facilities, equipment, and infrastructure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A panel on research strategy, technology transfer, and industry and university partnerships.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A panel on governance and oversight processes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Composition of Panels</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Each panel described in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (b) may be composed of subject matter and technical management experts from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> laboratories and research centers of the Army, Navy, and Air Force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> appropriate Defense Agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such other entities as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The panel described in subsection (b)(4) shall be composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at least one member from each of the science and technology reinvention laboratories; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such other members as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Governance of Panels</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The chairperson of each panel established pursuant to subsection (a) shall be selected by the members of the respective panel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each panel, in coordination with the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, shall transmit to the Science and Technology Executive Committee of the Department of Defense such information or findings on topics requiring decision or approval as the panel considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interpretation of Provisions of Law</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, acting under the guidance of the Secretary, shall issue regulations regarding the meaning, scope, implementation, and applicability of any provision of a statute relating to a science and technology reinvention laboratory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In interpreting or defining under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall, to the degree practicable, emphasize providing the maximum operational flexibility to the directors of the science and technology reinvention laboratories to discharge the missions of their laboratories.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In interpreting or defining under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, consult and coordinate with the secretaries of the military departments and such other agencies or entities as the Under Secretary considers relevant on any proposed revision to regulations under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In interpreting or defining under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall seek recommendations from the panel described in subsection (b)(4).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Science and Technology Reinvention Laboratory Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “science and technology reinvention laboratory” means a Department of Defense laboratory designated as a Department of Defense science and technology reinvention laboratory under <ref>section 4121 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title II, § 217(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1825</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4128.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002133">1</ref></num>
<heading> Joint Federated Assurance Center</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is in the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering a Joint Federated Assurance Center (referred to in this section as the “Center”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The purpose of the Center shall be to serve as a joint, Department-wide federation of organizations and capabilities to support the assurance needs of the Department of Defense by ensuring, pursuant to policies related to hardware and software assurance and supply chain risk management, that the software and hardware developed, acquired, maintained, and used by the Department are free from intentional and unintentional vulnerability during the life-cycle of development and deployment of assured, trustworthy defense systems.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Governance.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Center shall be governed by an Executive Steering Group. The Executive Steering Group shall continually evaluate the Center’s capabilities to support the hardware and software assurance needs of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Executive Steering Group shall be composed of one or more representatives from each of the organizations that comprise the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering and the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall serve as co-Chairpersons of the Executive Steering Group.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The duties of the Center are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Providing knowledge management capabilities for hardware and software assurance for the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Providing Department-wide visibility on strategy, use cases, procurement, investment, and other relevant activities to aggregate, to the extent practicable, assurance tool purchases by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Developing and standardizing policies, procedures, competencies, risk assessment methodologies, and independent validation and verification test capabilities—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to support timely and cost-effective fielding of current and future technologies to the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to ensure sustainment of enduring capability needs across the life-cycle of Department of Defense programs and determine the sustainment factors related to the assurance of future hardware and software systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to increase efficiencies across Department of Defense programs through the use of emerging assurance technologies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to leverage economies of scale through coordinated acquisition and use of hardware and software assurance technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Promoting assurance capabilities for hardware and software assurance—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to mature assessment criteria and enable scalable deployment of commercial best practices, such as through the fostering and maturation of evidence-based assurance of trusted defense microelectronics system needs, with emphasis on commercial security protocols that are transferable to defense applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to scale the Center for Department-wide access, through the resourcing of adequate personnel to address standardization and automation of data collection and analysis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to utilize data from commercial assurance processes to support the development of Department hardware and software that meet standards, applications, and requirements, including through comparative analysis and data modeling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to seek and apply commercial best practices, where practicable, through industry collaboration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to develop and align Department policy, investments, and activities with commercial best practices, to the extent practicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> For contracts for application-specific integrated circuits designed by defense industrial base contractors, develop guidance for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the consideration of evidence-based assurance processes and techniques that are included in the contract data requirements list, to the extent practicable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use of commercial best practices, as applicable, for confidentiality, integrity and availability; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the development of a library of certified third-party intellectual property for reuse, including streamlining legal mechanisms for data collection and sharing, and enhanced use of automation technology to achieve efficiency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The assessment, creation, prototyping, maturation, and maintenance of relevant assurance practices, including the validation and maturation of evidence based assurance methods, for the development, procurement, and deployment of hardware and software assurance tools and processes, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> development and assessment of validation methods for such processes and techniques, in coordination with the developmental and operational test and evaluation community, as the Executive Steering Group determines necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> development and assessment of threat models that comprehensively characterize the threat to microelectronics confidentiality, integrity, and availability across the entire supply chain, and the design, production, packaging, and deployment cycle to support risk management and risk mitigation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> support development of guides to inform use and decision-making by program evaluators, program offices, and industry to meet software and hardware assurance requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Revised Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Defense shall issue a revised charter for the Center. The charter shall set forth—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the role and authorities of the Center and the Executive Steering Group;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the requirement of the Center to establish guidelines for the development of improved software code vulnerability analysis and testing tools;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the requirement of the Center to establish guidelines for the development of improved hardware vulnerability testing and protection tools; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the manner in which the Center will connect to the Department’s major governance and resourcing processes to ensure the continuation of Center duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title IX, § 922(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2037</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>