<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 108—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE SCHOOLS</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 2161.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LIII, § 5324(e)(1)</ref>, formerly § 5324(g)(1), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2137</ref>, renumbered § 5324(e)(1), <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. W, title III, § 305(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2367</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2162.</num>
<heading> Preparation of budget requests for operation of professional military education schools</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Uniform Cost Accounting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, with the advice and assistance of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, shall promulgate a uniform cost accounting system for use by the Secretaries of the military departments in preparing budget requests for the operation of professional military education schools.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preparation of Budget Requests</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Amounts requested for a fiscal year for the operation of each professional military education school shall be set forth as a separate budget request in the materials submitted by the Secretary of Defense to Congress in support of the budget request for the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> As executive agent for funding professional development education at the National Defense University, including the Joint Forces Staff College, the Secretary of Defense, with the advice of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, shall prepare the annual budget for professional development education operations at the National Defense University and set forth that request as a separate budget request in the materials submitted to Congress in support of the budget request for the Department of Defense. Nothing in the preceding sentence affects policies in effect on <date date="2001-12-28">December 28, 2001</date>, with respect to budgeting for the funding of logistical and base operations support for components of the National Defense University through the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department preparing a budget request for a professional military education school shall carefully consider the views of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, particularly with respect to the amount of the request for the operation of the schools of the National Defense University and the joint professional military education curricula of the other professional military education schools.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Comparison of Budget Requests</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Materials prepared in support of the budget request for a professional military education school shall describe whether the amount requested for that school is comparable to the amounts requested for other professional military education schools, taking into consideration the size and activities of the schools.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Professional Military Education Schools</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section applies to each of the following professional military education schools:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The National Defense University.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Army War College.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The College of Naval Warfare.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Air War College.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The United States Army Command and General Staff College.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The College of Naval Command and Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Air Command and Staff College.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The Marine Corps University.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1625</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title IX, § 921(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1862</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 527(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1102</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1062(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2163.</num>
<heading> Degree granting authority for National Defense University</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the President of the National Defense University may, upon the recommendation of the faculty of the National Defense University, confer appropriate degrees upon graduates who meet the degree requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A degree may not be conferred under this section unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Education has recommended approval of the degree in accordance with the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the National Defense University is accredited by the appropriate civilian academic accrediting agency or organization to award the degree, as determined by the Secretary of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> When seeking to establish degree granting authority under this section, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a copy of the self assessment questionnaire required by the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies, at the time the assessment is submitted to the Department of Education’s National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the subsequent recommendations and rationale of the Secretary of Education regarding the establishment of the degree granting authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon any modification or redesignation of existing degree granting authority, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing the rationale for the proposed modification or redesignation and any subsequent recommendation of the Secretary of Education on the proposed modification or redesignation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing an explanation of any action by the appropriate academic accrediting agency or organization not to accredit the National Defense University to award any new or existing degree.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 922(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1730</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 526(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 104</ref>, 105; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 543(b)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4457</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2164.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense domestic dependent elementary and secondary schools</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of Defense makes a determination that appropriate educational programs are not available through a local educational agency for dependents of members of the armed forces and dependents of civilian employees of the Federal Government residing on a military installation in the United States (including territories, commonwealths, and possessions of the United States), the Secretary may enter into arrangements to provide for the elementary or secondary education of the dependents of such members of the armed forces and, to the extent authorized in subsection (c), the dependents of such civilian employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may, at the discretion of the Secretary, permit dependents of members of the armed forces and, to the extent provided in subsection (c), dependents of civilian employees of the Federal Government residing in a territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States but not on a military installation, to enroll in an educational program provided by the Secretary pursuant to this subsection. If a member of the armed forces is assigned to a remote location or is assigned to an unaccompanied tour of duty, a dependent of the member who resides, on or off a military installation, in a territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States, as authorized by the member’s orders, may be enrolled in an educational program provided by the Secretary under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Under the circumstances described in subparagraph (B), the Secretary may, at the discretion of the Secretary, permit a dependent of a member of the armed forces to enroll in an educational program provided by the Secretary pursuant to this subsection without regard to the requirement in paragraph (1) with respect to residence on a military installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Subparagraph (A) applies only if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the dependents reside in temporary housing (regardless of whether the temporary housing is on Federal property)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> because of the unavailability of adequate permanent living quarters on the military installation to which the member is assigned; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> while the member is wounded, ill, or injured; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that the circumstances of such living arrangements justify extending the enrollment authority to include the dependents.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors for Secretary To Consider</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Factors to be considered by the Secretary of Defense in making a determination under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The extent to which such dependents are eligible for free public education in the local area adjacent to the military installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The extent to which the local educational agency is able to provide an appropriate educational program for such dependents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), an appropriate educational program is a program that, as determined by the Secretary, is comparable to a program of free public education provided for children by the following local educational agencies:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a military installation located in a State (other than an installation referred to in subparagraph (B)), local educational agencies in the State that are similar to the local educational agency referred to in paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of a military installation with boundaries contiguous to two or more States, local educational agencies in the contiguous States that are similar to the local educational agency referred to in paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In the case of a military installation located in a territory, commonwealth, or possession, the District of Columbia public schools, except that an educational program determined comparable under this subparagraph may be considered appropriate for the purposes of paragraph (1)(B) only if the program is conducted in the English language.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility of Dependents of Federal Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A dependent of a Federal employee residing in permanent living quarters on a military installation at any time during the school year may enroll in an educational program provided by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to subsection (a) for dependents residing on such installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A dependent of a United States Customs Service employee who resides in Puerto Rico, but not on a military installation, may enroll in an educational program provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) in Puerto Rico in accordance with the same rules as apply to a dependent of a Federal employee residing in permanent living quarters on a military installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), a dependent of a Federal employee who is enrolled in an educational program provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) and who is not residing on a military installation may be enrolled in the program for not more than five consecutive school years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> At the discretion of the Secretary, a dependent referred to in subparagraph (A) may be enrolled in the program for more than five consecutive school years if the dependent is otherwise qualified for enrollment, space is available in the program, and the Secretary will be reimbursed for the educational services provided. Any such extension shall cover only one school year at a time.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to an individual who is a dependent of a Federal employee in the excepted service (as defined in <ref>section 2103 of title 5</ref>) and who is enrolled in an educational program provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) in Puerto Rico, Wake Island, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a dependent covered by paragraph (1)(B). No requirement under this paragraph for reimbursement for educational services provided for the dependent shall apply with respect to the dependent, except that the Secretary may require the United States Customs Service to reimburse the Secretary for the cost of the educational services provided for the dependent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">School Advisory Committees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Director of the Department of Defense Education Activity, shall provide for the establishment of an advisory committee for each Department of Defense elementary or secondary school established at a military installation under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An advisory committee established under paragraph (1) for a school at a military installation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall advise the principal or superintendent of the school with respect to the operation of the school;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may make recommendations with respect to curriculum and budget matters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> except in the case of an advisory committee for a school on a military installation described in paragraph (4), shall advise the commander of the military installation with respect to problems concerning the education of dependents within the jurisdiction of the commander.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The membership of each advisory committee established for a school described in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall include an equal number of parents of students enrolled in the school and of employees working at the school; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> when appropriate, may include a student enrolled in the school.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In addition to the members described in subparagraph (A), the membership of each advisory committee shall include one nonvoting member designated by the organization recognized as the exclusive bargaining representative of the employees working at the school.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In the case of a military installation where there is more than one school in the Department of Defense elementary and secondary school system, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall provide for the establishment of an advisory committee for the military installation to advise the commander of the military installation with respect to the education of dependents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except in the case of a nonvoting member designated under paragraph (3)(B), members of an advisory committee established under this subsection shall be elected by individuals of voting age residing in the area to be served by the advisory committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall by regulation prescribe the qualifications for election to an advisory committee established under this subsection and procedures for conducting elections of members to such an advisory committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Members of an advisory committee established under this subsection shall serve without pay.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration and Staff</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may enter into such arrangements as may be necessary to provide educational programs at the school.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may, without regard to the provisions of any other law relating to the number, classification, or compensation of employees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish positions for civilian employees in schools established under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> appoint individuals to such positions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> fix the compensation of such individuals for service in such positions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in fixing the compensation of employees appointed for a school pursuant to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the compensation of comparable employees of the local educational agency in the capital of the State where the military installation is located;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the compensation of comparable employees in the local educational agency that provides public education to students who reside adjacent to the military installation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the average compensation for similar positions in not more than three other local educational agencies in the State in which the military installation is located.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In fixing the compensation of employees in schools established in the territories, commonwealths, and possessions pursuant to the authority of this section, the Secretary shall determine the level of compensation required to attract qualified employees. For employees in such schools, the Secretary, without regard to the provisions of title 5, may provide for the tenure, leave, hours of work, and other incidents of employment to be similar to that provided for comparable positions in the public schools of the District of Columbia. For purposes of the first sentence, a school established before the effective date of this section pursuant to authority similar to the authority in this section shall be considered to have been established pursuant to the authority of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may, without regard to the provisions of any law relating to the number, classification, or compensation of employees—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> transfer employees from schools established under this section to schools in the defense dependents’ education system in order to provide the services referred to in subparagraph (B) to such system; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> transfer employees from such system to schools established under this section in order to provide such services to those schools.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The services referred to in subparagraph (A) are the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Administrative services.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Logistical services.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Personnel services.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Such other services as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Transfers under this paragraph shall extend for such periods as the Secretary considers appropriate. The Secretary shall provide appropriate compensation for employees so transferred.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary may provide that the transfer of an employee under this paragraph occur without reimbursement of the school or system concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> In this paragraph, the term “defense dependents’ education system” means the program established and operated under section 1402(a) of the Defense Dependents’ Education Act of 1978 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 921(a)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Substantive and Procedural Rights and Protections for Children</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall provide the following substantive rights, protections, and procedural safeguards (including due process procedures) in the educational programs provided for under this section:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of children with disabilities aged 3 to 5, inclusive, all substantive rights, protections, and procedural safeguards (including due process procedures) available to children with disabilities aged 3 to 5, inclusive, under part B of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1411</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of infants or toddlers with disabilities, all substantive rights, protections, and procedural safeguards (including due process procedures) available to infants or toddlers with disabilities under part C of such Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1431</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In the case of all other children with disabilities, all substantive rights, protections, and procedural safeguards (including due process procedures) available to children with disabilities who are 3 to 5 years old under part B of such Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) may not be construed as diminishing for children with disabilities enrolled in day educational programs provided for under this section the extent of substantive rights, protections, and procedural safeguards that were available under <ref>section 6(a) of Public Law 81–874</ref> (<ref>20 U.S.C. 241(a)</ref>) to children with disabilities as of <date date="1991-10-07">October 7, 1991</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “children with disabilities” has the meaning given the term in section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1401</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “infants or toddlers with disabilities” has the meaning given the term in section 632 of such Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1432</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Secretary of Defense provides educational services under this section to an individual who is a dependent of an employee of a Federal agency outside the Department of Defense, the head of the other Federal agency shall, upon request of the Secretary of Defense, reimburse the Secretary for those services at rates routinely prescribed by the Secretary for those services. Any payments received by the Secretary under this subsection shall be credited to the account designated by the Secretary for the operation of educational programs under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuation of Enrollment Despite Change in Status</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall permit a dependent of a member of the armed forces or a dependent of a Federal employee to continue enrollment in an educational program provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) for the remainder of a school year notwithstanding a change during such school year in the status of the member or Federal employee that, except for this paragraph, would otherwise terminate the eligibility of the dependent to be enrolled in the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may, for good cause, authorize a dependent of a member of the armed forces or a dependent of a Federal employee to continue enrollment in an educational program provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) notwithstanding a change in the status of the member or employee that, except for this paragraph, would otherwise terminate the eligibility of the dependent to be enrolled in the program. The enrollment may continue for as long as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Paragraphs (1) and (2) do not limit the authority of the Secretary to remove a dependent from enrollment in an educational program provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) at any time for good cause determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">American Red Cross Employee Dependents in Puerto Rico</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may authorize the dependent of an American Red Cross employee described in paragraph (2) to enroll in an education program provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) in Puerto Rico if the American Red Cross agrees to reimburse the Secretary for the educational services so provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An employee referred to in paragraph (1) is an American Red Cross employee who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> resides in Puerto Rico; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> performs, on a full-time basis, emergency services on behalf of members of the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In determining the dependency status of any person for the purposes of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall apply the same definitions as apply to the determination of such status with respect to Federal employees in the administration of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Subsection (g) shall apply with respect to determining the reimbursement rates for educational services provided pursuant to this subsection. Amounts received as reimbursement for such educational services shall be treated in the same manner as amounts received under subsection (g).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tuition-free Enrollment of Dependents of Foreign Military Personnel Residing on Domestic Military Installations and Dependents of Certain Deceased Members of the Armed Forces</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may authorize the enrollment in a Department of Defense education program provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) of a dependent not otherwise eligible for such enrollment who is the dependent of a member of a foreign armed force residing on a military installation in the United States (including territories, commonwealths, and possessions of the United States). Enrollment of such a dependent shall be on a tuition-free basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may authorize the enrollment in a Department of Defense education program provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) of a dependent not otherwise eligible for such enrollment who is the dependent of a member of the armed forces who died in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an international terrorist attack against the United States or a foreign country friendly to the United States, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> military operations while serving outside the United States (including the commonwealths, territories, and possessions of the United States) as part of a peacekeeping force; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the line of duty in a combat-related operation, as designated by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Except as provided by clause (ii), enrollment of a dependent described in subparagraph (A) in a Department of Defense education program provided pursuant to subsection (a) shall be on a tuition-free, space available basis.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> In the case of a dependent described in subparagraph (A) residing on a military installation in the United States (including territories, commonwealths, and possessions of the United States), the Secretary may authorize enrollment of the dependent in a Department of Defense education program provided pursuant to subsection (a) on a tuition-free, space required basis.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enrollment of Relocated Defense Dependents’ Education System Students</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may authorize the enrollment in a Department of Defense education program provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) of a dependent of a member of the armed forces or a dependent of a Federal employee who is enrolled in the defense dependents’ education system established under section 1402 of the Defense Dependents’ Education Act of 1978 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 921</ref>) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the dependents departed the overseas location as a result of a evacuation order;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the designated safe haven of the dependent is located within reasonable commuting distance of a school operated by the Department of Defense education program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the school possesses the capacity and resources necessary to enable the student to attend the school.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Unless waived by the Secretary of Defense, a dependent described in paragraph (1) who is enrolled in a school operated by the Department of Defense education program pursuant to such paragraph may attend the school only through the end of the school year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enrollment in Virtual Elementary and Secondary Education Program</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary may authorize the enrollment in the virtual elementary and secondary education program established as a component of the Department of Defense education program of a dependent of a member of the armed forces on active duty who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is enrolled in an elementary or secondary school operated by a local educational agency or another accredited educational program in the United States (other than a school operated by the Department of Defense education program); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is a home-schooled student.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “home-schooled student” means a student in a grade equivalent to kindergarten or any of grades 1 through 12 who receives educational instruction at home or by other nontraditional means outside of a public or private school system, either all or most of the time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meal Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may administer a meal program, consistent with Federal law and standards prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture for that meal program, for students enrolled in a school established under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “meal program” means a program established under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1771</ref> et seq.) or the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2727</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1075</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1608</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title III, § 371(a)</ref>–(c)(2), <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1988</ref>, 1989; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 352, 353, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, § 361], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–76; <ref>Pub. L. 108–446, title III, § 305(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-03">Dec. 3, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2804</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 534</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 561</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4221</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 565</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1749</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title V, § 553(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(52)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4311</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 591–594(a), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1917–1919</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2164a.</num>
<heading> Rights of parents of children attending schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The parent of a child who attends a school operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity has the following rights:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The right to review the curriculum of the school.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The right to be informed if the school or the Department of Defense Education Activity alters the school’s academic standards or learning benchmarks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The right to meet with each teacher of their child not less than twice during each school year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The right to review all instructional materials used by their students.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The right to inspect a list of the books and other reading materials contained in the library of the school.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The right to address the school advisory committee or the school board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The right to data about the school’s discipline policy and any disciplinary action that results in a suspension or expulsion from the school, unless such disclosure is prohibited by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The right to information about any plans to eliminate gifted and talented programs or accelerated coursework at the school.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosures and Notifications</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Consistent with the parental rights specified in subsection (a) and except as provided by subsection (c), a school operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> post on a publicly accessible website of the school—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the curriculum for each course and grade level;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the academic standards or other learning benchmarks used by the school; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> notice of any proposed revisions to such standards or benchmarks and a copy of any such revisions;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> provide the parent of a child attending the school with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the opportunity to meet in person with each teacher of their child not less frequently than twice during each school year at a time mutually agreed upon by both parties; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> notice of such opportunity at the beginning of each school year;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide parents access to the online school library catalog;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> notify parents in a timely manner of any plans to eliminate gifted and talented programs or accelerated coursework at the school;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> except as provided by paragraph (6) or subsection (c), notify parents of any medical examinations or screenings the school may administer to their child and receive written consent from parents for any such examination or screening prior to conducting the examination or screening;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> in the event of an emergency that requires a medical examination or screening without time for parental notification, promptly notify parents of such examination or screening and provide an explanation of the emergency that prevented notification prior to such examination or screening; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> notify parents of any medical information that will be collected on their child, receive written parental consent prior to collecting such information, and provide parents an opportunity to inspect such information at the parent’s request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Paragraph (5) of subsection (a) and paragraph (3) of subsection (b) shall not be effective until the day that is two years after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A requirement set forth in subsection (b) shall not apply in a case in which the requirement would violate any applicable provision of a Federal or State statute or regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">School Advisory Committees and Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not less frequently than four times per year, a school advisory committee or school board for a school operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity shall provide parents of children attending the school with the opportunity to address the advisory committee or school board on any matters relating to the school or the educational services provided to their children.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “medical examination or screening”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a physical examination provided by a health care provider; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include an evaluation by, or an encounter with, non-clinical school staff.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “school” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a Department of Defense domestic dependent elementary or secondary school, as described in <ref>section 2164 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any elementary or secondary school or program for dependents operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 589(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2164b.</num>
<heading> Eligibility of certain dependents for enrollment in domestic dependent elementary and secondary schools</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025, the Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program under which a dependent of a full-time, active-duty member of the armed forces may enroll in a covered DODEA school at the military installation to which the member is assigned, on a space-available basis as described in subsection (b), without regard to whether the member resides on the installation as described in <ref>section 2164(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enrollment on Space-available Basis</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A student participating in the program under subsection (a) may be enrolled in a covered DODEA school only if the school has the capacity to accept the student, as determined by the Director of the Department of Defense Education Activity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Locations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall select military installations for participation in the program under subsection (a) based on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the readiness needs of the Secretary of the military department concerned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the capacity of the covered DODEA schools located at the installation to accept additional students, as determined by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Briefings Required.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2025-04-01">April 1, 2025</date>, and annually thereafter for four years, the Secretary shall brief the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives on the program under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each briefing required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An identification of the military installations participating in the program under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The number of students enrolled in covered DODEA schools under the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notifications of Participating Installations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 90 days before officially announcing the participation of a new military installation in the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall notify the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives with respect to the participation of the installation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered DODEA School Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “covered DODEA school” means a domestic dependent elementary or secondary school operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> was established on or before the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is located in the continental United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 595(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1919</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2165.</num>
<heading> National Defense University: component institutions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a National Defense University in the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Component Institutions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The National Defense University consists of the following institutions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The National War College.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Dwight D. Eisenhower School for National Security and Resource Strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Joint Forces Staff College.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Institute for National Strategic Studies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The College of Information and Cyberspace.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The College of International Security Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Any other educational institution of the Department of Defense that the Secretary considers appropriate and designates as an institution of the university.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(c)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title IX, § 904(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2353</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Source of Funds for Professional Development Education Operations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funding for the professional development education operations of the National Defense University shall be provided from funds made available to the Secretary of Defense from the annual appropriation “Operation and Maintenance, Defense-wide”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Faculty Research Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may authorize the President of the National Defense University to accept qualifying research grants. Any such grant may only be accepted if the work under the grant is to be carried out by a professor or instructor of one of the institutions comprising the University for a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A qualifying research grant under this subsection is a grant that is awarded on a competitive basis by an entity referred to in paragraph (3) for a research project with a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A grant may be accepted under this subsection only from a corporation, fund, foundation, educational institution, or similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific, literary, or educational purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish an account for administering funds received as research grants under this subsection. The President of the University shall use the funds in the account in accordance with applicable provisions of the regulations and the terms and condition of the grants received.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the National Defense University may be used to pay expenses incurred by the University in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, the award of qualifying research grants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Research and Development Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In engaging in research and development projects pursuant to subsection (a) of <ref>section 4001 of this title</ref> by a contract, cooperative agreement, or grant pursuant to subsection (b)(1) of such section, the Secretary may enter into such contract or cooperative agreement or award such grant through the National Defense University.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The National Defense University shall be considered a Government-operated Federal laboratory for purposes of section 12 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 3710a</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title IX</ref>, §§ 921(a)(1), 922(a), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1862</ref>, 1863; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title IX</ref>, §§ 904, 905(a), <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2093</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title IX, § 913(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–230; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 527(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1102</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 522(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3240</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title IX, § 904(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2861(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1701</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, title XVI, § 1648(a), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2048</ref>, 2606; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1841(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4244</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title IX, § 912</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 365</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2166.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 343]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2167.</num>
<heading> National Defense University: admission of private sector civilians to professional military education program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority for Admission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may permit eligible private sector employees who work in organizations relevant to national security to receive instruction at the National Defense University in accordance with this section. No more than the equivalent of 35 full-time student positions may be filled at any one time by private sector employees enrolled under this section. Upon successful completion of the course of instruction in which enrolled, any such private sector employee may be awarded an appropriate diploma or degree under <ref>section 2165 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Private Sector Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, an eligible private sector employee is an individual employed by a private firm that is engaged in providing to the Department of Defense or other Government departments or agencies significant and substantial defense-related systems, products, or services or whose work product is relevant to national security policy or strategy. A private sector employee admitted for instruction at the National Defense University remains eligible for such instruction only so long as that person remains employed by the same firm.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Certification by Secretary of Defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Private sector employees may receive instruction at the National Defense University during any academic year only if, before the start of that academic year, the Secretary of Defense determines, and certifies to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, that providing instruction to private sector employees under this section during that year will further national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the curriculum for the professional military education program in which private sector employees may be enrolled under this section is not readily available through other schools and concentrates on national security relevant issues; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the course offerings at the National Defense University continue to be determined solely by the needs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tuition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President of the National Defense University shall charge students enrolled under this section a rate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that is at least the rate charged for employees of the United States outside the Department of Defense, less infrastructure costs, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that considers the value to the school and course of the private sector student.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards of Conduct</inline>.—</heading>
<content>While receiving instruction at the National Defense University, students enrolled under this section, to the extent practicable, are subject to the same regulations governing academic performance, attendance, norms of behavior, and enrollment as apply to Government civilian employees receiving instruction at the university.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts received by the National Defense University for instruction of students enrolled under this section shall be retained by the university to defray the costs of such instruction. The source, and the disposition, of such funds shall be specifically identified in records of the university.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 528(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1102</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 526</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 592</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4232</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2167a.</num>
<heading> Defense Cyber Investigations Training Academy: admission of private sector civilians to receive instruction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority for Admission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may permit eligible private sector employees to receive instruction at the Defense Cyber Investigations Training Academy operating under the direction of the Defense Cyber Crime Center. No more than the equivalent of 200 full-time student positions may be filled at any one time by private sector employees enrolled under this section, on a yearly basis. Upon successful completion of the course of instruction in which enrolled, any such private sector employee may be awarded an appropriate certification or diploma.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Private Sector Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, an eligible private sector employee is an individual employed by a private firm that is engaged in providing to the Department of Defense or other Government departments or agencies significant and substantial defense-related systems, products, or services, or whose work product is relevant to national security policy or strategy. A private sector employee remains eligible for such instruction only so long as that person remains employed by an eligible private sector firm.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the curriculum in which private sector employees may be enrolled under this section is not readily available through other schools; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the course offerings at the Defense Cyber Investigations Training Academy continue to be determined solely by the needs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tuition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall charge private sector employees enrolled under this section tuition at a rate that is at least equal to the rate charged for employees of the United States. In determining tuition rates, the Secretary shall include overhead costs of the Defense Cyber Investigations Training Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards of Conduct</inline>.—</heading>
<content>While receiving instruction at the Defense Cyber Investigations Training Academy, students enrolled under this section, to the extent practicable, are subject to the same regulations governing academic performance, attendance, norms of behavior, and enrollment as apply to Government civilian employees receiving instruction at the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts received by the Defense Cyber Investigations Training Academy for instruction of students enrolled under this section shall be retained by the Academy to defray the costs of such instruction. The source, and the disposition, of such funds shall be specifically identified in records of the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2168.</num>
<heading> Defense Language Institute Foreign Language Center: degree of Associate or Bachelor of Arts in foreign language</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to subsection (b), the Commandant of the Defense Language Institute may confer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an Associate of Arts degree in a foreign language upon any graduate of the Foreign Language Center of the Institute who fulfills the requirements for that degree; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a Bachelor of Arts degree in a foreign language upon any graduate of the Foreign Language Center of the Institute who fulfills the requirements for that degree.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A degree may be conferred upon a student under this section only if the Provost of the Center certifies to the Commandant that the student has satisfied all the requirements prescribed for the degree.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The authority provided by subsection (a) shall be exercised under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 531(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1104</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 556(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1739</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2169.</num>
<heading> School of Nursing: establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish a School of Nursing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Degree Granting Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The School of Nursing may include a program that awards a bachelor of science in nursing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Phased Development</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may develop the School of Nursing in phases as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 525(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>