<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 107—</num>
<heading>PROFESSIONAL MILITARY EDUCATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2151.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joint Professional Military Education</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Joint professional military education consists of the rigorous and thorough instruction and examination of officers of the armed forces in an environment designed to promote a theoretical and practical in-depth understanding of joint matters and, specifically, of the subject matter covered. The subject matter to be covered by joint professional military education shall include at least the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> National Military Strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Joint planning at all levels of war.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Joint doctrine.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Joint command and control.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Joint force and joint requirements development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Operational contract support.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “senior level service school” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Army War College.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The College of Naval Warfare.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Air War College.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Marine Corps War College.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “intermediate level service school” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The United States Army Command and General Staff College.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The College of Naval Command and Staff.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Air Command and Staff College.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Marine Corps Command and Staff College.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “joint intermediate level school” includes the National Intelligence University.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1897</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 552(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VIII, § 845(c)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1848</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 554</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1896</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2152.</num>
<heading> Joint professional military education: general requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall implement a comprehensive framework for the joint professional military education of officers, including officers nominated under <ref>section 661 of this title</ref> for the joint specialty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joint Military Education Schools</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, with the advice and assistance of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, shall periodically review and revise the curriculum of each school of the National Defense University (and of any other joint professional military education school) to enhance the education and training of officers in joint matters. The Secretary shall require such schools to maintain rigorous standards for the military education of officers with the joint specialty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Professional Military Education Schools</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall require that each Department of Defense school concerned with professional military education periodically review and revise its curriculum for senior and intermediate grade officers in order to strengthen the focus on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> joint matters; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> preparing officers for joint duty assignments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(2)</ref>, (b), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1897</ref>, 1900.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2153.</num>
<heading> Capstone course: newly selected general and flag officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each officer selected for promotion to the grade of brigadier general or, in the case of the Navy or the commissioned officer corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, rear admiral (lower half) shall be required, after such selection, to attend a military education course designed specifically to prepare new general and flag officers to work with the other uniformed services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Commerce, as applicable, may waive subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an officer whose immediately previous assignment was in a joint duty assignment and who is thoroughly familiar with joint matters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> when necessary for the good of the service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of an officer whose proposed selection for promotion is based primarily upon scientific and technical qualifications for which joint requirements do not exist (as determined under regulations prescribed under section 619(e)(4) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002083">1</ref> of this title); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in the case of a medical officer, dental officer, veterinary officer, medical service officer, nurse, biomedical science officer, or chaplain.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary of Defense to grant a waiver under paragraph (1) may only be delegated to the Deputy Secretary of Defense, an Under Secretary of Defense, or an Assistant Secretary of Defense. Such a waiver may be granted only on a case-by-case basis in the case of an individual officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1897</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–259, title II, § 205(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2154.</num>
<heading> Joint professional military education: three-phase approach</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Three-Phase Approach</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall implement a three-phase approach to joint professional military education, as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There shall be a course of instruction, designated and certified by the Secretary of Defense with the advice and assistance of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff as Phase I instruction, consisting of all the elements of a joint professional military education (as specified in <ref>section 2151(a) of this title</ref>), in addition to the principal curriculum taught to all officers at an intermediate level service school or at a joint intermediate level school.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> There shall be a course of instruction, designated and certified by the Secretary of Defense with the advice and assistance of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff as Phase II instruction, consisting of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a joint professional military education curriculum taught in residence at, or offered through, the Joint Forces Staff College or a senior level service school that has been designated and certified by the Secretary of Defense as a joint professional military education institution; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a senior level service course of at least ten months that has been designated and certified by the Secretary of Defense as a joint professional military education course.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> There shall be a course of instruction, designated and certified by the Secretary of Defense with the advice and assistance of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff as the Capstone course, for officers selected for promotion to the grade of brigadier general or, in the case of the Navy, rear admiral (lower half) and offered in accordance with <ref>section 2153 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sequenced Approach</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall require the sequencing of joint professional military education so that the standard sequence of assignments for such education requires an officer to complete Phase I instruction before proceeding to Phase II instruction, as provided in <ref>section 2155(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distance Education</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any distance education program offered to satisfy Phase I or Phase II instruction under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) shall include a pathway for a student who is a member of a reserve component to fully complete the course of instruction while physically separated from the course instructors and without any in-person attendance required to graduate from such program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “distance education” has the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1003</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1898</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 552(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 554</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 824</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 555</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1896</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2155.</num>
<heading> Joint professional military education Phase II program of instruction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prerequisite of Completion of Joint Professional Military Education Phase I Program of Instruction</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> After <date date="2009-09-30">September 30, 2009</date>, an officer of the armed forces may not be accepted for, or assigned to, a program of instruction designated by the Secretary of Defense as joint professional military education Phase II unless the officer has successfully completed a program of instruction designated by the Secretary of Defense as joint professional military education Phase I.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff may grant exceptions to the requirement under paragraph (1). Such an exception may be granted only on a case-by-case basis under exceptional circumstances, as determined by the Chairman. An officer selected to receive such an exception shall have knowledge of joint matters and other aspects of the Phase I curriculum that, to the satisfaction of the Chairman, qualifies the officer to meet the minimum requirements established for entry into Phase II instruction without first completing Phase I instruction. The number of officers selected to attend an offering of the principal course of instruction at the Joint Forces Staff College or a senior level service school designated by the Secretary of Defense as a joint professional military education institution who have not completed Phase I instruction should comprise no more than 10 percent of the total number of officers selected.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Phase II Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall require that the curriculum for Phase II joint professional military education at any school—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> focus on developing joint operational expertise and perspectives and honing joint warfighting skills; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> be structured—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> so as to adequately prepare students to perform effectively in an assignment to a joint, multiservice organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> so that students progress from a basic knowledge of joint matters learned in Phase I instruction to the level of expertise necessary for successful performance in the joint arena.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Curriculum Content</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the subjects specified in <ref>section 2151(a) of this title</ref>, the curriculum for Phase II joint professional military education shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> National security strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Theater strategy and campaigning.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Joint planning processes and systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Joint, interagency, and multinational capabilities and the integration of those capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Student Ratio; Faculty Ratio</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than <date date="2009-09-30">September 30, 2009</date>, for courses of instruction in a Phase II program of instruction that is offered at senior level service school that has been designated by the Secretary of Defense as a joint professional military education institution—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the percentage of students enrolled in any such course who are officers of the armed force that administers the school may not exceed 60 percent, with the remaining services proportionally represented; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> of the faculty at the school who are active-duty officers who provide instruction in such courses, the percentage who are officers of the armed force that administers the school may not exceed 60 percent, with the remaining services proportionally represented.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1898</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(13)</ref>, (14), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2399</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2156.</num>
<heading> Joint Forces Staff College: duration of principal course of instruction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The duration of the principal course of instruction offered at the Joint Forces Staff College may not be less than 10 weeks of resident instruction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “principal course of instruction” means any course of instruction offered at the Joint Forces Staff College as Phase II joint professional military education.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2157.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(10)(A)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1560</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>