<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>MILITARY SUPPORT FOR CIVILIAN LAW ENFORCEMENT AGENCIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 271.</num>
<heading> Use of information collected during military operations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may, in accordance with other applicable law, provide to Federal, State, or local civilian law enforcement officials any information collected during the normal course of military training or operations that may be relevant to a violation of any Federal or State law within the jurisdiction of such officials.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The needs of civilian law enforcement officials for information shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be taken into account in the planning and execution of military training or operations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure, to the extent consistent with national security, that intelligence information held by the Department of Defense and relevant to drug interdiction or other civilian law enforcement matters is provided promptly to appropriate civilian law enforcement officials.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 905(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1115</ref>, § 371; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2043</ref>; renumbered § 271, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 272.</num>
<heading> Use of military equipment and facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may, in accordance with other applicable law, make available any equipment (including associated supplies or spare parts), base facility, or research facility of the Department of Defense to any Federal, State, or local civilian law enforcement official for law enforcement purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 905(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1115</ref>, § 372; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 378</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1416(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2723</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title III, § 351</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1701</ref>; renumbered § 272, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 273.</num>
<heading> Training and advising civilian law enforcement officials</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may, in accordance with other applicable law, make Department of Defense personnel available—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to train Federal, State, and local civilian law enforcement officials in the operation and maintenance of equipment, including equipment made available under section 372 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002026">1</ref> of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide such law enforcement officials with expert advice relevant to the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 905(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1115</ref>, § 373; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIV, § 1423(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2043</ref>; renumbered § 273, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 274.</num>
<heading> Maintenance and operation of equipment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may, in accordance with other applicable law, make Department of Defense personnel available for the maintenance of equipment for Federal, State, and local civilian law enforcement officials, including equipment made available under section 372 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002027">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2) and in accordance with other applicable law, the Secretary of Defense may, upon request from the head of a Federal law enforcement agency, make Department of Defense personnel available to operate equipment (including equipment made available under section 372 <sup>1</sup> of this title) with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a criminal violation of a provision of law specified in paragraph (4)(A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assistance that such agency is authorized to furnish to a State, local, or foreign government which is involved in the enforcement of similar laws;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a foreign or domestic counter-terrorism operation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a rendition of a suspected terrorist from a foreign country to the United States to stand trial.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Department of Defense personnel made available to a civilian law enforcement agency under this subsection may operate equipment for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Detection, monitoring, and communication of the movement of air and sea traffic.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Detection, monitoring, and communication of the movement of surface traffic outside of the geographic boundary of the United States and within the United States not to exceed 25 miles of the boundary if the initial detection occurred outside of the boundary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Aerial reconnaissance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Interception of vessels or aircraft detected outside the land area of the United States for the purposes of communicating with such vessels and aircraft to direct such vessels and aircraft to go to a location designated by appropriate civilian officials.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Operation of equipment to facilitate communications in connection with law enforcement programs specified in paragraph (4)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to joint approval by the Secretary of Defense and the Attorney General (and the Secretary of State in the case of a law enforcement operation outside of the land area of the United States)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the transportation of civilian law enforcement personnel along with any other civilian or military personnel who are supporting, or conducting, a joint operation with civilian law enforcement personnel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the operation of a base of operations for civilian law enforcement and supporting personnel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the transportation of suspected terrorists from foreign countries to the United States for trial (so long as the requesting Federal law enforcement agency provides all security for such transportation and maintains custody over the suspect through the duration of the transportation).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Department of Defense personnel made available to operate equipment for the purpose stated in paragraph (2)(D) may continue to operate such equipment into the land area of the United States in cases involving the pursuit of vessels or aircraft where the detection began outside such land area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Federal law enforcement agency” means a Federal agency with jurisdiction to enforce any of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Controlled Substances Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.) or the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 951</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Any of sections 274 through 278 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1324–132</ref>8).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A law relating to the arrival or departure of merchandise (as defined in section 401 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 1401</ref>) into or out of the customs territory of the United States (as defined in general note 2 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States) or any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Chapter 705 of title 46.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Any law, foreign or domestic, prohibiting terrorist activities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “land area of the United States” includes the land area of any territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may, in accordance with other applicable law, make Department of Defense personnel available to any Federal, State, or local civilian law enforcement agency to operate equipment for purposes other than described in subsection (b)(2) only to the extent that such support does not involve direct participation by such personnel in a civilian law enforcement operation unless such direct participation is otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 905(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1115</ref>, § 374; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(9)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title III, § 3056</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–77</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIII, § 1373(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4007</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1214(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1155</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XII</ref>, §§ 1210, 1216(b), (c), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1566</ref>, 1569; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1042</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2492</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. B, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–567</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1706</ref>; renumbered § 274, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 275.</num>
<heading> Restriction on direct participation by military personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to ensure that any activity (including the provision of any equipment or facility or the assignment or detail of any personnel) under this chapter does not include or permit direct participation by a member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps in a search, seizure, arrest, or other similar activity unless participation in such activity by such member is otherwise authorized by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX</ref> § 905(a)(1), <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1116</ref>, § 375; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2045</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XII, § 1211</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1567</ref>; renumbered § 275, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 276.</num>
<heading> Support not to affect adversely military preparedness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Support (including the provision of any equipment or facility or the assignment or detail of any personnel) may not be provided to any civilian law enforcement official under this chapter if the provision of such support will adversely affect the military preparedness of the United States. The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to ensure that the provision of any such support does not adversely affect the military preparedness of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86</ref>, title, IX, § 905(a)(1), <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1116</ref>, § 376; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2045</ref>; renumbered § 276, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 277.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (c), to the extent otherwise required by <ref>section 1535 of title 31</ref> (popularly known as the “Economy Act”) or other applicable law, the Secretary of Defense shall require a civilian law enforcement agency to which support is provided under this chapter to reimburse the Department of Defense for that support.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense shall require a Federal agency to which law enforcement support or support to a national special security event is provided by National Guard personnel performing duty under <ref>section 502(f) of title 32</ref> to reimburse the Department of Defense for the costs of that support, notwithstanding any other provision of law. No other provision of this chapter shall apply to such support.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Any funds received by the Department of Defense under this subsection as reimbursement for support provided by personnel of the National Guard shall be credited, at the election of the Secretary of Defense, to the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The appropriation, fund, or account used to fund the support.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The appropriation, fund, or account currently available for reimbursement purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> An agency to which support is provided under this chapter or <ref>section 502(f) of title 32</ref> is not required to reimburse the Department of Defense for such support if the Secretary of Defense waives reimbursement. The Secretary may waive the reimbursement requirement under this subsection if such support—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is provided in the normal course of military training or operations; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> results in a benefit to the element of the Department of Defense or personnel of the National Guard providing the support that is substantially equivalent to that which would otherwise be obtained from military operations or training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 905(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1116</ref>, § 377; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2045</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1061</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 319</ref>; renumbered § 277, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 278.</num>
<heading> Nonpreemption of other law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to limit the authority of the executive branch in the use of military personnel or equipment for civilian law enforcement purposes beyond that provided by law before <date date="1981-12-01">December 1, 1981</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 905(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1116</ref>, § 378; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(10)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2045</ref>; renumbered § 278, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 279.</num>
<heading> Assignment of Coast Guard personnel to naval vessels for law enforcement purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide that there be assigned on board every appropriate surface naval vessel at sea in a drug-interdiction area members of the Coast Guard who are trained in law enforcement and have powers of the Coast Guard under title 14, including the power to make arrests and to carry out searches and seizures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Members of the Coast Guard assigned to duty on board naval vessels under this section shall perform such law enforcement functions (including drug-interdiction functions)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as may be agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as are otherwise within the jurisdiction of the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> No fewer than 500 active duty personnel of the Coast Guard shall be assigned each fiscal year to duty under this section. However, if at any time the Secretary of Homeland Security, after consultation with the Secretary of Defense, determines that there are insufficient naval vessels available for purposes of this section, such personnel may be assigned other duty involving enforcement of laws listed in section 374(b)(4)(A) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002028">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “drug-interdiction area” means an area outside the land area of the United States (as defined in section 374(b)(4)(B) <sup>1</sup> of this title) in which the Secretary of Defense (in consultation with the Attorney General) determines that activities involving smuggling of drugs into the United States are ongoing.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title III, § 3053(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–75</ref>, § 379; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2045</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; renumbered § 279, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 280.</num>
<heading> Enhancement of cooperation with civilian law enforcement officials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, in cooperation with the Attorney General, shall conduct an annual briefing of law enforcement personnel of each State (including law enforcement personnel of the political subdivisions of each State) regarding information, training, technical support, and equipment and facilities available to civilian law enforcement personnel from the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Each briefing conducted under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An explanation of the procedures for civilian law enforcement officials—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to obtain information, equipment, training, expert advice, and other personnel support under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to obtain surplus military equipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of the types of information, equipment and facilities, and training and advice available to civilian law enforcement officials from the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A current, comprehensive list of military equipment which is suitable for law enforcement officials from the Department of Defense or available as surplus property from the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General and the Administrator of General Services shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish or designate an appropriate office or offices to maintain the list described in subsection (b)(3) and to furnish information to civilian law enforcement officials on the availability of surplus military equipment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make available to civilian law enforcement personnel nationwide, tollfree telephone communication with such office or offices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XII, § 1243(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1163</ref>, § 380; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2046</ref>; renumbered § 280, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 281.</num>
<heading> Procurement of equipment by State and local governments through the Department of Defense: equipment for counter-drug, homeland security, and emergency response activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall establish procedures in accordance with this subsection under which States and units of local government may purchase equipment suitable for counter-drug, homeland security, and emergency response activities through the Department of Defense. The procedures shall require the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Each State desiring to participate in a procurement of equipment suitable for counter-drug, homeland security, or emergency response activities through the Department of Defense shall submit to the Department, in such form and manner and at such times as the Secretary prescribes, the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A request for equipment.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Advance payment for such equipment, in an amount determined by the Secretary based on estimated or actual costs of the equipment and administrative costs incurred by the Department.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A State may include in a request submitted under subparagraph (A) only the type of equipment listed in the catalog produced under subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A request for equipment shall consist of an enumeration of the equipment that is desired by the State and units of local government within the State. The Governor of a State may establish such procedures as the Governor considers appropriate for administering and coordinating requests for equipment from units of local government within the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A State requesting equipment shall be responsible for arranging and paying for shipment of the equipment to the State and localities within the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In establishing the procedures, the Secretary of Defense shall coordinate with the General Services Administration and other Federal agencies for purposes of avoiding duplication of effort.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement of Administrative Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of any purchase made by a State or unit of local government under the procedures established under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall require the State or unit of local government to reimburse the Department of Defense for the administrative costs to the Department of such purchase.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">GSA Catalog</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Administrator of General Services, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall produce and maintain a catalog of equipment suitable for counter-drug, homeland security, and emergency response activities for purchase by States and units of local government under the procedures established by the Secretary under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “unit of local government” means any city, county, township, town, borough, parish, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State; an Indian tribe which performs law enforcement or emergency response functions as determined by the Secretary of the Interior; or any agency of the District of Columbia government or the United States Government performing law enforcement or emergency response functions in and for the District of Columbia or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “equipment suitable for counter-drug, homeland security, and emergency response activities” has the meaning given such term in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. In prescribing the meaning of the term, the Secretary may not include any equipment that the Department of Defense does not procure for its own purposes and, in the case of equipment for homeland security activities, may not include any equipment that is not found on the Authorized Equipment List published by the Department of Homeland Security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1122(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1754</ref>, § 381; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 885(a), (b)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4560</ref>, 4561; renumbered § 281, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 282.</num>
<heading> Emergency situations involving weapons of mass destruction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, upon the request of the Attorney General, may provide assistance in support of Department of Justice activities relating to the enforcement of section 175, 229, or 2332a of title 18 during an emergency situation involving a weapon of mass destruction. Department of Defense resources, including personnel of the Department of Defense, may be used to provide such assistance if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense and the Attorney General jointly determine that an emergency situation exists; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense determines that the provision of such assistance will not adversely affect the military preparedness of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Emergency Situations Covered</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “emergency situation involving a weapon of mass destruction” means a circumstance involving a weapon of mass destruction—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that poses a serious threat to the interests of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> civilian expertise and capabilities are not readily available to provide the required assistance to counter the threat immediately posed by the weapon involved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> special capabilities and expertise of the Department of Defense are necessary and critical to counter the threat posed by the weapon involved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> enforcement of section 175, 229, or 2332a of title 18 would be seriously impaired if the Department of Defense assistance were not provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forms of Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The assistance referred to in subsection (a) includes the operation of equipment (including equipment made available under section 372 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002029">1</ref> of this title) to monitor, contain, disable, or dispose of the weapon involved or elements of the weapon.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense and the Attorney General shall jointly prescribe regulations concerning the types of assistance that may be provided under this section. Such regulations shall also describe the actions that Department of Defense personnel may take in circumstances incident to the provision of assistance under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the regulations may not authorize the following actions:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Arrest.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Any direct participation in conducting a search for or seizure of evidence related to a violation of section 175, 229, or 2332a of title 18.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Any direct participation in the collection of intelligence for law enforcement purposes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The regulations may authorize an action described in subparagraph (A) to be taken under the following conditions:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The action is considered necessary for the immediate protection of human life, and civilian law enforcement officials are not capable of taking the action.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The action is otherwise authorized under subsection (c) or under otherwise applicable law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall require reimbursement as a condition for providing assistance under this section to the extent required under section 377 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegations of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except to the extent otherwise provided by the Secretary of Defense, the Deputy Secretary of Defense may exercise the authority of the Secretary of Defense under this section. The Secretary of Defense may delegate the Secretary’s authority under this section only to an Under Secretary of Defense or an Assistant Secretary of Defense and only if the Under Secretary or Assistant Secretary to whom delegated has been designated by the Secretary to act for, and to exercise the general powers of, the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except to the extent otherwise provided by the Attorney General, the Deputy Attorney General may exercise the authority of the Attorney General under this section. The Attorney General may delegate that authority only to the Associate Attorney General or an Assistant Attorney General and only if the Associate Attorney General or Assistant Attorney General to whom delegated has been designated by the Attorney General to act for, and to exercise the general powers of, the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to restrict any executive branch authority regarding use of members of the armed forces or equipment of the Department of Defense that was in effect before <date date="1996-09-23">September 23, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1416(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2721</ref>, § 382; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(10)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1089</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1603</ref>; renumbered § 282, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 283.</num>
<heading> Situations involving bombings of places of public use, Government facilities, public transportation systems, and infrastructure facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon the request of the Attorney General, the Secretary of Defense may provide assistance in support of Department of Justice activities related to the enforcement of <ref>section 2332f of title 18</ref> during situations involving bombings of places of public use, Government facilities, public transportation systems, and infrastructure facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rendering-safe Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Military explosive ordnance disposal units providing rendering-safe support to Department of Justice activities relating to the enforcement of section 175, 229, or 2332a of title 18 in emergency situations involving weapons of mass destruction shall provide such support in a manner consistent with the provisions of section 382 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002030">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense and the Attorney General shall jointly prescribe regulations concerning the types of assistance that may be provided under this section. Such regulations shall also describe the actions that Department of Defense personnel may take in circumstances incident to the provision of assistance under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) may not authorize any of the following actions:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Arrest.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Any direct participation in conducting a search for or seizure of evidence related to a violation of section 175, 229, or 2332a of title 18.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Any direct participation in the collection of intelligence for law enforcement purposes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Such regulations may authorize an action described in subparagraph (A) to be taken under the following conditions:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The action is considered necessary for the immediate protection of human life, and civilian law enforcement officials are not capable of taking the action.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The action is otherwise authorized under subsection (a) or under otherwise applicable law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Explosive Ordnance Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “explosive ordnance”—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> bombs and warheads;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> guided and ballistic missiles;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> artillery, mortar, rocket, and small arms ammunition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> all mines, torpedoes, and depth charges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> grenades demolition charges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> pyrotechnics;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> clusters and dispensers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> cartridge- and propellant- actuated devices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> electroexplosives devices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> clandestine and improvised explosive devices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> all similar or related items or components explosive in nature; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> includes all munitions containing explosives, propellants, nuclear fission or fusion materials, and biological and chemical agents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1082(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1002</ref>, § 383; renumbered § 283, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 284.</num>
<heading> Support for counterdrug activities and activities to counter transnational organized crime</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support to Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may provide support for the counterdrug activities or activities to counter transnational organized crime of any other department or agency of the Federal Government or of any State, local, tribal, or foreign law enforcement agency for any of the purposes set forth in subsection (b) or (c), as applicable, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of support described in subsection (b), such support is requested—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by the official who has responsibility for the counterdrug activities or activities to counter transnational organized crime of the department or agency of the Federal Government, in the case of support for other departments or agencies of the Federal Government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by the appropriate official of a State, local, or tribal government, in the case of support for State, local, or tribal law enforcement agencies; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of support described in subsection (c), such support is requested by an appropriate official of a department or agency of the Federal Government, in coordination with the Secretary of State, that has counterdrug responsibilities or responsibilities for countering transnational organized crime.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Types of Support for Agencies of United States</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes for which the Secretary may provide support under subsection (a) for other departments or agencies of the Federal Government or a State, local, or tribal law enforcement agencies, are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The maintenance and repair of equipment that has been made available to any department or agency of the Federal Government or to any State, local, or tribal government by the Department of Defense for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> preserving the potential future utility of such equipment for the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upgrading such equipment to ensure compatibility of that equipment with other equipment used by the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The maintenance, repair, or upgrading of equipment (including computer software), other than equipment referred to in paragraph (1) for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensuring that the equipment being maintained or repaired is compatible with equipment used by the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upgrading such equipment to ensure the compatibility of that equipment with equipment used by the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The transportation of personnel of the United States and foreign countries (including per diem expenses associated with such transportation), and the transportation of supplies and equipment, for the purpose of facilitating counterdrug activities or activities to counter transnational organized crime within or outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The establishment (including an unspecified minor military construction project) and operation of bases of operations or training facilities for the purpose of facilitating counterdrug activities or activities to counter transnational organized crime of the Department of Defense or any Federal, State, local, or tribal law enforcement agency within or outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Counterdrug or counter-transnational organized crime related training of law enforcement personnel of the Federal Government, of State, local, and tribal governments, including associated support expenses for trainees and the provision of materials necessary to carry out such training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The detection, monitoring, and communication of the movement of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> air and sea traffic within 25 miles of and outside the geographic boundaries of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> surface traffic outside the geographic boundary of the United States and within the United States not to exceed 25 miles of the boundary if the initial detection occurred outside of the boundary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Construction of roads and fences and installation of lighting to block drug smuggling corridors across international boundaries of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Establishment of command, control, communications, and computer networks for improved integration of law enforcement, active military, and National Guard activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The provision of linguist, intelligence analysis, and planning services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Aerial and ground reconnaissance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Types of Support for Foreign Law Enforcement Agencies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes for which the Secretary may provide support under subsection (a) for foreign law enforcement agencies are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The transportation of personnel of the United States and foreign countries (including per diem expenses associated with such transportation), and the transportation of supplies and equipment, for the purpose of facilitating counterdrug activities or activities to counter transnational organized crime within or outside the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The establishment (including small scale construction) and operation of bases of operations or training facilities for the purpose of facilitating counterdrug activities or activities to counter transnational organized crime of a foreign law enforcement agency outside the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The detection, monitoring, and communication of the movement of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> air and sea traffic within 25 miles of and outside the geographic boundaries of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> surface traffic outside the geographic boundaries of the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Establishment of command, control, communications, and computer networks for improved integration of United States Federal and foreign law enforcement entities and United States Armed Forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The provision of linguist and intelligence analysis services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Aerial and ground reconnaissance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination with secretary of state</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In providing support for a purpose described in this subsection, the Secretary shall coordinate with the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary may acquire services or equipment by contract for support provided under that subsection if the Department of Defense would normally acquire such services or equipment by contract for the purpose of conducting a similar activity for the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limited Waiver of Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 276 of this title</ref>, the Secretary may provide support pursuant to subsection (a) in any case in which the Secretary determines that the provision of such support would adversely affect the military preparedness of the United States in the short term if the Secretary determines that the importance of providing such support outweighs such short-term adverse effect.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conduct of Training or Operation To Aid Civilian Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In providing support pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary may plan and execute otherwise valid military training or operations (including training exercises undertaken pursuant to section 1206(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1990 and 1991 (<ref>Public Law 101–189</ref>; <ref>103 Stat. 1564</ref>)) for the purpose of aiding civilian law enforcement agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Support Authorities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided in this section for the support of counterdrug activities or activities to counter transnational organized crime by the Department of Defense is in addition to, and except as provided in paragraph (2), not subject to the other requirements of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Support under this section shall be subject to the provisions of section 275 and, except as provided in subsection (e), <ref>section 276 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not less than 15 days before providing support for an activity under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a written and electronic notice of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of support for a purpose described in subsection (c)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the country the capacity of which will be built or enabled through the provision of such support;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the budget, implementation timeline with milestones, anticipated delivery schedule for support, and completion date for the purpose or project for which support is provided;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the source and planned expenditure of funds provided for the project or purpose;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a description of the arrangements, if any, for the sustainment of the project or purpose and the source of funds to support sustainment of the capabilities and performance outcomes achieved using such support, if applicable;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a description of the objectives for the project or purpose and evaluation framework to be used to develop capability and performance metrics associated with operational outcomes for the recipient;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<chapeau> information, including the amount, type, and purpose, about the support provided the country during the three fiscal years preceding the fiscal year for which the support covered by the notice is provided under this section under—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> this section;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> section 23 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2763</ref>);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> peacekeeping operations;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the International Narcotics Control and Law Enforcement program under section 481 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2291</ref>);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> Nonproliferation, Anti-Terrorism, Demining, and Related Programs;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> counterdrug activities authorized by section 1033 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998 (<ref>Public Law 105–85</ref>); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VII)</num>
<content> any other significant program, account, or activity for the provision of security assistance that the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State consider appropriate;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the capacity of the recipient country to absorb the support provided; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the manner in which the project or purpose for which the support is provided fits into the theater security cooperation strategy of the applicable geographic combatant command.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of support for a purpose described in subsection (b) or (c), a description of any small scale construction project for which support is provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination with secretary of state</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In providing notice under this subsection for a purpose described in subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense shall coordinate with the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Quarterly reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not less frequently than once each quarter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on Department of Defense support provided under subsection (b) during the quarter preceding the quarter during which the report is submitted. Each such report shall be submitted in written and electronic form and shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an identification of each recipient of such support;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a description of the support provided and anticipated duration of such support; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a description of the sources and amounts of funds used to provide such support;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate committees of congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (i)(1), for purposes of a report under this paragraph, the appropriate committees of Congress are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any committee with jurisdiction over the department or agency that receives support covered by the report.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Indian tribe” means a Federally recognized Indian tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “small scale construction” means construction at a cost not to exceed $1,000,000 for any project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “tribal government” means the governing body of an Indian tribe, the status of whose land is “Indian country” as defined in <ref>section 1151 of title 18</ref> or held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Indian tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “tribal law enforcement agency” means the law enforcement agency of a tribal government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “transnational organized crime” means self-perpetuating associations of individuals who operate transnationally for the purpose of obtaining power, influence, monetary, or commercial gains, wholly or in part by illegal means, while protecting their activities through a pattern of corruption or violence or through a transnational organization structure and the exploitation of transnational commerce or communication mechanisms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added § 384 and renumbered § 284, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1011(a)(1)</ref>, title XII, § 1241(a)(2), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2381</ref>, 2497; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1813</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1011</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3839</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1010, 1011, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>