<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 852—</num>
<heading>TRAINING GENERALLY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8431.</num>
<heading> Recruit basic training: separate housing for male and female recruits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Physically Separate Housing</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy shall provide for housing male recruits and female recruits separately and securely from each other during basic training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To meet the requirements of paragraph (1), the sleeping areas and latrine areas provided for male recruits shall be physically separated from the sleeping areas and latrine areas provided for female recruits by permanent walls, and the areas for male recruits and the areas for female recruits shall have separate entrances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure that, when a recruit is in an area referred to in paragraph (2), the area is supervised by one or more persons who are authorized and trained to supervise the area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternative Separate Housing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If male recruits and female recruits cannot be housed as provided under subsection (a) by <date date="2001-10-01">October 1, 2001</date>, at a particular installation, the Secretary of the Navy shall require (on and after that date) that male recruits in basic training at such installation be housed in barracks or other troop housing facilities that are only for males and that female recruits in basic training at such installation be housed in barracks or other troop housing facilities that are only for females.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction Planning</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In planning for the construction of housing to be used for housing recruits during basic training, the Secretary of the Navy shall ensure that the housing is to be constructed in a manner that facilitates the housing of male recruits and female recruits separately and securely from each other.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basic Training Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “basic training” means the initial entry training programs of the Navy and Marine Corps that constitute the basic training of new recruits.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 521(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2010</ref>, § 6931; renumbered § 8431, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8432.</num>
<heading> Recruit basic training: privacy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy shall require that access by recruit division commanders and other training personnel to a living area in which Navy recruits are housed during basic training shall be limited after the end of the training day, other than in the case of an emergency or other exigent circumstance, to recruit division commanders and other training personnel who are of the same sex as the recruits housed in that living area or to superiors in the chain of command of those recruits who, if not of the same sex as the recruits housed in that living area, are accompanied by a member (other than a recruit) who is of the same sex as the recruits housed in that living area.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 522(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2012</ref>, § 6932; renumbered § 8432, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>