<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 81—</num>
<heading>CIVILIAN EMPLOYEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1580.</num>
<heading> Emergency essential employees: designation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria for Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned may designate as an emergency essential employee any employee of the Department of Defense, whether permanent or temporary, the duties of whose position meet all of the following criteria:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It is the duty of the employee to provide immediate and continuing support for combat operations or to support maintenance and repair of combat essential systems of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> It is necessary for the employee to perform that duty in a combat zone after the evacuation of nonessential personnel, including any dependents of members of the armed forces, from the zone in connection with a war, a national emergency declared by Congress or the President, or the commencement of combat operations of the armed forces in the zone.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> It is impracticable to convert the employee’s position to a position authorized to be filled by a member of the armed forces because of a necessity for that duty to be performed without interruption.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility of Employees of Nonappropriated Fund Instrumentalities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A nonappropriated fund instrumentality employee is eligible for designation as an emergency essential employee under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “combat zone” has the meaning given that term in section 112(c)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “nonappropriated fund instrumentality employee” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1587(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title XI, § 1103(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 776</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1580a.</num>
<heading> Emergency essential employees: notification of required participation in anthrax vaccine immunization program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prescribe regulations for the purpose of ensuring that any civilian employee of the Department of Defense who is determined to be an emergency essential employee and who is required to participate in the anthrax vaccine immunization program is notified of the requirement to participate in the program and the consequences of a decision not to participate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that any individual who is being considered for a position as such an employee is notified of the obligation to participate in the program before being offered employment in such position.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title VII, § 751(c)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–194.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1581.</num>
<heading> Foreign National Employees Separation Pay Account</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established on the books of the Treasury an account to be known as the “Foreign National Employees Separation Pay Account, Defense”. The account shall be used for the accumulation of funds to finance obligations of the United States for separation pay for foreign nationals referred to in subsection (e).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposits Into Account</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall deposit into the account from applicable appropriations all amounts obligated for separation pay for foreign nationals referred to in subsection (e).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payments From Account</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts in the account shall remain available for expenditure in accordance with the purpose for which obligated until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deobligated Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any amount in the account that is deobligated shall be available for a period of two years from the date of deobligation for recording, adjusting, and liquidating amounts properly chargeable to the liability of the United States for which the obligation was made. Any such deobligated amount remaining at the end of such two-year period shall be canceled.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employees Covered</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section applies only with respect to separation pay of foreign nationals employed by the Department of Defense, and foreign nationals employed by a foreign government for the benefit of the Department of Defense, under any of the following agreements that provide for payment of separation pay:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A treaty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A memorandum of understanding with a foreign nation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1003(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1456</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(20)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2500</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 346</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1227</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1582.</num>
<heading> Assistive technology, assistive technology devices, and assistive technology services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may provide assistive technology, assistive technology devices, and assistive technology services to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Department of Defense employees with disabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Organizations within the Department that have requirements to make programs or facilities accessible to, and usable by, persons with disabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any other department or agency of the Federal Government, upon the request of the head of that department or agency, for its employees with disabilities or for satisfying a requirement to make its programs or facilities accessible to, and usable by, persons with disabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the terms “assistive technology”, “assistive technology device”, “assistive technology service”, and “disability” have the meanings given those terms in section 3 of the Assistive Technology Act of 1998 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 3002</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1102(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–311.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1583.</num>
<heading> Employment of certain persons without pay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments may each employ, without pay, not more than 10 persons of outstanding experience and ability. However, a person so employed may be allowed transportation, and not more than $15 a day instead of subsistence, while away from his home or regular place of business pursuant to employment under this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 14</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(20)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title XI, § 1111</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1616</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1584.</num>
<heading> Employment of non-citizens</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Laws prohibiting the employment of, or payment of pay or expenses to, a person who is not a citizen of the United States do not apply to personnel of the Department of Defense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(20)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV</ref>, §§ 1481(d)(1), (2), 1482(b), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1706</ref>, 1709; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1062(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 444</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1585.</num>
<heading> Carrying of firearms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, civilian officers and employees of the Department of Defense may carry firearms or other appropriate weapons while assigned investigative duties or such other duties as the Secretary may prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–577, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1958-07-31">July 31, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 455</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1585a.</num>
<heading> Special agents of the Defense Criminal Investigative Service: authority to execute warrants and make arrests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may authorize any DCIS special agent described in subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to execute and serve any warrant or other process issued under the authority of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to make arrests without a warrant—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for any offense against the United States committed in the presence of that agent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if the agent has probable cause to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing the felony.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agents To Have Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) applies to any DCIS special agent whose duties include conducting, supervising, or coordinating investigations of criminal activity in programs and operations of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines on Exercise of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided under subsection (a) shall be exercised in accordance with guidelines prescribed by the Inspector General of the Department of Defense and approved by the Attorney General and any other applicable guidelines prescribed by the Secretary of Defense or the Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">DCIS Special Agent Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “DCIS special agent” means an employee of the Department of Defense who is a special agent of the Defense Criminal Investigative Service (or any successor to that service).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1586.</num>
<heading> Rotation of career-conditional and career employees assigned to duty outside the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In order to advance the programs and activities of the Defense Establishment, it is hereby declared to be the policy of the Congress to facilitate the interchange of civilian employees of the Defense Establishment between posts of duty in the United States and posts of duty outside the United States through the establishment and operation of programs for the rotation, to the extent consistent with the missions of the Defense Establishment and sound principles of administration, of such employees who are assigned to duty outside the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Defense with respect to civilian employees of the Department of Defense other than employees of a military department, and the Secretary of each military department with respect to civilian employees of such military department, may, under such regulations as each such Secretary may prescribe with respect to the employees concerned and in accordance with the policy and other provisions of this section, establish and operate programs of rotation which provide for the granting of the right to return to a position in the United States to each civilian employee in the department concerned—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who, while serving under a career-conditional or career appointment in the competitive civil service, is assigned at the request of the department concerned to duty outside the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> who satisfactorily completes such duty, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> who applies, not later than 30 days after his completion of such duty, for the right to return to a position in the United States as provided by subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary of the department concerned may provide by regulation for the waiver of the provisions of paragraphs (2) and (3), or of either of such paragraphs, in those cases in which the application of such paragraphs, or either of them, would be against equity and good conscience or against the public interest.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The right to return to a position in the United States granted under this section shall be without reduction in the seniority, status, and tenure held by the employee immediately before his assignment to duty outside the United States and the employee shall be placed, not later than 30 days after the date on which he is determined to be immediately available to exercise such right in accordance with the following provisions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The employee shall be placed in the position which he held immediately before his assignment to duty outside the United States, if such position exists.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If such position does not exist, or with his consent, the employee shall be placed in a vacant existing position, or in a new continuing position, for which he is qualified, available for the purposes of this section in the department concerned, in the same geographical area as, with rights and benefits equal to the rights and benefits of, and in a grade equal to the grade of, the position which he held immediately before his assignment to duty outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the positions described in paragraph (1) and paragraph (2) do not exist, the employee shall be placed in an additional position which shall be established by the department concerned for a period not in excess of 90 days in order to carry out the purposes of this section. Such additional position shall be in the same geographical area as, with rights and benefits not less than the rights and benefits of, and in a grade not lower than the grade of, the position held by the employee immediately before his assignment to duty outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If, within 90 days after his placement in a position under paragraph (3) a vacant existing position or new continuing position, for which the employee is qualified, is available for the purposes of this section in the department concerned, in the same geographical area as, with rights and benefits equal to the rights and benefits of, and in a grade equal to the grade of, the position which he held immediately before his assignment to duty outside the United States, the employee shall be placed in such vacant existing position or new continuing position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> If, within the 90-day period referred to in paragraphs (3) and (4), the employee cannot be placed in a position under paragraph (4), he shall be reassigned or separated under the regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management to carry out sections 3501–3503 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> If there is a termination of or material change in the activity in which the former position of the employee (referred to in paragraph (1)) was located, he shall be placed, in the manner provided by paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), as applicable, in a position in the department concerned in a geographical area other than the geographical area in which such former position was located.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Each employee who is placed in a position under paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), or (6) of subsection (c) shall be paid at a rate of basic pay which is not less than the rate of basic pay to which he would have been entitled if he had not been assigned to duty outside the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each employee who is displaced from a position by reason of the exercise of a return right under subsection (c)(1) shall be placed, as of the date of such displacement, without reduction in seniority, status, and tenure, in a vacant existing position or new continuing position, for which he is qualified, available in the department concerned, in the same geographical area as, with rights and benefits equal to the rights and benefits of, in a grade equal to the grade of, and at a rate of basic pay not less than the last rate of basic pay which is not less than the last rate of basic pay to which he was entitled while in, the position from which he is displaced.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the employee cannot be placed in a position under paragraph (1), he shall be reassigned to a position other than the position from which he is displaced, or separated, under the regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management to carry out sections 3501–3503 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The President may, upon his determination that such action is necessary in the national interest, declare that, for such period as he may specify, an assignment of an employee to duty in Alaska or Hawaii shall be held and considered, for the purposes of this section, to be an assignment to duty outside the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “rotation” means the assignment of civilian employees referred to in subsection (b) to duty outside the United States and the return of such employees to duty within the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “grade” means, as applicable, a grade of the General Schedule as prescribed in <ref>section 5104 of title 5</ref> or a grade or level of the appropriate prevailing rate schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may, under such regulations as he may prescribe, make the provisions of subsections (a) through (g) applicable to civilian employees of the Department of Defense who are residents of Guam, the Virgin Islands, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico at the time of their employment by the Department of Defense in the same manner as if the references in such subsections to the United States (when used in a geographical sense) were references to Guam, the Virgin Islands, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, as the case may be.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 86–585, § 1</ref>, <date date="1960-07-05">July 5, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 325</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 15</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 3(3)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 220</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(61)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2925</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–600, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(20)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(29)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2623</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1605</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1587.</num>
<heading> Employees of nonappropriated fund instrumentalities: reprisals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “nonappropriated fund instrumentality employee” means a civilian employee who is paid from nonappropriated funds of Army and Air Force Exchange Service, Navy Exchange Service Command, Marine Corps exchanges, or any other instrumentality of the United States under the jurisdiction of the armed forces which is conducted for the comfort, pleasure, contentment, or physical or mental improvement of members of the armed forces. Such term includes a civilian employee of a support organization within the Department of Defense or a military department, such as the Defense Finance and Accounting Service, who is paid from nonappropriated funds on account of the nature of the employee’s duties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “civilian employee” has the meaning given the term “employee” by <ref>section 2105(a) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “personnel action”, with respect to a nonappropriated fund instrumentality employee (or an applicant for a position as such an employee), means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an appointment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a promotion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a disciplinary or corrective action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a detail, transfer, or reassignment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a reinstatement, restoration, or reemployment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a decision concerning pay, benefits, or awards, or concerning education or training if the education or training may reasonably be expected to lead to an appointment, promotion, or other action described in this paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any other significant change in duties or responsibilities that is inconsistent with the employee’s salary or grade level.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Any civilian employee or member of the armed forces who has authority to take, direct others to take, recommend, or approve any personnel action shall not, with respect to such authority, take or fail to take, or threaten to take or fail to take, a personnel action with respect to any nonappropriated fund instrumentality employee (or any applicant for a position as such an employee) as a reprisal for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a disclosure of information by such an employee or applicant which the employee or applicant reasonably believes evidences—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a violation of any law, rule, or regulation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">if such disclosure is not specifically prohibited by law and if the information is not specifically required by or pursuant to executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or the conduct of foreign affairs; or</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a disclosure by such an employee or applicant to any civilian employee or member of the armed forces designated by law or by the Secretary of Defense to receive disclosures described in clause (1), of information which the employee or applicant reasonably believes evidences—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a violation of any law, rule, or regulation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to an employee in a position excluded from the coverage of this section by the President based upon a determination by the President that the exclusion is necessary and warranted by conditions of good administration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall be responsible for the prevention of actions prohibited by subsection (b) and for the correction of any such actions that are taken. The authority of the Secretary to correct such actions may not be delegated to the Secretary of a military department or to the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Manpower and Logistics.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the Special Counsel of the Merit Systems Protection Board, shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Such regulations shall include provisions to protect the confidentiality of employees and applicants making disclosures described in clauses (1) and (2) of subsection (b) and to permit the reporting of alleged violations of subsection (b) directly to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title XII, § 1253(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 699</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IX, § 903(f)(3)</ref>, title X, § 1040(a)–(d)(1), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 402</ref>, 433; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VI, § 641</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 787</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1587a.</num>
<heading> Employees of nonappropriated fund instrumentalities: senior executive pay levels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To achieve the objective stated in subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense may regulate the amount of total compensation that is provided for senior executives of nonappropriated fund instrumentalities who, for the fixing of pay by administrative action, are under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pay Parity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The objective of an action taken with respect to the compensation of senior executives under subsection (a) is to provide for parity between the total compensation provided for such senior executives and total compensation that is provided for Department of Defense employees in Senior Executive Service positions or other senior executive positions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards of Comparability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (d), the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe the standards of comparison that are to apply in the making of the determinations necessary to achieve the objective stated in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Pay Rates</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall apply subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 5382 of title 5</ref> in the regulation of compensation under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Pay Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may exercise the authority provided in subsection (a) without regard to <ref>section 5373 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “compensation” includes rate of basic pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Senior Executive Service position” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 3132 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2073</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1588.</num>
<heading> Authority to accept certain voluntary services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Accept Services</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (b) and notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary concerned may accept from any person the following services:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Voluntary medical services, dental services, nursing services, or other health-care related services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Voluntary services to be provided for a museum or a natural resources program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Voluntary services to be provided for programs providing services to members of the uniformed services and the families of such members, including the following programs:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Family support programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Child development and youth services programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Library and education programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Religious programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Housing referral programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Programs providing employment assistance to spouses of such members.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Morale, welfare, and recreation programs, to the extent not covered by another subparagraph of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Voluntary services as a member of a funeral honors detail under <ref>section 1491 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Legal services voluntarily provided as legal assistance under <ref>section 1044 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Voluntary services as a proctor for administration to secondary school students of the test known as the “Armed Services Vocational Aptitude Battery”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Voluntary translation or interpretation services offered with respect to a foreign language by a person (A) who is registered for such foreign language on the National Foreign Language Skills Registry under <ref>section 1596b of this title</ref>, or (B) who otherwise is approved to provide voluntary translation or interpretation services for national security purposes, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Voluntary services to support programs of a committee of the Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve as authorized by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Voluntary services to facilitate accounting for missing persons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Voluntary legal support services provided by law students through internship and externship programs approved by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements and Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall notify the person of the scope of the services accepted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to a person providing voluntary services accepted under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> supervise the person to the same extent as the Secretary would supervise a compensated employee providing similar services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that the person is licensed, privileged, has appropriate credentials, or is otherwise qualified under applicable law or regulations to provide such services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to a person providing voluntary services accepted under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> place the person in a policy-making position; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> except as provided in subsection (e), compensate the person for the provision of such services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Recruit and Train Persons Providing Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned may recruit and train persons to provide voluntary services accepted under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Status of Persons Providing Services</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (3), while providing voluntary services accepted under subsection (a) or receiving training under subsection (c), a person, other than a person referred to in paragraph (2), shall be considered to be an employee of the Federal Government only for purposes of the following provisions of law:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5 (relating to compensation for work-related injuries).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2733 of this title</ref> and chapter 171 of title 28 (relating to claims for damages or loss) and chapters 309 and 311 of title 46 (relating to claims for damages or loss on navigable waters).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>Section 552a of title 5</ref> (relating to maintenance of records on individuals).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Chapter 11 of title 18 (relating to conflicts of interest).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content><ref>Section 1054 of this title</ref> (relating to legal malpractice), for a person voluntarily providing legal services accepted under subsection (a)(5), as if the person were providing the services as an attorney of a legal staff within the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (3), while providing a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the United States with voluntary services accepted under subsection (a), or receiving training under subsection (c) to provide such an instrumentality with services accepted under subsection (a), a person shall be considered an employee of that instrumentality only for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subchapter II of chapter 81 of title 5 (relating to compensation of nonappropriated fund employees for work-related injuries).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2733 of this title</ref> and chapter 171 of title 28 (relating to claims for damages or loss).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A person providing voluntary services accepted under subsection (a) shall be considered to be an employee of the Federal Government under paragraph (1) or (2) only with respect to services that are within the scope of the services so accepted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of determining the compensation for work-related injuries payable under chapter 81 of title 5 (pursuant to this subsection) to a person providing voluntary services accepted under subsection (a), the monthly pay of the person for such services shall be deemed to be the amount determined by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the average monthly number of hours that the person provided the services, by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the minimum wage determined in accordance with section 6(a)(1) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 206(a)(1)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement of Incidental Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned may provide for reimbursement of a person for incidental expenses incurred by the person in providing voluntary services accepted under subsection (a). The Secretary shall determine which expenses are eligible for reimbursement under this subsection. Any such reimbursement may be made from appropriated or nonappropriated funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Install Equipment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may install telephone lines and any necessary telecommunication equipment in the private residences of persons, designated in accordance with the regulations prescribed under paragraph (4), who provide voluntary services accepted under paragraph (3) or (8) of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of equipment installed under the authority of paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned may pay the charges incurred for the use of the equipment for authorized purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To carry out this subsection, the Secretary concerned may use appropriated funds (notwithstanding <ref>section 1348 of title 31</ref>) or nonappropriated funds of the military department under the jurisdiction of the Secretary or, with respect to the Coast Guard, the department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense and, with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary Concerned for Acceptance of Services for Programs Serving Members of NOAA Corps and Their Families</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of the acceptance of services described in subsection (a)(3), the term “Secretary concerned” in subsection (a) shall include the Secretary of Commerce with respect to members of the commissioned officer corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title XII, § 1266(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 704</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XVI, § 1624(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIII, § 1355</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3996</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(9)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 274</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1634</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1608</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title III, § 345</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1346</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2845</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1074(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2659</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title III, § 371(a)</ref>, title V, § 578(f), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 579</ref>, 627; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 583</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1125</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 553</ref>, title X, § 1064(b), <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2552</ref>, 2654; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 516</ref>, title X, § 1081, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1884</ref>, 2059; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1063(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 322</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 587(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1043</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–259, title II, § 205(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1589.</num>
<heading> Participation in management of specified non-Federal entities: authorized activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may authorize an employee described in paragraph (2) to serve without compensation as a director, officer, or trustee, or to otherwise participate, in the management of an entity designated under subsection (b). Any such authorization shall be made on a case-by-case basis, for a particular employee to participate in a specific capacity with a specific designated entity. Such authorization may be made only for the purpose of providing oversight and advice to, and coordination with, the designated entity, and participation of the employee in the activities of the designated entity may not extend to participation in the day-to-day operations of the entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) applies to any employee of the Department of Defense or, in the case of the Coast Guard when not operating as a service in the Navy, of the Department of Homeland Security. For purposes of this section, the term “employee” includes a civilian officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designated Entities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security in the case of the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, shall designate those entities for which authorization under subsection (a) may be provided. The list of entities so designated may not be revised more frequently than semiannually. In making such designations, the Secretary shall designate each military welfare society named in paragraph (2) of <ref>section 1033(b) of this title</ref> and may designate any other entity described in paragraph (3) of such section. No other entities may be designated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Publication of Designated Entities and of Authorized Persons</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A designation of an entity under subsection (b), and an authorization under subsection (a) of an employee to participate in the management of such an entity, shall be published in the Federal Register.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civilians Outside the Military Departments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Secretary concerned” includes the Secretary of Defense with respect to employees of the Department of Defense who are not employees of a military department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security in the case of the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 593(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1763</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1590.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1633(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2751</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1591.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement for travel and transportation expenses when accompanying Members of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary concerned may authorize reimbursement to a civilian employee who is accompanying a Member of Congress or a congressional employee on official travel for actual travel and transportation expenses incurred for such travel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The allowance provided in subsection (a) may be paid—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at a rate that does not exceed the rate approved for official congressional travel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> only when the travel of the member is directed or approved by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Member of Congress” means a member of the Senate or the House of Representatives, a Delegate to the House of Representatives, and the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “congressional employee” means an employee of a Member of Congress or an employee of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary concerned” includes the Secretary of Defense with respect to civilian employees of the Department of Defense other than a military department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VI, § 617(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1097</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1592.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on payment of severance pay to foreign nationals in the event of certain overseas base closures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds available to the Department of Defense (including funds in the Foreign National Employees Separation Pay Account, Defense, established under <ref>section 1581 of this title</ref>) may not be used to pay severance pay to a foreign national employed by the Department of Defense under a contract, a treaty, or a memorandum of understanding with a foreign nation that provides for payment of separation pay if the termination of the employment of the foreign national is the result of the closing of, or the curtailment of activities at, a United States military facility in that country at the request of the government of that country.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 311(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1411</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1003(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1456</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(21)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2500</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1593.</num>
<heading> Uniform allowance: civilian employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allowance Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may pay an allowance to each civilian employee of the Department of Defense who is required by law or regulation to wear a prescribed uniform in the performance of official duties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In lieu of providing an allowance under paragraph (1), the Secretary may provide a uniform to a civilian employee referred to in such paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This subsection shall not apply with respect to a civilian employee of the Defense Intelligence Agency who is entitled to an allowance under <ref>section 1622 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount of Allowance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 5901(a) of title 5</ref>, the amount of an allowance paid, and the cost of uniforms provided, under subsection (a) to a civilian employee may not exceed $400 per year (or such higher maximum amount as the Secretary of Defense may by regulation prescribe).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Allowance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An allowance paid, or uniform provided, under subsection (a) shall be treated in the same manner as is provided in <ref>section 5901(c) of title 5</ref> for an allowance paid under that section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Appropriated Funds for Allowance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated annually to the Department of Defense for the pay of civilian employees may be used for uniforms, or for allowance for uniforms, as authorized by this section and <ref>section 5901 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 336(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1419</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1481(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1633(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XI, § 1113</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1594.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement for financial institution charges incurred because of Government error in direct deposit of pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A civilian officer or employee of the Department of Defense who, in accordance with law or regulation, participates in a program for the automatic deposit of pay to a financial institution may be reimbursed for a covered late-deposit charge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A covered late-deposit charge for purposes of paragraph (1) is a charge (including an overdraft charge or a minimum balance charge) that is levied by a financial institution and that results from an administrative or mechanical error on the part of the Government that causes the pay of the officer or employee concerned to be deposited late or in an incorrect manner or amount.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Reimbursements under this section shall be made from appropriations available for the pay of the officer or employee concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretaries concerned shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section, including regulations for the manner in which reimbursement under this section is to be made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “financial institution” means a bank, savings and loan association, or similar institution or a credit union chartered by the United States or a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “pay” includes allowances.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VI, § 664(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1466</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1484(k)(6)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(e)(8)(A)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 564(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2029</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1595.</num>
<heading> Civilian faculty members at certain Department of Defense schools: employment and compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may employ as many civilians as professors, instructors, and lecturers at the organizations specified in subsection (c) as the Secretary considers necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation of Faculty Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The compensation of persons employed under this section shall be as prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section applies with respect to the following organizations of the Department of Defense:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The National Defense University.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Foreign Language Center of the Defense Language Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The English Language Center of the Defense Language Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Western Hemisphere Institute for Security Cooperation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Joint Special Operations University.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Defense Security Cooperation University.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Defense Institute for Security Governance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The Defense Institute of International Legal Studies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The United States Element of the Inter-American Defense College.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application to Faculty Members at</inline> NDU.—</heading>
<content>In the case of the National Defense University, this section applies with respect to persons selected by the Secretary for employment as professors, instructors, and lecturers at the National Defense University after <date date="1990-02-27">February 27, 1990</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XI, § 1124(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1558</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title IX, § 911</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1452</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title IX, § 923(a)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 923(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1607</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title IX</ref>, §§ 921(c), 922(b), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1863</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1115</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1636</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title IX, § 904(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 555</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1773</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1107</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3891</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XI, § 1104</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1950</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XI, § 1107</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2088</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1596.</num>
<heading> Foreign language proficiency: special pay for proficiency beneficial for intelligence interests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may pay special pay under this section to a civilian officer or employee of the Department of Defense who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has been certified as being proficient in a foreign language identified by the Secretary of Defense as being a language in which proficiency by civilian personnel of the Department is important for the effective collection, production, or dissemination of foreign intelligence information; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is serving in a position, or is subject to assignment to a position, in which proficiency in that language facilitates performance of officially assigned intelligence or intelligence-related duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The annual rate of special pay under subsection (a) shall be determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Special pay under this section may be paid in addition to any compensation authorized under <ref>section 1602 of this title</ref> for which an officer or employee is eligible.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–193, title V, § 501(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1707</ref>, § 1592; renumbered § 1596, <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1484(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1715</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1633(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1131(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–317.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1596a.</num>
<heading> Foreign language proficiency: special pay for proficiency beneficial for other national security interests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may pay special pay under this section to an employee of the Department of Defense who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has been certified by the Secretary to be proficient in a foreign language identified by the Secretary as being a language in which proficiency by civilian personnel of the Department is necessary because of national security interests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is assigned duties requiring proficiency in that foreign language; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is not receiving special pay under <ref>section 1596 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The rate of special pay for an employee under this section shall be prescribed by the Secretary, but may not exceed five percent of the employee’s rate of basic pay.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Pay and Allowances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Special pay under this section is in addition to any other pay or allowances to which the employee is entitled.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1131(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–317; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title XI, § 1102(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2072</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1596b.</num>
<heading> Foreign language proficiency: National Foreign Language Skills Registry</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may establish and maintain a registry of persons who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have proficiency in one or more critical foreign languages;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are willing to provide linguistic services to the United States in the interests of national security during war or a national emergency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> meet the eligibility requirements of subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The registry shall be known as the “National Foreign Language Skills Registry” (in this section referred to as the “Registry”).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Persons</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To be eligible for listing on the Registry, a person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> must be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a national of the United States (as defined in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>)); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence (as defined in section 101(a)(20) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(20)</ref>));</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> shall express willingness, in a form and manner prescribed by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to provide linguistic services for a foreign language as described in subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to be listed on the Registry; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall meet such language proficiency and other selection criteria as may be prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Registered Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Registry shall consist of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The names of eligible persons selected by the Secretary for listing on the Registry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such other information on such persons as the Secretary determines pertinent to the use of such persons to provide linguistic services as described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection of Privacy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may withhold from public disclosure the information maintained in the Registry in accordance with <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Critical Foreign Languages</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall designate those languages that are critical foreign languages for the purposes of this section. The Secretary shall make such a designation for any foreign language for which there is a shortage of experts in translation or interpretation available to meet requirements of the Secretary or of the head of any other department or agency of the United States for translation or interpretation in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Linguistic Services Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “linguistic services” means translation or interpretation of communication in a foreign language.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1064(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2653</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1596c.</num>
<heading> Programming language proficiency: special pay for proficiency beneficial for national security interests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, under the sole and exclusive discretion of the Secretary, may pay special pay under this section to an employee of the Department of Defense who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has been certified by the Secretary to be proficient in a computer or digital programming language identified by the Secretary as being a language in which proficiency by civilian personnel of the Department is necessary because of national security interests; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is assigned duties requiring proficiency in that programming language.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The rate of special pay for an employee under this section shall be prescribed by the Secretary, but may not exceed 20 percent of the employee’s rate of basic pay.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Pay and Allowances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Special pay under this section is in addition to any other pay or allowances to which the employee is entitled.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 241(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3487</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1597.</num>
<heading> Civilian positions: guidelines for reductions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement of Guidelines for Reductions in Civilian Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Reductions in the number of civilian positions of the Department of Defense during a fiscal year, if any, shall be carried out in accordance with the guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall establish guidelines for the manner in which reductions in the number of civilian positions of the Department of Defense are made. In establishing the guidelines, the Secretary shall ensure that nothing in the guidelines conflicts with the requirements of <ref>section 129 of this title</ref> or the policies and procedures established under <ref>section 129a of this title</ref>. The guidelines shall include procedures for reviewing civilian positions for reductions according to the following order:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Positions filled by foreign national employees overseas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> All other positions filled by civilian employees overseas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Overhead, indirect, and administrative positions in headquarters or field operating agencies in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Direct operating or production positions in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may permit a variation from the guidelines established under subsection (b) if the Secretary determines that such variation is critical to the national security. The Secretary shall immediately notify the Congress of any such variation and the reasons for such variation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Involuntary Reductions of Civilian Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may not implement any involuntary reduction or furlough of civilian positions in a military department, Defense Agency, or other component of the Department of Defense until the expiration of the 45-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary submits to Congress a report setting forth the reasons why such reductions or furloughs are required and a description of any change in workload or positions requirements that will result from such reductions or furloughs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration of Employee Performance in Reductions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish procedures to provide that, in implementing any reduction in force for civilian positions in the Department of Defense in the competitive service or the excepted service, the determination of which employees shall be separated from employment in the Department shall, among other factors as determined by the Secretary, account for employee performance, as determined under any applicable performance management system.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title III, § 322(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1528</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title III, § 371(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 98</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title III, § 363</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title IX, § 933(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1544</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XI, § 1101(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1022</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(6)(A)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1560</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XI, § 1105</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1950</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1598.</num>
<heading> Assistance to terminated employees to obtain certification and employment as teachers or employment as teachers’ aides</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Placement Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may establish a program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to assist eligible civilian employees of the Department of Defense and the Department of Energy after the termination of their employment to obtain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> certification or licensure as elementary or secondary school teachers; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the credentials necessary to serve as teachers’ aides; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to facilitate the employment of such employees by local educational agencies that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are receiving grants under title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6301</ref> et seq.) as a result of having within their jurisdictions concentrations of children from low-income families; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are also experiencing a shortage of teachers or teachers’ aides.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A civilian employee of the Department of Defense or the Department of Energy shall be eligible for selection by the Secretary of Defense to participate in the placement program authorized by subsection (a) if the employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> during the five-year period beginning <date date="1992-10-01">October 1, 1992</date>, is terminated from such employment as a result of reductions in defense spending or the closure or realignment of a military installation, as determined by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Energy, as the case may be;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> has received—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of an employee applying for assistance for placement as an elementary or secondary school teacher, a baccalaureate or advanced degree from an accredited institution of higher education; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of an employee applying for assistance for placement as a teacher’s aide in an elementary or secondary school, an associate, baccalaureate, or advanced degree from an accredited institution of higher education or a junior or community college; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> satisfies such other criteria for selection as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may accept an application from a civilian employee referred to in paragraph (1) who was terminated during the period beginning on <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, and ending on <date date="1992-10-01">October 1, 1992</date>, if the employee otherwise satisfies the eligibility criteria specified in that paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection of Participants</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Selection of civilian employees to participate in the placement program shall be made on the basis of applications submitted to the Secretary of Defense after the employees receive a notice of termination. An application shall be filed within such time, in such form, and contain such information as the Secretary of Defense may require.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In selecting participants to receive assistance for placement as elementary or secondary school teachers, the Secretary of Defense shall give priority to civilian employees who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have educational, military, or employment experience in science, mathematics, or engineering and agree to seek employment as science, mathematics, or engineering teachers in elementary or secondary schools; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have educational, military, or employment experience in another subject area identified by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, as important for national educational objectives and agree to seek employment in that subject area in elementary or secondary schools.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may not select a civilian employee to participate in the program unless the Secretary has sufficient appropriations for the placement program available at the time of the selection to satisfy the obligations to be incurred by the United States under the program with respect to that member.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A civilian employee selected to participate in the placement program shall be required to enter into an agreement with the Secretary of Defense in which the employee agrees—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to obtain, within such time as the Secretary may require, certification or licensure as an elementary or secondary school teacher or the necessary credentials to serve as a teacher’s aide in an elementary or secondary school; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to accept—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an employee selected for assistance for placement as a teacher, an offer of full-time employment as an elementary or secondary school teacher for not less than two school years with a local educational agency identified under section 1151(b)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002077">1</ref> of this title, as in effect on <date date="1999-10-04">October 4, 1999</date>, to begin the school year after obtaining that certification or licensure; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an employee selected for assistance for placement as a teacher’s aide, an offer of full-time employment as a teacher’s aide in an elementary or secondary school for not less than two school years with a local educational agency identified under section 1151(b)(3) <sup>1</sup> of this title, as in effect on <date date="1999-10-04">October 4, 1999</date>, to begin the school year after obtaining the necessary credentials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stipend for Participants</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of Defense shall pay to each participant in the placement program a stipend in an amount equal to the lesser of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $5,000; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total costs of the type described in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (8), and (9) <sup>1</sup> of section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1087</ref><i>ll</i>) incurred by the participant while obtaining teacher certification or licensure or the necessary credentials to serve as a teacher’s aide and employment as an elementary or secondary school teacher or teacher aide.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A civilian employee selected to participate in the placement program who receives separation pay under <ref>section 5597 of title 5</ref> shall not be paid a stipend under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A stipend paid under paragraph (1) shall be taken into account in determining the eligibility of the participant for Federal student financial assistance provided under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Placement of Participants as Teachers and Teachers’ Aides</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsections (h) through (k) of section 1151 <sup>1</sup> of this title, as in effect on <date date="1999-10-04">October 4, 1999</date>, shall apply with respect to the placement program authorized by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV, § 4442(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2730</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1331(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 391(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4021</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1503(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 576(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1087(a)(11)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–290.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1599.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 1611]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1599a.</num>
<heading> Financial assistance to certain employees in acquisition of critical skills</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish an undergraduate training program with respect to civilian employees in the Military Department Civilian Intelligence Personnel Management System that is similar in purpose, conditions, content, and administration to the program established by the Secretary of Defense under section 16 of the National Security Agency Act of 1959 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3614</ref>) for civilian employees of the National Security Agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds for Training Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any payment made by the Secretary to carry out the program required to be established by subsection (a) may be made in any fiscal year only to the extent that appropriated funds are available for that purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–93, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-01-06">Jan. 6, 1996</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 973</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(20)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1952</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(9)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1599b.</num>
<heading> Employees abroad: travel expenses; health care</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may provide civilian employees, and members of their families, abroad with benefits that are comparable to certain benefits that are provided by the Secretary of State to members of the Foreign Service and their families abroad as described in subsections (b) and (c). The Secretary may designate the employees and members of families who are eligible to receive the benefits.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel and Related Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may pay travel expenses and related expenses for purposes and in amounts that are comparable to the purposes for which, and the amounts in which, travel and related expenses are paid by the Secretary of State under section 901 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 4081</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Health Care Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish a health care program that is comparable to the health care program established by the Secretary of State under section 904 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 4084</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may enter into agreements with the heads of other departments and agencies of the Government in order to facilitate the payment of expenses authorized by subsection (b) and to carry out a health care program authorized by subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Abroad Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “abroad” means outside—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1604(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2735</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1599c.</num>
<heading> Health care professionals: enhanced appointment and compensation authority for personnel for care and treatment of wounded and injured members of the armed forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may, at the discretion of the Secretary, exercise any authority for the appointment and pay of health care personnel under chapter 74 of title 38 for purposes of the recruitment, employment, and retention of civilian health care professionals for the Department of Defense if the Secretary determines that the exercise of such authority is necessary in order to provide or enhance the capacity of the Department to provide care and treatment for members of the armed forces who are wounded or injured on active duty in the armed forces and to support the ongoing patient care and medical readiness, education, and training requirements of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of <ref>section 3304 of title 5</ref>, the Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> designate any category of medical or health professional positions within the Department of Defense as a shortage category occupation or critical need occupation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> utilize the authority in such section to recruit and appoint qualified persons directly in the competitive service to positions so designated.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In using the authority provided by this paragraph, the Secretary shall apply the principles of preference for the hiring of veterans and other persons established in subchapter I of chapter 33 of title 5.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any designation by the Secretary for purposes of subparagraph (A)(i) shall be based on an analysis of current and future Department of Defense workforce requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary of Defense under subsection (a)(1) to exercise authorities available under chapter 74 of title 38 for purposes of the recruitment, employment, and retention of civilian health care professionals for the Department of Defense expires <date date="2030-12-31">December 31, 2030</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not appoint a person to a position of employment under subsection (a)(2) after <date date="2030-12-31">December 31, 2030</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1236</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XVI, § 1636(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 463</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title XI, § 1107, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(22)</ref>, title XI, § 1104, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4370</ref>, 4383; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XI, § 1109</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 890</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1116</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3897</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VII, § 712</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1947</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1599d.</num>
<heading> Financial management positions: authority to prescribe professional certification and credential standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Prescribe Professional Certification and Credential Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may prescribe professional certification and credential standards for financial management positions within the Department of Defense, including requirements for formal education and requirements for certifications that individuals have met predetermined qualifications set by an agency of Government or by an industry or professional group. Any such professional certification or credential standard shall be prescribed as a Department regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may waive any standard prescribed under subsection (a) whenever the Secretary determines such a waiver to be appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary may, in the Secretary’s discretion—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> require that a standard prescribed under subsection (a) apply immediately to all personnel holding financial management positions designated by the Secretary; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> delay the imposition of such a standard for a reasonable period to permit persons holding financial management positions so designated time to comply.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A formal education requirement prescribed under subsection (a) shall not apply to any person employed by the Department in a financial management position before the standard is prescribed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Discharge of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe any professional certification or credential standards under subsection (a) through the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller), in consultation with the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than one year after the effective date of any regulations prescribed under subsection (a), or any significant modification of such regulations, the Secretary shall, in conjunction with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, submit to Congress a report setting forth the plans of the Secretary to provide training to appropriate Department personnel to meet any new professional certification or credential standard under such regulations or modification.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Financial Management Position Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “financial management position” means a position or group of positions (including civilian and military positions), as designated by the Secretary for purposes of this section, that perform, supervise, or manage work of a fiscal, financial management, accounting, auditing, cost, or budgetary nature, or that require the performance of financial management-related work.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2661</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title XI, § 1110, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4619</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1581</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1599e.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XI, § 1106(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1950</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1599f.</num>
<heading> United States Cyber Command recruitment and retention</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> establish, as positions in the excepted service, such qualified positions in the Department of Defense as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the responsibilities of the United States Cyber Command, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> positions held by staff of the headquarters of the United States Cyber Command;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> positions held by elements of the United States Cyber Command enterprise relating to cyberspace operations, including elements assigned to the Joint Task Force-Department of Defense Information Networks; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> positions held by elements of the military departments supporting the United States Cyber Command;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> appoint an individual to a qualified position (after taking into consideration the availability of preference eligibles for appointment to the position); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> subject to the requirements of subsections (b) and (c), fix the compensation of an individual for service in a qualified position.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary under this subsection applies without regard to the provisions of any other law relating to the appointment, number, classification, or compensation of employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basic Pay</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In accordance with this section, the Secretary shall fix the rates of basic pay for any qualified position established under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in relation to the rates of pay provided for employees in comparable positions in the Department, in which the employee occupying the comparable position performs, manages, or supervises functions that execute the cyber mission of the Department; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subject to the same limitations on maximum rates of pay established for such employees by law or regulation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consistent with <ref>section 5341 of title 5</ref>, adopt such provisions of that title to provide for prevailing rate systems of basic pay; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> apply those provisions to qualified positions for employees in or under which the Department may employ individuals described by section 5342(a)(2)(A) of such title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Compensation, Incentives, and Allowances</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may provide employees in qualified positions compensation (in addition to basic pay), including benefits, incentives, and allowances, consistent with, and not in excess of the level authorized for, comparable positions authorized by title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An employee in a qualified position whose rate of basic pay is fixed under subsection (b)(1) shall be eligible for an allowance under <ref>section 5941 of title 5</ref> on the same basis and to the same extent as if the employee was an employee covered by such section, including eligibility conditions, allowance rates, and all other terms and conditions in law or regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation Plan Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The authority granted in subsection (a) shall become effective 30 days after the date on which the Secretary of Defense provides to the congressional defense committees a plan for implementation of such authority. The plan shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An assessment of the current scope of the positions covered by the authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A plan for the use of the authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An assessment of the anticipated workforce needs of the United States Cyber Command across the future-years defense plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Other matters as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collective Bargaining Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in subsection (a) may be construed to impair the continued effectiveness of a collective bargaining agreement with respect to an office, component, subcomponent, or equivalent of the Department that is a successor to an office, component, subcomponent, or equivalent of the Department covered by the agreement before the succession.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall provide training to covered personnel on hiring and pay matters relating to authorities under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subsection, covered personnel are employees of the Department who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> carry out functions relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the management of human resources and the civilian workforce of the Department; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the writing of guidance for the implementation of authorities regarding hiring and pay under this section; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are employed in supervisory positions or have responsibilities relating to the hiring of individuals for positions in the Department and to whom the Secretary intends to delegate authority under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section and not less frequently than once each year thereafter until the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, in coordination with the Secretary, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a detailed report on the administration of this section during the most recent one-year period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include, for the period covered by the report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A discussion of the process used in accepting applications, assessing candidates, ensuring adherence to veterans’ preference, and selecting applicants for vacancies to be filled by an individual for a qualified position.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A description of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> How the Secretary plans to fulfill the critical need of the Department to recruit and retain employees in qualified positions.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The measures that will be used to measure progress.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Any actions taken during the reporting period to fulfill such critical need.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A discussion of how the planning and actions taken under subparagraph (B) are integrated into the strategic workforce planning of the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> The metrics on actions occurring during the reporting period, including the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The number of employees in qualified positions hired, disaggregated by occupation, grade, and level or pay band.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The placement of employees in qualified positions, disaggregated by military department, Defense Agency, or other component within the Department.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The total number of veterans hired.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The number of separations of employees in qualified positions, disaggregated by occupation and grade and level or pay band.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The number of retirements of employees in qualified positions, disaggregated by occupation, grade, and level or pay band.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The number and amounts of recruitment, relocation, and retention incentives paid to employees in qualified positions, disaggregated by occupation, grade, and level or pay band.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A description of the training provided to employees described in subsection (f)(2) on the use of authorities under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Three-year Probationary Period</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The probationary period for all employees hired under the authority established in this section shall be three years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incumbents of Existing Competitive Service Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An individual occupying a position on the date of the enactment of this section that is selected to be converted to a position in the excepted service under this section shall have the right to refuse such conversion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> After the date on which an individual who refuses a conversion under paragraph (1) stops serving in the position selected to be converted, the position may be converted to a position in the excepted service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “collective bargaining agreement” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 7103(a)(8) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “excepted service” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2103 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “preference eligible” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2108(3) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “qualified position” means a position, designated by the Secretary for the purpose of this section, in which the individual occupying such position performs, manages, or supervises functions that execute the responsibilities of the United States Cyber Command relating to cyber operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “Senior Executive Service” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2101a of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XI, § 1107(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1024</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XI, § 1103(a)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2444</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1599g.</num>
<heading> Public-private talent exchange</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary may, with the agreement of a private-sector organization and the consent of the employee, arrange for the temporary assignment of an employee to such private-sector organization, or from such private-sector organization to a Department of Defense organization under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall provide for a written agreement among the Department of Defense, the private-sector organization, and the employee concerned regarding the terms and conditions of the employee’s assignment under this section. The agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall require that the employee of the Department of Defense, upon completion of the assignment, will serve in the Department of Defense, or elsewhere in the civil service if approved by the Secretary, for a period equal to twice the length of the assignment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall provide that if the employee of the Department of Defense or of the private-sector organization (as the case may be) fails to carry out the agreement, such employee shall be liable to the United States for payment of all expenses of the assignment, unless that failure was for good and sufficient reason, as determined by the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall contain language ensuring that such employee of the Department does not improperly use information that such employee knows relates to a Department acquisition or procurement for the benefit or advantage of the private-sector organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An amount for which an employee is liable under paragraph (1) shall be treated as a debt due the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary may waive, in whole or in part, collection of a debt described in paragraph (2) based on a determination that the collection would be against equity and good conscience and not in the best interests of the United States, after taking into account any indication of fraud, misrepresentation, fault, or lack of good faith on the part of the employee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An assignment under this section may, at any time and for any reason, be terminated by the Department of Defense or the private-sector organization concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An assignment under this section shall be for a period of not less than three months and not more than two years, renewable up to a total of four years. No employee of the Department of Defense may be assigned under this section for more than a total of 4 years inclusive of all such assignments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An assignment under this section may be for a period in excess of two years, but not more than four years, if the Secretary determines that such assignment is necessary to meet critical mission or program requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Status of Federal Employees Assigned to Private-sector Organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee of the Department of Defense who is assigned to a private-sector organization under this section shall be considered, during the period of assignment, to be on detail to a regular work assignment in the Department for all purposes. The written agreement established under subsection (b)(1) shall address the specific terms and conditions related to the employee’s continued status as a Federal employee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In establishing a temporary assignment of an employee of the Department of Defense to a private-sector organization, the Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure that the normal duties and functions of such employee can be reasonably performed by other employees of the Department of Defense without the permanent transfer or reassignment of other personnel of the Department of Defense, including members of the armed forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that the normal duties and functions of such employees are not, as a result of and during the course of such temporary assignment, performed or augmented by contractor personnel in violation of the provisions of <ref>section 2461 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> certify that the temporary assignment of such employee shall not have an adverse or negative impact on mission attainment, warfighter support, or organizational capabilities associated with the assignment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms and Conditions for Private-sector Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An employee of a private-sector organization who is assigned to a Department of Defense organization under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall continue to receive pay and benefits from the private-sector organization from which such employee is assigned and shall not receive pay or benefits from the Department of Defense, except as provided in paragraph (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> is deemed to be an employee of the Department of Defense for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> chapters 73 and 81 of title 5;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> sections 201, 203, 205, 207, 208, 209, 603, 606, 607, 643, 654, 1905, and 1913 of title 18;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> sections 1343, 1344, and 1349(b) of title 31;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Federal Tort Claims Act and any other Federal tort liability statute;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Ethics in Government Act of 1978; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> chapter 21 of title 41;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall not have access to any trade secrets or to any other nonpublic information which is of commercial value to the private-sector organization from which such employee is assigned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> may not perform work that is considered inherently governmental in nature; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> may not be used to circumvent the provision of <ref>section 2461 of this title</ref> nor to circumvent any limitation or restriction on the size of the Department’s workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition Against Charging Certain Costs to the Federal Government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A private-sector organization may not charge the Department or any other agency of the Federal Government, as direct or indirect costs under a Federal contract, the costs of pay or benefits paid by the organization to an employee assigned to a Department organization under this section for the period of the assignment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out this section, the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall ensure that, of the assignments made under this section each year, at least 20 percent are from small business concerns (as defined by <ref>section 3703(e)(2)(A) of title 5</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall take into consideration the question of how assignments under this section might best be used to help meet the needs of the Department of Defense with respect to the training of employees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall take into consideration, where applicable, areas of particular private sector expertise, such as cybersecurity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conflicts of Interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A private-sector organization that is temporarily assigned a member of the acquisition workforce under this section shall not be considered to have a conflict of interest with the Department of Defense solely because of participation in the program established under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding; Use of Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds for the expenses for the program established under this section may be provided from amounts in the Department of Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund. Expenses for the program include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> notwithstanding <ref>section 1705(e)(5) of this title</ref>, the base salary of a civilian member of the acquisition workforce assigned to a private-sector organization under this section, during the period of that assignment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expenses relating to assignment under this section of a member of the acquisition workforce away from the member’s regular duty station, including expenses for travel, per diem, and lodging; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> expenses for the administration of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each member of the acquisition workforce that participates in the program established under this section shall, upon completion of such participation, submit to the President of the Defense Acquisition University for inclusion in the report required under section 1746a(e) a description and evaluation of such participation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2445</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 863(a)</ref>, title XI, § 1116, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1522</ref>, 1604; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1102(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3885</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 831(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2712</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1599h.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4092]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1599i.</num>
<heading> Recruitment incentives for placement at remote locations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Recruitment Incentive.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual appointed to a position in the Department of Defense at a covered location may be paid a recruitment incentive in connection with such appointment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The amount of a recruitment incentive payable to an individual under this subsection may not exceed the amount equal to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 25 percent of the annual rate of basic pay of the employee for the position concerned as of the date on which the service period in such position agreed to by the individual under paragraph (3) commences; multiplied by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of years (including fractions of a year) of such service period (not to exceed four years).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To receive a recruitment incentive under this subsection, an individual appointed to a position under paragraph (1) shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary of Defense to complete a period of service at the covered location. The period of obligated service of the individual at such location under the agreement may not exceed four years. The agreement shall include such repayment or alternative employment obligations as the Secretary considers appropriate for failure of the individual to complete the period of obligated service specified in the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered locations defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, a covered location is a location for which the Secretary of Defense has determined that critical hiring needs are not being met due to the geographic remoteness or isolation or extreme climate conditions of the location.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Effective on <date date="2022-09-30">September 30, 2022</date>, the authority provided under subsection (a) shall expire.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1120(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3898</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1599j.</num>
<heading> Restricted reports of incidents of adult sexual assault</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restricted Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may provide a civilian employee of the Department of Defense an opportunity to submit to an individual described in subsection (d) a restricted report of an alleged incident of adult sexual assault for the purpose of assisting the employee in obtaining information and access to authorized victim support services provided by the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restrictions on Disclosures and Initiating Investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Unless the Secretary determines that a disclosure is necessary to prevent or mitigate a serious and imminent safety threat to the employee submitting the report or to another person, a restricted report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be disclosed to the supervisor of the employee or any other management official; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> cause the initiation of a Federal civil or criminal investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties Under Other Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The receipt of a restricted report submitted under subsection (a) shall not be construed as imputing actual or constructive knowledge of an alleged incident of sexual assault to the Department of Defense for any purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Individuals Authorized to Receive Restricted Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An individual described in this subsection is an individual who performs victim advocate duties under a program for one or more of the following purposes (or any other program designated by the Secretary):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Sexual assault prevention and response.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Victim advocacy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Equal employment opportunity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Workplace violence prevention and response.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Employee assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Family advocacy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civilian employee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “civilian employee” has the meaning given the term “employee” in <ref>section 2105 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sexual assault</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “sexual assault” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 920 of this title</ref> (article 120 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice), and includes penetrative offenses and sexual contact offenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XI, § 1101(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>