<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 851—</num>
<heading>OFFICER PROCUREMENT PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8411.</num>
<heading> Aviation cadets: grade; procurement; transfer</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The grade of aviation cadet is a special enlisted grade in the naval service. Under such regulations as the Secretary of the Navy prescribes, citizens in civil life may be enlisted as, and enlisted members of the naval service with their consent may be designated as, aviation cadets.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except in time of war or emergency declared by Congress, 20 percent of the aviation cadets procured in each fiscal year shall be procured from qualified enlisted members of the Regular Navy and the Regular Marine Corps.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> No person may be enlisted or designated as an aviation cadet unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> he agrees in writing that, upon his successful completion of the course of training as an aviation cadet, he will accept a commission as an ensign in the Navy Reserve or a second lieutenant in the Marine Corps Reserve, and will serve on active duty as such for at least three years, unless sooner released; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if under 21 years of age, he has the consent of his parent or guardian to his agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary prescribes, an aviation cadet may be transferred to another enlisted grade or rating in the naval service, released from active duty, or discharged.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 426</ref>, § 6911; <ref>Pub. L. 85–578</ref>, <date date="1958-07-31">July 31, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 456</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title III, § 373(f)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2903</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(N)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>; renumbered § 8411, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8412.</num>
<heading> Aviation cadets: benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in section 402(a) and (b) of title 37, aviation cadets or their beneficiaries are entitled to the same allowances, pensions, gratuities, and other benefits as are provided for enlisted members in pay grade E–4. While on active duty, an aviation cadet is entitled to uniforms, clothing, and equipment at the expense of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 426</ref>, § 6912; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(147)(A)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1513</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 6(f)(6)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 494</ref>; renumbered § 8412, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8413.</num>
<heading> Aviation cadets: appointment as reserve officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An aviation cadet who fulfills the requirements of <ref>section 2003 of this title</ref> may be appointed an ensign in the Navy Reserve or a second lieutenant in the Marine Corps Reserve and designated a naval aviator.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Aviation cadets who complete their training at approximately the same time are considered for all purposes to have begun their commissioned service on the same date, and the decision of the Secretary of the Navy in this regard is conclusive.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 427</ref>, § 6913; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(20)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2932</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(O)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>; renumbered § 8413, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8415.</num>
<heading> Reserve student aviation pilots; reserve aviation pilots: appointments in commissioned grade</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary of the Navy prescribes, enlisted members of the Navy Reserve and the Marine Corps Reserve may be designated as student aviation pilots.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A member who is not a qualified civilian aviator may not be designated as a student aviation pilot unless he agrees in writing, with the consent of his parent or guardian if he is a minor, to serve on active duty for a period of two years after successfully completing flight training, unless sooner released. Such a student aviation pilot may be released from active duty or discharged at any time by any administrative authority prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If he is a qualified civilian aviator, a student aviation pilot may be given a brief refresher course in flight training.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> While he is in flight training, a student aviation pilot shall have uniforms and equipment issued to him at Government expense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, a student aviation pilot of the Navy Reserve or the Marine Corps Reserve may be designated an aviation pilot upon successfully completing flight training.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> In time of peace, an aviation pilot who is obligated under subsection (b) to serve on active duty for a period of two years may serve, with his consent, for an additional period of not more than two years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> An aviation pilot of the Navy Reserve or the Marine Corps Reserve may be released from active duty or discharged at any time by any administrative authority prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> An aviation pilot of the Navy Reserve or the Marine Corps Reserve may, if qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, be appointed an ensign in the Navy Reserve or a second lieutenant in the Marine Corps Reserve, as appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 427</ref>, § 6915; <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 14c(51)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(21)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2932</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(P)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>; renumbered § 8415, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>