<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1401—</num>
<heading>APPLICABILITY AND RESERVE ACTIVE-STATUS LISTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 14001.</num>
<heading> Applicability of this part</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter and chapters 1403 through 1411 of this title apply, as appropriate, to all reserve officers of the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps except warrant officers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2922</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14002.</num>
<heading> Reserve active-status lists: requirement for each armed force</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of each military department shall maintain a single list, to be known as the reserve active-status list, for each armed force under the Secretary’s jurisdiction. That list shall include the names of all reserve officers of that armed force who are in an active status other than those on an active-duty list described in <ref>section 620 of this title</ref> or warrant officers (including commissioned warrant officers).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The reserve active-status list for the Army shall include officers in the Army Reserve and the Army National Guard of the United States. The reserve active-status list for the Air Force shall include officers in the Air Force Reserve and the Air National Guard of the United States. The Secretary of the Navy shall maintain separate lists for the Navy Reserve and the Marine Corps Reserve.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2922</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(OO)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14003.</num>
<heading> Reserve active-status lists: position of officers on the list</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Position on List</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Officers shall be carried on the reserve active-status list of the armed force of which they are members in the order of seniority of the grade in which they are serving in an active status. Officers serving in the same grade shall be carried in the order of their rank in that grade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect on Position Held by Reason of Temporary Appointment or Assignment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer whose position on the reserve active-status list results from service under a temporary appointment or in a grade held by reason of assignment to a position has, when that appointment or assignment ends, the grade and position on that list that the officer would have held if the officer had not received that appointment or assignment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2923</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(22)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14004.</num>
<heading> Reserve active-status lists: eligibility for Reserve promotion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided by law, an officer must be on a reserve active-status list to be eligible under chapter 1405 of this title for consideration for selection for promotion or for promotion.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14005.</num>
<heading> Competitive categories</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each officer whose name appears on a reserve active-status list shall be placed in a competitive category. The competitive categories for each armed force shall be specified by the Secretary of the military department concerned under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. Officers in the same competitive category shall compete among themselves for promotion.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14006.</num>
<heading> Determination of years in grade</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of chapters 1403 through 1411 of this title, an officer’s years of service in a grade are computed from the officer’s date of rank in grade as determined under <ref>section 741(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>