<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 825—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8211.</num>
<heading> Navy Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">United States Navy Regulations shall be issued by the Secretary of the Navy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 375</ref>, § 6011; <ref>Pub. L. 97–60, title II, § 204(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-14">Oct. 14, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1007</ref>; renumbered § 8211, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8212.</num>
<heading> Additional regulations for Marine Corps</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may prescribe military regulations for the discipline of the Marine Corps.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 375</ref>, § 6012; renumbered § 8212, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8213.</num>
<heading> Enlisted grades and ratings: authority to establish</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy may establish such enlisted grades and ratings as are necessary for the proper administration of the Navy and the Marine Corps.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 375</ref>, § 6013; renumbered § 8213, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8214.</num>
<heading> Enlisted members: authority for transfer between Marine Corps and Hospital Corps of the Navy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy, enlisted members of the Marine Corps are eligible for transfer to the Hospital Corps of the Navy, and enlisted members of the Hospital Corps are eligible for transfer to the Marine Corps.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 375</ref>, § 6014; renumbered § 8214, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8215.</num>
<heading> Citizenship of officers of vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The officers of vessels of the United States shall in all cases by citizens of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 376</ref>, § 6019; renumbered § 8215, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8216.</num>
<heading> Aviation duties: number of personnel assigned</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The number of officers and enlisted members of the Navy and the Marine Corps detailed to duty involving flying and to other duties in connection with aircraft shall be in accordance with the requirements of naval aviation as determined by the Secretary of the Navy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 376</ref>, § 6021; renumbered § 8216, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8217.</num>
<heading> Aviation training facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may maintain facilities to provide flight training for 16,000 members of the naval service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 376</ref>, § 6022; renumbered § 8217, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8218.</num>
<heading> Aviation designations: naval flight officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any officer of the naval service may be designated a naval flight officer if he has successfully completed the course prescribed for naval flight officers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 377</ref>, § 6024; <ref>Pub. L. 91–198, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-02-26">Feb. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 15</ref>; renumbered § 8218, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8219.</num>
<heading> Medical Department: composition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Medical Corps and Dental Corps, and such other staff corps as the Secretary of the Navy may establish under <ref>section 8090(b) of this title</ref> and designate to be in the Medical Department of the Navy, are in the Medical Department of the Navy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 377</ref>, § 6027; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title III, § 353</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 514(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1055</ref>; renumbered § 8219 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(b)(7), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8220.</num>
<heading> Dental services: responsibilities of senior dental officer</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy shall prescribe regulations for dental services on ships and at shore stations. Such services shall be under the senior dental officer, who is responsible to the commanding officer of the ship or station for all professional, technical, and administrative matters concerning dental services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section does not impose any administrative requirements that would interfere with the proper functioning of battle organizations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 377</ref>, § 6029; renumbered § 8220, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8221.</num>
<heading> Chaplains: divine services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An officer in the Chaplain Corps may conduct public worship according to the manner and forms of the church of which he is a member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The commanders of vessels and naval activities to which chaplains are attached shall cause divine service to be performed on Sunday, whenever the weather and other circumstances allow it to be done; and it is earnestly recommended to all officers, seamen, and others in the naval service diligently to attend at every performance of the worship of Almighty God.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> All persons in the Navy and in the Marine Corps are enjoined to behave themselves in a reverent and becoming manner during divine service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 378</ref>, § 6031; <ref>Pub. L. 86–140</ref>, <date date="1959-08-07">Aug. 7, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 288</ref>; renumbered § 8221, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8222.</num>
<heading> Indebtedness to Marine Corps Exchanges: payment from appropriated funds in certain cases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy, appropriations for the pay of the Marine Corps are available to pay any indebtedness to Marine Corps Exchanges of members of the Marine Corps who are discharged, who desert, or who are sentenced to prison.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 378</ref>, § 6032; renumbered § 8222, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8225.</num>
<heading> Female members: congressional review period for assignment to duty on submarines or for reconfiguration of submarines</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> No change in the Department of the Navy policy limiting service on submarines to males, as in effect on <date date="2000-05-10">May 10, 2000</date>, may take effect until—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense submits to Congress written notice of the proposed change; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a period of 30 days of continuous session of Congress (excluding any day on which either House of Congress is not in session) expires following the date on which the notice is received.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> No funds available to the Department of the Navy may be expended to reconfigure any existing submarine, or to design any new submarine, to accommodate female crew members until—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense submits to Congress written notice of the proposed reconfiguration or design; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a period of 30 days of continuous session of Congress (excluding any day on which either House of Congress is not in session) expires following the date on which the notice is received.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the continuity of a session of Congress is broken only by an adjournment of the Congress sine die.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 573(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–136, § 6035; renumbered § 8225, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8226.</num>
<heading> Fatality reviews</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of Fatalities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Navy shall conduct a multidisciplinary, impartial review (referred to as a “fatality review”) in the case of each fatality known or suspected to have resulted from domestic violence or child abuse against any of the following.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A member of the naval service on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A current or former dependent of a member of the naval service on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A current or former intimate partner who has a child in common or has shared a common domicile with a member of the naval service on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matters To Be Included</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The report of a fatality review under subsection (a) shall, at a minimum, include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An executive summary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Data setting forth victim demographics, injuries, autopsy findings, homicide or suicide methods, weapons, police information, assailant demographics, and household and family information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Legal disposition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> System intervention and failures, if any, within the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A discussion of significant findings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Recommendations for systemic changes, if any, within the Department of the Navy and the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading> OSD <inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe guidance, which shall be uniform for the military departments, for the conduct of reviews by the Secretary under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 576(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1487</ref>, § 6036; renumbered § 8226, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8227.</num>
<heading> Notifications on manning of afloat naval forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Navy shall notify the congressional defense committees, in writing, not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year quarter, of each covered ship (if any) that met either condition as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The manning fit for such ship was less than 87 percent for more than 14 days during such fiscal year quarter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The manning fill for such ship was less than 90 percent for more than 14 days during such fiscal year quarter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The notification required by subsection (a) shall include, with respect to a covered ship, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The name and hull number of the ship.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The homeport location of the ship.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The current manning fit and fill of the ship.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If the lowest level of manning fit or manning fill for the ship occurred during the fiscal year quarter concerned, the level concerned and the date on which such level occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> If the lowest level of manning fit or manning fill for the ship is projected to occur after the fiscal year quarter concerned, the projected level and the date on which such level is projected to occur.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> If not achieved as of the date of the notification the projected date on which the Navy will achieve a manning fit and fill at least 87 percent and 90 percent, respectively, for the ship.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> If not achieved as of the date of the notification, the projected date on which the Navy will achieve a manning fit and fill of at least 92 percent and 95 percent, respectively, for the ship.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> A description of the reasons the Navy has not achieved, or will not achieve, as applicable, manning fit and fill of at least 87 percent and 90 percent, respectively, for the ship, including a detailed description of the specific ratings or skillset areas that must be manned to achieve those percentages.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> A description of corrective actions the Navy is taking to improve manning fit or manning fill on the ship.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Rule</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of determining whether a percentage of manning fit or manning fill has been achieved, a sailor in a more senior paygrade may count as filling the billet of a more junior paygrade, but a sailor in a more junior paygrade may not count as filling the billet of a more senior paygrade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crewing of a Surface Combatant Vessel: Prohibition; Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Beginning on <date date="2025-10-01">October 1, 2025</date>, the Secretary of the Navy may not assign more than one crew to a covered ship that is a surface combatant vessel if any surface combatant vessel was included in a notification under subsection (a) during the 12 months preceding such assignment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The prohibition under paragraph (1) shall not apply to a littoral combat ship configured to conduct mine countermeasures if the Secretary of the Navy submits to the congressional defense committees a certification and detailed explanation that such ship is unable to meet operational requirements regarding mine countermeasures, determined by the commander of a combatant command concerned, with only one crew.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “covered ship” means a commissioned battle force ship that is included in the battle force count of the Naval Vessel Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “manning fill”, in the case of a ship, means the total number of military personnel assigned to the ship by rating when compared with the ship manpower document requirement and billets authorized for the ship by rating.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “manning fit”, in the case of a ship, means the skills (rating), specialty skills (Navy Enlisted Classifications), and experience (paygrade) for the ship when compared with the ship manpower document requirement and billets authorized for such skills and experience.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “surface combatant vessel” means any littoral combat ship (including the LCS–1 and LCS–2 classes), frigate (including the FFG–62 class), destroyer (excluding the DDG–1000 class), or cruiser (including the CG–47 class).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 592(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2612</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>