<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 384—</num>
<heading>MANUFACTURING TECHNOLOGY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4841.</num>
<heading> Manufacturing Technology Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a Manufacturing Technology Program to further the national security objectives of <ref>section 4811(a) of this title</ref> through the development and application of advanced manufacturing technologies and processes that will reduce the acquisition and supportability costs of defense weapon systems and reduce manufacturing and repair cycle times across the life cycles of such systems. The Secretary shall use the joint planning process of the directors of the Department of Defense laboratories in establishing the program. The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall administer the program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall use the program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide centralized guidance and direction (including goals, milestones, and priorities) to the military departments and the Defense Agencies on all matters relating to manufacturing technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to direct the development and implementation of Department of Defense plans, programs, projects, activities, and policies that promote the development and application of advanced technologies to manufacturing processes, tools, and equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to improve the manufacturing quality, productivity, technology, and practices of businesses and workers providing goods and services to the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to focus Department of Defense support for the development and application of advanced manufacturing technologies and processes for use to meet manufacturing requirements that are essential to the national defense, as well as for repair and remanufacturing in support of the operations of systems commands, depots, air logistics centers, and shipyards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to disseminate information concerning improved manufacturing improvement concepts, including information on such matters as best manufacturing practices, product data exchange specifications, computer-aided acquisition and logistics support, and rapid acquisition of manufactured parts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to sustain and enhance the skills and capabilities of the manufacturing work force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to promote high-performance work systems (with development and dissemination of production technologies that build upon the skills and capabilities of the work force), high levels of worker education and training; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to ensure appropriate coordination between the manufacturing technology programs and industrial preparedness programs of the Department of Defense and similar programs undertaken by other departments and agencies of the Federal Government or by the private sector.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Execution</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may carry out projects under the program through the Secretaries of the military departments and the heads of the Defense Agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the establishment and review of requirements for an advanced manufacturing technology or process, the Secretary shall ensure the participation of those prospective technology users that are expected to be the users of that technology or process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure that each project under the program for the development of an advanced manufacturing technology or process includes an implementation plan for the transition of that technology or process to the prospective technology users that will be the users of that technology or process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In the periodic review of a project under the program, the Secretary shall ensure participation by those prospective technology users that are the expected users for the technology or process being developed under the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In order to promote increased dissemination and use of manufacturing technology throughout the national defense technology and industrial base, the Secretary shall seek, to the maximum extent practicable, the participation of manufacturers of manufacturing equipment in the projects under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “prospective technology users” means the following officials and elements of the Department of Defense:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Program and project managers for defense weapon systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Systems commands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Depots.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Air logistics centers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Shipyards.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competition and Cost Sharing</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In accordance with the policy stated in <ref>section 4008 of this title</ref>, competitive procedures shall be used for awarding all grants and entering into all contracts, cooperative agreements, and other transactions under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Under the competitive procedures used, the factors to be considered in the evaluation of each proposed grant, contract, cooperative agreement, or other transaction for a project under the program shall include the extent to which that proposed transaction provides for the proposed recipient to share in the cost of the project. For a project for which the Government receives an offer from only one offeror, the contracting officer shall negotiate the ratio of contract recipient cost to Government cost that represents the best value to the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Five-Year Strategic Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall develop a plan for the program that includes the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The overall manufacturing technology goals, milestones, priorities, and investment strategy for the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The objectives of, and funding for, the program for each military department and each Defense Agency that shall participate in the program during the period of the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall include in the plan mechanisms for assessing the effectiveness of the program under the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall update the plan not less frequently than once every four years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Each plan, and each update to the plan, shall cover a period of five fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VIII, § 801(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1700</ref>, § 2525; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title II, § 256(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2704</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title II, § 276(a)</ref>, title X, § 1081(e), title XV, § 1503(a)(28), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 241</ref>, 454, 512; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1657</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1947</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title II, § 216</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 543</ref>; renumbered § 2521, <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, § 344(c)(1)(A)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–71; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2481</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(24)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title II, § 238(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(c)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3325</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(76)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1552</ref>; renumbered § 4841 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1869(b)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4283</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4842.</num>
<heading> Joint Defense Manufacturing Technology Panel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is in the Department of Defense the Joint Defense Manufacturing Technology Panel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chair of the Joint Defense Manufacturing Technology Panel shall be the head of the Panel. The Chair shall be appointed, on a rotating basis, from among the appropriate personnel of the military departments and Defense Agencies with manufacturing technology programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Panel shall be composed of at least one individual from among appropriate personnel of each military department and Defense Agency with manufacturing technology programs. The Panel may include as ex-officio members such individuals from other government organizations, academia, and industry as the Chair considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The purposes of the Panel shall be as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To identify and integrate requirements for the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To conduct joint planning for the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To develop joint strategies for the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out the purposes specified in subsection (c), the Panel shall perform the functions as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Conduct comprehensive reviews and assessments of defense-related manufacturing issues being addressed by the manufacturing technology programs and related activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Execute strategic planning to identify joint planning opportunities for increased cooperation in the development and implementation of technological products and the leveraging of funding for such purposes with the private sector and other government agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Ensure the integration and coordination of requirements and programs under the program with the Office of the Secretary of Defense and other national-level initiatives, including the establishment of information exchange processes with other government agencies, private industry, academia, and professional associations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Conduct such other functions as the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall specify.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Panel shall report to and receive direction from one or more individuals designated by the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering for purposes of this subsection on manufacturing technology issues of multi-service concern and application.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The administrative expenses of the Panel shall be borne by each military department and Defense Agency with manufacturing technology programs in such manner as the Panel shall provide.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1869(c)(1)(B)</ref>, (2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4283</ref>, 4284.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4843.</num>
<heading> Manufacturing engineering education program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Manufacturing Engineering Education Program</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program under which the Secretary makes grants or other awards to support—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the enhancement of existing programs in manufacturing engineering education to further a mission of the department; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the establishment of new programs in manufacturing engineering education that meet such requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Grants and awards under this section may be made to industry, not-for-profit institutions, institutions of higher education, or to consortia of such institutions or industry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish the program in consultation with the Secretary of Education, the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and the secretaries of such other relevant Federal agencies as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure that the program is coordinated with Department programs associated with advanced manufacturing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The program shall be known as the “Manufacturing Engineering Education Program”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading> Geographical Distribution of Grants and Awards.—</heading>
<content>In awarding grants and other awards under this subsection, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, avoid geographical concentration of awards.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A program of engineering education supported pursuant to this section shall meet the requirements of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Components of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The program of education for which such a grant is made shall be a consolidated and integrated multidisciplinary program of education with an emphasis on the following components:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Multidisciplinary instruction that encompasses the total manufacturing engineering enterprise and that may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> manufacturing engineering education and training through classroom activities, laboratory activities, thesis projects, individual or team projects, internships, cooperative work-study programs, and interactions with industrial facilities, consortia, or such other activities and organizations in the United States and foreign countries as the Secretary considers appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> faculty development programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recruitment of educators highly qualified in manufacturing engineering to teach or develop manufacturing engineering courses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> presentation of seminars, workshops, and training for the development of specific manufacturing engineering skills;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> activities involving interaction between students and industry, including programs for visiting scholars, personnel exchange, or industry executives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> development of new, or updating and modification of existing, manufacturing curriculum, course offerings, and education programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> establishment of programs in manufacturing workforce training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> establishment of joint manufacturing engineering programs with defense laboratories and depots; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> expansion of manufacturing training and education programs and outreach for members of the armed forces, dependents and children of such members, veterans, and employees of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Opportunities for students to obtain work experience in manufacturing through such activities as internships, summer job placements, or cooperative work-study programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Faculty and student engagement with industry that is directly related to, and supportive of, the education of students in manufacturing engineering because of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the increased understanding of manufacturing engineering challenges and potential solutions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the enhanced quality and effectiveness of the instruction that result from that increased understanding.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proposals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall solicit proposals for grants and other awards to be made pursuant to this section for the support of programs of manufacturing engineering education that are consistent with the purposes of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Merit Competition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Applications for awards shall be evaluated on the basis of merit pursuant to competitive procedures prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may select a proposal for an award pursuant to this section if the proposal, at a minimum, does each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Contains innovative approaches for improving engineering education in manufacturing technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Demonstrates a strong commitment by the proponents to apply the resources necessary to achieve the objectives for which the award is to be made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Provides for effective engagement with industry or government organizations that supports the instruction to be provided in the proposed program and is likely to improve manufacturing engineering and technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Demonstrates a significant level of involvement of United States industry in the proposed instructional and research activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Is likely to attract superior students and promote careers in manufacturing engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Proposes to involve fully qualified personnel who are experienced in manufacturing engineering education and technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Proposes a program that, within three years after the award is made, is likely to attract from sources other than the Federal Government the financial and other support necessary to sustain such program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Proposes to achieve a significant level of participation by women, members of minority groups, and individuals with disabilities through active recruitment of students from among such persons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Trains students in advanced manufacturing and in relevant emerging technologies and production processes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Institution of Higher Education Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VIII, § 825(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1438</ref>, § 2196; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2048</ref>; renumbered § 4843, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1869(d)(1)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(p)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4844.</num>
<heading> Manufacturing experts in the classroom</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Education and the Secretary of Commerce, shall conduct a program to support the following activities of one or more manufacturing experts at institutions of higher education:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Identifying the education and training requirements of United States manufacturing firms located in the same geographic region as an institution participating in the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Assisting in the development of teaching curricula for classroom and in-factory education and training classes at such an institution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Teaching such classes and overseeing the teaching of such classes by others.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Improving the knowledge and expertise of permanent faculty and staff of such an institution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Marketing the programs and facilities of such an institution to firms referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Coordinating the activities described in the other provisions of this subsection with other programs conducted by the Federal Government, any State, any local government, or any private, nonprofit organization to modernize United States manufacturing firms, especially the regional centers for the transfer of manufacturing technology and programs receiving financial assistance under <ref>section 4843 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Merit Competition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Applications for assistance under this section shall be evaluated on the basis of merit pursuant to competitive procedures prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall select institutions for the award of financial assistance under this section from among institutions submitting applications for such assistance that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> demonstrate that the proposed activities are of an appropriate scale and a sufficient quality to ensure long term improvement in the applicant’s capability to serve the education and training needs of United States manufacturing firms in the same region as the applicant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> demonstrate a significant level of industry involvement and support;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> demonstrate attention to the needs of any United States industries that supply manufactured products to the Department of Defense or to a contractor of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> meet such other criteria as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of financial assistance furnished to an institution under this section may not exceed 50 percent of the estimated cost of carrying out the activities proposed to be supported in part with such financial assistance for the period for which the assistance is to be provided. In no event may the amount of the financial assistance provided to an institution exceed $250,000 per year. The period for which financial assistance is provided an institution under this section shall be at least two years unless such assistance is earlier terminated for cause determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Manufacturing Expert Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “manufacturing expert” means manufacturing managers and workers having experience in the organization of production and education and training needs and other experts in manufacturing.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VIII, § 825(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1440</ref>, § 2197; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLII, § 4238(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2694</ref>; renumbered § 4844 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1869(d)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(p)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4845.</num>
<heading> Armament retooling and manufacturing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army is authorized by chapter 764 of this title to carry out programs for the support of armaments retooling and manufacturing in the national defense industrial and technology base.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, § 344(c)(1)(B)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–71, § 2522; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>; renumbered § 4845, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1869(d)(1)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(p)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>