<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 365—</num>
<heading>CONTRACTOR WORKFORCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4701.</num>
<heading> Contractor employees: protection from reprisal for disclosure of certain information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition of Reprisals</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An employee of a contractor, subcontractor, grantee, or subgrantee or personal services contractor may not be discharged, demoted, or otherwise discriminated against as a reprisal for disclosing to a person or body described in paragraph (2) information that the employee reasonably believes is evidence of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Gross mismanagement of a Department of Defense contract or grant, a gross waste of Department funds, an abuse of authority relating to a Department contract or grant, or a violation of law, rule, or regulation related to a Department contract (including the competition for or negotiation of a contract) or grant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Gross mismanagement of a National Aeronautics and Space Administration contract or grant, a gross waste of Administration funds, an abuse of authority relating to an Administration contract or grant, or a violation of law, rule, or regulation related to an Administration contract (including the competition for or negotiation of a contract) or grant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A substantial and specific danger to public health or safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The persons and bodies described in this paragraph are the persons and bodies as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A Member of Congress or a representative of a committee of Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An Inspector General.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Government Accountability Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> An employee of the Department of Defense or the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, as applicable, responsible for contract oversight or management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> An authorized official of the Department of Justice or other law enforcement agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A court or grand jury.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> A management official or other employee of the contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor who has the responsibility to investigate, discover, or address misconduct.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an employee who initiates or provides evidence of contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor misconduct in any judicial or administrative proceeding relating to waste, fraud, or abuse on a Department of Defense or National Aeronautics and Space Administration contract or grant shall be deemed to have made a disclosure covered by such paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a reprisal described in paragraph (1) is prohibited even if it is undertaken at the request of a Department or Administration official, unless the request takes the form of a nondiscretionary directive and is within the authority of the Department or Administration official making the request.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Investigation of Complaints</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A person who believes that the person has been subjected to a reprisal prohibited by subsection (a) may submit a complaint to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense, or the Inspector General of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration in the case of a complaint regarding the National Aeronautics and Space Administration. Unless the Inspector General determines that the complaint is frivolous, fails to allege a violation of the prohibition in subsection (a), or has previously been addressed in another Federal or State judicial or administrative proceeding initiated by the complainant, the Inspector General shall investigate the complaint and, upon completion of such investigation, submit a report of the findings of the investigation to the person, the contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor concerned, and the head of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided under subparagraph (B), the Inspector General shall make a determination that a complaint is frivolous, fails to allege a violation of the prohibition in subsection (a), or has previously been addressed in another Federal or State judicial or administrative proceeding initiated by the complainant or submit a report under paragraph (1) within 180 days after receiving the complaint.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If the Inspector General is unable to complete an investigation in time to submit a report within the 180-day period specified in subparagraph (A) and the person submitting the complaint agrees to an extension of time, the Inspector General shall submit a report under paragraph (1) within such additional period of time, up to 180 days, as shall be agreed upon between the Inspector General and the person submitting the complaint.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Inspector General may not respond to any inquiry or disclose any information from or about any person alleging the reprisal, except to the extent that such response or disclosure is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> made with the consent of the person alleging the reprisal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> made in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref> or as required by any other applicable Federal law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> necessary to conduct an investigation of the alleged reprisal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A complaint may not be brought under this subsection more than three years after the date on which the alleged reprisal took place.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Remedy and Enforcement Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 30 days after receiving an Inspector General report pursuant to subsection (b), the head of the agency concerned shall determine whether there is sufficient basis to conclude that the contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor concerned has subjected the complainant to a reprisal prohibited by subsection (a) and shall either issue an order denying relief or shall take one or more of the following actions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Order the contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor to take affirmative action to abate the reprisal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Order the contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor to reinstate the person to the position that the person held before the reprisal, together with compensatory damages (including back pay), employment benefits, and other terms and conditions of employment that would apply to the person in that position if the reprisal had not been taken.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Order the contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor to pay the complainant an amount equal to the aggregate amount of all costs and expenses (including attorneys’ fees and expert witnesses’ fees) that were reasonably incurred by the complainant for, or in connection with, bringing the complaint regarding the reprisal, as determined by the head of the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Consider disciplinary or corrective action against any official of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after receiving an Inspector General report pursuant to subsection (b), the head of the agency concerned shall notify the complainant and the Inspector General, in writing, of either the actions ordered or the decision to deny relief. After such notification, if the head of the agency concerned changes the actions ordered or the decision to deny relief, the head of the agency concerned shall notify the complainant and the Inspector General, in writing, of the change not later than 30 days after the change occurs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the head of an executive agency issues an order denying relief under paragraph (1) or has not issued an order within 210 days after the submission of a complaint under subsection (b), or in the case of an extension of time under paragraph (2)(B) of such subsection, not later than 30 days after the expiration of the extension of time, and there is no showing that such delay is due to the bad faith of the complainant, the complainant shall be deemed to have exhausted all administrative remedies with respect to the complaint, and the complainant may bring a de novo action at law or equity against the contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor to seek compensatory damages and other relief available under this section in the appropriate district court of the United States, which shall have jurisdiction over such an action without regard to the amount in controversy. Such an action shall, at the request of either party to the action, be tried by the court with a jury. An action under this paragraph may not be brought more than two years after the date on which remedies are deemed to have been exhausted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An Inspector General determination and an agency head order denying relief under paragraph (3) shall be admissible in evidence in any de novo action at law or equity brought pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Whenever a person fails to comply with an order issued under paragraph (1), the head of the agency shall file an action for enforcement of such order in the United States district court for a district in which the reprisal was found to have occurred. In any action brought under this paragraph, the court may grant appropriate relief, including injunctive relief, compensatory and exemplary damages, and reasonable attorney fees and costs. The person upon whose behalf an order was issued may also file such an action or join in an action filed by the head of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Any person adversely affected or aggrieved by an order issued under paragraph (1) may obtain review of the order’s conformance with this subsection, and any regulations issued to carry out this section, in the United States court of appeals for a circuit in which the reprisal is alleged in the order to have occurred. No petition seeking such review may be filed more than 60 days after issuance of the order by the head of the agency. Review shall conform to chapter 7 of title 5. Filing such an appeal shall not act to stay the enforcement of the order of the head of an agency, unless a stay is specifically entered by the court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The legal burdens of proof specified in <ref>section 1221(e) of title 5</ref> shall be controlling for the purposes of any investigation conducted by an Inspector General, decision by the head of an agency, or judicial or administrative proceeding to determine whether discrimination prohibited under this section has occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The rights and remedies provided for in this section may not be waived by any agreement, policy, form, or condition of employment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall ensure that contractors, subcontractors, grantees, subgrantees, or personal services contractors of the Department of Defense and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, as applicable, inform their employees in writing of the rights and remedies provided under this section, in the predominant native language of the workforce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply to any element of the intelligence community, as defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> This section shall not apply to any disclosure made by an employee of a contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor of an element of the intelligence community if such disclosure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> relates to an activity of an element of the intelligence community; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> was discovered during contract, subcontract, grantee, or subgrantee services provided to an element of the intelligence community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize the discharge of, demotion of, or discrimination against an employee for a disclosure other than a disclosure protected by subsection (a) or to modify or derogate from a right or remedy otherwise available to the employee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “agency” means an agency named in <ref>section 3063 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>[(2)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1863(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4278</ref>.]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “contract” means a contract awarded by the head of an agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “contractor” means a person awarded a contract with an agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “Inspector General” means an Inspector General appointed under chapter 4 of title 5 and any Inspector General that receives funding from, or has oversight over contracts or grants awarded for or on behalf of, the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The term “abuse of authority” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An arbitrary and capricious exercise of authority that is inconsistent with the mission of the Department of Defense or the successful performance of a Department contract or grant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An arbitrary and capricious exercise of authority that is inconsistent with the mission of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration or the successful performance of an Administration contract or grant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “grantee” means a person awarded a grant with an agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title X, § 942(a)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–82</ref>, 1783–162, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title X, § 942(a)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–82</ref>, 3341–162, § 2409; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IX</ref>, formerly title IV, § 942(a)(1), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3942</ref>, renumbered title IX, <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 273</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(30)(A)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2500</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title VI, § 6005(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 671</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VIII, § 846</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VIII, § 827(a)</ref>–(f), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1833–1836</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title VIII, § 856</ref>, title X, § 1071(c)(10), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3460</ref>, 3509; <ref>Pub. L. 114–261, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-14">Dec. 14, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1362</ref>; renumbered § 4701 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1863(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4278</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2703</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(28)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4346</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 837</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4702.</num>
<heading> Incentives and consideration for qualified training programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incentives</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop workforce development investment incentives for a contractor that implements a qualified training program to develop the workforce of the contractor in a manner consistent with the needs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration of Qualified Training Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall revise the Department of Defense Supplement to the Federal Acquisition Regulation to require that the system used by the Federal Government to monitor or record contractor past performance includes an analysis of the availability, quality, and effectiveness of a qualified training program of an offeror as part of the past performance rating of such offeror.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified Training Program Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “qualified training program” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A program eligible to receive funds under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 3101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A program eligible to receive funds under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 2301</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A program registered under the Act of <date date="1937-08-16">August 16, 1937</date> (commonly known as the “National Apprenticeship Act”; <ref>50 Stat. 664</ref>; chapter 663; <ref>29 U.S.C. 50</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any other program determined to be a qualified training program for purposes of this section, and that meets the workforce needs of the Department of Defense, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 864(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1522</ref>, § 2409a; renumbered § 4702 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(40)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1863(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3873</ref>, 4278.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4703.</num>
<heading> Displaced contractor employees: assistance to obtain certification and employment as teachers or employment as teachers’ aides</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may enter into a cooperative agreement with a defense contractor in order—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to assist an eligible scientist or engineer employed by the contractor whose employment is terminated to obtain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> certification or licensure as an elementary or secondary school teacher; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the credentials necessary to serve as a teacher’s aide; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to facilitate the employment of the scientist or engineer by a local educational agency that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is receiving a grant under title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 6301</ref> et seq.) as a result of having within its jurisdiction concentrations of children from low-income families; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is also experiencing a shortage of teachers or teachers’ aides.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Defense Contractors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish an application and selection process for the participation of defense contractors in a cooperative agreement authorized under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall determine which defense contractors are eligible to participate in the placement program on the basis of applications submitted under subsection (c). The Secretary shall limit participation to those defense contractors or subcontractors that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> produce goods or services for the Department of Defense pursuant to a defense contract or operate nuclear weapons manufacturing facilities for the Department of Energy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have recently reduced operations, or are likely to reduce operations, due to the completion or termination of a defense contract or program or by reductions in defense spending.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall give special consideration to defense contractors who are located in areas that have been hit particularly hard by reductions in defense spending.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense Contractor Applications</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A defense contractor desiring to enter into a cooperative agreement with the Secretary of Defense under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary containing the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Evidence that the contractor has been, or is expected to be, adversely affected by the completion or termination of a defense contract or program or by reductions in defense spending.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An explanation that scientists and engineers employed by the contractor have been terminated, laid off, or retired, or are likely to be terminated, laid off, or retired, as a result of the completion or termination of a defense contract or program or reductions in defense spending.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A description of programs implemented or proposed by the contractor to assist these scientists and engineers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A commitment to help fund the costs associated with the placement program by paying 50 percent of the stipend provided under subsection (g) to an employee or former employee of the contractor selected to receive assistance under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Once a cooperative agreement is entered into under subsection (a) between the Secretary and the defense contractor, the contractor shall publicize the program and distribute applications to prospective participants, and assist the prospective participants with the State screening process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Scientists and Engineers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An individual shall be eligible for selection by the Secretary of Defense to receive assistance under this section if the individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is employed or has been employed for not less than five years as a scientist or engineer with a private defense contractor that has entered into an agreement under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> has received—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an individual applying for assistance for placement as an elementary or secondary school teacher, a baccalaureate or advanced degree from an accredited institution of higher education; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an individual applying for assistance for placement as a teacher’s aide in an elementary or secondary school, an associate, baccalaureate, or advanced degree from an accredited institution of higher education or a junior or community college; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has been terminated or laid off (or received notice of termination or lay off) as a result of the completion or termination of a defense contract or program or reductions in defense spending; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> satisfies such other criteria for selection as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection of Participants</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In selecting participants to receive assistance for placement as elementary or secondary school teachers, the Secretary shall give priority to individuals who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have educational, military, or employment experience in science, mathematics, or engineering and agree to seek employment as science, mathematics, or engineering teachers in elementary or secondary schools; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have educational, military, or employment experience in another subject area identified by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, as important for national educational objectives and agree to seek employment in that subject area in elementary or secondary schools.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not select an individual under this section unless the Secretary has sufficient appropriations to carry out this section available at the time of the selection to satisfy the obligations to be incurred by the United States under this section with respect to that individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An individual selected under this section shall be required to enter into an agreement with the Secretary in which the participant agrees—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to obtain, within such time as the Secretary may require, certification or licensure as an elementary or secondary school teacher or the necessary credentials to serve as a teacher’s aide in an elementary or secondary school; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to accept—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an individual selected for assistance for placement as a teacher, an offer of full-time employment as an elementary or secondary school teacher for not less than two school years with a local educational agency identified under <ref>section 1151(b)(2) of this title</ref>, as in effect on <date date="1999-10-04">October 4, 1999</date>, to begin the school year after obtaining that certification or licensure; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an individual selected for assistance for placement as a teacher’s aide, an offer of full-time employment as a teacher’s aide in an elementary or secondary school for not less than two school years with a local educational agency identified under <ref>section 1151(b)(3) of this title</ref>, as in effect on <date date="1999-10-04">October 4, 1999</date>, to begin the school year after obtaining the necessary credentials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stipend for Participants</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall pay to each participant in the placement program a stipend in an amount equal to the lesser of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $5,000; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total costs of the type described in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (8), and (9) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002138">1</ref> of section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1087</ref><i>ll</i>) incurred by the participant while obtaining teacher certification or licensure or the necessary credentials to serve as a teacher’s aide and employment as an elementary or secondary school teacher or teacher aide.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A stipend provided under this section shall be taken into account in determining the eligibility of the participant for Federal student financial assistance provided under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Placement of Participants as Teachers and Teachers’ Aides</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsections (h) through (k) of <ref>section 1151 of this title</ref>, as in effect on <date date="1999-10-04">October 4, 1999</date>, shall apply with respect to the placement as teachers and teachers’ aides of individuals selected under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV, § 4443(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2732</ref>, § 2410c; renumbered § 2410j and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (g)(6), <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 97</ref>, 100; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1331(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 391(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4022</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1503(a)(23)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 576(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1087(a)(14)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–291; renumbered § 4703, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1863(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4278</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4704.</num>
<heading> Defense contractors: listing of suitable employment openings with local employment service office</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall promulgate regulations containing the requirement described in subsection (b) and such other provisions as the Secretary considers necessary to administer such requirement. Such regulations shall require that each contract described in subsection (c) shall contain a clause requiring the contractor to comply with such regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The regulations promulgated under this section shall require each contractor carrying out a contract described in subsection (c) to list immediately with the appropriate local employment service office, and where appropriate the Interstate Job Bank (established by the United States Employment Service), all of its suitable employment openings under such contract.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The regulations promulgated under this section shall apply to any contract entered into with the Department of Defense in an amount of $500,000 or more.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV, § 4470(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2753</ref>, § 2410d; renumbered § 2410k and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II</ref>, §§ 201(b)(1)(A), 202(a)(18)(A), <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 97</ref>, 102; renumbered § 4704, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1863(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4278</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4705.</num>
<heading> Notice of contract cancellation or termination relating to remote or isolated installations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided by subsection (c), not later than 30 days before the date on which the Secretary of Defense or any other official of an element of the Department of Defense cancels or terminates a contract, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a notice of such cancellation or termination if such cancellation or termination involves a reduction in employment of not fewer than—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 50 remote or isolated installation contractor employees; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 100 employees of contractors, including remote or isolated installation contractor employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A notice described in subsection (a) shall include an assessment of the effect of such cancellation or termination on members of the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive the requirements of subsection (a) with respect to the cancellation or termination of a contract if the Secretary determines that such waiver is in the interest of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the Secretary waives the requirements of subsection (a) with respect to the cancellation or termination of a contract, the Secretary shall submit the notice required by such subsection with respect to such cancellation or termination not later than one week after such cancellation or termination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “remote or isolated installation” means a military installation (as defined in <ref>section 2801 of this title</ref>) that is a remote military installation, as determined by the Secretary pursuant to the policy required by section 565 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (<ref>10 U.S.C. 1781b</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “remote or isolated installation contractor employee” means an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is an employee of a contractor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as such an employee, provides goods or services to a remote or isolated installation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> resides in the same geographic area as such remote or isolated installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 808</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1977</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>