<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 305—</num>
<heading>UNIVERSITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4141.</num>
<heading> Award of grants and contracts to colleges and universities: requirement of competition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may not make a grant or award a contract to a college or university for the performance of research and development, or for the construction of any research or other facility, unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of a grant, the grant is made using competitive procedures; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a contract, the contract is awarded in accordance with <ref>section 3204 of this title</ref> (other than pursuant to subsection (a)(5) of that section).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A provision of law may not be construed as modifying or superseding the provisions of subsection (a), or as requiring funds to be made available by the Secretary of Defense to a particular college or university by grant or contract, unless that provision of law—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> specifically refers to this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> specifically states that such provision of law modifies or supersedes the provisions of this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> specifically identifies the particular college or university involved and states that the grant to be made or the contract to be awarded, as the case may be, pursuant to such provision of law is being made or awarded in contravention of subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A grant may not be made, or a contract awarded, pursuant to a provision of law that authorizes or requires the making of the grant, or the awarding of the contract, in a manner that is inconsistent with subsection (a) until—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense submits to Congress a notice in writing of the intent to make the grant or award the contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a period of 180 days has elapsed after the date on which the notice is received by Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title II, § 220(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1940</ref>, § 2361; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title II, § 252(a)</ref>, (b)(1), (c)(1), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1404</ref>, 1405; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1311(4)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1669</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(g)(5)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VIII, § 821(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1704</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title VIII, § 813</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2816</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title II, § 264</ref>, title XV, § 1502(a)(1), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 237</ref>, 502; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title II, § 265</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2466</ref>; renumbered § 4141, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1844(b)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1841(c), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4243</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(38)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4142.</num>
<heading> Extramural acquisition innovation and research activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment and in coordination with the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, shall establish and maintain extramural acquisition innovation and research activities as described in subsection (c), which shall include an acquisition research organization within a civilian college or university that is not owned or operated by the Federal Government that is established to provide and maintain essential research and development capabilities through a long-term strategic relationship with the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Goals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The goal of any activity conducted pursuant to this section shall be to provide academic analyses and policy alternatives for innovation in defense acquisition policies and practices to policymakers in the Federal Government by using a variety of means intended to widely disseminate research findings from such an activity, in addition to executing demonstration and pilot programs of innovative acquisition policies and practices.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The activities described in this subsection are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Research on past and current defense acquisition policies and practices, commercial and international best practices, and the application of new technologies and analytical capabilities to improve acquisition policies and practices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Pilot programs to prototype and demonstrate new acquisition practices for potential transition to wider use in the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Establishment of data repositories and development of analytical capabilities, in coordination with the Chief Data Officer of the Department of Defense, to enable researchers and acquisition professionals to access and analyze historical data sets to support research and new policy and practice development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Executive education to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> support acquisition workforce development, including for early career, mid-career, and senior leaders; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide appropriate education on acquisition issues to non-acquisition professionals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> On an ongoing basis, a review of the implementation of recommendations contained in relevant Department of Defense and private sector studies on acquisition policies and practices, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for recommendations for the enactment of legislation, identify the extent to which the recommendations have been enacted into law by Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for recommendations for the issuance of regulations, identify the extent to which the recommendations have been adopted through the issuance or revision of regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for recommendations for revisions to policies and procedures in the executive branch, identify the extent to which the recommendations have been adopted through issuance of an appropriate implementing directive or other form of guidance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for recommendations for the resources required to implement recommendations contained in relevant Department of Defense and private sector studies on acquisition policies and practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Engagement with researchers and acquisition professionals in the Department of Defense, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary may use amounts available in the Defense Acquisition Workforce and Development Account to carry out the requirements of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than <date date="2021-09-30">September 30, 2021</date>, and annually thereafter, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall submit to the Secretary of Defense and the congressional defense committees a report describing the activities conducted under this section during the previous year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 835(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1494</ref>, § 2361a; renumbered § 4142, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1844(b)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1842(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4244</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(q)(1)</ref>, (u)(3)(B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2148</ref>, 2152; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 835</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4143.</num>
<heading> Research and development laboratories: contracts for services of university students</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, the Secretary of Defense may procure by contract under the authority of this section the temporary or intermittent services of students at institutions of higher learning for the purpose of providing technical support at defense research and development laboratories. Such contracts may be made directly with such students or with nonprofit organizations employing such students.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Students providing services pursuant to a contract made under subsection (a) shall be considered to be employees for the purposes of chapter 81 of title 5, relating to compensation for work injuries, and to be employees of the government for the purposes of chapter 171 of title 28, relating to tort claims. Such students who are not otherwise employed by the Federal Government shall not be considered to be Federal employees for any other purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Such regulations shall include definitions for the purposes of this section of the terms “student”, “institution of higher learning”, and “nonprofit organization”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1110</ref>, § 2360; renumbered § 4143, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1844(b)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1843(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4144.</num>
<heading> Research and educational programs and activities: historically black colleges and universities and minority-serving institutions of higher education</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Established</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering and the Secretary of each military department, shall carry out a program to provide assistance to covered educational institutions to assist the Department in defense-related research, development, testing, and evaluation activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may not delegate or transfer to an individual outside the Office of the Secretary of Defense the authority regarding the programming or budgeting of the program established by this section that is carried out by the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Objective</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The objective of the program established by subsection (a)(1) is to enhance defense-related research and education at covered educational institutions. Such objective shall be accomplished through initiatives designed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enhance the research and educational capabilities of such institutions in areas of importance to national defense, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage the participation of such institutions in the research, development, testing, and evaluation programs and activities of the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> increase the number of graduates from such institutions engaged in disciplines important to the national security functions of the Department of Defense, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> encourage research and educational collaborations between such institutions and other institutions of higher education, Government defense organizations, and the defense industry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance Provided</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under the program established by subsection (a)(1), the Secretary of Defense may provide covered educational institutions with funding or technical assistance, including any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Support for research, development, testing, evaluation, or educational enhancements in areas important to national defense through the competitive awarding of grants, cooperative agreements, contracts, scholarships, fellowships, or the acquisition of research equipment or instrumentation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Support to assist in the attraction and retention of faculty in scientific disciplines important to the national security functions of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Establishing partnerships between such institutions and defense laboratories, Government defense organizations, the defense industry, and other institutions of higher education in research, development, testing, and evaluation in areas important to the national security functions of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Other such non-monetary assistance as the Secretary finds appropriate to enhance defense-related research, development, testing, and evaluation activities at such institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incentives</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may develop incentives to encourage research and educational collaborations between covered educational institutions and other institutions of higher education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall establish goals and incentives to encourage federally funded research and development centers, science and technology reinvention laboratories, and University Affiliated Research Centers funded by the Department of Defense—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to assess the capacity of covered educational institutions to address the research and development needs of the Department through partnerships and collaborations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if appropriate, to enter into partnerships and collaborations with such institutions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criteria for Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish procedures under which the Secretary may limit funding under this section to institutions that have not otherwise received a significant amount of funding from the Department of Defense for research, development, testing, and evaluation programs supporting the national security functions of the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Covered Educational Institution</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section the term “covered educational institution” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an institution of higher education eligible for assistance under title III or V of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1051</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an accredited postsecondary minority institution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title II, § 252(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2242</ref>, § 2362; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(32)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4370</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title II, § 219</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1335</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(c)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title II, § 245</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1257</ref>; renumbered § 4144, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1844(b)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1838(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title II, § 220(c)</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(v)(2)(A), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1599</ref>, 2154.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4145 to 4147.</num>
<heading> Omitted]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>