<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1213—</num>
<heading>SPECIAL APPOINTMENTS, ASSIGNMENTS, DETAILS, AND DUTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12501.</num>
<heading> Reserve components: detail of members of regular and reserve components to assist</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary concerned shall detail such members of the regular and reserve components under his jurisdiction as are necessary to effectively develop, train, instruct, and administer those reserve components.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12502.</num>
<heading> Chief and assistant chief of staff of National Guard divisions and wings in Federal service: detail</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President may detail a regular or reserve officer of the Army as chief of staff, and a regular or reserve officer or an officer of the Army National Guard as assistant to the chief of staff, of any division of the Army National Guard that is in Federal service as an Army National Guard organization.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The President may detail a regular or reserve officer of the Air Force as chief of staff, and a regular or reserve officer or an officer of the Air National Guard as assistant to the chief of staff, of any wing of the Air National Guard that is in Federal service as an Air National Guard organization.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12503.</num>
<heading> Ready Reserve: funeral honors duty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order to Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of the Ready Reserve may be ordered to funeral honors duty, with the consent of the member, in preparation for or to perform funeral honors functions at the funeral of a veteran as defined in <ref>section 1491 of this title</ref>. Performance of funeral honors duty by a Reserve not on active duty shall be treated as inactive-duty training (including with respect to travel to and from such duty) for purposes of any provision of law other than sections 206 and 435 of title 37.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service Credit</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A member ordered to funeral honors duty under this section shall be required to perform a minimum of two hours of such duty in order to receive—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> service credit under <ref>section 12732(a)(2)(E) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> as directed by the Secretary concerned, either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the allowance under <ref>section 435 of title 37</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compensation under <ref>section 206 of title 37</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursable Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member who performs funeral honors duty under this section may be reimbursed for travel and transportation expenses incurred in conjunction with such duty as authorized under <ref>section 452 of title 37</ref> if such duty is performed at a location 50 miles or more from the member’s residence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The exercise of authority under subsection (a) is subject to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members of the National Guard</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply to members of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States. The performance of funeral honors duty by those members is provided for in <ref>section 115 of title 32</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 578(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 628</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 575(a)(2)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–138; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 562(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1119</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VI, § 631(f)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1465</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1948</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 626(c)(9)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2628</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 12505.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 507(f)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–105]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>