<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 207—</num>
<heading>BUDGETING AND APPROPRIATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3131.</num>
<heading> Availability of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for research and development remain available for obligation for a period of two consecutive years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for research and development may be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the purposes of <ref>section 4141 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for purposes related to research and development for which expenditures are specifically authorized in other appropriations of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(b)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1052</ref>, § 2361; renumbered § 2351 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 846</ref>; renumbered § 3131 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1809(b), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4161</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2136</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3132.</num>
<heading> Availability of appropriations for procurement of technical military equipment and supplies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for the procurement of technical military equipment and supplies remain available until spent.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(b)(4)(B)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1052</ref>, § 2394; renumbered § 2395 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(28)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1291</ref>; renumbered § 3132, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1809(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4161</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3133.</num>
<heading> Contracts for periods crossing fiscal years: severable service contracts; leases of real or personal property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of a military department, or the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, may enter into a contract for a purpose described in paragraph (2) for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in the next fiscal year if (without regard to any option to extend the period of the contract) the contract period does not exceed one year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The purpose of a contract described in this paragraph is as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The procurement of severable services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The lease of real or personal property, including the maintenance of such property when contracted for as part of the lease agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligation of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds made available for a fiscal year may be obligated for the total amount of a contract entered into under the authority of subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 847</ref>, § 2410a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title III, § 342</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1343</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 214(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3915</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VIII, § 801(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1831</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1005(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1584</ref>; renumbered § 3133, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1809(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4161</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3134.</num>
<heading> Allocation of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Appropriations available for procurement by an agency named in <ref>section 3063 of this title</ref> may, through administrative allotment, be made available for obligation for procurement by any other agency in amounts authorized by the head of the allotting agency and without transfer of funds on the books of the Department of the Treasury.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A disbursing official of the allotting agency may make any disbursement chargeable to an allotment under subsection (a) upon a voucher certified by an officer or civilian employee of the procuring agency.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 132</ref>, § 2309; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1052</ref>; renumbered § 3134 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1809(e)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4161</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2132</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3135.</num>
<heading> Comparable budgeting for common procurement weapon systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matters To Be Included in Annual Defense Budgets</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In preparing the defense budget for any fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specifically identify each common procurement weapon system included in the budget;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> take all feasible steps to minimize variations in procurement unit costs for any such system as shown in the budget requests of the different armed forces requesting procurement funds for the system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify and justify in the budget all such variations in procurement unit costs for common procurement weapon systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Comptroller</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall carry out this section through the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “defense budget” means the budget of the Department of Defense included in the President’s budget submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> for a fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “common procurement weapon system” means a weapon system for which two or more of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force request procurement funds in a defense budget.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(d)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 843</ref>, § 2217; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1503(a)(20)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 512</ref>; renumbered § 3135 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(1)(N)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1809(f)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3820</ref>, 4161.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3136.</num>
<heading> Defense Modernization Account</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established in the Treasury an account to be known as the “Defense Modernization Account”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funds Available for Account</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Defense Modernization Account shall consist of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Amounts appropriated to the Defense Modernization Account for the costs of projects described in subsection (d)(1), and amounts reimbursed to the Defense Modernization Account under subsection (c)(1)(B)(ii) out of savings derived from such projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts transferred to the Defense Modernization Account under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfers to Account</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Upon a determination by the Secretary of a military department, or the Secretary of Defense with respect to Defense-wide appropriations accounts, of the availability and source of funds described in subparagraph (B), the Secretary concerned may transfer to the Defense Modernization Account during any fiscal year any amount of funds available to the Secretary described in that subparagraph. Such funds may be transferred to that account only after the Secretary concerned notifies the congressional defense committees in writing of the amount and source of the proposed transfer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> This subsection applies to the following funds that have been appropriated for fiscal years after fiscal year 2016 and are available to the Secretary concerned:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Unexpired funds in appropriations accounts that are available for new obligations and that, as a result of economies, efficiencies, and other savings achieved in carrying out an acquisition program, are excess to the requirements of that program.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Unexpired funds in appropriations accounts that are available for procurement or operation and maintenance of a system, if and to the extent that savings are achieved for such accounts through reductions in life cycle costs of such system that result from one or more projects undertaken with respect to such systems with funds made available from the Defense Modernization Account under subsection (b)(1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any transfer under subparagraph (A) shall be made under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds referred to in paragraph (1) may not be transferred to the Defense Modernization Account if the balance of funds in the account, after transfer of funds to the account, would exceed $1,000,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Amounts deposited in the Defense Modernization Account shall remain available for transfer and obligation until the end of the third fiscal year that follows the fiscal year in which the amounts are deposited in the account.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds in the Defense Modernization Account may be used for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For paying the costs of any project that, in accordance with criteria prescribed by the Secretary concerned, is undertaken by the Secretary of a military department or the head of a Defense Agency or other element of the Department of Defense to reduce the life cycle cost of a new or existing system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For increasing, subject to subsection (e), the quantity of items and services procured under an acquisition program in order to achieve a more efficient production or delivery rate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For research, development, test, and evaluation, for procurement, and for sustainment activities necessary for paying costs of unforeseen contingencies that are approved by the milestone decision authority concerned, that could prevent an ongoing acquisition program from meeting critical schedule or performance requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For paying costs of changes to program requirements or system configuration that are approved by the configuration steering board for a major defense acquisition program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For procuring and integrating available commercial technologies and services to satisfy a joint urgent operational need, joint emergent operational need, or a validated service requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For providing infrastructure to support Department goals of accelerating the fielding and adoption of new capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Funds in the Defense Modernization Account may not be used to increase the quantity of an item or services procured under a particular acquisition program to the extent that doing so would—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> result in procurement of a total quantity of items or services in excess of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a specific limitation provided by law on the quantity of the items or services that may be procured; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the requirement for the items or services as approved by the Joint Requirements Oversight Council and reported to Congress by the Secretary of Defense; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> result in an obligation or expenditure of funds in excess of a specific limitation provided by law on the amount that may be obligated or expended, respectively, for that acquisition program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds in the Defense Modernization Account may not be used for a purpose or program for which Congress has not authorized appropriations, unless the procedures for initiating a new start program are complied with.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Funds may not be transferred from the Defense Modernization Account in any year for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> making an expenditure for which there is no corresponding obligation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> making an expenditure that would satisfy an unliquidated or unrecorded obligation arising in a prior fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department, or the Secretary of Defense with respect to Defense-wide appropriations accounts, may transfer funds in the Defense Modernization Account to appropriations available for purposes set forth in subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds in the Defense Modernization Account may not be transferred under paragraph (1) until 30 days after the date on which the Secretary concerned notifies the congressional defense committees in writing of the amount and purpose of the proposed transfer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The total amount of transfers from the Defense Modernization Account during any fiscal year under this subsection may not exceed $500,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds by Appropriation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to transfers under subsection (f), funds in the Defense Modernization Account may be made available for purposes set forth in subsection (d), but only to the extent authorized in an Act other than an appropriations Act. Funds deposited in the Defense Modernization Account shall remain available for obligation until the end of the third fiscal year that follows the fiscal year in which the amounts are deposited in the account.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary To Act Through Comptroller</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall carry out this section through the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller), who shall be authorized to implement this section through the issuance of any necessary regulations, policies, and procedures after consultation with the General Counsel and Inspector General of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) shall, at a minimum, provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the establishment and management of subaccounts for each of the military departments and Defense Agencies concerned for the use of funds in the Defense Modernization Account, consistent with each military department’s or Defense Agency’s deposits in the Account;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the submission of proposals by the Secretaries concerned or heads of Defense Agencies or other elements of the Department of Defense to the Comptroller for the use of Defense Modernization Account funds for purposes set forth in subsection (d);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the use of a competitive process for the evaluation of such proposals and the selection of programs, projects, and activities to be funded out of the Defense Modernization Account and subaccounts from among those proposed for such funding; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> the calculation of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the savings to be derived from projects described in subsection (d)(1) that are to be funded out of the Defense Modernization Account; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amounts to be reimbursed to the Defense Modernization Account out of such savings pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(B)(ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “major defense acquisition program” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 4201 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “unexpired funds” means funds appropriated for a definite period that remain available for obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IX, § 912(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 407</ref>, § 2216; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1008(a)–(f)(1), 1043(b)(8), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1586</ref>, 1587, 1611; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2399</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1084(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 871</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 804</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2250</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(30)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1814</ref>; renumbered § 3136 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1809(g)(1), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4161</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 813</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2707</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title X, § 1003(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2047</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 3137.</num>
<heading> Omitted]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3138.</num>
<heading> Obligations for contract services: reporting in budget object classes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Reporting in Miscellaneous Services Object Class</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, in reporting to the Office of Management and Budget (pursuant to OMB Circular A–11 (relating to preparation and submission of budget estimates)) obligations of the Department of Defense for any period of time for contract services, no more than 15 percent of the total amount of obligations so reported is reported in the miscellaneous services object class.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Reporting Categories for Advisory and Assistance Services</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out <ref>section 1105(g) of title 31</ref> for the Department of Defense (and in determining what services are to be reported to the Office of Management and Budget in the advisory and assistance services object class), the Secretary of Defense shall apply to the terms used for the definition of “advisory and assistance services” in paragraph (2)(A) of that section the following meanings (subject to the authorized exemptions):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Management and professional support services</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “management and professional support services” (used in clause (i) of <ref>section 1105(g)(2)(A) of title 31</ref>) means services that provide engineering or technical support, assistance, advice, or training for the efficient and effective management and operation of organizations, activities, or systems. Those services—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are closely related to the basic responsibilities and mission of the using organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> include efforts that support or contribute to improved organization or program management, logistics management, project monitoring and reporting, data collection, budgeting, accounting, auditing, and administrative or technical support for conferences and training programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Studies, analyses, and evaluations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “studies, analyses, and evaluations” (used in clause (ii) of <ref>section 1105(g)(2)(A) of title 31</ref>) means services that provide organized, analytic assessments to understand or evaluate complex issues to improve policy development, decisionmaking, management, or administration and that result in documents containing data or leading to conclusions or recommendations. Those services may include databases, models, methodologies, and related software created in support of a study, analysis, or evaluation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Engineering and technical services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “engineering and technical services” (used in clause (iii) of <ref>section 1105(g)(2)(A) of title 31</ref>) means services that take the form of advice, assistance, training, or hands-on training necessary to maintain and operate fielded weapon systems, equipment, and components (including software when applicable) at design or required levels of effectiveness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proper Classification of Advisory and Assistance Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before the submission to the Office of Management and Budget of the proposed Department of Defense budget for inclusion in the President’s budget for a fiscal year pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller), shall conduct a review of Department of Defense services expected to be performed as contract services during the fiscal year for which that budget is to be submitted in order to ensure that those services that are advisory and assistance services (as defined in accordance with subsection (b)) are in fact properly classified, in accordance with that subsection, in the advisory and assistance services object class.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall submit to Congress each year, not later than 30 days after the date on which the budget for the next fiscal year is submitted pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, a report containing the information derived from the review under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment by Comptroller General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Comptroller General shall conduct a review of the report of the Secretary of Defense under subsection (d) each year and shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assess the methodology used by the Secretary in obtaining the information submitted to Congress in that report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assess the information submitted to Congress in that report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than 120 days after the date on which the Secretary submits to Congress the report required under subsection (d) for any year, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress the Comptroller General’s report containing the results of the review for that year under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “contract services” means all services that are reported to the Office of Management and Budget pursuant to OMB Circular A–11 (relating to preparation and submission of budget estimates) in budget object classes that are designated in the Object Class 25 series.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “advisory and assistance services object class” means those contract services constituting the budget object class that is denominated “Advisory and Assistance Service” and designated (as of <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>) as Object Class 25.1 (or any similar object class established after <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>, for the reporting of obligations for advisory and assistance contract services).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “miscellaneous services object class” means those contract services constituting the budget object class that is denominated “Other Services (services not otherwise specified in the 25 series)” and designated (as of <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>) as Object Class 25.2 (or any similar object class established after <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>, for the reporting of obligations for miscellaneous or unspecified contract services).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “authorized exemptions” means those exemptions authorized (as of <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>) under Department of Defense Directive 4205.2, captioned “Acquiring and Managing Contracted Advisory and Assistance Services (CAAS)” and issued by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Technology on <date date="1992-02-10">February 10, 1992</date>, such exemptions being set forth in Enclosure 3 to that directive (captioned “CAAS Exemptions”).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2097</ref>, § 2212; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 771</ref>; renumbered § 3138, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1809(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4162</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>