<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 875—</num>
<heading>DISPOSAL OF OBSOLETE OR SURPLUS MATERIAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8761.</num>
<heading> Obsolete and other material: gift or sale to Boy Scouts of America, Naval Sea Cadet Corps and Young Marines of the Marine Corps League</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to regulations under <ref>section 121 of title 40</ref>, the Secretary of the Navy may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> give obsolete material not needed for naval purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> sell other material that may be spared at a price representing its fair value;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">to the Boy Scouts of America for the sea scouts, to the Naval Sea Cadet Corps for the sea cadets, and to the Young Marines of the Marine Corps League for the young marines. The cost of transportation and delivery of material given or sold under this section shall be charged to the Boy Scouts of America, to the Naval Sea Cadets, or to the Young Marines of the Marine Corps League, as the case may be.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 465</ref>, § 7541; <ref>Pub. L. 93–628, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(39)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2934</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(31)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1297</ref>; renumbered § 8761, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8761a.</num>
<heading> Uniform clothing: sale to Naval Sea Cadet Corps</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to regulations under <ref>section 121 of title 40</ref>, the Secretary of the Navy, under regulations prescribed by him, may sell any item of enlisted naval uniform clothing that may be spared, at a price representing its fair value, to the Naval Sea Cadet Corps for the sea cadets and to any Federal or State maritime academy having a department of naval science for the maritime cadets and midshipmen. The cost of transportation and delivery of items sold under this section shall be charged to the Naval Sea Cadet Corps and to such Federal and State maritime academies.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–266, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1965-10-19">Oct. 19, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 990</ref>, § 7541a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(39)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2934</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(32)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1297</ref>; renumbered § 8761a, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8761b.</num>
<heading> Authority to make grants for purposes of Naval Sea Cadet Corps</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of funds for this purpose, the Secretary of the Navy may make grants to support the purposes of Naval Sea Cadet Corps, a federally chartered corporation under chapter 1541 of title 36.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 592(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2337</ref>, § 7541b; renumbered § 8761b, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8762.</num>
<heading> Excess clothing: sale for distribution to needy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to regulations under <ref>section 121 of title 40</ref>, the Secretary of the Navy, under regulations prescribed by him, may sell, at nominal prices, to recognized charitable organizations, to States and subdivisions thereof, and to municipalities nonregulation and excess clothing that may be available for distribution to the needy. The clothing may be sold only if the purchaser agrees not to resell it but to give it to the needy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A fair proportionate allotment of clothing to be sold under this section shall be set aside for distribution in each State and the District of Columbia. An allotment so set aside may not be sold for other distribution until at least 30 days after the allotment was made.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 465</ref>, § 7542; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(39)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2934</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(33)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1297</ref>; renumbered § 8762, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8763.</num>
<heading> Useless ordnance material: disposition of proceeds on sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The net proceeds of sales of useless ordnance material by the Department of the Navy shall be covered into the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 465</ref>, § 7543; renumbered § 8763, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8764.</num>
<heading> Devices and trophies: transfer to other agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy may, without reimbursement, transfer to the Secretary of the Treasury devices and trophies for the promotion of the sale of war bonds or victory bonds. The Secretary of the Treasury may sell or donate the devices and trophies for the promotion of the sale of such bonds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy may, without reimbursement, transfer to any agency of the United States devices and trophies for scientific, experimental, monumental, or display purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 465</ref>, § 7544; renumbered § 8764, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8765.</num>
<heading> Obsolete material and articles of historical interest: loan or gift</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Make Loans and Gifts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Navy may lend or give, without expense to the United States, items described in subsection (b) that are not needed by the Department of the Navy to any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A State, Commonwealth, or possession of the United States, or political subdivision or municipal corporation thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A library.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A historical society.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An educational institution whose graduates or students fought in a foreign war.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A servicemen’s monument association.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> A State museum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> A museum or memorial operated and maintained for educational purposes only, whose charter denies it the right to operate for profit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> A post of the Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> A post of the American Legion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Any other recognized war veterans’ association.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> A post of the Sons of Veterans Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Items Eligible for Disposal</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>This section applies to the following types of property held by the Department of the Navy:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Captured, condemned, or obsolete ordnance material.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Captured, condemned, or obsolete combat or shipboard material.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A loan or gift made under this section shall be subject to regulations prescribed by the Secretary and to regulations under <ref>section 121 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maintenance of the Records of the Government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Records of the Government as defined in <ref>section 3301 of title 44</ref> may not be disposed of under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternative Authorities To Make Gifts or Loans</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If any disposition is authorized by this section and <ref>section 2572 of this title</ref>, the Secretary may make the gift or loan under either section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Transfer a Portion of a Vessel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may lend, give, or otherwise transfer any portion of the hull or superstructure of a vessel stricken from the Naval Vessel Register and designated for scrapping to a qualified organization specified in subsection (a). The terms and conditions of an agreement for the transfer of a portion of a vessel under this section shall include a requirement that the transferee will maintain the material conveyed in a condition that will not diminish the historical value of the material or bring discredit upon the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 466</ref>, § 7545; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 513(39)</ref>, (40), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2934</ref>, 2935; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1061(i)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 443</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1043(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1218</ref>, 1219; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(34)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1062(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2651</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3440</ref>; renumbered § 8765, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8766.</num>
<heading> Loan or gift of articles to ships’ sponsors and donors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy, under regulations prescribed by him and without expense to the United States, may lend or give—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to the sponsor of a vessel the name plate or any small article of negligible or sentimental value from that vessel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to any State, group, or organization named in <ref>section 8765 of this title</ref> any article, material, or equipment, including silver service, given by it.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 466</ref>, § 7546; renumbered § 8766 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(d)(8), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8767.</num>
<heading> Equipment for instruction in seamanship: loan to military schools</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Upon the application of the governor of any State having a seacoast or bordering on any of the Great Lakes, the President may direct the Secretary of the Navy to lend to one well-established military school in that State that desires to instruct its cadets in elementary seamanship one fully equipped cutter for every 25 cadets attending the school, and such other equipment adequate for instruction in elementary seamanship as may be spared.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> To be eligible for a loan under this section a school must—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> have adequate facilities for cutter drill;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> have at least 75 cadets—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at least 15 years of age;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in uniform;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> receiving military instruction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> quartered in barracks under military regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> have the capacity to quarter and educate 150 cadets at one time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whenever a loan is made under this section, the Secretary shall require a bond in double the value of the property for its care and return when required.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 466</ref>, § 7547; renumbered § 8767, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>