<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 763—</num>
<heading>PROCUREMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7532.</num>
<heading> Factories and arsenals: manufacture at</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army shall have supplies needed for the Department of the Army made in factories or arsenals owned by the United States, so far as those factories or arsenals can make those supplies on an economical basis.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 254</ref>, § 4532; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title III, § 323(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3343</ref>; renumbered § 7532, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7536.</num>
<heading> Equipment: post bakeries, schools, kitchens, and mess halls</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Money necessary for the following items for the use of enlisted members of the Army may be spent from appropriations for regular supplies:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Equipment for post bakeries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Furniture, textbooks, paper, and equipment for post schools.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Tableware and mess furniture for kitchens and mess halls.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 254</ref>, § 4536; renumbered § 7536, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7540.</num>
<heading> Architectural and engineering services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whenever he considers that it is advantageous to the national defense and that existing facilities of the Department of the Army are inadequate, the Secretary of the Army may, by contract or otherwise, employ the architectural or engineering services of any person outside that Department for producing and delivering designs, plans, drawings, and specifications needed for any public works or utilities project of the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The fee for any service under this section may not be more than 10 percent of the estimated cost, as determined by the Secretary, of the project to which it applies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Sections 305, 3324, and 7204, chapter 51, and subchapters III, IV, and VI of chapter 53 of title 5 do not apply to employment under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 255</ref>, § 4540; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 28</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1119</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 703(c)(3)</ref>, title VIII, § 801(a)(3)(I), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1217</ref>, 1222; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 512(16)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2930</ref>; renumbered § 7540, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2881(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 780</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7541.</num>
<heading> Army arsenals: treatment of unutilized or underutilized plant-capacity costs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Estimate of Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Army shall include in the budget justification documents submitted to Congress in support of the President’s budget for a fiscal year submitted under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> an estimate of the funds to be required in that fiscal year to cover unutilized and underutilized plant-capacity costs at Army arsenals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds appropriated to the Secretary of the Army for a fiscal year to cover unutilized and underutilized plant-capacity costs at Army arsenals shall be used in such fiscal year only for such costs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army shall not include unutilized and underutilized plant-capacity costs when evaluating the bid of an Army arsenal for purposes of the arsenal’s contracting to provide a good or service to a Government agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When an Army arsenal is serving as a subcontractor to a private-sector entity with respect to a good or service to be provided to a Government agency, the cost charged by the arsenal shall not include unutilized and underutilized plant-capacity costs that are funded by a direct appropriation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Army arsenal” means a Government-owned, Government-operated defense plant of the Department of the Army that manufactures weapons, weapon components, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “unutilized and underutilized plant-capacity costs” means the costs associated with operating and maintaining the facilities and equipment of an Army arsenal that the Secretary of the Army determines are required to be kept for mobilization needs, in those months in which the facilities and equipment are not used or are used only 20 percent or less of available work days.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, § 342(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–64, § 4541; renumbered § 7541, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7542.</num>
<heading> Technical data packages for large-caliber cannon: prohibition on transfers to foreign countries; exception</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Rule</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense may not be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to transfer to a foreign country a technical data package for a defense item being manufactured or developed in an arsenal; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist a foreign country in producing such a defense item.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Army may use funds appropriated to the Department of Defense to transfer a technical data package, or to provide assistance, described in subsection (a) if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the transfer or provision of assistance is to a friendly foreign country (as determined by the Secretary of Defense in consultation with the Secretary of State);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of the Army determines that such action—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> would have a clear benefit to the preservation of the production base for the production of cannon at the arsenal concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> would not transfer technology (including production techniques) considered unique to the arsenal concerned, except as provided in subsection (e); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense enters into an agreement with the country concerned described in subsection (c) or (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coproduction Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An agreement under this subsection shall be in the form of a Government-to-Government Memorandum of Understanding and shall include provisions that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prescribe the content of the technical data package or assistance to be transferred to the foreign country participating in the agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require that production by the participating foreign country of the defense item to which the technical data package or assistance relates be shared with the arsenal concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> subject to such exceptions as may be approved under subsection (f), prohibit transfer by the participating foreign country to a third party or country of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any defense article, technical data package, technology, or assistance provided by the United States under the agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any defense article produced by the participating foreign country under the agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> require the Secretary of Defense to monitor compliance with the agreement and the participating foreign country to report periodically to the Secretary of Defense concerning the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Project Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An agreement under this subsection is a cooperative project agreement under section 27 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2767</ref>) which includes provisions that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for development phases describe the technical data to be transferred and for the production phase prescribe the content of the technical data package or assistance to be transferred to the foreign country participating in the agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require that at least the United States production of the defense item to which the technical data package or assistance relates be carried out by the arsenal concerned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> require the Secretary of Defense to monitor compliance with the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Licensing Fees and Royalties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The limitation in subsection (b)(2)(B) shall not apply if the technology (or production technique) transferred is subject to nonexclusive license and payment of any negotiated licensing fee or royalty that reflects the cost of development, implementation, and prove-out of the technology or production technique. Any negotiated license fee or royalty shall be placed in the operating fund of the arsenal concerned for the purpose of capital investment and technology development at that arsenal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfers to Third Parties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A transfer described in subsection (c)(3) may be made if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the defense article, technical data package, or technology to be transferred is a product of a cooperative research and development program or a cooperative project in which the United States and the participating foreign country were partners; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the President—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> complies with all requirements of section 3(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2753(d)</ref>) with respect to such transfer; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> certifies to Congress, before the transfer, that the transfer would provide a clear benefit to the production base of the United States for large-caliber cannon.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and Reports to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army shall submit to Congress a notice of each agreement entered into under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall submit to Congress a semi-annual report on the operation of this section and of agreements entered into under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Arsenal Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “arsenal” means a Government-owned, Government-operated defense plant that manufactures large-caliber cannon.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title IX, § 9036(b)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–82</ref>, 1783–107, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title IX, § 9036(b)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–82</ref>, 3341–107, § 4542; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XII, § 1203(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3968</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1489</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1061(a)(24), 1086, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1473</ref>, 1483; renumbered § 7542, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7543.</num>
<heading> Army industrial facilities: sales of manufactured articles or services outside Department of Defense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Sell Outside DOD</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Regulations under <ref>section 2208(h) of this title</ref> shall authorize a working-capital funded Army industrial facility (including a Department of the Army arsenal) that manufactures large caliber cannons, gun mounts, recoil mechanisms, ammunition, munitions, or components thereof to sell manufactured articles or services to a person outside the Department of Defense if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an article, the article is sold to a United States manufacturer, assembler, developer, or other concern—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for use in developing new products;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for incorporation into items to be sold to, or to be used in a contract with, an agency of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for incorporation into items to be sold to, or to be used in a contract with, or to be used for purposes of soliciting a contract with, a friendly foreign government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for use in commercial products;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of an article, the purchaser is determined by the Department of Defense to be qualified to carry out the proposed work involving the article to be purchased;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the sale is to be made on a basis that does not interfere with performance of work by the facility for the Department of Defense or for a contractor of the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in the case of services, the services are related to an article authorized to be sold under this section and are to be performed in the United States for the purchaser;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Army determines that the articles or services are not available from a commercial source located in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the purchaser of an article or service agrees to hold harmless and indemnify the United States, except in a case of willful misconduct or gross negligence, from any claim for damages or injury to any person or property arising out of the article or service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the article to be sold can be manufactured, or the service to be sold can be substantially performed, by the industrial facility with only incidental subcontracting;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> it is in the public interest to manufacture such article or perform such service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the sale will not interfere with performance of the military mission of the industrial facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The regulations shall also—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require that the authority to sell articles or services under the regulations be exercised at the level of the commander of the major subordinate command of the Army with responsibility over the facility concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> authorize a purchaser of articles or services to use advance incremental funding to pay for the articles or services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a sale of commercial articles or commercial services in accordance with subsection (a) by a facility that manufactures large caliber cannons, gun mounts, or recoil mechanisms, or components thereof, authorize such facility—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to charge the buyer, at a minimum, the variable costs that are associated with the commercial articles or commercial services sold;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to enter into a firm, fixed-price contract or, if agreed by the buyer, a cost reimbursement contract for the sale; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to develop and maintain (from sources other than appropriated funds) working capital to be available for paying design costs, planning costs, procurement costs, and other costs associated with the commercial articles or commercial services sold.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Arms Export Control Act</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the application of the export controls provided for in section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2778</ref>) to items which incorporate or are produced through the use of an article sold under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “commercial article” means an article that is usable for a nondefense purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “commercial service” means a service that is usable for a nondefense purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “advance incremental funding”, with respect to a sale of articles or services, means a series of partial payments for the articles or services that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> one or more partial payments before the commencement of work or the incurring of costs in connection with the production of the articles or the performance of the services, as the case may be; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subsequent progress payments that result in full payment being completed as the required work is being completed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The term “variable costs”, with respect to sales of articles or services, means the costs that are expected to fluctuate directly with the volume of sales and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of articles, the volume of production necessary to satisfy the sales orders; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of services, the extent of the services sold.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title I, § 158(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1581</ref>, § 4543; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title I, § 141</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2688</ref>; renumbered § 7543, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7544.</num>
<heading> Army industrial facilities: cooperative activities with non-Army entities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Arrangements Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A working-capital funded Army industrial facility may enter into a contract or other cooperative arrangement with a non-Army entity to carry out with the non-Army entity a military or commercial project described in subsection (b), subject to the conditions prescribed in subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A cooperative arrangement entered into by an Army industrial facility under subsection (a) may provide for any of the following activities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The sale of articles manufactured by the facility or services performed by the facility to persons outside the Department of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The performance of work by a non-Army entity at the facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The performance of work by the facility for a non-Army entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The sharing of work by the facility and a non-Army entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The leasing, or use under a facilities use contract or otherwise, of the facility (including excess capacity) or equipment (including excess equipment) of the facility by a non-Army entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The preparation and submission of joint offers by the facility and a non-Army entity for competitive procurements entered into with Federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An activity authorized by subsection (b) may be carried out at an Army industrial facility under a cooperative arrangement entered into under subsection (a) only under the following conditions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of an article to be manufactured or services to be performed by the facility, the articles can be substantially manufactured, or the services can be substantially performed, by the facility without subcontracting for more than incidental performance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The activity does not interfere with performance of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> work by the facility for the Department of Defense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a military mission of the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The activity meets one of the following objectives:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Maximized utilization of the capacity of the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Reduction or elimination of the cost of ownership of the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Reduction in the cost of manufacturing or maintaining Department of Defense products at the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Preservation of skills or equipment related to a core competency of the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The non-Army entity agrees to hold harmless and indemnify the United States from any liability or claim for damages or injury to any person or property arising out of the activity, including any damages or injury arising out of a decision by the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of Defense to suspend or terminate an activity, or any portion thereof, during a war or national emergency or to require the facility to perform other work or provide other services on a priority basis, except—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in any case of willful misconduct or gross negligence; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a claim by a purchaser of articles or services under this section that damages or injury arose from the failure of the United States to comply with quality, schedule, or cost performance requirements in the contract to carry out the activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Arrangement Methods and Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To establish a cooperative arrangement under subsection (a) with a non-Army entity, the approval authority described in subsection (f) for an Army industrial facility may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enter into a firm, fixed-price contract (or, if agreed to by the non-Army entity, a cost reimbursement contract) for a sale of articles or services or use of equipment or facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enter into a multiyear contract for a period not to exceed five years, unless a longer period is specifically authorized by law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> charge the non-Army entity the amounts necessary to recover the full costs of the articles or services provided, including capital improvement costs, and equipment depreciation costs associated with providing the articles, services, equipment, or facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> authorize the non-Army entity to use incremental funding to pay for the articles, services, or use of equipment or facilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> accept payment-in-kind.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proceeds Credited to Working Capital Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The proceeds received from the sale of an article or service pursuant to a contract or other cooperative arrangement under this section shall be credited to the working capital fund that incurs the cost of manufacturing the article or performing the service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of an Army industrial facility to enter into a cooperative arrangement under subsection (a) shall be exercised at the level of the commander of the major subordinate command of the Army that has responsibility for the facility. The commander may approve such an arrangement on a case-by-case basis or a class basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commercial Sales</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except in the case of work performed for the Department of Defense, for a contract of the Department of Defense, for foreign military sales, or for authorized foreign direct commercial sales (defense articles or defense services sold to a foreign government or international organization under export controls), a sale of articles or services may be made under this section only if the approval authority described in subsection (f) determines that the articles or services are not available from a commercial source located in the United States in the required quantity or quality, or within the time required.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion From Depot-Level Maintenance and Repair Percentage Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts expended for the performance of a depot-level maintenance and repair workload by non-Federal Government personnel at an Army industrial facility shall not be counted for purposes of applying the percentage limitation in <ref>section 2466(a) of this title</ref> if the personnel are provided by a non-Army entity pursuant to a cooperative arrangement entered into under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the application of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> foreign military sales and the export controls provided for in sections 30 and 38 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2770</ref> and 2778) to activities of a cooperative arrangement entered into under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>section 2667 of this title</ref> to leases of non-excess property in the administration of such an arrangement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Army industrial facility” includes an ammunition plant, an arsenal, a depot, and a manufacturing plant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “non-Army entity” includes the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A Federal agency (other than the Department of the Army).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An entity in industry or commercial sales.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A State or political subdivision of a State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> An institution of higher education or vocational training institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “incremental funding” means a series of partial payments that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are made as the work on manufacture or articles is being performed or services are being performed or equipment or facilities are used, as the case may be; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> result in full payment being completed as the required work is being completed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “full costs”, with respect to articles or services provided under a cooperative arrangement entered into under subsection (a), means the variable costs and the fixed costs that are directly related to the production of the articles or the provision of the services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “variable costs” means the costs that are expected to fluctuate directly with the volume of sales or services provided or the use of equipment or facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title III, § 353(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1859</ref>, § 4544; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3191</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(29)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2399</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title III, § 328(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 66</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title III, § 324(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2253</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 323(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1362</ref>; renumbered § 7544, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>