<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 47A—</num>
<heading>MILITARY COMMISSIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 948a.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alien</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “alien” means an individual who is not a citizen of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Classified information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “classified information” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any information or material that has been determined by the United States Government pursuant to statute, Executive order, or regulation to require protection against unauthorized disclosure for reasons of national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any restricted data, as that term is defined in section 11 y. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2014(y)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coalition partner</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “coalition partner”, with respect to hostilities engaged in by the United States, means any State or armed force directly engaged along with the United States in such hostilities or providing direct operational support to the United States in connection with such hostilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Geneva convention relative to the treatment of prisoners of war</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Geneva Convention Relative to the Treatment of Prisoners of War” means the Convention Relative to the Treatment of Prisoners of War, done at Geneva <date date="1949-08-12">August 12, 1949</date> (6 UST 3316).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Geneva conventions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Geneva Conventions” means the international conventions signed at Geneva on <date date="1949-08-12">August 12, 1949</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Privileged belligerent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “privileged belligerent” means an individual belonging to one of the eight categories enumerated in Article 4 of the Geneva Convention Relative to the Treatment of Prisoners of War.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unprivileged enemy belligerent</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “unprivileged enemy belligerent” means an individual (other than a privileged belligerent) who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has engaged in hostilities against the United States or its coalition partners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has purposefully and materially supported hostilities against the United States or its coalition partners; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> was a part of al Qaeda at the time of the alleged offense under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National security</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “national security” means the national defense and foreign relations of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hostilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “hostilities” means any conflict subject to the laws of war.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2574</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 948b.</num>
<heading> Military commissions generally</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This chapter establishes procedures governing the use of military commissions to try alien unprivileged enemy belligerents for violations of the law of war and other offenses triable by military commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority for Military Commissions Under This Chapter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President is authorized to establish military commissions under this chapter for offenses triable by military commission as provided in this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction of Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The procedures for military commissions set forth in this chapter are based upon the procedures for trial by general courts-martial under chapter 47 of this title (the Uniform Code of Military Justice). Chapter 47 of this title does not, by its terms, apply to trial by military commission except as specifically provided therein or in this chapter, and many of the provisions of chapter 47 of this title are by their terms inapplicable to military commissions. The judicial construction and application of chapter 47 of this title, while instructive, is therefore not of its own force binding on military commissions established under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of Certain Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The following provisions of this title shall not apply to trial by military commission under this chapter:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Section 810 (article 10 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice), relating to speedy trial, including any rule of courts-martial relating to speedy trial.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Sections 831(a), (b), and (d) (articles 31(a), (b), and (d) of the Uniform Code of Military Justice), relating to compulsory self-incrimination.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Section 832 (article 32 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice), relating to preliminary hearing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Other provisions of chapter 47 of this title shall apply to trial by military commission under this chapter only to the extent provided by the terms of such provisions or by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Geneva Conventions Not Establishing Private Right of Action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No alien unprivileged enemy belligerent subject to trial by military commission under this chapter may invoke the Geneva Conventions as a basis for a private right of action.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2575</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(c)(3)(E)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 958</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 948c.</num>
<heading> Persons subject to military commissions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any alien unprivileged enemy belligerent is subject to trial by military commission as set forth in this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2576</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 948d.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction of military commissions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A military commission under this chapter shall have jurisdiction to try persons subject to this chapter for any offense made punishable by this chapter, sections 904 and 906 of this title (articles 104 and 106 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice), or the law of war, whether such offense was committed before, on, or after <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, and may, under such limitations as the President may prescribe, adjudge any punishment not forbidden by this chapter, including the penalty of death when specifically authorized under this chapter. A military commission is a competent tribunal to make a finding sufficient for jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2576</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COMPOSITION OF MILITARY COMMISSIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 948h.</num>
<heading> Who may convene military commissions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Military commissions under this chapter may be convened by the Secretary of Defense or by any officer or official of the United States designated by the Secretary for that purpose.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2576</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 948i.</num>
<heading> Who may serve on military commissions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any commissioned officer of the armed forces on active duty is eligible to serve on a military commission under this chapter, including commissioned officers of the reserve components of the armed forces on active duty, commissioned officers of the National Guard on active duty in Federal service, or retired commissioned officers recalled to active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detail of Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When convening a military commission under this chapter, the convening authority shall detail as members thereof such members of the armed forces eligible under subsection (a) who, in the opinion of the convening authority, are best qualified for the duty by reason of age, education, training, experience, length of service, and judicial temperament. No member of an armed force is eligible to serve as a member of a military commission when such member is the accuser or a witness for the prosecution or has acted as an investigator or counsel in the same case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Excuse of Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before a military commission under this chapter is assembled for the trial of a case, the convening authority may excuse a member from participating in the case.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2576</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 948j.</num>
<heading> Military judge of a military commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detail of Military Judge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A military judge shall be detailed to each military commission under this chapter. The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations providing for the manner in which military judges are so detailed to military commissions. The military judge shall preside over each military commission to which such military judge has been detailed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A military judge shall be a commissioned officer of the armed forces who is a member of the bar of a Federal court, or a member of the bar of the highest court of a State, and who is certified to be qualified for duty under <ref>section 826 of this title</ref> (article 26 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice) as a military judge of general courts-martial by the Judge Advocate General of the armed force of which such military judge is a member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ineligibility of Certain Individuals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person is eligible to act as military judge in a case of a military commission under this chapter if such person is the accuser or a witness or has acted as investigator or a counsel in the same case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation With Members; Ineligibility to Vote</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A military judge detailed to a military commission under this chapter may not consult with the members except in the presence of the accused (except as otherwise provided in <ref>section 949d of this title</ref>), trial counsel, and defense counsel, nor may such military judge vote with the members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A commissioned officer who is certified to be qualified for duty as a military judge of a military commission under this chapter may perform such other duties as are assigned to such officer by or with the approval of the Judge Advocate General of the armed force of which such officer is a member or the designee of such Judge Advocate General.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Evaluation of Fitness by Convening Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The convening authority of a military commission under this chapter may not prepare or review any report concerning the effectiveness, fitness, or efficiency of a military judge detailed to the military commission which relates to such judge’s performance of duty as a military judge on the military commission.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2577</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 948k.</num>
<heading> Detail of trial counsel and defense counsel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detail of Counsel Generally</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Trial counsel and military defense counsel shall be detailed for each military commission under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Assistant trial counsel and assistant and associate defense counsel may be detailed for a military commission under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Military defense counsel for a military commission under this chapter shall be detailed as soon as practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations providing for the manner in which trial counsel and military defense counsel are detailed for military commissions under this chapter and for the persons who are authorized to detail such counsel for such military commissions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Trial Counsel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (e), a trial counsel detailed for a military commission under this chapter shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a judge advocate (as that term is defined in <ref>section 801 of this title</ref> (article 1 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice)) who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a graduate of an accredited law school or a member of the bar of a Federal court or of the highest court of a State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> certified as competent to perform duties as trial counsel before general courts-martial by the Judge Advocate General of the armed force of which such judge advocate is a member; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a civilian who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a member of the bar of a Federal court or of the highest court of a State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> otherwise qualified to practice before the military commission pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense Counsel</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to subsection (e), a military defense counsel detailed for a military commission under this chapter shall be a judge advocate (as so defined) who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a graduate of an accredited law school or a member of the bar of a Federal court or of the highest court of a State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> certified as competent to perform duties as defense counsel before general courts-martial by the Judge Advocate General of the armed force of which such judge advocate is a member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the appointment and performance of defense counsel in capital cases under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chief Prosecutor; Chief Defense Counsel</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chief Prosecutor in a military commission under this chapter shall meet the requirements set forth in subsection (b)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chief Defense Counsel in a military commission under this chapter shall meet the requirements set forth in subsection (c)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ineligibility of Certain Individuals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person who has acted as an investigator, military judge, or member of a military commission under this chapter in any case may act later as trial counsel or military defense counsel in the same case. No person who has acted for the prosecution before a military commission under this chapter may act later in the same case for the defense, nor may any person who has acted for the defense before a military commission under this chapter act later in the same case for the prosecution.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2577</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 948l.</num>
<heading> Detail or employment of reporters and interpreters</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Court Reporters</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, the convening authority of a military commission under this chapter shall detail to or employ for the military commission qualified court reporters, who shall prepare a verbatim record of the proceedings of and testimony taken before the military commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interpreters</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, the convening authority of a military commission under this chapter may detail to or employ for the military commission interpreters who shall interpret for the military commission, and, as necessary, for trial counsel and defense counsel for the military commission, and for the accused.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transcript; Record</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The transcript of a military commission under this chapter shall be under the control of the convening authority of the military commission, who shall also be responsible for preparing the record of the proceedings of the military commission.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2578</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 948m.</num>
<heading> Number of members; excuse of members; absent and additional members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), a military commission under this chapter shall have at least five primary members and as many alternate members as the convening authority shall detail. Alternate members shall be designated in the order in which they will replace an excused primary member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In a case in which the accused before a military commission under this chapter may be sentenced to a penalty of death, the military commission shall have the number of primary members prescribed by <ref>section 949m(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Primary Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Primary members of a military commission under this chapter are voting members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternate Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A military commission may include alternate members to replace primary members who are excused from service on the commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Whenever a primary member is excused from service on the commission, an alternate member, if available, shall replace the excused primary member and the trial may proceed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Excuse of Members</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No primary or alternate member of a military commission under this chapter may be absent or excused after the military commission has been assembled for the trial of a case unless excused—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as a result of challenge;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by the military judge for physical disability or other good cause;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by order of the convening authority for good cause; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in the case of an alternate member, in order to reduce the number of alternate members required for service on the commission, as determined by the convening authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Absent and Additional Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the number of primary members of a military commission under this chapter is reduced below the number of primary members required by subsection (a) and there are no remaining alternate members to replace the excused primary members, the trial may not proceed unless the convening authority details new members sufficient to provide not less than such number. The trial may proceed with the new members present after the recorded evidence previously introduced before the members has been read to the military commission in the presence of the military judge, the accused (except as provided in <ref>section 949d of this title</ref>), and counsel for both sides. An alternate member who was present for the introduction of all evidence shall not be considered to be a new or additional member.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2579</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 849</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PRE-TRIAL PROCEDURE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 948q.</num>
<heading> Charges and specifications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Charges and Specifications</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Charges and specifications against an accused in a military commission under this chapter shall be signed by a person subject to chapter 47 of this title under oath before a commissioned officer of the armed forces authorized to administer oaths and shall state—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the signer has personal knowledge of, or reason to believe, the matters set forth therein; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that such matters are true in fact to the best of the signer’s knowledge and belief.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to Accused</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon the swearing of the charges and specifications in accordance with subsection (a), the accused shall be informed of the charges and specifications against the accused as soon as practicable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2579</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 948r.</num>
<heading> Exclusion of statements obtained by torture or cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment; prohibition of self-incrimination; admission of other statements of the accused</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of Statements Obtain by Torture or Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No statement obtained by the use of torture or by cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment (as defined by section 1003 of the Detainee Treatment Act of 2005 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000dd</ref>)), whether or not under color of law, shall be admissible in a military commission under this chapter, except against a person accused of torture or such treatment as evidence that the statement was made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Self-incrimination Prohibited</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person shall be required to testify against himself or herself at a proceeding of a military commission under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Statements of the Accused</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A statement of the accused may be admitted in evidence in a military commission under this chapter only if the military judge finds—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the totality of the circumstances renders the statement reliable and possessing sufficient probative value; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the statement was made incident to lawful conduct during military operations at the point of capture or during closely related active combat engagement, and the interests of justice would best be served by admission of the statement into evidence; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the statement was voluntarily given.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of Voluntariness</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In determining for purposes of subsection (c)(2)(B) whether a statement was voluntarily given, the military judge shall consider the totality of the circumstances, including, as appropriate, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The details of the taking of the statement, accounting for the circumstances of the conduct of military and intelligence operations during hostilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The characteristics of the accused, such as military training, age, and education level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The lapse of time, change of place, or change in identity of the questioners between the statement sought to be admitted and any prior questioning of the accused.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added by <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2580</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 948s.</num>
<heading> Service of charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The trial counsel assigned to a case before a military commission under this chapter shall cause to be served upon the accused and military defense counsel a copy of the charges upon which trial is to be had in English and, if appropriate, in another language that the accused understands, sufficiently in advance of trial to prepare a defense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2580</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>TRIAL PROCEDURE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 949a.</num>
<heading> Rules</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures and Rules of Evidence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Pretrial, trial, and post-trial procedures, including elements and modes of proof, for cases triable by military commission under this chapter may be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. Such procedures may not be contrary to or inconsistent with this chapter. Except as otherwise provided in this chapter or chapter 47 of this title, the procedures and rules of evidence applicable in trials by general courts-martial of the United States shall apply in trials by military commission under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In trials by military commission under this chapter, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Attorney General, may make such exceptions in the applicability of the procedures and rules of evidence otherwise applicable in general courts-martial as may be required by the unique circumstances of the conduct of military and intelligence operations during hostilities or by other practical need consistent with this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any exceptions authorized by paragraph (1), the procedures and rules of evidence in trials by military commission under this chapter shall include, at a minimum, the following rights of the accused:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To present evidence in the accused’s defense, to cross-examine the witnesses who testify against the accused, and to examine and respond to all evidence admitted against the accused on the issue of guilt or innocence and for sentencing, as provided for by this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To be present at all sessions of the military commission (other than those for deliberations or voting), except when excluded under <ref>section 949d of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> When none of the charges sworn against the accused are capital, to be represented before a military commission by civilian counsel if provided at no expense to the Government, and by either the defense counsel detailed or the military counsel of the accused’s own selection, if reasonably available.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> When any of the charges sworn against the accused are capital, to be represented before a military commission in accordance with clause (i) and, to the greatest extent practicable, by at least one additional counsel who is learned in applicable law relating to capital cases and who, if necessary, may be a civilian and compensated in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> To self-representation, if the accused knowingly and competently waives the assistance of counsel, subject to the provisions of paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> To the suppression of evidence that is not reliable or probative.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> To the suppression of evidence the probative value of which is substantially outweighed by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the danger of unfair prejudice, confusion of the issues, or misleading the members; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> considerations of undue delay, waste of time, or needless presentation of cumulative evidence.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In making exceptions in the applicability in trials by military commission under this chapter from the procedures and rules otherwise applicable in general courts-martial, the Secretary of Defense may provide the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Evidence seized outside the United States shall not be excluded from trial by military commission on the grounds that the evidence was not seized pursuant to a search warrant or authorization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A statement of the accused that is otherwise admissible shall not be excluded from trial by military commission on grounds of alleged coercion or compulsory self-incrimination so long as the evidence complies with the provisions of <ref>section 948r of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Evidence shall be admitted as authentic so long as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the military judge of the military commission determines that there is sufficient evidence that the evidence is what it is claimed to be; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the military judge instructs the members that they may consider any issue as to authentication or identification of evidence in determining the weight, if any, to be given to the evidence.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Hearsay evidence not otherwise admissible under the rules of evidence applicable in trial by general courts-martial may be admitted in a trial by military commission only if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the proponent of the evidence makes known to the adverse party, sufficiently in advance to provide the adverse party with a fair opportunity to meet the evidence, the proponent’s intention to offer the evidence, and the particulars of the evidence (including information on the circumstances under which the evidence was obtained); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the military judge, after taking into account all of the circumstances surrounding the taking of the statement, including the degree to which the statement is corroborated, the indicia of reliability within the statement itself, and whether the will of the declarant was overborne, determines that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the statement is offered as evidence of a material fact;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the statement is probative on the point for which it is offered;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> direct testimony from the witness is not available as a practical matter, taking into consideration the physical location of the witness, the unique circumstances of military and intelligence operations during hostilities, and the adverse impacts on military or intelligence operations that would likely result from the production of the witness; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the general purposes of the rules of evidence and the interests of justice will best be served by admission of the statement into evidence.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The accused in a military commission under this chapter who exercises the right to self-representation under paragraph (2)(D) shall conform the accused’s deportment and the conduct of the defense to the rules of evidence, procedure, and decorum applicable to trials by military commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Failure of the accused to conform to the rules described in subparagraph (A) may result in a partial or total revocation by the military judge of the right of self-representation under paragraph (2)(D). In such case, the military counsel of the accused or an appropriately authorized civilian counsel shall perform the functions necessary for the defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation of Authority To Prescribe Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may delegate the authority of the Secretary to prescribe regulations under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to Congress of Modification of Rules</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 60 days before the date on which any proposed modification of the rules in effect for military commissions under this chapter goes into effect, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report describing the proposed modification.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2581</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1034(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1572</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949b.</num>
<heading> Unlawfully influencing action of military commission and United States Court of Military Commission Review</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Military Commissions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No authority convening a military commission under this chapter may censure, reprimand, or admonish the military commission, or any member, military judge, or counsel thereof, with respect to the findings or sentence adjudged by the military commission, or with respect to any other exercises of its or their functions in the conduct of the proceedings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> No person may attempt to coerce or, by any unauthorized means, influence—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the action of a military commission under this chapter, or any member thereof, in reaching the findings or sentence in any case;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the action of any convening, approving, or reviewing authority with respect to their judicial acts; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the exercise of professional judgment by trial counsel or defense counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of this subsection shall not apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> general instructional or informational courses in military justice if such courses are designed solely for the purpose of instructing members of a command in the substantive and procedural aspects of military commissions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> statements and instructions given in open proceedings by a military judge or counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United States Court of Military Commission Review</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> No person may attempt to coerce or, by any unauthorized means, influence—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the action of a judge on the United States Court of Military Commissions Review in reaching a decision on the findings or sentence on appeal in any case; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the exercise of professional judgment by trial counsel or defense counsel appearing before the United States Court of Military Commission Review.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No person may censure, reprimand, or admonish a judge on the United States Court of Military Commission Review, or counsel thereof, with respect to any exercise of their functions in the conduct of proceedings under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of this subsection shall not apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> general instructional or informational courses in military justice if such courses are designed solely for the purpose of instructing members of a command in the substantive and procedural aspects of military commissions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> statements and instructions given in open proceedings by a judge on the United States Court of Military Commission Review, or counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> No appellate military judge on the United States Court of Military Commission Review may be reassigned to other duties, except under circumstances as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The appellate military judge voluntarily requests to be reassigned to other duties and the Secretary of Defense, or the designee of the Secretary, in consultation with the Judge Advocate General of the armed force of which the appellate military judge is a member, approves such reassignment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The appellate military judge retires or otherwise separates from the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The appellate military judge is reassigned to other duties by the Secretary of Defense, or the designee of the Secretary, in consultation with the Judge Advocate General of the armed force of which the appellate military judge is a member, based on military necessity and such reassignment is consistent with service rotation regulations (to the extent such regulations are applicable).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The appellate military judge is withdrawn by the Secretary of Defense, or the designee of the Secretary, in consultation with the Judge Advocate General of the armed force of which the appellate military judge is a member, for good cause consistent with applicable procedures under chapter 47 of this title (the Uniform Code of Military Justice).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Consideration of Actions on Commission in Evaluation of Fitness</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the preparation of an effectiveness, fitness, or efficiency report or any other report or document used in whole or in part for the purpose of determining whether a commissioned officer of the armed forces is qualified to be advanced in grade, or in determining the assignment or transfer of any such officer or whether any such officer should be retained on active duty, no person may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consider or evaluate the performance of duty of any member of a military commission under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> give a less favorable rating or evaluation to any commissioned officer because of the zeal with which such officer, in acting as counsel, represented any accused before a military commission under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2583</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1034(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1573</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949c.</num>
<heading> Duties of trial counsel and defense counsel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Trial Counsel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The trial counsel of a military commission under this chapter shall prosecute in the name of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense Counsel</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The accused shall be represented in the accused’s defense before a military commission under this chapter as provided in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The accused may be represented by military counsel detailed under <ref>section 948k of this title</ref> or by military counsel of the accused’s own selection, if reasonably available.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The accused may be represented by civilian counsel if retained by the accused, provided that such civilian counsel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a United States citizen;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is admitted to the practice of law in a State, district, or possession of the United States, or before a Federal court;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has not been the subject of any sanction of disciplinary action by any court, bar, or other competent governmental authority for relevant misconduct;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> has been determined to be eligible for access to information classified at the level Secret or higher; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> has signed a written agreement to comply with all applicable regulations or instructions for counsel, including any rules of court for conduct during the proceedings.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If the accused is represented by civilian counsel, military counsel shall act as associate counsel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The accused is not entitled to be represented by more than one military counsel. However, the person authorized under regulations prescribed under <ref>section 948k of this title</ref> to detail counsel, in such person’s sole discretion, may detail additional military counsel to represent the accused.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Defense counsel may cross-examine each witness for the prosecution who testifies before a military commission under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Civilian defense counsel shall protect any classified information received during the course of representation of the accused in accordance with all applicable law governing the protection of classified information, and may not divulge such information to any person not authorized to receive it.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2585</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949d.</num>
<heading> Sessions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sessions Without Presence of Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> At any time after the service of charges which have been referred for trial by military commission under this chapter, the military judge may call the military commission into session without the presence of the members for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> hearing and determining motions raising defenses or objections which are capable of determination without trial of the issues raised by a plea of not guilty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> hearing and ruling upon any matter which may be ruled upon by the military judge under this chapter, whether or not the matter is appropriate for later consideration or decision by the members;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if permitted by regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, receiving the pleas of the accused; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> performing any other procedural function which may be performed by the military judge under this chapter or under rules prescribed pursuant to <ref>section 949a of this title</ref> and which does not require the presence of the members.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsections (b), (c), and (d), any proceedings under paragraph (1) shall be conducted in the presence of the accused, defense counsel, and trial counsel, and shall be made part of the record.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deliberation or Vote of Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the members of a military commission under this chapter deliberate or vote, only the members may be present.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Closure of Proceedings</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The military judge may close to the public all or part of the proceedings of a military commission under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The military judge may close to the public all or a portion of the proceedings under paragraph (1) only upon making a specific finding that such closure is necessary to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> protect information the disclosure of which could reasonably be expected to cause damage to the national security, including intelligence or law enforcement sources, methods, or activities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure the physical safety of individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A finding under paragraph (2) may be based upon a presentation, including a presentation ex parte or in camera, by either trial counsel or defense counsel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of Accused From Certain Proceedings</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The military judge may exclude the accused from any portion of a proceeding upon a determination that, after being warned by the military judge, the accused persists in conduct that justifies exclusion from the courtroom—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to ensure the physical safety of individuals; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to prevent disruption of the proceedings by the accused.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2585</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949e.</num>
<heading> Continuances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The military judge in a military commission under this chapter may, for reasonable cause, grant a continuance to any party for such time, and as often, as may appear to be just.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2586</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949f.</num>
<heading> Challenges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Challenges Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The military judge and primary or alternate members of a military commission under this chapter may be challenged by the accused or trial counsel for cause stated to the military commission. The military judge shall determine the relevance and validity of challenges for cause, and may not receive a challenge to more than one person at a time. Challenges by trial counsel shall ordinarily be presented and decided before those by the accused are offered.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Peremptory Challenges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The accused and trial counsel are each entitled to one peremptory challenge, but the military judge may not be challenged except for cause. Nothing in this section prohibits the military judge from awarding to each party such additional peremptory challenges as may be required in the interests of justice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Challenges Against Additional Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever additional members are detailed to a military commission under this chapter, and after any challenges for cause against such additional members are presented and decided, the accused and trial counsel are each entitled to one peremptory challenge against members not previously subject to peremptory challenge.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2586</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1031(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 850</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949g.</num>
<heading> Oaths</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Before performing their respective duties in a military commission under this chapter, military judges, members, trial counsel, defense counsel, reporters, and interpreters shall take an oath to perform their duties faithfully.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The form of the oath required by paragraph (1), the time and place of the taking thereof, the manner of recording thereof, and whether the oath shall be taken for all cases in which duties are to be performed or for a particular case, shall be as provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. The regulations may provide that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an oath to perform faithfully duties as a military judge, trial counsel, or defense counsel may be taken at any time by any judge advocate or other person certified to be qualified or competent for the duty; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if such an oath is taken, such oath need not again be taken at the time the judge advocate or other person is detailed to that duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Witnesses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each witness before a military commission under this chapter shall be examined on oath.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Oath Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “oath” includes an affirmation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2587</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949h.</num>
<heading> Former jeopardy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person may, without the person’s consent, be tried by a military commission under this chapter a second time for the same offense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of Trial</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No proceeding in which the accused has been found guilty by military commission under this chapter upon any charge or specification is a trial in the sense of this section until the finding of guilty has become final after review of the case has been fully completed.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2587</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949i.</num>
<heading> Pleas of the accused</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Plea of Not Guilty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an accused in a military commission under this chapter after a plea of guilty sets up matter inconsistent with the plea, or if it appears that the accused has entered the plea of guilty through lack of understanding of its meaning and effect, or if the accused fails or refuses to plead, a plea of not guilty shall be entered in the record, and the military commission shall proceed as though the accused had pleaded not guilty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Finding of Guilt After Guilty Plea</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to any charge or specification to which a plea of guilty has been made by the accused in a military commission under this chapter and accepted by the military judge, including a charge or specification that has been referred capital, a finding of guilty of the charge or specification may be entered by the military judge immediately without a vote by the members. The finding shall constitute the finding of the military commission unless the plea of guilty is withdrawn prior to announcement of the sentence, in which event the proceedings shall continue as though the accused had pleaded not guilty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pre-Trial Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A plea of guilty made by the accused that is accepted by a military judge under subsection (b) and not withdrawn prior to announcement of the sentence may form the basis for an agreement reducing the maximum sentence approved by the convening authority, including the reduction of a sentence of death to a lesser punishment, or that the case will be referred to a military commission under this chapter without seeking the penalty of death. Such an agreement may provide for terms and conditions in addition to a guilty plea by the accused in order to be effective.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A plea agreement under this subsection may not provide for a sentence of death imposed by a military judge alone. A sentence of death may only be imposed by the unanimous vote of all members of a military commission concurring in the sentence of death as provided in <ref>section 949m(b)(2)(D) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2587</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1030(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(f)(9)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3510</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949j.</num>
<heading> Opportunity to obtain witnesses and other evidence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Defense counsel in a military commission under this chapter shall have a reasonable opportunity to obtain witnesses and other evidence as provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. The opportunity to obtain witnesses and evidence shall be comparable to the opportunity available to a criminal defendant in a court of the United States under article III of the Constitution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Process issued in military commissions under this chapter to compel witnesses to appear and testify and to compel the production of other evidence—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be similar to that which courts of the United States having criminal jurisdiction may lawfully issue; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall run to any place where the United States shall have jurisdiction thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure of Exculpatory Evidence</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> As soon as practicable, trial counsel in a military commission under this chapter shall disclose to the defense the existence of any evidence that reasonably tends to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> negate the guilt of the accused of an offense charged; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reduce the degree of guilt of the accused with respect to an offense charged.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The trial counsel shall, as soon as practicable, disclose to the defense the existence of evidence that reasonably tends to impeach the credibility of a witness whom the government intends to call at trial.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The trial counsel shall, as soon as practicable upon a finding of guilt, disclose to the defense the existence of evidence that is not subject to paragraph (1) or paragraph (2) but that reasonably may be viewed as mitigation evidence at sentencing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The disclosure obligations under this subsection encompass evidence that is known or reasonably should be known to any government officials who participated in the investigation and prosecution of the case against the defendant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2587</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949k.</num>
<heading> Defense of lack of mental responsibility</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Affirmative Defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It is an affirmative defense in a trial by military commission under this chapter that, at the time of the commission of the acts constituting the offense, the accused, as a result of a severe mental disease or defect, was unable to appreciate the nature and quality or the wrongfulness of the acts. Mental disease or defect does not otherwise constitute a defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Burden of Proof</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The accused in a military commission under this chapter has the burden of proving the defense of lack of mental responsibility by clear and convincing evidence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Findings Following Assertion of Defense</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whenever lack of mental responsibility of the accused with respect to an offense is properly at issue in a military commission under this chapter, the military judge shall instruct the members as to the defense of lack of mental responsibility under this section and shall charge the members to find the accused—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> guilty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not guilty; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> subject to subsection (d), not guilty by reason of lack of mental responsibility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Majority Vote Required for Finding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The accused shall be found not guilty by reason of lack of mental responsibility under subsection (c)(3) only if a majority of the members present at the time the vote is taken determines that the defense of lack of mental responsibility has been established.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2588</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949l.</num>
<heading> Voting and rulings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Vote by Secret Written Ballot</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Voting by members of a military commission under this chapter on the findings and on the sentence shall be by secret written ballot.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rulings</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The military judge in a military commission under this chapter shall rule upon all questions of law, including the admissibility of evidence and all interlocutory questions arising during the proceedings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any ruling made by the military judge upon a question of law or an interlocutory question (other than the factual issue of mental responsibility of the accused) is conclusive and constitutes the ruling of the military commission. However, a military judge may change such a ruling at any time during the trial.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Instructions Prior to Vote</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before a vote is taken of the findings of a military commission under this chapter, the military judge shall, in the presence of the accused and counsel, instruct the members as to the elements of the offense and charge the members—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the accused must be presumed to be innocent until the accused’s guilt is established by legal and competent evidence beyond a reasonable doubt;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that in the case being considered, if there is a reasonable doubt as to the guilt of the accused, the doubt must be resolved in favor of the accused and the accused must be acquitted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that, if there is reasonable doubt as to the degree of guilt, the finding must be in a lower degree as to which there is no reasonable doubt; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> that the burden of proof to establish the guilt of the accused beyond a reasonable doubt is upon the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2589</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949m.</num>
<heading> Number of votes required</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conviction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person may be convicted by a military commission under this chapter of any offense, except as provided in <ref>section 949i(b) of this title</ref> or by concurrence of two-thirds of the primary members present at the time the vote is taken.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sentences</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), sentences shall be determined by a military commission by the concurrence of two-thirds of the primary members present at the time the vote is taken.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> No person may be sentenced to death by a military commission, except insofar as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the penalty of death has been expressly authorized under this chapter, chapter 47 of this title, or the law of war for an offense of which the accused has been found guilty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> trial counsel expressly sought the penalty of death by filing an appropriate notice in advance of trial;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the accused was convicted of the offense by the concurrence of all the primary members present at the time the vote is taken, or a guilty plea was accepted and not withdrawn prior to announcement of the sentence in accordance with <ref>section 949i(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> all primary members present at the time the vote was taken on the sentence concurred in the sentence of death.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No person may be sentenced to life imprisonment, or to confinement for more than 10 years, by a military commission under this chapter except by the concurrence of three-fourths of the primary members present at the time the vote is taken.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The primary members present for a vote on a sentence need not be the same primary members who voted on the conviction if the requirements of <ref>section 948m(d) of this title</ref> are met.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of Members Required for Penalty of Death</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), in a case in which the penalty of death is sought, the number of primary members of the military commission under this chapter shall be not less than 12 primary members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In any case described in paragraph (1) in which 12 primary members are not reasonably available for a military commission because of physical conditions or military exigencies, the convening authority shall specify a lesser number of primary members for the military commission (but not fewer than 9 primary members), and the military commission may be assembled, and the trial held, with not less than the number of primary members so specified. In any such case, the convening authority shall make a detailed written statement, to be appended to the record, stating why a greater number of primary members were not reasonably available.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2589</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1030(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1031(c)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 850</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949n.</num>
<heading> Military commission to announce action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A military commission under this chapter shall announce its findings and sentence to the parties as soon as determined.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2590</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949o.</num>
<heading> Record of trial</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Record; Authentication</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each military commission under this chapter shall keep a separate, verbatim, record of the proceedings in each case brought before it, and the record shall be authenticated by the signature of the military judge. If the record cannot be authenticated by the military judge by reason of death, disability, or absence, it shall be authenticated by the signature of the trial counsel or by a member of the commission if the trial counsel is unable to authenticate it by reason of death, disability, or absence. Where appropriate, and as provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the record of a military commission under this chapter may contain a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Complete Record Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A complete record of the proceedings and testimony shall be prepared in every military commission under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provision of Copy to Accused</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A copy of the record of the proceedings of the military commission under this chapter shall be given the accused as soon as it is authenticated. If the record contains classified information, or a classified annex, the accused shall receive a redacted version of the record consistent with the requirements of subchapter V of this chapter. Defense counsel shall have access to the unredacted record, as provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2590</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>CLASSIFIED INFORMATION PROCEDURES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 949p–1.</num>
<heading> Protection of classified information: applicability of subchapter</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection of Classified Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Classified information shall be protected and is privileged from disclosure if disclosure would be detrimental to the national security. Under no circumstances may a military judge order the release of classified information to any person not authorized to receive such information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access to Evidence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any information admitted into evidence pursuant to any rule, procedure, or order by the military judge shall be provided to the accused.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Declassification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Trial counsel shall work with the original classification authorities for evidence that may be used at trial to ensure that such evidence is declassified to the maximum extent possible, consistent with the requirements of national security. A decision not to declassify evidence under this section shall not be subject to review by a military commission or upon appeal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction of Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The judicial construction of the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.) shall be authoritative in the interpretation of this subchapter, except to the extent that such construction is inconsistent with the specific requirements of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2590</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949p–2.</num>
<heading> Pretrial conference</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Motion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At any time after service of charges, any party may move for a pretrial conference to consider matters relating to classified information that may arise in connection with the prosecution.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conference</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Following a motion under subsection (a), or sua sponte, the military judge shall promptly hold a pretrial conference. Upon request by either party, the court shall hold such conference ex parte to the extent necessary to protect classified information from disclosure, in accordance with the practice of the Federal courts under the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Matters To Be Established at Pretrial Conference.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timing of subsequent actions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At the pretrial conference, the military judge shall establish the timing of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> requests for discovery;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the provision of notice required by <ref>section 949p–5 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the initiation of the procedure established by <ref>section 949p–6 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other matters</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At the pretrial conference, the military judge may also consider any matter—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which relates to classified information; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which may promote a fair and expeditious trial.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Admissions by Accused at Pretrial Conference</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No admission made by the accused or by any counsel for the accused at a pretrial conference under this section may be used against the accused unless the admission is in writing and is signed by the accused and by the counsel for the accused.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2591</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949p–3.</num>
<heading> Protective orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon motion of the trial counsel, the military judge shall issue an order to protect against the disclosure of any classified information that has been disclosed by the United States to any accused in any military commission under this chapter or that has otherwise been provided to, or obtained by, any such accused in any such military commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2591</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949p–4.</num>
<heading> Discovery of, and access to, classified information by the accused</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Discovery or Access by the Accused.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Declarations by the united states of damage to national security</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any case before a military commission in which the United States seeks to delete, withhold, or otherwise obtain other relief with respect to the discovery of or access to any classified information, the trial counsel shall submit a declaration invoking the United States’ classified information privilege and setting forth the damage to the national security that the discovery of or access to such information reasonably could be expected to cause. The declaration shall be signed by a knowledgeable United States official possessing authority to classify information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standard for authorization of discovery or access</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon the submission of a declaration under paragraph (1), the military judge may not authorize the discovery of or access to such classified information unless the military judge determines that such classified information would be noncumulative, relevant, and helpful to a legally cognizable defense, rebuttal of the prosecution’s case, or to sentencing, in accordance with standards generally applicable to discovery of or access to classified information in Federal criminal cases. If the discovery of or access to such classified information is authorized, it shall be addressed in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Discovery of Classified Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Substitutions and other relief</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The military judge, in assessing the accused’s discovery of or access to classified information under this section, may authorize the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to delete or withhold specified items of classified information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to substitute a summary for classified information; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to substitute a statement admitting relevant facts that the classified information or material would tend to prove.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ex parte presentations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The military judge shall permit the trial counsel to make a request for an authorization under paragraph (1) in the form of an ex parte presentation to the extent necessary to protect classified information, in accordance with the practice of the Federal courts under the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.). If the military judge enters an order granting relief following such an ex parte showing, the entire presentation (including the text of any written submission, verbatim transcript of the ex parte oral conference or hearing, and any exhibits received by the court as part of the ex parte presentation) shall be sealed and preserved in the records of the military commission to be made available to the appellate court in the event of an appeal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action by military judge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The military judge shall grant the request of the trial counsel to substitute a summary or to substitute a statement admitting relevant facts, or to provide other relief in accordance with paragraph (1), if the military judge finds that the summary, statement, or other relief would provide the accused with substantially the same ability to make a defense as would discovery of or access to the specific classified information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reconsideration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An order of a military judge authorizing a request of the trial counsel to substitute, summarize, withhold, or prevent access to classified information under this section is not subject to a motion for reconsideration by the accused, if such order was entered pursuant to an ex parte showing under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949p–5.</num>
<heading> Notice by accused of intention to disclose classified information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notice by Accused.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of trial counsel and military judge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an accused reasonably expects to disclose, or to cause the disclosure of, classified information in any manner in connection with any trial or pretrial proceeding involving the prosecution of such accused, the accused shall, within the time specified by the military judge or, where no time is specified, within 30 days before trial, notify the trial counsel and the military judge in writing. Such notice shall include a brief description of the classified information. Whenever the accused learns of additional classified information the accused reasonably expects to disclose, or to cause the disclosure of, at any such proceeding, the accused shall notify trial counsel and the military judge in writing as soon as possible thereafter and shall include a brief description of the classified information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on disclosure by accused</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No accused shall disclose, or cause the disclosure of, any information known or believed to be classified in connection with a trial or pretrial proceeding until—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> notice has been given under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the United States has been afforded a reasonable opportunity to seek a determination pursuant to the procedure set forth in <ref>section 949p–6 of this title</ref> and the time for the United States to appeal such determination under <ref>section 950d of this title</ref> has expired or any appeal under that section by the United States is decided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure To Comply</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the accused fails to comply with the requirements of subsection (a), the military judge—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may preclude disclosure of any classified information not made the subject of notification; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may prohibit the examination by the accused of any witness with respect to any such information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949p–6.</num>
<heading> Procedure for cases involving classified information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Motion for Hearing.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Request for hearing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Within the time specified by the military judge for the filing of a motion under this section, either party may request the military judge to conduct a hearing to make all determinations concerning the use, relevance, or admissibility of classified information that would otherwise be made during the trial or pretrial proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conduct of hearing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon a request by either party under paragraph (1), the military judge shall conduct such a hearing and shall rule prior to conducting any further proceedings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In camera hearing upon declaration to court by appropriate official of risk of disclosure of classified information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any hearing held pursuant to this subsection (or any portion of such hearing specified in the request of a knowledgeable United States official) shall be held in camera if a knowledgeable United States official possessing authority to classify information submits to the military judge a declaration that a public proceeding may result in the disclosure of classified information. Classified information is not subject to disclosure under this section unless the information is relevant and necessary to an element of the offense or a legally cognizable defense and is otherwise admissible in evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Military judge to make determinations in writing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As to each item of classified information, the military judge shall set forth in writing the basis for the determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Notice and Use of Classified Information by the Government.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to accused</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before any hearing is conducted pursuant to a request by the trial counsel under subsection (a), trial counsel shall provide the accused with notice of the classified information that is at issue. Such notice shall identify the specific classified information at issue whenever that information previously has been made available to the accused by the United States. When the United States has not previously made the information available to the accused in connection with the case the information may be described by generic category, in such forms as the military judge may approve, rather than by identification of the specific information of concern to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order by military judge upon request of accused</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the trial counsel requests a hearing under subsection (a), the military judge, upon request of the accused, may order the trial counsel to provide the accused, prior to trial, such details as to the portion of the charge or specification at issue in the hearing as are needed to give the accused fair notice to prepare for the hearing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Substitutions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In camera pretrial hearing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon request of the trial counsel pursuant to the Military Commission Rules of Evidence, and in accordance with the security procedures established by the military judge, the military judge shall conduct a classified in camera pretrial hearing concerning the admissibility of classified information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection of sources, methods, and activities by which evidence acquired</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When trial counsel seeks to introduce evidence before a military commission under this chapter and the Executive branch has classified the sources, methods, or activities by which the United States acquired the evidence, the military judge shall permit trial counsel to introduce the evidence, including a substituted evidentiary foundation pursuant to the procedures described in subsection (d), while protecting from disclosure information identifying those sources, methods, or activities, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the evidence is otherwise admissible; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the military judge finds that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the evidence is reliable; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the redaction is consistent with affording the accused a fair trial.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Alternative Procedure for Disclosure of Classified Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Motion by the united states</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Upon any determination by the military judge authorizing the disclosure of specific classified information under the procedures established by this section, the trial counsel may move that, in lieu of the disclosure of such specific classified information, the military judge order—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the substitution for such classified information of a statement admitting relevant facts that the specific classified information would tend to prove;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the substitution for such classified information of a summary of the specific classified information; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other procedure or redaction limiting the disclosure of specific classified information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action on motion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The military judge shall grant such a motion of the trial counsel if the military judge finds that the statement, summary, or other procedure or redaction will provide the defendant with substantially the same ability to make his defense as would disclosure of the specific classified information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hearing on motion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The military judge shall hold a hearing on any motion under this subsection. Any such hearing shall be held in camera at the request of a knowledgeable United States official possessing authority to classify information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of statement of damage to national security if disclosure ordered</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The trial counsel may, in connection with a motion under paragraph (1), submit to the military judge a declaration signed by a knowledgeable United States official possessing authority to classify information certifying that disclosure of classified information would cause identifiable damage to the national security of the United States and explaining the basis for the classification of such information. If so requested by the trial counsel, the military judge shall examine such declaration during an ex parte presentation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sealing of Records of in Camera Hearings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If at the close of an in camera hearing under this section (or any portion of a hearing under this section that is held in camera), the military judge determines that the classified information at issue may not be disclosed or elicited at the trial or pretrial proceeding, the record of such in camera hearing shall be sealed and preserved for use in the event of an appeal. The accused may seek reconsideration of the military judge’s determination prior to or during trial.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Disclosure of Classified Information by the Accused; Relief for Accused When the United States Opposes Disclosure.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order to prevent disclosure by accused</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the military judge denies a motion by the trial counsel that the judge issue an order under subsection (a), (c), or (d) and the trial counsel files with the military judge a declaration signed by a knowledgeable United States official possessing authority to classify information objecting to disclosure of the classified information at issue, the military judge shall order that the accused not disclose or cause the disclosure of such information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Result of order under paragraph (1)</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whenever an accused is prevented by an order under paragraph (1) from disclosing or causing the disclosure of classified information, the military judge shall dismiss the case, except that, when the military judge determines that the interests of justice would not be served by dismissal of the case, the military judge shall order such other action, in lieu of dismissing the charge or specification, as the military judge determines is appropriate. Such action may include, but need not be limited to, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Dismissing specified charges or specifications.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Finding against the United States on any issue as to which the excluded classified information relates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Striking or precluding all or part of the testimony of a witness.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time for the united states to seek interlocutory appeal</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An order under paragraph (2) shall not take effect until the military judge has afforded the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an opportunity to appeal such order under <ref>section 950d of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an opportunity thereafter to withdraw its objection to the disclosure of the classified information at issue.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reciprocity.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure of rebuttal information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the military judge determines that classified information may be disclosed in connection with a trial or pretrial proceeding, the military judge shall, unless the interests of fairness do not so require, order the United States to provide the accused with the information it expects to use to rebut the classified information. The military judge may place the United States under a continuing duty to disclose such rebuttal information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sanction for failure to comply</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the United States fails to comply with its obligation under this subsection, the military judge—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may exclude any evidence not made the subject of a required disclosure; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may prohibit the examination by the United States of any witness with respect to such information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949p–7.</num>
<heading> Introduction of classified information into evidence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preservation of Classification Status</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Writings, recordings, and photographs containing classified information may be admitted into evidence in proceedings of military commissions under this chapter without change in their classification status.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Precautions by Military Judges.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Precautions in admitting classified information into evidence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The military judge in a trial by military commission, in order to prevent unnecessary disclosure of classified information, may order admission into evidence of only part of a writing, recording, or photograph, or may order admission into evidence of the whole writing, recording, or photograph with excision of some or all of the classified information contained therein, unless the whole ought in fairness be considered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Classified information kept under seal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The military judge shall allow classified information offered or accepted into evidence to remain under seal during the trial, even if such evidence is disclosed in the military commission, and may, upon motion by the United States, seal exhibits containing classified information for any period after trial as necessary to prevent a disclosure of classified information when a knowledgeable United States official possessing authority to classify information submits to the military judge a declaration setting forth the damage to the national security that the disclosure of such information reasonably could be expected to cause.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Taking of Testimony.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objection by trial counsel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>During the examination of a witness, trial counsel may object to any question or line of inquiry that may require the witness to disclose classified information not previously found to be admissible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action by military judge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Following an objection under paragraph (1), the military judge shall take such suitable action to determine whether the response is admissible as will safeguard against the compromise of any classified information. Such action may include requiring trial counsel to provide the military judge with a proffer of the witness’ response to the question or line of inquiry and requiring the accused to provide the military judge with a proffer of the nature of the information sought to be elicited by the accused. Upon request, the military judge may accept an ex parte proffer by trial counsel to the extent necessary to protect classified information from disclosure, in accordance with the practice of the Federal courts under the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Disclosure at Trial of Certain Statements Previously Made by a Witness.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Motion for production of statements in possession of the united states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After a witness called by the trial counsel has testified on direct examination, the military judge, on motion of the accused, may order production of statements of the witness in the possession of the United States which relate to the subject matter as to which the witness has testified. This paragraph does not preclude discovery or assertion of a privilege otherwise authorized.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Invocation of privilege by the united states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the United States invokes a privilege, the trial counsel may provide the prior statements of the witness to the military judge during an ex parte presentation to the extent necessary to protect classified information from disclosure, in accordance with the practice of the Federal courts under the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action by military judge on motion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the military judge finds that disclosure of any portion of the statement identified by the United States as classified would be detrimental to the national security in the degree to warrant classification under the applicable Executive Order, statute, or regulation, that such portion of the statement is consistent with the testimony of the witness, and that the disclosure of such portion is not necessary to afford the accused a fair trial, the military judge shall excise that portion from the statement. If the military judge finds that such portion of the statement is inconsistent with the testimony of the witness or that its disclosure is necessary to afford the accused a fair trial, the military judge, shall, upon the request of the trial counsel, review alternatives to disclosure in accordance with <ref>section 949p–6(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2596</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>SENTENCES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 949s.</num>
<heading> Cruel or unusual punishments prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Punishment by flogging, or by branding, marking, or tattooing on the body, or any other cruel or unusual punishment, may not be adjudged by a military commission under this chapter or inflicted under this chapter upon any person subject to this chapter. The use of irons, single or double, except for the purpose of safe custody, is prohibited under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949t.</num>
<heading> Maximum limits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The punishment which a military commission under this chapter may direct for an offense may not exceed such limits as the President or Secretary of Defense may prescribe for that offense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949u.</num>
<heading> Execution of confinement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, a sentence of confinement adjudged by a military commission under this chapter may be carried into execution by confinement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in any place of confinement under the control of any of the armed forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in any penal or correctional institution under the control of the United States or its allies, or which the United States may be allowed to use.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment During Confinement by Other Than the Armed Forces</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Persons confined under subsection (a)(2) in a penal or correctional institution not under the control of an armed force are subject to the same discipline and treatment as persons confined or committed by the courts of the United States or of the State, District of Columbia, or place in which the institution is situated.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>POST-TRIAL PROCEDURE AND REVIEW OF MILITARY COMMISSIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 950a.</num>
<heading> Error of law; lesser included offense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Error of Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A finding or sentence of a military commission under this chapter may not be held incorrect on the ground of an error of law unless the error materially prejudices the substantial rights of the accused.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lesser Included Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any reviewing authority with the power to approve or affirm a finding of guilty by a military commission under this chapter may approve or affirm, instead, so much of the finding as includes a lesser included offense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2599</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950b.</num>
<heading> Review by the convening authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to Convening Authority of Findings and Sentence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The findings and sentence of a military commission under this chapter shall be reported in writing promptly to the convening authority after the announcement of the sentence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submittal of Matters by Accused to Convening Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The accused may submit to the convening authority matters for consideration by the convening authority with respect to the findings and the sentence of the military commission under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a submittal under paragraph (1) shall be made in writing within 20 days after the accused has been given an authenticated record of trial under section 949<i>o</i>(c) of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If the accused shows that additional time is required for the accused to make a submittal under paragraph (1), the convening authority may, for good cause, extend the applicable period under subparagraph (A) for not more than an additional 20 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The accused may waive the accused’s right to make a submittal to the convening authority under paragraph (1). Such a waiver shall be made in writing, and may not be revoked. For the purposes of subsection (c)(2), the time within which the accused may make a submittal under this subsection shall be deemed to have expired upon the submittal of a waiver under this paragraph to the convening authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action by Convening Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The authority under this subsection to modify the findings and sentence of a military commission under this chapter is a matter of the sole discretion and prerogative of the convening authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The convening authority is not required to take action on the findings of a military commission under this chapter. If the convening authority takes action on the findings, the convening authority may, in the sole discretion of the convening authority, only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> dismiss any charge or specification by setting aside a finding of guilty thereto; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> change a finding of guilty to a charge to a finding of guilty to an offense that is a lesser included offense of the offense stated in the charge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The convening authority shall take action on the sentence of a military commission under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subject to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, action under this paragraph may be taken only after consideration of any matters submitted by the accused under subsection (b) or after the time for submitting such matters expires, whichever is earlier.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In taking action under this paragraph, the convening authority may, in the sole discretion of the convening authority, approve, disapprove, commute, or suspend the sentence in whole or in part. The convening authority may not increase a sentence beyond that which is found by the military commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The convening authority shall serve on the accused or on defense counsel notice of any action taken by the convening authority under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order of Revision or Rehearing</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the convening authority of a military commission under this chapter may, in the sole discretion of the convening authority, order a proceeding in revision or a rehearing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a proceeding in revision may be ordered by the convening authority if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> there is an apparent error or omission in the record; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the record shows improper or inconsistent action by the military commission with respect to the findings or sentence that can be rectified without material prejudice to the substantial rights of the accused.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> In no case may a proceeding in revision—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> reconsider a finding of not guilty of a specification or a ruling which amounts to a finding of not guilty;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reconsider a finding of not guilty of any charge, unless there has been a finding of guilty under a specification laid under that charge, which sufficiently alleges a violation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> increase the severity of the sentence unless the sentence prescribed for the offense is mandatory.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A rehearing may be ordered by the convening authority if the convening authority disapproves the findings and sentence and states the reasons for disapproval of the findings. If the convening authority disapproves the finding and sentence and does not order a rehearing, the convening authority shall dismiss the charges. A rehearing as to the findings may not be ordered by the convening authority when there is a lack of sufficient evidence in the record to support the findings. A rehearing as to the sentence may be ordered by the convening authority if the convening authority disapproves the sentence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2599</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(f)(10)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3510</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950c.</num>
<heading> Appellate referral; waiver or withdrawal of appeal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Automatic Referral for Appellate Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), in each case in which the final decision of a military commission under this chapter (as approved by the convening authority) includes a finding of guilty, the convening authority shall refer the case to the United States Court of Military Commission Review. Any such referral shall be made in accordance with procedures prescribed under regulations of the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver of Right of Review</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except in a case in which the sentence as approved under <ref>section 950b of this title</ref> extends to death, an accused may file with the convening authority a statement expressly waiving the right of the accused to appellate review by the United States Court of Military Commission Review under <ref>section 950f of this title</ref> of the final decision of the military commission under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A waiver under paragraph (1) shall be signed by both the accused and a defense counsel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A waiver under paragraph (1) must be filed, if at all, within 10 days after notice of the action is served on the accused or on defense counsel under <ref>section 950b(c)(4) of this title</ref>. The convening authority, for good cause, may extend the period for such filing by not more than 30 days.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Withdrawal of Appeal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except in a case in which the sentence as approved under <ref>section 950b of this title</ref> extends to death, the accused may withdraw an appeal at any time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Waiver or Withdrawal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A waiver of the right to appellate review or the withdrawal of an appeal under this section bars review under <ref>section 950f of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2600</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950d.</num>
<heading> Interlocutory appeals by the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interlocutory Appeal</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (b), in a trial by military commission under this chapter, the United States may take an interlocutory appeal to the United States Court of Military Commission Review of any order or ruling of the military judge—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that terminates proceedings of the military commission with respect to a charge or specification;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that excludes evidence that is substantial proof of a fact material in the proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that relates to a matter under subsection (c) or (d) of <ref>section 949d of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> that, with respect to classified information—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> authorizes the disclosure of such information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> imposes sanctions for nondisclosure of such information; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> refuses a protective order sought by the United States to prevent the disclosure of such information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States may not appeal under subsection (a) an order or ruling that is, or amounts to, a finding of not guilty by the military commission with respect to a charge or specification.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of Appeal Right With Respect to Classified Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States has the right to appeal under paragraph (4) of subsection (a) whenever the military judge enters an order or ruling that would require the disclosure of classified information, without regard to whether the order or ruling appealed from was entered under this chapter, another provision of law, a rule, or otherwise. Any such appeal may embrace any preceding order, ruling, or reasoning constituting the basis of the order or ruling that would authorize such disclosure.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Timing and Action on Interlocutory Appeals Relating to Classified Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appeal to be expedited</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An appeal taken pursuant to paragraph (4) of subsection (a) shall be expedited by the United States Court of Military Commission Review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appeals before trial</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If such an appeal is taken before trial, the appeal shall be taken within 10 days after the order or ruling from which the appeal is made and the trial shall not commence until the appeal is decided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appeals during trial</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If such an appeal is taken during trial, the military judge shall adjourn the trial until the appeal is decided, and the court of appeals—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall hear argument on such appeal within 4 days of the adjournment of the trial (excluding weekends and holidays);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may dispense with written briefs other than the supporting materials previously submitted to the military judge;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall render its decision within four days of argument on appeal (excluding weekends and holidays); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> may dispense with the issuance of a written opinion in rendering its decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and Timing of Other Appeals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States shall take an appeal of an order or ruling under subsection (a), other than an appeal under paragraph (4) of that subsection, by filing a notice of appeal with the military judge within 5 days after the date of the order or ruling.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Method of Appeal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An appeal under this section shall be forwarded, by means specified in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, directly to the United States Court of Military Commission Review.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appeals Court To Act Only With Respect to Matter of Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In ruling on an appeal under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a), the appeals court may act only with respect to matters of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subsequent Appeal Rights of Accused Not Affected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An appeal under paragraph (4) of subsection (a), and a decision on such appeal, shall not affect the right of the accused, in a subsequent appeal from a judgment of conviction, to claim as error reversal by the military judge on remand of a ruling appealed from during trial.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2601</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950e.</num>
<heading> Rehearings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Composition of Military Commission for Rehearing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each rehearing under this chapter shall take place before a military commission under this chapter composed of members who were not members of the military commission which first heard the case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of Rehearing</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Upon a rehearing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the accused may not be tried for any offense of which the accused was found not guilty by the first military commission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> no sentence in excess of or more than the original sentence may be imposed unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the sentence is based upon a finding of guilty of an offense not considered upon the merits in the original proceedings; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the sentence prescribed for the offense is mandatory.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon a rehearing, if the sentence approved after the first military commission was in accordance with a pretrial agreement and the accused at the rehearing changes his plea with respect to the charges or specifications upon which the pretrial agreement was based, or otherwise does not comply with pretrial agreement, the sentence as to those charges or specifications may include any punishment not in excess of that lawfully adjudged at the first military commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2602</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950f.</num>
<heading> Review by United States Court of Military Commission Review</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a court of record to be known as the “United States Court of Military Commission Review” (in this section referred to as the “Court”). The Court shall consist of one or more panels, each composed of not less than three judges on the Court. For the purpose of reviewing decisions of military commissions under this chapter, the Court may sit in panels or as a whole, in accordance with rules prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Judges</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Judges on the Court shall be assigned or appointed in a manner consistent with the provisions of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may assign persons who are appellate military judges to be judges on the Court. Any judge so assigned shall be a commissioned officer of the armed forces, and shall meet the qualifications for military judges prescribed by <ref>section 948j(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The President may appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, additional judges to the United States Court of Military Commission Review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> No person may serve as a judge on the Court in any case in which that person acted as a military judge, counsel, or reviewing official.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> For purposes of sections 203, 205, 207, 208, and 209 of title 18, the term “special Government employee” shall include a judge of the Court appointed under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A person appointed as a judge of the Court under paragraph (3) shall be considered to be an officer or employee of the United States with respect to such person’s status as a judge, but only during periods in which such person is performing the duties of such a judge. Any provision of law that prohibits or limits the political or business activities of an employee of the United States shall only apply to such a judge during such periods.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The term of an appellate military judge assigned to the Court under paragraph (2) or appointed to the Court under paragraph (3) shall expire on the earlier of the date on which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the judge leaves active duty; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the judge is reassigned to other duties in accordance with <ref>section 949b(b)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cases To Be Reviewed</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Court shall, in accordance with procedures prescribed under regulations of the Secretary, review the record in each case that is referred to the Court by the convening authority under <ref>section 950c of this title</ref> with respect to any matter properly raised by the accused.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standard and Scope of Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In a case reviewed by the Court under this section, the Court may act only with respect to the findings and sentence as approved by the convening authority. The Court may affirm only such findings of guilty, and the sentence or such part or amount of the sentence, as the Court finds correct in law and fact and determines, on the basis of the entire record, should be approved. In considering the record, the Court may weigh the evidence, judge the credibility of witnesses, and determine controverted questions of fact, recognizing that the military commission saw and heard the witnesses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rehearings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Court sets aside the findings or sentence, the Court may, except where the setting aside is based on lack of sufficient evidence in the record to support the findings, order a rehearing. If the Court sets aside the findings or sentence and does not order a rehearing, the Court shall order that the charges be dismissed.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2603</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1034(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1082</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1602</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 541(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1761</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 567(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1905</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950g.</num>
<heading> Review by United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit; writ of certiorari to Supreme Court</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusive Appellate Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit shall have exclusive jurisdiction to determine the validity of a final judgment rendered by a military commission (as approved by the convening authority and, where applicable, as affirmed or set aside as incorrect in law by the United States Court of Military Commission Review) under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exhaustion of Other Appeals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit may not review a final judgment described in subsection (a) until all other appeals under this chapter have been waived or exhausted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time for Seeking Review</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A petition for review by the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit must be filed in the Court of Appeals—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not later than 20 days after the date on which written notice of the final decision of the United States Court of Military Commission Review is served on the parties; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the accused submits, in the form prescribed by <ref>section 950c of this title</ref>, a written notice waiving the right of the accused to review by the United States Court of Military Commission Review, not later than 20 days after the date on which such notice is submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope and Nature of Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit may act under this section only with respect to the findings and sentence as approved by the convening authority and as affirmed or set aside as incorrect in law by the United States Court of Military Commission Review, and shall take action only with respect to matters of law, including the sufficiency of the evidence to support the verdict.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review by Supreme Court</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Supreme Court may review by writ of certiorari pursuant to <ref>section 1254 of title 28</ref> the final judgment of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2603</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1034(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1573</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950h.</num>
<heading> Appellate counsel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall, by regulation, establish procedures for the appointment of appellate counsel for the United States and for the accused in military commissions under this chapter. Appellate counsel shall meet the qualifications of counsel for appearing before military commissions under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Representation of United States</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Appellate counsel appointed under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall represent the United States in any appeal or review proceeding under this chapter before the United States Court of Military Commission Review; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may, when requested to do so by the Attorney General in a case arising under this chapter, represent the United States before the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit or the Supreme Court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Representation of Accused</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The accused shall be represented by appellate counsel appointed under subsection (a) before the United States Court of Military Commission Review, the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, and the Supreme Court, and by civilian counsel if retained by the accused. Any such civilian counsel shall meet the qualifications under paragraph (3) of <ref>section 949c(b) of this title</ref> for civilian counsel appearing before military commissions under this chapter and shall be subject to the requirements of paragraph (7) of that section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2604</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950i.</num>
<heading> Execution of sentence; suspension of sentence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense is authorized to carry out a sentence imposed by a military commission under this chapter in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Execution of Sentence of Death Only Upon Approval by the President</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the sentence of a military commission under this chapter extends to death, that part of the sentence providing for death may not be executed until approved by the President. In such a case, the President may commute, remit, or suspend the sentence, or any part thereof, as he sees fit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Execution of Sentence of Death Only Upon Final Judgment of Legality of Proceedings</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the sentence of a military commission under this chapter extends to death, the sentence may not be executed until there is a final judgment as to the legality of the proceedings (and with respect to death, approval under subsection (b)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A judgment as to legality of proceedings is final for purposes of paragraph (1) when review is completed in accordance with the judgment of the United States Court of Military Commission Review and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the time for the accused to file a petition for review by the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit has expired, the accused has not filed a timely petition for such review, and the case is not otherwise under review by the Court of Appeals; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> review is completed in accordance with the judgment of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a petition for a writ of certiorari is not timely filed;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such a petition is denied by the Supreme Court; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> review is otherwise completed in accordance with the judgment of the Supreme Court.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Suspension of Sentence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Defense, or the convening authority acting on the case (if other than the Secretary), may suspend the execution of any sentence or part thereof in the case, except a sentence of death.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2605</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950j.</num>
<heading> Finality of proceedings, findings, and sentences</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The appellate review of records of trial provided by this chapter, and the proceedings, findings, and sentences of military commissions as approved, reviewed, or affirmed as required by this chapter, are final and conclusive. Orders publishing the proceedings of military commissions under this chapter are binding upon all departments, courts, agencies, and officers of the United States, subject only to action by the Secretary or the convening authority as provided in <ref>section 950i(c) of this title</ref> and the authority of the President.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2605</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VIII—</num>
<heading>PUNITIVE MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 950p.</num>
<heading> Definitions; construction of certain offenses; common circumstances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “military objective” means combatants and those objects during hostilities which, by their nature, location, purpose, or use, effectively contribute to the war-fighting or war-sustaining capability of an opposing force and whose total or partial destruction, capture, or neutralization would constitute a definite military advantage to the attacker under the circumstances at the time of an attack.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “protected person” means any person entitled to protection under one or more of the Geneva Conventions, including civilians not taking an active part in hostilities, military personnel placed out of combat by sickness, wounds, or detention, and military medical or religious personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “protected property” means any property specifically protected by the law of war, including buildings dedicated to religion, education, art, science, or charitable purposes, historic monuments, hospitals, and places where the sick and wounded are collected, but only if and to the extent such property is not being used for military purposes or is not otherwise a military objective. The term includes objects properly identified by one of the distinctive emblems of the Geneva Conventions, but does not include civilian property that is a military objective.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction of Certain Offenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The intent required for offenses under paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), and (12) of <ref>section 950t of this title</ref> precludes the applicability of such offenses with regard to collateral damage or to death, damage, or injury incident to a lawful attack.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Common Circumstances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An offense specified in this subchapter is triable by military commission under this chapter only if the offense is committed in the context of and associated with hostilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provisions of this subchapter codify offenses that have traditionally been triable by military commission. This chapter does not establish new crimes that did not exist before the date of the enactment of this subchapter, as amended by the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010, but rather codifies those crimes for trial by military commission. Because the provisions of this subchapter codify offenses that have traditionally been triable under the law of war or otherwise triable by military commission, this subchapter does not preclude trial for offenses that occurred before the date of the enactment of this subchapter, as so amended.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2606</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950q.</num>
<heading> Principals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any person punishable under this chapter who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> commits an offense punishable by this chapter, or aids, abets, counsels, commands, or procures its commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> causes an act to be done which if directly performed by him would be punishable by this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is a superior commander who, with regard to acts punishable by this chapter, knew, had reason to know, or should have known, that a subordinate was about to commit such acts or had done so and who failed to take the necessary and reasonable measures to prevent such acts or to punish the perpetrators thereof,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is a principal.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2606</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950r.</num>
<heading> Accessory after the fact</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person subject to this chapter who, knowing that an offense punishable by this chapter has been committed, receives, comforts, or assists the offender in order to hinder or prevent his apprehension, trial, or punishment shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2607</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950s.</num>
<heading> Conviction of lesser offenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An accused may be found guilty of an offense necessarily included in the offense charged or of an attempt to commit either the offense charged or an attempt to commit either the offense charged or an offense necessarily included therein.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2607</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950t.</num>
<heading> Crimes triable by military commission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following offenses shall be triable by military commission under this chapter at any time without limitation:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Murder of protected persons</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally kills one or more protected persons shall be punished by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attacking civilians</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally engages in an attack upon a civilian population as such, or individual civilians not taking active part in hostilities, shall be punished, if death results to one or more of the victims, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to any of the victims, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attacking civilian objects</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally engages in an attack upon a civilian object that is not a military objective shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attacking protected property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally engages in an attack upon protected property shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pillaging</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally and in the absence of military necessity appropriates or seizes property for private or personal use, without the consent of a person with authority to permit such appropriation or seizure, shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Denying quarter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who, with effective command or control over subordinate groups, declares, orders, or otherwise indicates to those groups that there shall be no survivors or surrender accepted, with the intent to threaten an adversary or to conduct hostilities such that there would be no survivors or surrender accepted, shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Taking hostages</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who, having knowingly seized or detained one or more persons, threatens to kill, injure, or continue to detain such person or persons with the intent of compelling any nation, person other than the hostage, or group of persons to act or refrain from acting as an explicit or implicit condition for the safety or release of such person or persons, shall be punished, if death results to one or more of the victims, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to any of the victims, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employing poison or similar weapons</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally, as a method of warfare, employs a substance or weapon that releases a substance that causes death or serious and lasting damage to health in the ordinary course of events, through its asphyxiating, bacteriological, or toxic properties, shall be punished, if death results to one or more of the victims, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to any of the victims, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Using protected persons as a shield</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who positions, or otherwise takes advantage of, a protected person with the intent to shield a military objective from attack, or to shield, favor, or impede military operations, shall be punished, if death results to one or more of the victims, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to any of the victims, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Using protected property as a shield</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who positions, or otherwise takes advantage of the location of, protected property with the intent to shield a military objective from attack, or to shield, favor, or impede military operations, shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Torture.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who commits an act specifically intended to inflict severe physical or mental pain or suffering (other than pain or suffering incidental to lawful sanctions) upon another person within his custody or physical control for the purpose of obtaining information or a confession, punishment, intimidation, coercion, or any reason based on discrimination of any kind, shall be punished, if death results to one or more of the victims, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to any of the victims, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Severe mental pain or suffering defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this paragraph, the term “severe mental pain or suffering” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2340(2) of title 18</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cruel or inhuman treatment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who subjects another person in their custody or under their physical control, regardless of nationality or physical location, to cruel or inhuman treatment that constitutes a grave breach of common Article 3 of the Geneva Conventions shall be punished, if death results to the victim, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to the victim, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Intentionally causing serious bodily injury.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally causes serious bodily injury to one or more persons, including privileged belligerents, in violation of the law of war shall be punished, if death results to one or more of the victims, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to any of the victims, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Serious bodily injury defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this paragraph, the term “serious bodily injury” means bodily injury which involves—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a substantial risk of death;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> extreme physical pain;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> protracted and obvious disfigurement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> protracted loss or impairment of the function of a bodily member, organ, or mental faculty.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mutilating or maiming</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally injures one or more protected persons by disfiguring the person or persons by any mutilation of the person or persons, or by permanently disabling any member, limb, or organ of the body of the person or persons, without any legitimate medical or dental purpose, shall be punished, if death results to one or more of the victims, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to any of the victims, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Murder in violation of the law of war</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally kills one or more persons, including privileged belligerents, in violation of the law of war shall be punished by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Destruction of property in violation of the law of war</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally destroys property belonging to another person in violation of the law of war shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Using treachery or perfidy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who, after inviting the confidence or belief of one or more persons that they were entitled to, or obliged to accord, protection under the law of war, intentionally makes use of that confidence or belief in killing, injuring, or capturing such person or persons shall be punished, if death results to one or more of the victims, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to any of the victims, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Improperly using a flag of truce</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who uses a flag of truce to feign an intention to negotiate, surrender, or otherwise suspend hostilities when there is no such intention shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Improperly using a distinctive emblem</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally uses a distinctive emblem recognized by the law of war for combatant purposes in a manner prohibited by the law of war shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Intentionally mistreating a dead body</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally mistreats the body of a dead person, without justification by legitimate military necessary, shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rape</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who forcibly or with coercion or threat of force wrongfully invades the body of a person by penetrating, however slightly, the anal or genital opening of the victim with any part of the body of the accused, or with any foreign object, shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sexual assault or abuse</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who forcibly or with coercion or threat of force engages in sexual contact with one or more persons, or causes one or more persons to engage in sexual contact, shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hijacking or hazarding a vessel or aircraft</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally seizes, exercises unauthorized control over, or endangers the safe navigation of a vessel or aircraft that is not a legitimate military objective shall be punished, if death results to one or more of the victims, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to any of the victims, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terrorism</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who intentionally kills or inflicts great bodily harm on one or more protected persons, or intentionally engages in an act that evinces a wanton disregard for human life, in a manner calculated to influence or affect the conduct of government or civilian population by intimidation or coercion, or to retaliate against government conduct, shall be punished, if death results to one or more of the victims, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to any of the victims, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Providing material support for terrorism.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who provides material support or resources, knowing or intending that they are to be used in preparation for, or in carrying out, an act of terrorism (as set forth in paragraph (24) of this section), or who intentionally provides material support or resources to an international terrorist organization engaged in hostilities against the United States, knowing that such organization has engaged or engages in terrorism (as so set forth), shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Material support or resources defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this paragraph, the term “material support or resources” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2339A(b) of title 18</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Wrongfully aiding the enemy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who, in breach of an allegiance or duty to the United States, knowingly and intentionally aids an enemy of the United States, or one of the co-belligerents of the enemy, shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(27)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Spying</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who, in violation of the law of war and with intent or reason to believe that it is to be used to the injury of the United States or to the advantage of a foreign power, collects or attempts to collect information by clandestine means or while acting under false pretenses, for the purpose of conveying such information to an enemy of the United States, or one of the co-belligerents of the enemy, shall be punished by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(28)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Attempts.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who attempts to commit any offense punishable by this chapter shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of offense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An act, done with specific intent to commit an offense under this chapter, amounting to more than mere preparation and tending, even though failing, to effect its commission, is an attempt to commit that offense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of consummation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter may be convicted of an attempt to commit an offense although it appears on the trial that the offense was consummated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(29)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conspiracy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who conspires to commit one or more substantive offenses triable by military commission under this subchapter, and who knowingly does any overt act to effect the object of the conspiracy, shall be punished, if death results to one or more of the victims, by death or such other punishment as a military commission under this chapter may direct, and, if death does not result to any of the victims, by such punishment, other than death, as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(30)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Solicitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person subject to this chapter who solicits or advises another or others to commit one or more substantive offenses triable by military commission under this chapter shall, if the offense solicited or advised is attempted or committed, be punished with the punishment provided for the commission of the offense, but, if the offense solicited or advised is not committed or attempted, shall be punished as a military commission under this chapter may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(31)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contempt</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A military commission under this chapter may punish for contempt any person who uses any menacing word, sign, or gesture in its presence, or who disturbs its proceedings by any riot or disorder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(32)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Perjury and obstruction of justice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A military commission under this chapter may try offenses and impose such punishment as the military commission may direct for perjury, false testimony, or obstruction of justice related to the military commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2607</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1983</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>