<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 363—</num>
<heading>PROHIBITION AND PENALTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4651.</num>
<heading> Expenditure of appropriations: limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Money appropriated to the Department of Defense may not be spent under a contract other than a contract for personal services unless that contract provides that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States may, by written notice to the contractor, terminate the right of the contractor to proceed under the contract if the Secretary concerned or his designee finds, after notice and hearing, that the contractor, or his agent or other representative, offered or gave any gratuity, such as entertainment or a gift, to an officer, official, or employee of the United States to obtain a contract or favorable treatment in the awarding, amending, or making of determinations concerning the performance, of a contract; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if a contract is terminated under clause (1), the United States has the same remedies against the contractor that it would have had if the contractor had breached the contract and, in addition to other damages, is entitled to exemplary damages in an amount at least three, but not more than 10, as determined by the Secretary or his designee, times the cost incurred by the contractor in giving gratuities to the officer, official, or employee concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The existence of facts upon which the Secretary makes findings under clause (1) may be reviewed by any competent court.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to a contract that is for an amount not greater than the simplified acquisition threshold (as defined in <ref>section 134 of title 41</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 87–651, title II, § 207(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 520</ref>, § 2207; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 389</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3842</ref>; renumbered § 4651, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1862(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4652.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on use of funds for documenting economic or employment impact of certain acquisition programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No funds appropriated by the Congress may be obligated or expended to assist any contractor of the Department of Defense in preparing any material, report, lists, or analysis with respect to the actual or projected economic or employment impact in a particular State or congressional district of an acquisition program for which all research, development, testing, and evaluation has not been completed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title VII, § 7202(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3379</ref>, § 2247; renumbered § 2249, <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 672</ref>; renumbered § 4652, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1862(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4653.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on use of funds to relieve economic dislocations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In order to help avoid the uneconomic use of Department of Defense funds in the procurement of goods and services, the Congress finds that it is necessary to prohibit the use of such funds for certain purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> No funds appropriated to or for the use of the Department of Defense may be used to pay, in connection with any contract awarded by the Department of Defense, a price differential for the purpose of relieving economic dislocations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 913(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1123</ref>, § 2392; renumbered § 4653, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1862(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4654.</num>
<heading> Prohibition against doing business with certain offerors or contractors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of a military department may not solicit an offer from, award a contract to, extend an existing contract with, or, when approval by the Secretary of the award of a subcontract is required, approve the award of a subcontract to, an offeror or contractor which to the Secretary’s knowledge has been debarred or suspended by another Federal agency unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of debarment, the debarment of the offeror or contractor by all other agencies has been terminated or the period of time specified for such debarment has expired; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a suspension, the period of time specified by all other agencies for the suspension of the offeror or contractor has expired.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) does not apply in any case in which the Secretary concerned determines that there is a compelling reason to solicit an offer from, award a contract to, extend a contract with, or approve a subcontract with such offeror or contractor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whenever the Secretary concerned makes a determination described in subsection (a)(2), he shall, at the time of the determination, transmit a notice to the Administrator of General Services describing the determination. The Administrator of General Services shall maintain each such notice on a publicly accessible website to the maximum extent practicable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “debar” means to exclude, pursuant to established administrative procedures, from Government contracting and subcontracting for a specified period of time commensurate with the seriousness of the failure or offense or the inadequacy of performance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “suspend” means to disqualify, pursuant to established administrative procedures, from Government contracting and subcontracting for a temporary period of time because a concern or individual is suspected of engaging in criminal, fraudulent, or seriously improper conduct.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe in regulations a requirement that each contractor under contract with the Department of Defense shall require each contractor to whom it awards a contract (in this section referred to as a subcontractor) to disclose to the contractor whether the subcontractor is or is not, as of the time of the award of the subcontract, debarred or suspended by the Federal Government from Government contracting or subcontracting. The requirement shall apply to any subcontractor whose subcontract is in an amount greater than the simplified acquisition threshold (as defined in <ref>section 134 of title 41</ref>). The requirement shall not apply in the case of a subcontract for the acquisition of commercial products or commercial services (as defined in sections 103 and 103a, respectively, of title 41).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 914(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1124</ref>, § 2393; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XII, § 1231(17)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1161</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title VIII, § 813</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1473</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title IV, § 4102(e)</ref>, title VIII, § 8105(c), <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3340</ref>, 3392; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(24)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3844</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VIII, § 813</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 808</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1869</ref>; renumbered § 4654, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1862(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4655.</num>
<heading> Prohibition of contractors limiting subcontractor sales directly to the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Each contract for the purchase of supplies or services made by the Department of Defense shall provide that the contractor will not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enter into any agreement with a subcontractor under the contract that has the effect of unreasonably restricting sales by the subcontractor directly to the United States of any item or process (including computer software) made or furnished by the subcontractor under the contract (or any follow-on production contract); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> otherwise act to restrict unreasonably the ability of a subcontractor to make sales to the United States described in clause (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section does not prohibit a contractor from asserting rights it otherwise has under law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to a contract that is for an amount not greater than the simplified acquisition threshold (as defined in <ref>section 134 of title 41</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An agreement between the contractor in a contract for the acquisition of commercial products or commercial services and a subcontractor under such contract that restricts sales by such subcontractor directly to persons other than the contractor may not be considered to unreasonably restrict sales by that subcontractor to the United States in violation of the provision included in such contract pursuant to subsection (a) if the agreement does not result in the United States being treated differently with regard to the restriction than any other prospective purchaser of such commercial products or commercial services from that subcontractor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In paragraph (1), the terms “commercial product” and “commercial service” have the meanings given those terms in sections 103 and 103a, respectively, of title 41.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XII, § 1234(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2601</ref>, § 2402; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title IV, § 4102(f)</ref>, title VIII, § 8105(g), <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3340</ref>, 3392; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(25)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3844</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1869</ref>; renumbered § 4655, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1862(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4656.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on persons convicted of defense-contract related felonies and related criminal penalty on defense contractors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An individual who is convicted of fraud or any other felony arising out of a contract with the Department of Defense shall be prohibited from each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Working in a management or supervisory capacity on any defense contract or any first tier subcontract of a defense contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Serving on the board of directors of any defense contractor or any subcontractor awarded a contract directly by a defense contractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Serving as a consultant to any defense contractor or any subcontractor awarded a contract directly by a defense contractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Being involved in any other way, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, with a defense contract or first tier subcontract of a defense contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (3), the prohibition in paragraph (1) shall apply for a period, as determined by the Secretary of Defense, of not less than five years after the date of the conviction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The prohibition in paragraph (1) may apply with respect to an individual for a period of less than five years if the Secretary determines that the five-year period should be waived in the interests of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The prohibition in paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A contract referred to in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of such paragraph that is not greater than the simplified acquisition threshold (as defined in <ref>section 134 of title 41</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A contract referred to in such subparagraph that is for the acquisition of commercial products or commercial services (as defined in sections 103 and 103a, respectively, of title 41).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A subcontract referred to in such subparagraph that is under a contract described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A defense contractor or subcontractor shall be subject to a criminal penalty of not more than $500,000 if such contractor or subcontractor is convicted of knowingly—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> employing a person under a prohibition under subsection (a); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> allowing such a person to serve on the board of directors of such contractor or subcontractor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Single Point of Contact for Information</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall ensure that a single point of contact is established to enable a defense contractor or subcontractor to promptly obtain information regarding whether a person that the contractor or subcontractor proposes to use for an activity covered by paragraph (1) of subsection (a) is under a prohibition under that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The procedure for obtaining such information shall be specified in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title X, § 941(a)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–82</ref>, 1783–161, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title X, § 941(a)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–82</ref>, 3341–161, § 2408; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IX</ref>, formerly title IV, § 941(a)(1), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3941</ref>, renumbered title IX, <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 273</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title VIII, § 831(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2023</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title VIII, § 812</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 815(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2454</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title IV, § 4102(g)</ref>, title VIII, § 8105(h), <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3340</ref>, 3393; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1062(e)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 444</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(26)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3844</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(e)(5)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1870</ref>; renumbered § 4656, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1862(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4657.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on criminal history inquiries by contractors prior to conditional offer</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Criminal History Inquiries.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the head of an agency—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may not require that an individual or sole proprietor who submits a bid for a contract to disclose criminal history record information regarding that individual or sole proprietor before determining the apparent awardee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall require as a condition of receiving a Federal contract and receiving payments under such contract that the contractor may not verbally or through written form request the disclosure of criminal history record information regarding an applicant for a position related to work under such contract before such contractor extends a conditional offer to the applicant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Otherwise required by law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibition under paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to a contract if consideration of criminal history record information prior to a conditional offer with respect to the position is otherwise required by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exception for certain positions.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The prohibition under paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a contract that requires an individual hired under the contract to access classified information or to have sensitive law enforcement or national security duties; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a position that the Secretary of Defense identifies under the regulations issued under subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Regulations.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Issuance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 16 months after the date of enactment of the Fair Chance to Compete for Jobs Act of 2019, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Administrator of General Services, shall issue regulations identifying additional positions with respect to which the prohibition under paragraph (1) shall not apply, giving due consideration to positions that involve interaction with minors, access to sensitive information, or managing financial transactions.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compliance with civil rights laws</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The regulations issued under clause (i) shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> be consistent with, and in no way supersede, restrict, or limit the application of title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e</ref> et seq.) or other relevant Federal civil rights laws; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> ensure that all hiring activities conducted pursuant to the regulations are conducted in a manner consistent with relevant Federal civil rights laws.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Complaint Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish and publish procedures under which an applicant for a position with a Department of Defense contractor may submit a complaint, or any other information, relating to compliance by the contractor with subsection (a)(1)(B).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Action for Violations of Prohibition on Criminal History Inquiries.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">First violation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the Secretary of Defense determines that a contractor has violated subsection (a)(1)(B), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> notify the contractor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide 30 days after such notification for the contractor to appeal the determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> issue a written warning to the contractor that includes a description of the violation and the additional remedies that may apply for subsequent violations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subsequent violations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the Secretary of Defense determines that a contractor that was subject to paragraph (1) has committed a subsequent violation of subsection (a)(1)(B), the Secretary shall notify the contractor, shall provide 30 days after such notification for the contractor to appeal the determination, and, in consultation with the relevant Federal agencies, may take actions, depending on the severity of the infraction and the contractor’s history of violations, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing written guidance to the contractor that the contractor’s eligibility for contracts requires compliance with this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> requiring that the contractor respond within 30 days affirming that the contractor is taking steps to comply with this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> suspending payment under the contract for which the applicant was being considered until the contractor demonstrates compliance with this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditional offer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “conditional offer” means an offer of employment for a position related to work under a contract that is conditioned upon the results of a criminal history inquiry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal history record information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “criminal history record information” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 9201 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XI, § 1123(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1612</ref>, § 2339; renumbered § 4657, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1862(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4658.</num>
<heading> Debarment of persons convicted of fraudulent use of “Made in America” labels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of Defense determines that a person has been convicted of intentionally affixing a label bearing a “Made in America” inscription, or another inscription with the same meaning, to any product sold in or shipped to the United States that is not made in America, the Secretary shall determine, not later than 90 days after determining that the person has been so convicted, whether the person should be debarred from contracting with the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “debar” has the meaning given that term by <ref>section 4654(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 834(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2461</ref>, § 2410f; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1062(f)</ref>, title XV, § 1503(a)(22), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 444</ref>, 512; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(a)(20)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1223</ref>; renumbered § 4658 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1862(b)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>, 4278; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(20)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4659.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on contracting with entities that comply with the secondary Arab boycott of Israel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under section 3(5)(A) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002136">1</ref> of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 4602(5)(A)</ref>), it is the policy of the United States to oppose restrictive trade practices or boycotts fostered or imposed by foreign countries against other countries friendly to the United States or against any other United States person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Consistent with the policy referred to in subsection (a), the Department of Defense may not award a contract for an amount in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold (as defined in <ref>section 134 of title 41</ref>) to a foreign entity unless that entity certifies to the Secretary of Defense that it does not comply with the secondary Arab boycott of Israel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In paragraph (1), the term “foreign entity” means a foreign person, a foreign company, or any other foreign entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may waive the prohibition in subsection (b) in specific instances when the Secretary determines that the waiver is necessary in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (b) does not apply—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to contracts for consumable supplies, provisions, or services that are intended to be used for the support of United States forces or of allied forces in a foreign country; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to contracts pertaining to the use of any equipment, technology, data, or services for intelligence or classified purposes by the United States Government in the interests of national security or to the acquisition or lease of any such equipment, technology, data, or services by the United States Government in the interests of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIII, § 1332(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2555</ref>, § 2410i; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–350</ref>, §§ 4, 5(b)(31), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3841</ref>, 3845; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1081(b)(3)(D)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2419</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1561</ref>; renumbered § 4659, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1862(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4660.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on collection of political information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Requiring Submission of Political Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of an agency may not require a contractor to submit political information related to the contractor or a subcontractor at any tier, or any partner, officer, director, or employee of the contractor or subcontractor—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as part of a solicitation, request for bid, request for proposal, or any other form of communication designed to solicit offers in connection with the award of a contract for procurement of property or services; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> during the course of contract performance as part of the process associated with modifying a contract or exercising a contract option.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibition under this section applies to the procurement of commercial products and commercial services, the procurement of commercial-off-the-shelf-items, and the non-commercial procurement of supplies, property, services, and manufactured items, irrespective of contract vehicle, including contracts, purchase orders, task or deliver orders under indefinite delivery/indefinite quantity contracts, blanket purchase agreements, and basic ordering agreements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> waiving, superseding, restricting, or limiting the application of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<ref>52 U.S.C. 30101</ref> et seq.) or preventing Federal regulatory or law enforcement agencies from collecting or receiving information authorized by law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> precluding the Defense Contract Audit Agency from accessing and reviewing certain information, including political information, for the purpose of identifying unallowable costs and administering cost principles established pursuant to subchapter I of chapter 273 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contractor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “contractor” includes contractors, bidders, and offerors, and individuals and legal entities who would reasonably be expected to submit offers or bids for Federal Government contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Political information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “political information” means information relating to political spending, including any payment consisting of a contribution, expenditure, independent expenditure, or disbursement for an electioneering communication that is made by the contractor, any of its partners, officers, directors or employees, or any of its affiliates or subsidiaries to a candidate or on behalf of a candidate for election for Federal office, to a political committee, to a political party, to a third party entity with the intention or reasonable expectation that it would use the payment to make independent expenditures or electioneering communications, or that is otherwise made with respect to any election for Federal office, party affiliation, and voting history.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other terms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each of the terms “contribution”, “expenditure”, “independent expenditure”, “candidate”, “election”, “electioneering communication”, and “Federal office” has the meaning given that term in the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<ref>52 U.S.C. 30101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 823(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1502</ref>, § 2335; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(f)(17)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(32)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(c)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1866</ref>; renumbered § 4660 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1862(b), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4277</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(d)(14)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2137</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4661.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on certain procurements from the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on the Availability of Funds for Certain Procurements From XUAR</inline>.—</heading>
<content>None of the funds authorized to be appropriated by a national defense authorization Act or any other Act, or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of Defense, may be obligated or expended to knowingly procure any products mined, produced, or manufactured wholly or in part by forced labor from XUAR or from an entity that has used labor from within or transferred from XUAR as part of a “poverty alleviation” or “pairing assistance” program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the terms “forced labor” and “XUAR” have the meanings given, respectively, in <ref>section 2496 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 855(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2723</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4662.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on the transfer of certain data on employees of the Department of Defense to third parties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each contract entered into by the Department of Defense on or after the date of the enactment of this section shall include a provision prohibiting the contractor and each subcontractor under such contract from selling, licensing, or otherwise transferring covered individually identifiable Department employee data to any individual or entity other than the Federal Government, except to the extent required to perform such contract or a subcontract under such contract. This provision does not apply in circumstances where the transfer of such data would otherwise be authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may waive the requirements of subsection (a) with respect to the sale, licensing, or other transfer of covered individually identifiable Department employee data if the Secretary determines that such waiver—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> appropriately considers the privacy risks to the employee of the Department of Defense to which such data relates; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is necessary in the interest of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than <date date="2026-01-15">January 15, 2026</date>, and annually thereafter for four years, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the use of the waiver authority under subsection (b) for the fiscal year preceding the date of submission of the report. The report shall include, for each use of the waiver—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the specific justification for providing the waiver;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an identification of the contractor or subcontractor that is the subject of the waiver request; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an identification of the purpose of the sale, licensing, or transfer of covered individually identifiable Department employee data that is the subject of the waiver request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “covered individually identifiable Department employee data” means individually identifiable Department employee data obtained by a contractor or subcontractor described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “individually identifiable Department employee data” means information related to an employee of the Department of Defense, including a member of the Armed Forces, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identifies such employee; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which may be used to infer, by either direct or indirect means, the identity of such an employee to whom the information applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 312</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 836</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4663.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on contracting with covered entities that contract with lobbyists for Chinese military companies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Entering Into Contracts With Covered Entities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense may not enter into a contract with an entity, a parent company of such entity, or a subsidiary of such entity is <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002137">1</ref> a party to a contract with a covered lobbyist.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to an entity that made reasonable inquires regarding the lobbying activities of another entity and determined such entity was not a covered lobbyist.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon notification to Congress, the Secretary of Defense may waive the requirements of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “covered lobbyist” means an entity that engages in lobbying activities for any entity determined to be a Chinese military company listed in accordance with section 1260H of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<ref>10 U.S.C. 113</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “lobbying activities” has the meaning given in section 1045(c) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 (<ref>10 U.S.C. 971</ref> note prec.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 851(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>