<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 135—</num>
<heading>SPACE PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2271.</num>
<heading> Management of space programs: joint program offices and officer management programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joint Program Offices</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall take appropriate actions to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that space development and acquisition programs of the Department of Defense are carried out through joint program offices.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officer Management Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall take appropriate actions to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Army, Navy, and Marine Corps officers, as well as Air Force officers, are assigned to the space development and acquisition programs of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Army, Navy, and Marine Corps officers, as well as Air Force officers, are eligible, on the basis of qualification, to hold leadership positions within the joint program offices referred to in subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall designate those positions in the Office of the National Security Space Architect of the Department of Defense (or any successor office) that qualify as joint duty assignment positions for purposes of chapter 38 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1195</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2271a.</num>
<heading> Space Contractor Responsibility Watch List</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Assistant Secretary of the Air Force for Space Acquisition and Integration, acting as the service acquisition executive for the Air Force for space systems and programs, shall maintain a list of contractors with a history of poor performance on space procurement contracts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basis for Inclusion on Watch List</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary shall place a contractor, which may consist of the entire contracting entity or a specific division of the contracting entity, on the watch list based on a determination made under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> In considering whether to place a contractor on the watch list, the Assistant Secretary shall determine whether there is evidence of any of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Poor performance on one or more space procurement contracts, or award fee scores below 50 percent.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Inadequate management, operational or financial controls, or resources.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Inadequate security controls or resources, including unremediated vulnerabilities arising from foreign ownership, control, or influence.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Any other failure of controls or performance of a nature so serious or compelling as to warrant placement of the contractor on the watch list.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If the Assistant Secretary determines, based on evidence described in any of clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (A), that the ability of a contractor to responsibly perform is meaningfully impaired, the Assistant Secretary shall place the contractor on the watch list.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The Assistant Secretary shall establish written policies for the consideration of contractors for placement on the watch list, including policies that require that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> contractors proposed for placement on the watch list shall be provided with notice and an opportunity to respond;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the basis for a final determination placing a contractor on the watch list shall be documented in writing; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> at the request of a contractor, the contractor shall be removed from the watch list if the Assistant Secretary determines that there is evidence that the issue resulting in placement on the list has been satisfactorily remediated.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Listing</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary may not solicit an offer from, award a contract to, consent to a subcontract with, execute a grant, cooperative agreement, or other transaction with, or exercise an option on any space procurement contract with, an entity included on the watch list unless the Assistant Secretary makes a written determination that there is a compelling reason to do so.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than 10 days after the Assistant Secretary makes a determination under paragraph (1), the Assistant Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees and the Interagency Committee on Debarment and Suspension constituted under sections 4 and 5 of Executive Order 12549 (51 Fed. Reg. 6370; relating to debarment and suspension) of the determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Assistant Secretary may delegate the authority to make a determination under subsection (b)(2)(B) or subsection (c)(1) only if the following criteria are met:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The delegation is to the suspension and debarment official of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The delegation is made on a case-by-case basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Not later than seven days after the date on which such determination is made, the Assistant Secretary notifies the congressional defense committees of the delegation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as preventing the suspension or debarment of a contractor, but inclusion on the watch list shall not be construed as a punitive measure or de facto suspension or debarment of a contractor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “contract” includes a grant, cooperative agreement, or other transaction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “contractor” means any individual or entity that enters into a contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “watch list” means the watch list maintained under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1601(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2272.</num>
<heading> Space science and technology strategy: coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence shall jointly develop and implement a space science and technology strategy and shall review and, as appropriate, revise the strategy biennially. Functions of the Secretary under this section shall be carried out jointly by the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering and the official of the Department of Defense designated as the Department of Defense Executive Agent for Space.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002088">1</ref></p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1563</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2428</ref>, 2429; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title IX, § 901(j)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4324</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1604</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1098</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(28)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1546</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2273.</num>
<heading> Policy regarding assured access to space: national security payloads</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It is the policy of the United States for the President to undertake actions appropriate to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the United States has the capabilities necessary to launch and insert United States national security payloads into space whenever such payloads are needed in space.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Included Actions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The appropriate actions referred to in subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, providing resources and policy guidance to sustain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the availability of at least two space launch vehicles (or families of space launch vehicles) capable of delivering into space any payload designated by the Secretary of Defense or the Director of National Intelligence as a national security payload;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a robust space launch infrastructure and industrial base; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the availability of rapid, responsive, and reliable space launches for national security space programs to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improve the responsiveness and flexibility of a national security space system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> lower the costs of launching a national security space system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> maintain risks of mission success at acceptable levels.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall, to the maximum extent practicable, pursue the attainment of the capabilities described in subsection (a) in coordination with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 912(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1565</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 932(a)(11), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(c)(10)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVI, § 1603(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(34)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2273a.</num>
<heading> Space Rapid Capabilities Office</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is within the Space Force a program office known as the Space Rapid Capabilities Office (in this section referred to as the “Office”). The facilities of the Office may not be co-located with the headquarters facilities of the Air Force Space and Missile Systems Center.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Head of Office</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of the Office shall be the designee of the Secretary of the Air Force. The head of the Office shall report to the Chief of Space Operations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mission</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The mission of the Office shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to contribute to the development of low-cost, rapid reaction payloads, busses, launch, and launch control capabilities in order to fulfill joint military operational requirements for on-demand space support and reconstitution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to coordinate and execute space rapid capabilities efforts across the Department of Defense with respect to planning, acquisition, and operations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to rapidly develop and field new classified space capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The acquisition activities of the Office shall be subject to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force shall designate the acquisition executive of the Office who shall provide streamlined acquisition authorities for projects of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Joint Capabilities Integration and Development System process shall not apply to acquisitions by the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Program Element</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Air Force shall ensure, within budget program elements for space programs, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there are separate, dedicated unclassified and classified program elements for space rapid capabilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Office executes the responsibilities of the Office through such program elements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Office shall manage the program elements required by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force shall establish for the Office a Board of Directors (to be known as the “Space Rapid Capabilities Board of Directors”) to provide coordination, oversight, and approval of projects of the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IX, § 913(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2028</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title IX, § 913(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2355</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title IX, § 914</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1876</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVI, § 1601(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1720</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVI, § 1602</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2104</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 958(a)(2)</ref>, title XVI, § 1601(b)(2), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1567</ref>, 1722; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(31)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3825</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2274.</num>
<heading> Space situational awareness services and information: provision to non-United States Government entities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided by paragraph (2), the Secretary of Defense may provide space situational awareness services and information to, and may obtain space situational awareness data and information from, non-United States Government entities in accordance with this section. Any such action may be taken only if the Secretary determines that such action is consistent with the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Beginning <date date="2024-01-01">January 1, 2024</date>, the Secretary may provide space situational awareness services and information to, and may obtain space situational awareness data and information from, non-United States Government entities under paragraph (1) only to the extent that the Secretary determines such actions are necessary to meet the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Entities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may provide services and information under subsection (a) to, and may obtain data and information under subsection (a) from, any non-United States Government entity, including any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A political subdivision of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A United States commercial entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The government of a foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A foreign commercial entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may not provide space situational awareness services and information under subsection (a) to a non-United States Government entity unless that entity enters into an agreement with the Secretary under which the entity—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> agrees to pay an amount that may be charged by the Secretary under subsection (d);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> agrees not to transfer any data or technical information received under the agreement, including the analysis of data, to any other entity without the express approval of the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> agrees to any other terms and conditions considered necessary by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Charges</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As a condition of an agreement under subsection (c), the Secretary may (except as provided in paragraph (2)) require the non-United States Government entity entering into the agreement to pay to the Department of Defense such amounts as the Secretary determines appropriate to reimburse the Department for the costs to the Department of providing space situational awareness services or information under the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not require the government of a State, or of a political subdivision of a State, to pay any amount under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crediting of Funds Received</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Funds received for the provision of space situational awareness services or information pursuant to an agreement under this section shall be credited, at the election of the Secretary, to the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The appropriation, fund, or account used in incurring the obligation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An appropriate appropriation, fund, or account currently available for the purposes for which the expenditures were made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds credited under paragraph (1) shall be merged with, and remain available for obligation with, the funds in the appropriation, fund, or account to which credited.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish procedures by which the authority under this section shall be carried out. As part of those procedures, the Secretary may allow space situational awareness services or information to be provided through a contractor of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Immunity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States, any agencies and instrumentalities thereof, and any individuals, firms, corporations, and other persons acting for the United States, shall be immune from any suit in any court for any cause of action arising from the provision or receipt of space situational awareness services or information, whether or not provided in accordance with this section, or any related action or omission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Concerns of Disclosure of Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary determines that a commercial or foreign entity has declined or is reluctant to provide data or information to the Secretary in accordance with this section due to the concerns of such entity about the potential disclosure of such data or information, the Secretary shall, not later than 60 days after the Secretary makes that determination, provide notice to the congressional defense committees of the declination or reluctance of such entity.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 913(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1565</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title IX, § 912</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2355</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 911, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4571</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title IX, § 912(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVI, § 1604(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2275.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1603(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2160</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2275a.</num>
<heading> Requirements for protection of satellites</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before a major satellite acquisition program achieves Milestone A approval, or equivalent, the Chief of Staff of the Space Force, in consultation with the Commander of the United States Space Command, shall establish requirements for the defense and resilience of the satellites under that program against the capabilities of adversaries to target, degrade, or destroy the satellites.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “major satellite acquisition program” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2275 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Milestone A approval” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 4251 of this title</ref> 10.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XVI, § 1601</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2275b.</num>
<heading> Requirements for appropriate classification guidance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before a space major defense acquisition program achieves Milestone B approval, or equivalent, the milestone decision authority shall determine whether the classification guidance for the program remains appropriate and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if such guidance is determined to be appropriate, submit to the congressional defense committees a certification of such determination; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if such guidance is determined to be inappropriate, initiate an update to such guidance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Milestone B approval” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 4172(e)(7) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “major defense acquisition program” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 4201 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “space major defense acquisition program” means a major defense acquisition program for the acquisition of a satellite, ground system, or command and control system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVI, § 1602</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 584</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(27)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2275c.</num>
<heading> Space Force satellite ground systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Assistant Secretary of the Air Force for Space Acquisitions and Integration, acting as the service acquisition executive for the Air Force for space systems and programs, may not authorize a launch associated with a Space Force satellite acquisition program unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the associated ground systems and modifications are completed and ready for operation at the time of the launch; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the applicable satellite capabilities may be used on completion of the launch.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force may waive the requirement under subsection (a) if the Secretary determines that such waiver is necessary for reasons of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than 10 days after making a waiver under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees of such waiver.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1603(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2160</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2276.</num>
<heading> Commercial space launch cooperation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may take such actions as the Secretary considers to be in the best interest of the Federal Government to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maximize the use of the capacity of the space transportation infrastructure of the Department of Defense by the private sector in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> maximize the effectiveness and efficiency of the space transportation infrastructure of the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> reduce the cost of services provided by the Department of Defense related to space transportation infrastructure at launch support facilities and space recovery support facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> encourage commercial space activities by enabling investment by covered entities in the space transportation infrastructure of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> foster cooperation between the Department of Defense and covered entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority for Contracts and Other Agreements Relating to Space Transportation Infrastructure</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may enter into an agreement with a covered entity to provide the covered entity with support and services related to the space transportation infrastructure of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> upon the request of such covered entity, may include such support and services in the space launch and reentry range support requirements of the Department of Defense if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary determines that the inclusion of such support and services in such requirements—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is in the best interest of the Federal Government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> does not interfere with the requirements of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> does not compete with the commercial space activities of other covered entities, unless that competition is in the national security interests of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any commercial requirement included in the agreement has full non-Federal funding before the execution of the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may enter into an agreement with a covered entity on a cooperative and voluntary basis to accept contributions of funds, services, and equipment to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any funds, services, or equipment accepted by the Secretary under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may be used only for the objectives specified in this section in accordance with terms of use set forth in the agreement entered into under this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be managed by the Secretary in accordance with regulations of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements with respect to agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An agreement entered into with a covered entity under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall address the terms of use, ownership, and disposition of the funds, services, or equipment contributed pursuant to the agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall include a provision that the covered entity will not recover the costs of its contribution through any other agreement with the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Defense Cooperation Space Launch Account.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a special account to be known as the “Defense Cooperation Space Launch Account”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Crediting of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds received by the Secretary of Defense under subsection (c) shall be credited to the Defense Cooperation Space Launch Account.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds deposited in the Defense Cooperation Space Launch Account under paragraph (2) are authorized to be appropriated and shall be available for obligation only to the extent provided in advance in an appropriation Act for costs incurred by the Department of Defense in carrying out subsection (b). Funds in the Account shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(e)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 813(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1851</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered entity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “covered entity” means a non-Federal entity that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is engaged in commercial space activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Launch support facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “launch support facilities” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 50501(7) of title 51</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Space recovery support facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “space recovery support facilities” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 50501(11) of title 51</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Space transportation infrastructure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “space transportation infrastructure” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 50501(12) of title 51</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title IX, § 912(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1872</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 813(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2276a.</num>
<heading> Special authority for provision of space launch support services to increase space launch capacity</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may support Federal and commercial space launch capacity on any domestic real property under the control of the Secretary through the provision of space launch support services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Provision of Launch Equipment and Services to Commercial Entities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract or other transaction authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may enter into a contract or other transaction with one or more commercial entities that intend to conduct space launch activities on a military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary. Under such a contract or agreement, the Secretary may agree to provide to the commercial entity supplies, services, equipment, and construction needed for commercial space launch.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Costs.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Direct costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of a military department enters into a contract or other transaction with a commercial entity under paragraph (1), such contract or transaction shall include a provision that requires the commercial entity to reimburse the Department of Defense for all direct costs to the United States that are associated with any good, service, or equipment provided to the commercial entity under the contract or other transaction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Indirect costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of a military department enters into a contract or other transaction with a commercial entity under paragraph (1), such contract or transaction may include a provision that requires the commercial entity to reimburse the Department of Defense for such indirect costs as the Secretary considers to be appropriate. In such a case, such contract or other transaction may provide for the reimbursement of such indirect costs through the establishment of a rate, fixed price, or similar mechanism the Secretary concerned determines is reasonable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention of funds collected from commercial users</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any amount collected from a commercial entity as a reimbursement under paragraph (2) shall be credited to the appropriations account from which the cost for which such reimbursement is provided was derived.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each of the military departments shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Space launch</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “space launch” includes all activities, supplies, equipment, facilities, or services supporting launch preparation, launch, reentry, recovery, and other launch-related activities for both the payload and the space transportation vehicle.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commercial entity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “commercial entity” or “commercial” means a non-Federal entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transition Limitations and Reporting Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each of fiscal years 2024, 2025, and 2026, the Secretary of a military department shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> with respect to any contract or other transaction authority entered into pursuant to subsection (b), limit the amount of the indirect costs that are reimbursable under paragraph (2)(B) of such subsection to not more than 30 percent, not to exceed $5,000,000 annually (based on fiscal year 2024 constant dollars), of the total amount of the direct costs reimbursable under paragraph (2)(A) of such subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 90 days after the last day of each such fiscal year, provide for each of the congressional defense committees a briefing that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an identification of the total amounts of direct and indirect costs reimbursed to each spaceport for the fiscal year covered by the report;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the support provided by reimbursed indirect costs for the fiscal year covered by the report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an identification of the rate, fixed price, or similar mechanism, if any, used to calculate the amount of the indirect costs that are reimbursable for the fiscal year following the fiscal year covered by the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVI, § 1603</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2277.</num>
<heading> Disclosure of National Security Space Launch program contract pricing terms</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to any contract awarded by the Secretary of the Air Force for the launch of a national security payload under the National Security Space Launch program, not later than 30 days after entering into such a contract, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a description of the pricing terms of the contract. For those contracts that include the launch of assets of the National Reconnaissance Office, the Secretary shall also submit the pricing terms to the congressional intelligence committees (as defined by section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>)).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competitively Sensitive Trade Secret Data</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The congressional defense committees and the congressional intelligence committees shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> treat a description of pricing terms submitted under subsection (a) as competitively sensitive trade secret data; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use the description solely for committee purposes, subject to appropriate restrictions to maintain the confidentiality of the description.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of <ref>section 1905 of title 18</ref>, a disclosure of contract pricing terms under subsection (a) shall be construed as a disclosure authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVI, § 1601(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2073</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2278.</num>
<heading> Notification of foreign interference of national security space</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice Required</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided by paragraph (2), the Commander of the United States Space Command shall, with respect to each intentional attempt by a foreign actor to disrupt, degrade, or destroy a United States critical national security space capability, provide to the appropriate congressional committees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not later than 48 hours after the Commander determines that there is reason to believe such attempt occurred, notice of such attempt; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not later than 10 days after the date on which the Commander determines that there is reason to believe such attempt occurred, a notification described in subsection (b) with respect to such attempt.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to intentional attempts by a foreign actor to disrupt, degrade, or destroy a United States critical national security space capability that are continuous or repetitive in nature, the Commander shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide the notice and notification regarding the first attempt by such foreign actor in accordance with paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> during the period in which such foreign actor continues or repeats such attempts, provide to the appropriate congressional committees a consolidated monthly notice and notification of such attempts by not later than the tenth day of each month following the month in which the first notice under paragraph (1) was provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification Description</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A notification described in this subsection is a written notification that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name and a brief description of the national security space capability that was impacted by an attempt by a foreign actor to disrupt, degrade, or destroy a United States national security space capability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of such attempt, including the foreign actor, the date and time of such attempt, and any related capability outage and the mission impact of such outage; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other information the Commander considers relevant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The congressional defense committees.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> With respect to a notice or notification relating to an attempt by a foreign actor to disrupt, degrade, or destroy a capability that is intelligence-related, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “United States critical national security space capability” means a national security space capability of the United States provided by an asset on the critical asset list established by the Commander of the United States Space Command pursuant to Department of Defense Directive 3020.40, Department of Defense Instruction 3020.45, Joint Publication 3-01 of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, or such other relevant requirements of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 823</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVI, § 1604(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4044</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1604</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2160</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2279.</num>
<heading> Foreign commercial satellite services and foreign launches</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense may not enter into a contract for satellite services with a foreign entity if the Secretary reasonably believes that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the foreign entity is an entity in which the government of a covered foreign country has an ownership interest that enables that government to affect satellite operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the foreign entity plans to or is expected to provide satellite services under the contract from a covered foreign country; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> entering into such contract would create an unacceptable cybersecurity risk for the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Launches and Manufacturers.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the prohibition in subsection (a), and except as provided in paragraph (2) and in subsection (c), the Secretary may not enter into a contract for satellite services with any entity if the Secretary reasonably believes that such satellite services will be provided using satellites that will be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> designed or manufactured in a covered foreign country, or by an entity controlled in whole or in part by, or acting on behalf of, the government of a covered foreign country; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> launched using a launch vehicle that is designed or manufactured in a covered foreign country, or that is provided by the government of a covered foreign country or by an entity controlled in whole or in part by, or acting on behalf of, the government of a covered foreign country, regardless of the location of the launch (unless such location is in the United States).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The limitation in paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a launch that occurs prior to <date date="2022-12-31">December 31, 2022</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a contract or other agreement relating to launch services that, prior to the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, was either fully paid for by the contractor or covered by a legally binding commitment of the contractor to pay for such services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Launch vehicle defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “launch vehicle” means a fully integrated space launch vehicle.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The prohibitions in subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to a contract if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines it is in the national security of the United States to enter into such contract; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 7 days before entering into such contract, the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, submits to the congressional defense committees a national security assessment for such contract that includes the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The projected period of performance (including any period covered by options to extend the contract), the financial terms, and a description of the services to be provided under the contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To the extent practicable, a description of the ownership interest that a covered foreign country has in the foreign entity providing satellite services to the Department of Defense under the contract and the launch or other satellite services that will be provided in a covered foreign country under the contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A justification for entering into a contract with such foreign entity and a description of the actions necessary to eliminate the need to enter into such a contract with such foreign entity in the future.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A risk assessment of entering into a contract with such foreign entity, including an assessment of mission assurance and security of information and a description of any measures necessary to mitigate risks found by such risk assessment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation of Notice and Exception Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may only delegate the authority under subsection (c) to enter into a contract subject to the prohibition under subsection (a) or (b) to the Deputy Secretary of Defense, the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy, or the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment and such authority may not be further delegated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form of Assessments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each assessment under subsection (c) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered foreign country” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A country described in section 1261(c)(2) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<ref>Public Law 112–239</ref>; <ref>126 Stat. 2019</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Russian Federation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “cybersecurity risk” means threats to and vulnerabilities of information or information systems and any related consequences caused by or resulting from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, degradation, disruption, modification, or destruction of such information or information systems, including such related consequences caused by an act of terrorism.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XVI, § 1602(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 941</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVI, § 1603(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1722</ref>, 1723; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1984</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(30)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1546</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2279a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVI, § 1601(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1719</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2279b.</num>
<heading> Council on Oversight of the Department of Defense Positioning, Navigation, and Timing Enterprise</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is within the Department of Defense a council to be known as the “Council on Oversight of the Department of Defense Positioning, Navigation, and Timing Enterprise” (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The members of the Council shall be as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Commander of the United States Strategic Command.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Commander of the United States Northern Command.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Commander of the United States Space Command.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The Commander of United States Cyber Command.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Security Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The Secretaries of the military departments, who shall be ex officio members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Such other officers of the Department of Defense as the Secretary may designate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Co-chair</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall be co-chaired by the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, and the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Council shall be responsible for oversight of the Department of Defense positioning, navigation, and timing enterprise, including positioning, navigation, and timing services provided to civil, commercial, scientific, and international users.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out the responsibility for oversight of the Department of Defense positioning, navigation, and timing enterprise as specified in paragraph (1), the Council shall be responsible for the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Oversight of performance assessments (including interoperability).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Vulnerability identification and mitigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Architecture development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Alternative methods to perform position navigation and timing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Resource prioritization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Such other responsibilities as the Secretary of Defense shall specify for purposes of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At the same time each year that the budget of the President is submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, the Council shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the activities of the Council. Each report shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A description and assessment of the activities of the Council during the previous fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of the activities proposed to be undertaken by the Council during the period covered by the current future-years defense program under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any changes to the requirements of the Department of Defense positioning, navigation, and timing enterprise made during the previous year, along with an explanation for why the changes were made and a description of the effects of the changes to the capability of such enterprise.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A breakdown of each program element in such budget that relates to the Department of Defense positioning, navigation, and timing enterprise, including how such program element relates to the operation and sustainment, research and development, procurement, or other activity of such enterprise.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget and Funding Matters</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 30 days after the President submits to Congress the budget for a fiscal year under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, the Commander of the United States Space Command shall submit to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff an assessment of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whether such budget allows the Federal Government to meet the required capabilities of the Department of Defense positioning, navigation, and timing enterprise during the fiscal year covered by the budget and the four subsequent fiscal years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the Commander determines that such budget does not allow the Federal Government to meet such required capabilities, a description of the steps being taken to meet such required capabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff receives the assessment of the Commander of the United States Space Command under paragraph (1), the Chairman shall submit to the congressional defense committees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such assessment as it was submitted to the Chairman; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any comments of the Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If a House of Congress adopts a bill authorizing or appropriating funds for the activities of the Department of Defense positioning, navigation, and timing enterprise that, as determined by the Council, provides insufficient funds for such activities for the period covered by such bill, the Council shall notify the congressional defense committees of the determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of Anomalies</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees written notification of an anomaly in the Department of Defense positioning, navigation, and timing enterprise that is reported to the Secretary or the Council by not later than 14 days after the date on which the Secretary or the Council learns of such anomaly, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “anomaly” means any unplanned, irregular, or abnormal event, whether unexplained or caused intentionally or unintentionally by a person or a system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1603(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1096</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(31)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1546</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVI, § 1604(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(27)</ref>, title XVI, § 1604, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1921</ref>, 2077.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2279c.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 9081]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2279d.</num>
<heading> Limitation on construction on United States territory of satellite positioning ground monitoring stations of certain foreign governments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Certification.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may not authorize or permit the construction of a global navigation satellite system ground monitoring station directly or indirectly controlled by a foreign government (including a ground monitoring station owned, operated, or controlled on behalf of a foreign government) in the territory of the United States unless the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence jointly certify to the appropriate congressional committees that such ground monitoring station will not possess the capability or potential to be used for the purpose of gathering intelligence in the United States or improving any foreign weapon system.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each certification under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National security waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence may jointly waive the certification requirement in paragraph (1) for a ground monitoring station if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary and the Director jointly determine that the waiver is in the vital interests of the national security of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary and the Director ensure that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all data collected or transmitted from ground monitoring stations covered by the waiver are not encrypted;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all persons involved in the construction, operation, and maintenance of such ground monitoring stations are United States persons;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> such ground monitoring stations are not located in geographic proximity to sensitive United States national security sites;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the United States approves all equipment to be located at such ground monitoring stations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> appropriate actions are taken to ensure that any such ground monitoring stations do not pose a cyber espionage or other threat, including intelligence or counterintelligence, to the national security of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> any improvements to such ground monitoring stations do not reduce or compete with the advantages of Global Positioning System technology for users.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each waiver under paragraph (2), the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall jointly submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the reason why it is not possible to provide the certification under paragraph (1) for the ground monitoring stations covered by such waiver;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment of the impact of the exercise of authority under paragraph (2) with respect to such ground monitoring stations on the national security of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of the means to be used to mitigate any such impact to the United States for the duration that such ground monitoring stations are operated in the territory of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other information in connection with the waiver that the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of State, consider appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days before the exercise of the authority to waive under paragraph (2) the certification requirement under paragraph (1) for a ground monitoring station, the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence shall jointly provide to the appropriate congressional committees notice of the exercise of such authority and the report required under paragraph (3) with respect to such ground monitoring station.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The limitation in subsection (a) shall not apply to foreign governments that are allies of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The limitation in subsection (a) shall terminate on <date date="2023-12-31">December 31, 2023</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVI, § 1602</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1721</ref>, § 2279c; renumbered § 2279d, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(18)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1984</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(35)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>