<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1205—</num>
<heading>APPOINTMENT OF RESERVE OFFICERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12201.</num>
<heading> Reserve officers: qualifications for appointment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To become an officer of a reserve component a person must be appointed as a Reserve of an armed force in a grade corresponding to a grade authorized for the regular component of the armed force concerned and, except as provided in paragraph (2), subscribe to the oath prescribed by <ref>section 3331 of title 5</ref>. In addition, to become an officer of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States, he must first be appointed to, and be federally recognized in, the same grade in the Army National Guard or the Air National Guard, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If an officer is transferred from the active-duty list of an armed force to a reserve active-status list of an armed force in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the officer is not required to subscribe to the oath referred to in paragraph (1) in order to qualify for an appointment under that paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Except as otherwise provided by law, the Secretary concerned shall prescribe physical, mental, moral, professional, and age qualifications for the appointment of persons as Reserves of the armed forces under his jurisdiction. However, no person may be appointed as a Reserve unless he is at least 18 years of age and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> he is a citizen of the United States or has been lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> he has previously served in the armed forces or in the National Security Training Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A person who is otherwise qualified, but who has a physical defect that the Secretary concerned determines will not interfere with the performance of the duties to which that person may be assigned, may be appointed as a Reserve of any armed force under the jurisdiction of that Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In prescribing age qualifications under subsection (b) for the appointment of persons as Reserves of the armed forces under his jurisdiction, the Secretary concerned may not prescribe a maximum age qualification of less than 47 years of age for the initial appointment of a person as a Reserve to serve in a health profession specialty which has been designated by the Secretary concerned as a specialty critically needed in wartime.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 24</ref>, § 591; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(10)(A)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–236</ref>, <date date="1963-12-23">Dec. 23, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–130, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1967-11-08">Nov. 8, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 374</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V</ref> § 511(16), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2921</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VII, § 718(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1115</ref>; renumbered § 12201 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1631(b), 1662(c)(2), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2964</ref>, 2990; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(a)(5)(B)</ref>, (b)(11)(A), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 495</ref>, 496; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 501(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 515</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12202.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officer grades</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except for commissioned warrant officers, the reserve commissioned officer grades in each armed force are those authorized for regular commissioned officers of that armed force.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(10)(B)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1440</ref>, § 592; renumbered § 12202, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12203.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers: appointment, how made; term</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Appointments of reserve officers in commissioned grades of lieutenant colonel and commander or below, except commissioned warrant officer, shall be made by the President alone. Appointments of reserve officers in commissioned grades above lieutenant colonel and commander shall be made by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, except as provided in section 624, 12213, or 12214 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the President, the Secretary of Defense may appoint as a reserve commissioned officer any regular officer transferred from the active-duty list of an armed force to the reserve active-status list of a reserve component under <ref>section 647 of this title</ref>, notwithstanding the requirements of subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Appointments of Reserves in commissioned grades are for an indefinite term and are held during the pleasure of the President.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 25</ref>, § 593; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(10)(C)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–129, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1971-09-28">Sept. 28, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 361</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 501(7)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2907</ref>; renumbered § 12203 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1632, 1662(c)(2), 1675(b)(1), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2965</ref>, 2990, 3017; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 495</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 501(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(54)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4372</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1343</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12204.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers: original appointment; limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> No person may be appointed as a Reserve in a commissioned grade above major or lieutenant commander, unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> he was formerly a commissioned officer of an armed force; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such an appointment is recommended by a board of officers convened by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to adjutants general and assistant adjutants general of the several States, Puerto Rico, and the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 25</ref>, § 594; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; renumbered § 12204, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3440</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12205.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers: appointment; educational requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person may be appointed to a grade above the grade of first lieutenant in the Army Reserve, Air Force Reserve, or Marine Corps Reserve or to a grade above the grade of lieutenant (junior grade) in the Navy Reserve, or be federally recognized in a grade above the grade of first lieutenant as a member of the Army National Guard or Air National Guard, unless that person has been awarded a baccalaureate degree by a qualifying educational institution.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) does not apply to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The appointment to or recognition in a higher grade of a person who is appointed in or assigned for service in a health profession for which a baccalaureate degree is not a condition of original appointment or assignment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The appointment in the Navy Reserve or Marine Corps Reserve of a person appointed for service as an officer designated as a limited duty officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The appointment in the Navy Reserve of a person appointed for service under the Naval Aviation Cadet (NAVCAD) program or the Seaman to Admiral program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The appointment to or recognition in a higher grade of any person who was appointed to, or federally recognized in, the grade of captain or, in the case of the Navy, lieutenant before <date date="1995-10-01">October 1, 1995</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Recognition in the grade of captain or major in the Alaska Army National Guard of a person who resides permanently at a location in Alaska that is more than 50 miles from each of the cities of Anchorage, Fairbanks, and Juneau, Alaska, by paved road and who is serving in a Scout unit or a Scout supporting unit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifying Educational Institutions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A qualifying educational institution for purposes of this section is an educational institution that is accredited or that meets the requirements of paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An unaccredited educational institution shall be considered to be a qualifying educational institution for purposes of the appointment or recognition of a person who is a graduate of that institution if the Secretary concerned determines that (as of the year of the graduation of that person from that institution) at least three educational institutions that are accredited and that maintain Reserve Officers’ Training Corps programs each generally grant baccalaureate degree credit for completion of courses of the unaccredited institution equivalent to the baccalaureate degree credit granted by the unaccredited institution for the completion of those courses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In order to assist the Secretary concerned in making determinations under subparagraph (A), any unaccredited institution that seeks to be considered to be a qualifying educational institution for purposes of this paragraph shall submit to the Secretary of Defense each year such information as the Secretary may require concerning the program of instruction at that institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In the case of a person with a degree from an unaccredited institution that is a qualifying educational institution under this paragraph, the degree may not have been awarded more than eight years before the date on which the person is to be appointed to, or recognized in, the grade of captain or, in the case of the Navy Reserve, lieutenant, in order for that person to be considered for purposes of subsection (a) to have been awarded a baccalaureate degree by a qualifying educational institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority for Army OCS Graduates and Certain Marine Corps Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army may waive the applicability of subsection (a) to any officer whose original appointment in the Army as a Reserve officer is through the Army Officer Candidate School program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Navy may waive the applicability of subsection (a) to any officer whose original appointment in the Marine Corps as a Reserve officer is through the Marine Corps meritorious commissioning program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any such waiver shall be made on a case-by-case basis, considering the individual circumstances of the officer involved, and may continue in effect for no more than two years after the waiver is granted. The Secretary concerned may provide for such a waiver to be effective before the date of the waiver, as appropriate in an individual case.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title V, § 515(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2406</ref>, § 596; renumbered § 12205 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 519, 520, title XVI, § 1662(c)(2), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2755</ref>, 2990; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 504, 505, title X, § 1074(a)(22), <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2512</ref>, 2660; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 512(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1092</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(KK)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12206.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers: appointment of former commissioned officers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, a person who is a former commissioned officer may, if otherwise qualified, be appointed as a reserve officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps. A person so appointed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may be placed on the reserve active-status list of that armed force in the grade equivalent to the permanent regular or reserve grade, and in the same competitive category, in which the person previously served satisfactorily on active duty or in an active status; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may be credited for the purpose of determining date of rank under <ref>section 741(d) of this title</ref> with service in grade equal to that held by that person when discharged or separated.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added § 596a and renumbered § 12206, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1633, 1662(c)(2), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2965</ref>, 2990.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12207.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers: service credit upon original appointment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purpose of determining the grade and the rank within grade of a person receiving an original appointment as a reserve commissioned officer (other than a commissioned warrant officer) in the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps, the person shall be credited at the time of the appointment with any commissioned service (other than service as a commissioned warrant officer) performed before such appointment as a regular officer, or as a reserve officer in an active status, in any armed force, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or the Public Health Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations, which shall apply uniformly among the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps, to authorize the Secretary of the military department concerned to limit the amount of prior commissioned service with which a person receiving an original appointment may be credited under paragraph (1), or to deny any such credit, in the case of a person who at the time of such appointment is credited with constructive service under subsection (b) or (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, a person who is receiving an original appointment as a reserve commissioned officer (other than a commissioned warrant officer) of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps, and who has special training or experience, or advanced education (if applicable), shall be credited with constructive service for such education, training, or experience, as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> One year for each year of advanced education beyond the baccalaureate degree level, for persons appointed or designated in, or assigned to, officer categories requiring such advanced education or an advanced degree as a prerequisite for such appointment, designation, or assignment. In determining the number of years of constructive service to be credited under this subparagraph to officers in any professional field, the Secretary concerned shall credit an officer with, but with not more than, the number of years of advanced education required by a majority of institutions that award degrees in that professional field for completion of the advanced education or award of the advanced degree.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Credit for any period of advanced education in a health profession (other than medicine and dentistry) beyond the baccalaureate degree level which exceeds the basic education criteria for such appointment, designation, or assignment, if such advanced education will be directly used by the armed force concerned.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Credit for experience in a health profession (other than medicine or dentistry), if such experience will be directly used by the armed force concerned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Additional credit of (i) not more than one year for internship or equivalent graduate medical, dental, or other formal health professional training required by the armed forces, and (ii) not more than one year for each additional year of such graduate-level training or experience creditable toward certification in a speciality required by the armed force concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Additional credit as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> For special training or experience in a particular officer field as designated by the Secretary concerned, if such training or experience is directly related to the operational needs of the armed force concerned.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> During fiscal years 2021 through 2025, for advanced education in an officer field so designated, if such education is directly related to the operational needs of the armed force concerned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Additional credit for experience as a physician or dentist, if appointed, assigned, or designated as a medical or dental officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of Defense determines that the number of officers in a health profession described in subparagraph (B) who are serving in an active status in a reserve component of the Army, Navy, or Air Force in grades below major or lieutenant commander is critically below the number needed in such health profession by such reserve component in such grades, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary of the military department concerned to credit any person who is receiving an original appointment as an officer for service in such health profession with a period of constructive credit in such amount (in addition to any amount credited such person under paragraph (1)) as will result in the grade of such person being that of captain or, in the case of the Navy Reserve, lieutenant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The types of health professions referred to in subparagraph (A) include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Any health profession performed by officers in the Medical Corps of the Army or the Navy or by officers of the Air Force designated as a medical officer.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Any health profession performed by officers in the Dental Corps of the Army or the Navy or by officers of the Air Force designated as a dental officer.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Any health profession performed by officers in the Medical Service Corps of the Army or the Navy or by officers of the Air Force designated as a medical service officer or biomedical sciences officer.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Any health profession performed by officers in the Army Medical Specialist Corps.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Any health profession performed by officers of the Nurse Corps of the Army or the Navy or by officers of the Air Force designated as a nurse.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Any health profession performed by officers in the Veterinary Corps of the Army or by officers designated as a veterinary officer.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The amount of constructive service credit credited to an officer under this subsection may not exceed the amount required in order for the officer to be eligible for an original appointment as a reserve officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps in the grade of colonel or as a reserve officer of the Navy in the grade of captain.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Constructive service credited an officer under this subsection is in addition to any service credited that officer under subsection (a) and shall be credited at the time of the original appointment of the officer or assignment to or designation in an officer category in which advanced education or training or special experience is required.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Constructive service may not be credited under subsection (b) for education, training, or experience obtained while serving as a commissioned officer (other than a warrant officer) on active duty or in an active status. However, in the case of an officer who completes advanced education or receives an advanced degree while on active duty or in an active status and in less than the number of years normally required to complete such advanced education or receive such advanced degree, constructive service may, subject to regulations prescribed under subsection (a)(2), be credited to the officer under subsection (b)(1)(A) to the extent that the number of years normally required to complete such advanced education or receive such advanced degree exceeds the actual number of years in which such advanced education or degree is obtained by the officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of Defense determines that the number of qualified judge advocates serving on the active-duty list of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps in grades below lieutenant commander or major is critically below the number needed by that armed force in those grades, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary of the military department concerned to credit any person who is receiving an original appointment with a view to assignment to the Judge Advocate General’s Corps of the Army or appointment to the Judge Advocate General’s Corps of the Navy, or who is receiving an original appointment in the Air Force or Marine Corps with a view to designation as a judge advocate, with a period of constructive service in such an amount (in addition to any amount credited such person under subsection (b)) as will result in the grade of such person being that of captain or, in the case of the Navy, lieutenant, and the date of rank of such person being junior to that of all other officers of the same grade serving on the active-duty list.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> Constructive service credited an officer under subsection (b) or (d) shall be used only for determining the officer’s—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> initial grade as a reserve officer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> rank in grade; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> service in grade for promotion eligibility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The grade and position on the reserve active-status list of a person receiving an appointment as a reserve officer who at the time of appointment is credited with service under this section shall be determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense based upon the amount of service credited.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added § 596b and renumbered § 12207, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1634, 1662(c)(2), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2965</ref>, 2990; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(LL)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 98</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 512(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1376</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1739</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3564</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12208.</num>
<heading> Officers: appointment upon transfer</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A person who would otherwise be required to be transferred to a reserve component under <ref>section 651 of this title</ref> or under the Military Selective Service Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.), is entitled, if he is qualified and accepted, to be appointed as an officer of any armed force that he chooses and to participate in the programs authorized for that armed force. However, unless the two Secretaries concerned consent, he may not be appointed as a Reserve of an armed force other than that from which he is transferred. All periods of his participation shall be credited against the total period of service required of him under <ref>section 651 of this title</ref> or under the Military Selective Service Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.). However, no period may be credited more than once.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A person covered by subsection (a) shall perform the rest of his required term of service in the armed force in which he is so appointed or in any other armed force in which he is later appointed or enlisted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section does not change any term of service under an appointment, enlistment, or agreement, including an agreement made before or at the time when the member entered upon a program authorized by an armed force.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 25</ref>, § 595; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(17)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2921</ref>; renumbered § 12208, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1081(b)(1)(A)(ix)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12209.</num>
<heading> Officer candidates: enlisted Reserves</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Within such numbers as the Secretary concerned may prescribe, enlisted Reserves may, with their consent, be selected for training as officer candidates. Enlisted Reserves so selected shall be designated as officer candidates during that training. However, no member of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States may be so selected or designated unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> he is on active duty; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the governor or other appropriate authority of the jurisdiction concerned consents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The enlistment or term of service of a Reserve who is designated as an officer candidate under this section is extended to include any period, beyond its normal expiration date, during which he is an officer candidate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> While he is on active duty, other than active duty for training without pay, or performing authorized travel to and from that duty, an officer candidate designated under this section is entitled to the pay and allowances of his enlisted grade, but not less than those prescribed for pay grade E–2.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> An officer candidate designated under this section may not participate in the program of a reserve officer training corps of any armed force.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 26</ref>, § 600; renumbered § 12209, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(12)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 496</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12210.</num>
<heading> Attending Physician to the Congress: reserve grade</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">While serving as Attending Physician to the Congress, a Reserve holds the reserve grade of major general or rear admiral, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V, § 508(d)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3867</ref>, § 600a; renumbered § 12210, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2990</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(12)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 496</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(2)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12211.</num>
<heading> Officers: Army National Guard of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Upon being federally recognized, an officer of the Army National Guard shall be appointed as a Reserve for service as a member of the Army National Guard of the United States in the grade that he holds in the Army National Guard. However, an officer of the Army Reserve who is federally recognized as an officer of the Army National Guard becomes an officer of the Army National Guard of the United States and ceases to be an officer of the Army Reserve. The acceptance of an appointment as a Reserve for service as a member of the Army National Guard of the United States by an officer of the Army National Guard does not vacate his office in the Army National Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When an officer of the Army National Guard to whom temporary Federal recognition has been extended is appointed as a Reserve for service as a member of the Army National Guard of the United States, his appointment shall bear the date of the temporary recognition and shall be considered to have been accepted and effective on that date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> When the Army National Guard of the United States is ordered to active duty, any officer of the Army National Guard who is not a Reserve of the Army may be appointed by the President as a Reserve for service as a member of the Army National Guard of the United States in the grade that he holds in the Army National Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 193</ref>, § 3351; renumbered § 12211, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 496</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12212.</num>
<heading> Officers: Air National Guard of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Upon being federally recognized, an officer of the Air National Guard shall be appointed as a Reserve for service as a member of the Air National Guard of the United States in the grade that he holds in the Air National Guard. However, an officer of the Air Force Reserve who is federally recognized as an officer of the Air National Guard becomes an officer of the Air National Guard of the United States and ceases to be an officer of the Air Force Reserve. The acceptance of an appointment as a Reserve for service as a member of the Air National Guard of the United States by an officer of the Air National Guard does not vacate his office in the Air National Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When an officer of the Air National Guard to whom temporary Federal recognition has been extended is appointed as a Reserve for service as a member of the Air National Guard of the United States, his appointment shall bear the date of the temporary recognition and shall be considered to have been accepted and effective on that date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> When the Air National Guard of the United States is ordered to active duty, any officer of the Air National Guard who is not a Reserve of the Air Force may be appointed by the President as a Reserve for service as a member of the Air National Guard of the United States in the grade that he holds in the Air National Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 519</ref>, § 8351; renumbered § 12212, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 496</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12213.</num>
<heading> Officers; Army Reserve: transfer from Army National Guard of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary of the Army may prescribe, and with the consent of the governor or other appropriate authority of the State concerned, an officer of the Army National Guard of the United States may be transferred in grade to the Army Reserve.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Unless discharged from his appointment as a Reserve, an officer of the Army National Guard of the United States whose Federal recognition as a member of the Army National Guard is withdrawn becomes a member of the Army Reserve. An officer who so becomes a member of the Army Reserve ceases to be a member of the Army National Guard of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 194</ref>, § 3352; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(80)(A)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1468</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–559, § 1(7)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-30">June 30, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 265</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; renumbered § 12213 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1636(a), 1662(c)(3), 1675(b)(2), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2968</ref>, 2990, 3017; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(13)(A)</ref>, (14), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 496</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12214.</num>
<heading> Officers; Air Force Reserve: transfer from Air National Guard of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary of the Air Force may prescribe, and with the consent of the governor or other appropriate authority of the State concerned, an officer of the Air National Guard of the United States may be transferred in grade to the Air Force Reserve.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Unless discharged from his appointment as a Reserve, an officer of the Air National Guard of the United States whose Federal recognition as a member of the Air National Guard is withdrawn becomes a member of the Air Force Reserve. An officer who so becomes a member of the Air Force Reserve ceases to be a member of the Air National Guard of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 520</ref>, § 8352; <ref>Pub. L. 87–651, title I, § 126</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 514</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; renumbered § 12214 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(c)(3), 1675(b)(2), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2990</ref>, 3017; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 496</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12215.</num>
<heading> Commissioned officers: reserve grade of adjutants general and assistant adjutants general</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The adjutant general or an assistant adjutant general of the Army National Guard of a State may, upon being extended Federal recognition, be appointed as a reserve officer of the Army as of the date on which he is so recognized.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The adjutant general or an assistant adjutant general of the Air National Guard of a State may be appointed in the reserve commissioned grade in which Federal recognition in the Air National Guard is extended to him.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>