<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 382—</num>
<heading>POLICIES AND PLANNING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4811.</num>
<heading> National security strategy for national technology and industrial base</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Security Strategy for National Technology and Industrial Base</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall develop a national security strategy for the national technology and industrial base. The Secretary shall submit such strategy to Congress as an integrated part of the report submitted under <ref>section 4814 of this title</ref>. Such strategy shall be based on a prioritized assessment of risks and challenges to the defense supply chain and shall ensure that the national technology and industrial base is capable of achieving the following national security objectives:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Supplying, equipping, and supporting the force structure of the armed forces that is necessary to achieve—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the objectives set forth in the national security strategy report submitted to Congress by the President pursuant to section 108 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3043</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the policy guidance of the Secretary of Defense provided pursuant to <ref>section 113(g) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the future-years defense program submitted to Congress by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Sustaining production, maintenance, repair, logistics, and other activities in support of military operations of various durations and intensity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Maintaining advanced research and development activities to provide the armed forces with systems capable of ensuring technological superiority over potential adversaries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Reconstituting within a reasonable period the capability to develop, produce, and support supplies and equipment, including technologically advanced systems, in sufficient quantities to prepare fully for a war, national emergency, or mobilization of the armed forces before the commencement of that war, national emergency, or mobilization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Providing for the development, manufacture, and supply of items and technologies critical to the production and sustainment of advanced military weapon systems within the national technology and industrial base.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Providing for the generation of services capabilities that are not core functions of the armed forces and that are critical to military operations within the national technology and industrial base.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Providing for the development, production, and integration of information technology within the national technology and industrial base.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Maintaining critical design skills to ensure that the armed forces are provided with systems capable of ensuring technological superiority over potential adversaries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Ensuring reliable sources of services, supplies, and materials that are critical to national security, such as specialty metals, essential minerals, armor plate, and rare earth elements, including by reducing reliance on potential adversaries for such services, supplies, and materials to the maximum extent practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Reducing, to the maximum extent practicable, the presence of counterfeit parts in the supply chain and the risk associated with such parts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Providing for the provision of drugs, biological products, vaccines, and critical medical supplies required to enable combat readiness and protect the health of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil-Military Integration Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the United States attains the national technology and industrial base objectives set forth in subsection (a) through acquisition policy reforms that have the following objectives:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Relying, to the maximum extent practicable, upon the commercial national technology and industrial base that is required to meet the national security needs of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Reducing the reliance of the Department of Defense on technology and industrial base sectors that are economically dependent on Department of Defense business.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Reducing Federal Government barriers to the use of commercial products, processes, and standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Department of Defense Technology and Industrial Base Policy Guidance.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Departmental Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe departmental guidance for the attainment of each of the national security objectives set forth in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose of Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The guidance prescribed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall provide for technological and industrial capability considerations to be integrated into the strategy, management, budget allocation, acquisition, and logistics support decision processes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLII, § 4211</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2662</ref>, § 2501; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(c)(7)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 98</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1182(a)(10)</ref>, title XIII, § 1313, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1771</ref>, 1786; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 452</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 829(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2612</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–23, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 895(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVI, § 1603(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2062</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 882</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2316</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 846(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1503</ref>; renumbered § 4811 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VII, § 713(a)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1867(b), (c)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3692</ref>, 4281; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VIII, § 851</ref>, title X, § 1061(b), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 343</ref>, 398.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4812.</num>
<heading> National Defense Technology and Industrial Base Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a National Defense Technology and Industrial Base Council.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council is composed of the following members:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, who shall serve as chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Labor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other officials as may be determined by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall have the responsibility to ensure effective cooperation among departments and agencies of the Federal Government, and to provide advice and recommendations to the President, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Labor, concerning—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the capabilities of the national technology and industrial base to meet the national security objectives set forth in <ref>section 4811(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> programs for achieving such national security objectives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> changes in acquisition policy that strengthen the national technology and industrial base; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> collaboration with government officials of member countries of the national technology and industrial base in order to strengthen the national technology and industrial base.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternative Performance of Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (c), the President may assign the responsibilities of the Council to another interagency organization of the executive branch that includes among its members the officials specified in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLII, § 4212(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2664</ref>, § 2502; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1312(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1786</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1070(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2856</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1081(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 452</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 829(c)(2)</ref>, formerly § 829(c)(2), (3), <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2613</ref>, renumbered <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(c)(7)(B)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1904</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(c)(7)(A)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1904</ref>; renumbered § 4812 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 846(c)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1867(b), (d)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3768</ref>, 4281.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4813.</num>
<heading> National defense program for analysis of the technology and industrial base</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program for analysis of the national technology and industrial base.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supervision of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out the program through the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering and the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment. In carrying out the program, the Under Secretaries shall consult with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Labor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The functions of the program shall include, with respect to the national technology and industrial base, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The assembly of timely and authoritative information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Initiation of studies and analyses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Provision of technical support and assistance to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense for the preparation of the periodic assessments required by <ref>section 4816 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the defense acquisition university structure and its elements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other departments and agencies of the Federal Government in accordance with guidance established by the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Dissemination, through the National Technical Information Service of the Department of Commerce, of unclassified information and assessments for further dissemination within the Federal Government and to the private sector.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLII, § 4213(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2665</ref>, § 2503; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 829(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2612</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(74)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1552</ref>; renumbered § 4813 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1867(b)</ref>, (d)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4814.</num>
<heading> National technology and industrial base: biennial report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall transmit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives by March 1 of each odd-numbered year a report which shall include the following information:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A description of the departmental guidance prepared pursuant to <ref>section 4811(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of the assessments prepared pursuant to <ref>section 4816 of this title</ref> and other analyses used in developing the budget submission of the Department of Defense for the next fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Based on the strategy required by <ref>section 4811 of this title</ref> and on the assessments prepared pursuant to Executive order or <ref>section 4816 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a map of the industrial base;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a prioritized list of gaps or vulnerabilities in the national technology and industrial base (including vulnerabilities related to the current and projected impacts of extreme weather and to cyber attacks or disruptions), including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of mitigation strategies necessary to address such gaps or vulnerabilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the identification of the Secretary concerned or the head of the Defense Agency responsible for addressing such gaps or vulnerabilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a proposed timeline for action to address such gaps or vulnerabilities; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other steps necessary to foster and safeguard the national technology and industrial base.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Identification of each program designed to sustain specific essential technological and industrial capabilities and processes of the national technology and industrial base.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> A detailed description of any use by the Secretary of Defense or a Secretary concerned, as applicable, during the prior 12 months of a waiver or exception to the sourcing requirements or prohibitions established by chapter 83 of title 41 or chapter 385 of this title, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the type of waiver or exception used; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the reasoning for the use of each such waiver or exception.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 829(e)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2614</ref>, § 2504; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVI, § 1603(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 846(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1503</ref>; renumbered § 4814 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 842(a)</ref>, (b)(1), title XVIII, § 1867(b), (d)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3764</ref>, 3765, 4281; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 333</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(b)(22)(A), (d)(15), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1638</ref>, 2135, 2137; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1061(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 399</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4815.</num>
<heading> Unfunded priorities of the national technology and industrial base: annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 10 days after the date on which the budget of the President for a fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall submit to the Secretary of Defense, the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and the congressional defense committees a report on the unfunded priorities to address gaps or vulnerabilities in the national technology and industrial base.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Elements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report under subsection (a) shall specify, for each unfunded priority covered by such report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A summary description of such priority, including the objectives to be achieved if such priority is funded (whether in whole or in part).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The additional amount of funds recommended in connection with the objectives under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Account information with respect to such priority, including the following (as applicable):</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Line Item Number (LIN) for applicable procurement accounts.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Program Element (PE) number for applicable research, development, test, and evaluation accounts.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Sub-activity group (SAG) for applicable operation and maintenance accounts.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prioritization of priorities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each report shall present the unfunded priorities covered by such report in order of urgency of priority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unfunded Priority Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “unfunded priority”, in the case of a fiscal year, means a program, activity, or mission requirement of the national technology and industrial base that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is not funded in the budget of the President for the fiscal year as submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is necessary to address gaps or vulnerabilities in the national technology and industrial base; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> would have been recommended for funding through the budget referred to in paragraph (1) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> additional resources had been available for the budget to fund the program, activity, or mission requirement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the program, activity, or mission requirement had emerged before the budget was formulated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 846(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1504</ref>, § 2504a; renumbered § 4815, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1867(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4816.</num>
<heading> National technology and industrial base: periodic defense capability assessments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Periodic Assessment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall prepare selected assessments of the capability of the national technology and industrial base to attain the national security objectives set forth in <ref>section 4811(a) of this title</ref>. The Secretary of Defense shall prepare such assessments in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment Process</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that technology and industrial capability assessments—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describe sectors or capabilities, their underlying infrastructure and processes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> analyze present and projected financial performance of industries supporting the sectors or capabilities in the assessment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> determine the extent to which the requirements associated with defense acquisition programs can be satisfied by the present and projected performance capacities of industries supporting the sectors or capabilities in the assessment, evaluate the reasons for any variance from applicable preceding determinations, and identify the extent to which those industries are comprised of only one potential source in the national technology and industrial base or have multiple potential sources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> determine the extent to which the requirements associated with defense acquisition programs can be satisfied by the present and projected performance capacities of industries that do not actively support Department of Defense acquisition programs and identify the barriers to the participation of those industries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> identify technological and industrial capabilities and processes for which there is potential for the national industrial and technology base not to be able to support the achievement of national security objectives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> consider the effects of the termination of major defense acquisition programs (as the term is defined in <ref>section 4201 of this title</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002140">1</ref> in the previous fiscal year on the sectors and capabilities in the assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment of Extent of Dependency on Foreign Source Items</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each assessment under subsection (a) shall include a separate discussion and presentation regarding the extent to which the national technology and industrial base is dependent on items for which the source of supply, manufacture, or technology is outside of the United States and Canada and for which there is no immediately available source in the United States or Canada. The discussion and presentation regarding foreign dependency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify cases that pose an unacceptable risk of foreign dependency, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> present actions being taken or proposed to be taken to remedy the risk posed by the cases identified under paragraph (1), including efforts to develop a domestic source for the item in question.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment of Extent of Effects of Foreign Boycotts</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each assessment under subsection (a) shall include an examination of the extent to which the national technology and industrial base is affected by foreign boycotts. If it is determined that a foreign boycott (other than a boycott addressed in a previous assessment) is subjecting the national technology and industrial base to significant harm, the assessment shall include a separate discussion and presentation regarding that foreign boycott that shall, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify the sectors that are subject to such harm;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> describe the harm resulting from such boycott; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify actions necessary to minimize the effects of such boycott on the national technology and industrial base.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Integrated Process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that consideration of the technology and industrial base assessments is integrated into the overall budget, acquisition, and logistics support decision processes of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLII, § 4215</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2667</ref>, § 2505; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(g)(7)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 829(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2612</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–23, title III, § 303(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 895(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVI, § 1602</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2062</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 876</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 941</ref>; renumbered § 4816 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1867(b), (d)(4), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4281</ref>, 4282, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(41)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4817.</num>
<heading> Industrial Base Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish an Industrial Base Fund (in this section referred to as the “Fund”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Control of Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Fund shall be under the control of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, acting through the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Manufacturing and Industrial Base Policy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amounts in Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Fund shall consist of amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to the Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (e), the Fund shall be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to support the monitoring and assessment of the industrial base required by chapters 381 through 385 and chapter 389;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to address critical issues in the industrial base relating to urgent operational needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to support efforts to expand the industrial base; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to address supply chain vulnerabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Fund Subject to Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary of Defense to use the Fund under this section in any fiscal year is subject to the availability of appropriations for that purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Expenditures</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall establish procedures for expending monies in the Fund in support of the uses identified in subsection (d), including the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Direct obligations from the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Transfers of monies from the Fund to relevant appropriations of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 896(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4315</ref>, § 2508; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1601</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(75)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1552</ref>; renumbered § 4817, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1867(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4281</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1867(d)(7)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(22)(C)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4818.</num>
<heading> Data collection authority of President</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President shall be entitled, by regulation, subpoena, or otherwise, to obtain such information from, require such reports and the keeping of such records by, make such inspection of the books, records, and other writings, premises or property of, and take the sworn testimony of, and administer oaths and affirmations to, any person as may be necessary or appropriate, in the President’s discretion, to the enforcement or the administration of chapters 381 through 385 and chapter 389 and the regulations issued under such chapters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Condition for Use of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President shall issue regulations insuring that the authority of this section will be used only after the scope and purpose of the investigation, inspection, or inquiry to be made have been defined by competent authority and it is assured that no adequate and authoritative data are available from any Federal or other responsible agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty for Noncompliance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who willfully performs any act prohibited or willfully fails to perform any act required by the provisions of subsection (a), or any rule, regulation, or order thereunder, shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Disclosure of Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Information obtained under subsection (a) which the President deems confidential or with reference to which a request for confidential treatment is made by the person furnishing such information shall not be published or disclosed unless the President determines that the withholding thereof is contrary to the interest of the national defense. Any person who willfully violates this subsection shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may make such rules, regulations, and orders as he considers necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section. Any regulation or order under this section may be established in such form and manner, may contain such classification and differentiations, and may provide for such adjustments and reasonable exceptions as in the judgment of the President are necessary or proper to effectuate the purposes of this section, or to prevent circumvention or evasion, or to facilitate enforcement of this section, or any rule, regulation, or order issued under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “person” includes an individual, corporation, partnership, association, or any other organized group of persons, or legal successor or representative of the foregoing, and includes the United States or any agency thereof, or any other government, or any of its political subdivisions, or any agency of any of the foregoing, except that no punishment provided by this section shall apply to the United States, or to any such government, political subdivision, or government agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “national defense” means programs for military and atomic energy production or construction, military assistance to any foreign nation, stockpiling, space, and directly related activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLII, § 4217</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2670</ref>, § 2507; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1182(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1056(c)(5)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3439</ref>; renumbered § 4818 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1867(b)</ref>, (d)(5), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4281</ref>, 4282; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(22)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4819.</num>
<heading> Modernization of acquisition processes to ensure integrity of industrial base</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Digitization and Modernization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall streamline and digitize the Department of Defense approach for identifying and mitigating risks to the defense industrial base.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objective</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The objective of subsection (a) shall be to employ digital tools, technologies, and approaches to ensure the accessibility of relevant defense industrial base data to key decision-makers in the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Analytical Framework</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, in coordination with the Director of the Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency and the heads of other elements of the Department of Defense as appropriate, shall develop an analytical framework for risk mitigation across the acquisition process in implementing subsections (a) and (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The analytical framework required under paragraph (1) shall include the following elements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Characterization and monitoring of supply chain risks, such as those identified through the supply chain risk management process of the Department and by the Federal Acquisition Security Council, and including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> material sources and fragility, including the extent to which sources, items, materials, and articles are mined, produced, or manufactured within or outside the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> telecommunications services or equipment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> counterfeit parts;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> cybersecurity of contractors;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> video surveillance services or equipment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> vendor vetting in contingency or operational environments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> other electronic or information technology products and services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> other risk areas as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Characterization and monitoring of risks posed by contractor behavior that constitutes or may constitute violations of laws or regulations, including those relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> fraud;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ownership structures;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> trafficking in persons;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> workers’ health and safety;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> affiliation with the enemy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> foreign influence; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> other risk areas as deemed appropriate by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Characterization and assessment of the acquisition processes and procedures of the Department of Defense, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> market research;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> responsibility determinations, including consideration of the need for special standards of responsibility to address the risks described in subparagraphs (A) and (B);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> facilities clearances;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the development of contract requirements;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the technical evaluation of offers and contract awards;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> contractor mobilization, including hiring, training, and establishing facilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> contract administration, contract management, and oversight;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> contract audit for closeout;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> suspension and debarment activities and administrative appeals activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> contractor business system reviews;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> processes and procedures related to supply chain risk management and processes and procedures implemented pursuant to <ref>section 3252 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(xii)</num>
<content> other relevant processes and procedures.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Characterization and monitoring of the health and activities of the defense industrial base, including those relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> balance sheets, revenues, profitability, and debt;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> investment, innovation, and technological and manufacturing sophistication;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> finances, access to capital markets, and cost of raising capital within those markets;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> corporate governance, leadership, and culture of performance; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> history of performance on past Department of Defense and government contracts.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> Characterization and assessment of industrial base support policies, programs, and procedures, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> limitations and acquisition guidance relevant to the national technology and industrial base;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> limitations and acquisition guidance relevant to <ref>section 4862 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Industrial Base Analysis and Sustainment program of the Department, including direct support and common design activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Small Business Innovation Research Program (as defined in section 9(e) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 638(e)</ref>);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the Manufacturing Technology Program established under sections 4841 and 4842 of this title;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> programs relating to the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 4511</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002141">1</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> programs operating in each military department.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Roles and Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall designate the roles and responsibilities of organizations and individuals to execute activities under this section, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, including the Office of Defense Pricing and Contracting and the Office of Industrial Policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> service acquisition executives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> program offices and procuring contracting officers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> administrative contracting officers within the Defense Contract Management Agency and the Supervisor of Shipbuilding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Defense Contract Audit Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> each element of the Department of Defense which own or operate systems containing data relevant to contractors of the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the suspension and debarment official of the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the Chief Information Officer; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> other relevant organizations and individuals as deemed appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enabling Data, Tools, and Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, in consultation with the Chief Data Officer of the Department of Defense and the Director of the Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency, shall assess the extent to which existing systems of record relevant to risk assessments and contracting are producing, exposing, and maintaining valid and reliable data for the purposes of the Department’s continuous assessment and mitigation of risks in the defense industrial base.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The assessment required under subparagraph (A) shall include the following elements:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Identification of the necessary source data, to include data from contractors, intelligence and security activities, program offices, and commercial research entities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A description of modern data infrastructure, tools, and applications and an assessment of the extent to which new capabilities would improve the effectiveness and efficiency of mitigating the risks described in subsection (c)(2).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> An assessment of the following systems owned or operated outside of the Department of Defense that the Department depends upon or to which it provides data, including the following:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The Federal Awardee Performance and Integrity Information System (FAPIIS).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> The System for Award Management (SAM).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> The Federal Procurement Data System–Next Generation (FPDS–NG).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> The Electronic Data Management Information System.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> Other systems the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> An assessment of systems owned or operated by the Department of Defense, including the Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency and other defense agencies and field activities used to capture and analyze the status and performance (including past performance) of vendors and contractors.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Based on the findings pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall develop a unified set of activities to modernize the systems of record, data sources and collection methods, and data exposure mechanisms. The unified set of activities should include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the ability to continuously collect data on, assess, and mitigate risks;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> data analytics and business intelligence tools and methods; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> continuous development and continuous delivery of secure software to implement the activities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In connection with the assessments described in this section, the Secretary shall develop capabilities to map supply chains and to assess risks to the supply chain for major end items by business sector, vendor, program, part, and other metrics as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit or modify any other procurement policy, procedure, requirement, or restriction provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 845(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1500</ref>, § 2509; renumbered § 4819 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 843(a)</ref>, title XVIII, §§ 1867(b), (d)(6), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3765</ref>, 4281, 4282, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 841</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(d)(16), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1839</ref>, 2137.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4820.</num>
<heading> National technology and industrial base plans, policy, and guidance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations requiring consideration of the national technology and industrial base, in accordance with the strategy required by <ref>section 4811 of this title</ref>, in the development and implementation of acquisition plans for each major defense acquisition program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition Policy and Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop and promulgate acquisition policy and guidance to the service acquisition executives, the heads of the appropriate Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities, and relevant program managers. Such policy and guidance shall be germane to the use of the research and development, manufacturing, and production capabilities identified pursuant to chapters 381 through 385 and chapter 389 of this title and the technologies, companies, laboratories, and factories in specific Department of Defense research and development, international cooperative research, procurement, and sustainment activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLII, § 4216(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2669</ref>, § 2440; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2399</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVI, § 1603(c)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 846(b)(1)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1847(b)(2)(A), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3768</ref>, 4253; renumbered § 4820 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(s)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(A), (C), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2149</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(36)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>