<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 88—</num>
<heading>MILITARY FAMILY PROGRAMS AND MILITARY CHILD CARE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>MILITARY FAMILY PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1781.</num>
<heading> Office of Military Family Readiness Policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is in the Office of the Secretary of Defense an Office of Military Family Readiness Policy (in this section referred to as the “Office”). The Office shall be headed by the Director of Military Family Readiness Policy, who shall serve within the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Office—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall coordinate programs and activities of the military departments to the extent that they relate to military families; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall make recommendations to the Secretaries of the military departments with respect to programs and policies regarding military families.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Staff</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Office shall have not less than five professional staff members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-medical Counseling Services</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In carrying out its duties under subsection (b), the Office may coordinate programs and activities to provide non-medical counseling services to military families through the Department of Defense Military and Family Life Counseling Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A mental health care professional described in paragraph (3) may provide non-medical counseling services at any location in a State, the District of Columbia, or a territory or possession of the United States, without regard to where the professional or recipient of such services is located or delivery of such services is provided (including face-to-face and telehealth), if the provision of such services is within the scope of the authorized Federal duties of the professional.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A non-medical mental health professional described in this subsection is a person who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a currently licensed mental health care provider who holds a license that is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> issued by a State, the District of Columbia, or a territory or possession of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> recognized by the Secretary of Defense as an appropriate license for the provision of non-medical counseling services;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a member of the armed forces, a civilian employee of the Department of Defense, or a contractor designated by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> performing authorized duties for the Department of Defense under a program or activity referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The authority under this subsection shall terminate three years after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “non-medical counseling services” means mental health care services that are non-clinical, short-term and solution focused, and address topics related to personal growth, development, and positive functioning.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 330</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title IX, § 901(h)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(21)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1952</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 933(a)(1)</ref>, (4)(A), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 581</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1781a.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense Military Family Readiness Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is in the Department of Defense the Department of Defense Military Family Readiness Council (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Council shall consist of the following members:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness, who shall serve as chair of the Council and who may designate a representative to chair the council in the Under Secretary’s absence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The following persons, who shall be appointed or designated by the Secretary of Defense:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> One representative of each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force, each of whom shall be a member or civilian employee of the armed force to be represented.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> One representative, who shall be a member or civilian employee of the National Guard Bureau, to represent both the Army National Guard and the Air National Guard.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> One spouse or parent of a member of each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force, two of whom shall be the spouse or parent of an active component member, two of whom shall be the spouse or parent of a reserve component member, and one of whom shall be the spouse or parent of a member of the Space Force.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Three individuals appointed by the Secretary of Defense from among representatives of military family organizations, including military family organizations of families of members of the regular components and of families of members of the reserve components.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The senior enlisted advisor from each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force, except that two of these members may instead be selected from among the spouses of the senior enlisted advisors.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Director of the Office of Military Family Readiness Policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term on the Council of the members appointed or designated under subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) shall be two years and may be renewed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term on the Council of the members appointed under subparagraph (C) of paragraph (1) shall be two years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall meet not less often than twice each year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The duties of the Council shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To review and make recommendations to the Secretary of Defense regarding the policy and plans required under <ref>section 1781b of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To monitor requirements for the support of military family readiness programs and activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To evaluate and assess the effectiveness of the military family readiness programs and activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To make recommendations to the Secretary of Defense to improve collaboration, awareness, and promotion of accurate and timely military family readiness information and support services by policy makers, service providers, and targeted beneficiaries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Military Family Readiness Working Group for Military Housing.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is in the Council the Military Family Readiness Working Group for Military Housing (in this section referred to as the “Housing Working Group”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Housing Working Group shall be composed of the following members:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment, who shall serve as chair of the Housing Working Group on a nondelegable basis.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> One representative of each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> each of whom shall be a member of the armed force to be represented; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> not fewer than two of whom shall be enlisted members.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> One spouse of a member of each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force on active duty, not fewer than two of which shall be the spouse of an enlisted member.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> One commander or senior official of a military installation from each military department with responsibility for the public works or civil engineering systems of such installation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> One individual appointed by the Secretary of Defense among representatives of a voluntary consensus standards body that develops personnel certification standards for building maintenance, inspections, or restoration.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The Director of the Office of Military Family Readiness Policy.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term of Housing Working Group members specified under clauses (ii) through (v) of subparagraph (A) shall be two years and may be renewed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The chair of the Housing Working Group shall extend an invitation to all landlords for one representative of each landlord to attend such meetings of the Housing Working Group as the chair considers appropriate but at a minimum of once per year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Housing Working Group shall meet at least two times each year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The duties of the Housing Working Group shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To review and make recommendations to the Secretary of Defense on policies for covered military housing, including inspections practices and resident surveys.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> To make recommendations to the Secretary of Defense to improve—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> awareness and promotion of accurate and timely information about covered military housing, accommodations available through the Exceptional Family Member Program of the Department, and other support services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> collaboration among policymakers, providers of such accommodations and other support services, and targeted beneficiaries of such accommodations and other support services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “landlord” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2871 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “covered military housing” means housing acquired or constructed pursuant to subchapter IV of chapter 169 of this title that is owned by an entity other than the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 581(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 120</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 562</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2303</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 581</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4226</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 574</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1427</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 933(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 571(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1777</ref>, 1778; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(29)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3825</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(k)(1)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821(a), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 673</ref>, 749.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1781b.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense policy and plans for military family readiness</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy and Plans Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop a policy and plans for the Department of Defense for the support of military family readiness.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purposes of the policy and plans required under subsection (a) are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To ensure that the military family readiness programs and activities of the Department of Defense are comprehensive, effective, and properly supported.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To ensure that support is continuously available to military families in peacetime and in war, as well as during periods of force structure change and relocation of military units.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To ensure that the military family readiness programs and activities of the Department of Defense are available to all military families, including military families of members of the regular components, the reserve components, and the Space Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To make military family readiness an explicit element of applicable Department of Defense plans, programs, and budgeting activities, and that achievement of military family readiness is expressed through Department-wide goals that are identifiable and measurable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To ensure that the military family readiness programs and activities of the Department of Defense undergo continuous evaluation in order to ensure that resources are allocated and expended for such programs and activities to achieve Department-wide family readiness goals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The policy required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A list of military family readiness programs and activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Department of Defense-wide goals for military family support, including joint programs, for military families of members of the regular components, members of the reserve components, and members of the Space Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Policies on access to military family support programs and activities based on military family populations served and geographical location.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Metrics to measure the performance and effectiveness of the military family readiness programs and activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A summary, by fiscal year, of the allocation of funds (including appropriated funds and nonappropriated funds) for major categories of military family readiness programs and activities of the Department of Defense, set forth for each of the military departments and for the Office of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 581(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 121</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(23)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4370</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1560</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1781c.</num>
<heading> Office of Special Needs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is in the Office of Military Family Readiness Policy the Office of Special Needs (in this section referred to as the “Office”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The purpose of the Office is to standardize, enhance, and improve Department of Defense support around the world for military families with special needs (whether medical or educational needs) through the development of appropriate policies, enhancement and dissemination of appropriate information throughout the Department of Defense, support for such families in obtaining referrals for services and in obtaining service, and oversight of the activities of the military departments in support of such families.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Office shall have the responsibilities as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To develop and implement a comprehensive and standard policy on support for military families with special needs as required by subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To establish and oversee the programs required by subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To identify gaps in services available through the Department of Defense for military families with special needs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To develop plans to address gaps identified under paragraph (3) through appropriate mechanisms, such as enhancing resources and training and ensuring the provision of special assistance to military families with special needs and military parents of individuals with special needs (including through the provision of training and seminars to members of the armed forces).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To monitor the programs of the military departments for the assignment of members of the armed forces who are members of military families with special needs, and the programs for the support of such military families, and to advise the Secretary of Defense on the adequacy of such programs in conjunction with the preparation of future-years defense programs and other budgeting and planning activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> To monitor the availability and accessibility of programs provided by other Federal, State, local, and non-governmental agencies to military families with special needs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> To conduct periodic reviews of best practices in the United States in the provision of medical and educational services for children with special needs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> To carry out such other matters with respect to the programs and activities of the Department of Defense regarding military families with special needs as the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness shall specify.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Office shall develop, and regularly update, a uniform policy for the Department of Defense regarding military families with special needs. The policy shall apply with respect to members of the armed forces without regard to their location, whether within or outside the continental United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The policy developed under this subsection shall include elements regarding the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The assignment of members of the armed forces who are members of military families with special needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Support for military families with special needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In addressing the assignment of members of the armed forces under paragraph (2)(A), the policy developed under this subsection shall, in a manner consistent with the needs of the armed forces and responsive to the career development of members of the armed forces on active duty, provide for such members each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Assignment to locations where care and support for family members with special needs are available.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Stabilization of assignment for a minimum of 4 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Ability to request a second review of the approved assignment within or outside the continental United States if the member believes the location is inappropriate for the member’s family and would cause undue hardship.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Protection from having a medical recommendation for an approved assignment overridden by the commanding officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Ability to request continuation of location when there is a documented substantial risk of transferring medical care or educational services to a new provider or school at the specific time of permanent change of station.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In addressing support for military families under paragraph (2)(B), the policy developed under this subsection shall provide the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Procedures to identify members of the armed forces who are members of military families with special needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Mechanisms to ensure timely and accurate evaluations of members of such families who have special needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Procedures to facilitate the enrollment of such members of the armed forces and their families in programs of the military department for the support of military families with special needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Procedures to ensure the coordination of Department of Defense health care programs and support programs for military families with special needs, and the coordination of such programs with other Federal, State, local, and non-governmental health care programs and support programs intended to serve such families.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Requirements for resources (including staffing) to ensure the availability through the Department of Defense of appropriate numbers of case managers to provide individualized support for military families with special needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Requirements regarding the development and continuous updating by an appropriate office of an individualized services plan (whether medical, educational, or both) for each military family with special needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Requirements for record keeping, reporting, and continuous monitoring of available resources and family needs under individualized services support plans for military families with special needs, including the establishment and maintenance of a central or various regional databases for such purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Procedures for the development of an individualized services plan for military family members with special needs who have requested family support services and have a completed family needs assessment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Requirements to prohibit disenrollment from the Exceptional Family Member Program unless there is new supporting medical or educational information that indicates the original condition is no longer present, and to track disenrollment data in each armed force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Office shall establish, maintain, and oversee a program to provide information and referral services on special needs matters to military families with special needs on a continuous basis regardless of the location of the member’s assignment. The program shall provide for timely access by members of such military families to individual case managers and counselors on matters relating to special needs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Office shall establish, maintain, and oversee a program of outreach on special needs matters for military families with special needs. The program shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assist military families in identifying whether or not they have a member with special needs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide military families with special needs with information on the services, support, and assistance available through the Department of Defense regarding such members with special needs, including information on enrollment in programs of the military departments for such services, support, and assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Office shall provide support to the Secretary of each military department in the establishment and sustainment by such Secretary of a program for the support of military families with special needs under the jurisdiction of such Secretary. Each program shall be consistent with the policy developed by the Office under subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Each program under this paragraph shall provide for appropriate numbers of case managers for the development and oversight of individualized services plans for educational and medical support for military families with special needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Services under a program under this paragraph may be provided by contract or other arrangements with non-Department of Defense entities qualified to provide such services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Resources</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall assign to the Office such resources, including personnel, as the Secretary considers necessary for the discharge of the responsibilities of the Office, including a sufficient number of members of the armed forces to ensure appropriate representation by the military departments in the personnel of the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than April 30 each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the activities of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report under this subsection shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of any gaps in services available through the Department of Defense for military families with special needs that were identified under subsection (c)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the actions being taken, or planned, to address such gaps, including any plans developed under subsection (c)(4).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to the Extended Care Health Option program under <ref>section 1079(d) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the utilization rates of services under such program by eligible dependents (as such term is defined in such section) during the prior year;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a description of gaps in such services, as ascertained by the Secretary from information provided by families of eligible dependents;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an assessment of factors that prevent knowledge of and access to such program, including a discussion of actions the Secretary may take to address these factors; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> an assessment of the average wait time for an eligible dependent enrolled in the program to access alternative health coverage for a qualifying condition (as such term is defined in such section), including a discussion of any adverse health outcomes associated with such wait.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Such recommendations for legislative action as the Secretary considers appropriate to provide for the continuous improvement of support and services for military families with special needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Military Family With Special Needs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, a military family with special needs is any military family with one or more members who has a medical or educational special need (as defined by the Secretary in regulations for purposes of this section), including a condition covered by the Extended Health Care Option Program under <ref>section 1079f of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 563(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2304</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 582(a)</ref>, (b), title X, § 1075(b)(24), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4226</ref>, 4227, 4370; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 933(b)(1)</ref>–(5)(A), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2364</ref>, 2365; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 582(a)</ref>, title VII, § 704(c), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3651</ref>, 3688.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1782.</num>
<heading> Surveys of military families</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, in order to determine the effectiveness of Federal programs relating to military families and the need for new programs, may conduct surveys of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> members of the armed forces who are on active duty, in an active status, or retired;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> family members of such members; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> survivors of deceased retired members and of members who died while on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responses To Be Voluntary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Responses to surveys conducted under this section shall be voluntary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Recordkeeping Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to a survey authorized under subsection (a) that includes a person referred to in that subsection who is not an employee of the United States or is not otherwise considered an employee of the United States for the purposes of <ref>section 3502(3)(A)(i) of title 44</ref>, the person shall be considered as being an employee of the United States for the purposes of that section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Survey Required for Fiscal Year</inline> 2010.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (a), during fiscal year 2010, the Secretary of Defense shall conduct a survey otherwise authorized under such subsection. Thereafter, additional surveys may be conducted not less often than once every three fiscal years.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 330</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 572</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 581(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 122</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1783.</num>
<heading> Family members serving on advisory committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A committee within the Department of Defense which advises or assists the Department in the performance of any function which affects members of military families and which includes members of military families in its membership shall not be considered an advisory committee under <ref>section 1001(2) of title 5</ref> solely because of such membership.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 330</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(50)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4311</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1784.</num>
<heading> Employment opportunities for military spouses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President shall order such measures as the President considers necessary to increase employment opportunities for spouses of members of the armed forces. Such measures may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> excepting, pursuant to <ref>section 3302 of title 5</ref>, from the competitive service positions in the Department of Defense located outside of the United States to provide employment opportunities for qualified spouses of members of the armed forces in the same geographical area as the permanent duty station of the members; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> providing preference in hiring for positions in nonappropriated fund activities to qualified spouses of members of the armed forces stationed in the same geographical area as the nonappropriated fund activity for positions in wage grade UA–8 and below and equivalent positions and for positions paid at hourly rates.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to implement such measures as the President orders under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide preference to qualified spouses of members of the armed forces in hiring for any civilian position in the Department of Defense if the spouse is among persons determined to be best qualified for the position and if the position is located in the same geographical area as the permanent duty station of the member;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to ensure that notice of any vacant position in the Department of Defense is provided in a manner reasonably designed to reach spouses of members of the armed forces whose permanent duty stations are in the same geographic area as the area in which the position is located; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to ensure that the spouse of a member of the armed forces who applies for a vacant position in the Department of Defense shall, to the extent practicable, be considered for any such position located in the same geographic area as the permanent duty station of the member.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Status of Preference Eligibles</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide a spouse of a member of the armed forces with preference in hiring over an individual who is a preference eligible.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Space-Available Use of Facilities for Spouse Training Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of a military department may make available to a non-Department of Defense entity space in non-excess facilities controlled by that Secretary for the purpose of the non-Department of Defense entity providing employment-related training for military spouses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment by Other Federal Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall work with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies to expand and facilitate the use of existing Federal programs and resources in support of military spouse employment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Private-Sector Employment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall seek to develop partnerships with firms in the private sector to enhance employment opportunities for spouses of members of the armed forces and to provide for improved job portability for such spouses, especially in the case of the spouse of a member of the armed forces accompanying the member to a new geographical area because of a change of permanent duty station of the member; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall work with the United States Chamber of Commerce and other appropriate private-sector entities to facilitate the formation of such partnerships.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment With DOD Contractors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall examine and seek ways for incorporating hiring preferences for qualified spouses of members of the armed forces into contracts between the Department of Defense and private-sector entities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Improvement of Occupational License Portability Through Interstate Compacts.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into a cooperative agreement with the Council of State Governments to assist with funding of the development of interstate compacts on licensed occupations in order to alleviate the burden associated with relicensing in such an occupation by spouse of a members of the armed forces in connection with a permanent change of duty station of members to another State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on assistance per compact</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount provided under paragraph (1) as assistance for the development of any particular interstate compact may not exceed $1,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on total amount of assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total amount of assistance provided under paragraph (1) in any fiscal year may not exceed $4,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than February 28 each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on interstate compacts described in paragraph (1) developed through assistance provided under that paragraph. Each report shall set forth the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any interstate compact developed during the preceding calendar year, including the occupational licenses covered by such compact and the States agreeing to enter into such compact.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any interstate compact developed during a prior calendar year into which one or more additional States agreed to enter during the preceding calendar year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 330</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 571(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 575</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(33)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3872</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 581(a), 582(a), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1910</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1784a.</num>
<heading> Education and training opportunities for military spouses to expand employment and portable career opportunities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programs and Tuition Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may establish programs to assist the spouse of a member of the armed forces described in subsection (b) in achieving—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the education and training required for a degree or credential at an accredited college, university, or technical school in the United States that expands employment and portable career opportunities for the spouse; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the education prerequisites and professional licensure or credential required, by a government or government sanctioned licensing body, for an occupation that expands employment and portable career opportunities for the spouse.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> As an alternative to, or in addition to, establishing a program under this subsection, the Secretary may provide tuition assistance to an eligible spouse who is pursuing education, training, or a license or credential to expand the spouse’s employment and portable career opportunities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Spouses</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Assistance under this section is limited to a spouse of a member of the armed forces who is serving on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A spouse who is eligible for a program under this section and begins a course of education or training for a degree, license, or credential described in subsection (a) may not become ineligible to complete such course of education or training solely because the member to whom the spouse is married is promoted to a higher grade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (b) does not include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a person who is married to, but legally separated from, a member of the armed forces under court order or statute of any State or territorial possession of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a spouse of a member of the armed forces who is also a member of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Doula and IBCLC Certifications</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the programs authorized by subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide assistance to the spouse of a member of the armed forces described in subsection (b) with obtaining certification—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as a doula or International Board Certified Lactation Consultant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provided by an organization that receives reimbursement under the extramedical maternal health providers demonstration project required by section 746 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<ref>Public Law 116–283</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 1073</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Portable Career Opportunities Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “portable career” includes an occupation identified by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, as requiring education and training that results in a credential that is recognized nationwide by industry or specific businesses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to govern the availability and use of assistance under this section. The Secretary shall ensure that programs established under this section do not result in inequitable treatment for spouses of members of the armed forces who are also members, since they are excluded from participation in the programs under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 582(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4473</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 576</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VI, § 634</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1785.</num>
<heading> Youth sponsorship program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall require that there be at each military installation a youth sponsorship program to facilitate the integration of dependent children of members of the armed forces into new surroundings when moving to that military installation as a result of a parent’s permanent change of station.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Description of Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The program at each installation shall provide for involvement of dependent children of members presently stationed at the military installation and shall be directed primarily toward children in their preteen and teenage years.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 331</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1786.</num>
<heading> Dependent student travel within the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds available to the Department of Defense for the travel and transportation of dependent students of members of the armed forces stationed overseas may be obligated for transportation allowances for travel within or between the contiguous States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 331</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1787.</num>
<heading> Reporting of child abuse</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall request each State to provide for the reporting to the Secretary of any report the State receives of known or suspected instances of child abuse and neglect in which the person having care of the child is a member of the armed forces (or the spouse of the member).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “child abuse and neglect” has the meaning provided in section 3 of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<ref>Public Law 93–247</ref>; <ref>42 U.S.C. 5101</ref> note).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 331</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1951</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1788.</num>
<heading> Additional family assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may provide for the families of members of the armed forces serving on active duty, in addition to any other assistance available for such families, any assistance that the Secretary considers appropriate to ensure that the children of such members obtain needed child care, education, and other youth services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Primary Purpose of Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The assistance authorized by this section should be directed primarily toward providing needed family support, including child care, education, and other youth services, for children of members of the armed forces who are deployed, assigned to duty, or ordered to active duty in connection with a contingency operation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VI, § 652(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2581</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(25)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1788a.</num>
<heading> Support programs: special operations forces personnel; immediate family members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programs Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Consistent with such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe to carry out this section, the Commander of the United States Special Operations Command may conduct programs to provide family support services. In selecting and conducting any program under this subsection, the Commander shall coordinate with the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection of Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In selecting the programs to be conducted under subsection (a), the Commander shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify family support services that have a direct and concrete impact on the readiness of special operations forces, but that are not being provided by the Secretary of a military department to covered individuals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conduct a cost-benefit analysis of each family support service proposed to be included in a program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commander may expend up to $10,000,000 during each fiscal year, from funds available for Major Force Program 11, to carry out family support programs under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(d)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1796</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Commander” means the Commander of the United States Special Operations Command.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “immediate family members” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1789(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “special operations forces” means those forces of the armed forces identified as special operations forces under <ref>section 167(j) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “family support services” includes psychological support, spiritual support, and costs of transportation, food, lodging, child care, supplies, fees, and training materials for covered individuals while participating in programs under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered individuals” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> members of the Armed Forces (including the reserve components) assigned to special operations forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> service personnel assigned to support special operations forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> immediate family members of individuals described in subparagraphs (A) and (B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> immediate family members of individuals described in subparagraphs (A) or (B) in a case in which such individual died—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> as a direct result of armed conflict;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> while engaged in hazardous service;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the performance of duty under conditions simulating war; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> through an instrumentality of war.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 555(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1402</ref>, 1403; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 572</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII</ref>, §§ 1702(c)(1), 1731(a)(28), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1796</ref>, 1813; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 583(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3653</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 561</ref>, title X, § 1081(a)(24), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1746</ref>, 1920.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1789.</num>
<heading> Chaplain-led programs: authorized support</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may provide support services described in subsection (b) to support a chaplain-led program to assist a covered individual in building and maintaining a strong family structure, or to support the resiliency, suicide prevention, or holistic wellness of such covered individual.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Support Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The support services referred to in subsection (a) are costs of transportation, food, lodging, child care, supplies, fees, and training materials for a covered individual while participating in a program referred to in that subsection, including participation at a retreat or conference.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Individual Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “covered individual” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a member of the armed forces on active duty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a member of the reserve components in an active status; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a dependent of an individual described in paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 582(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1489</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 571(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2600</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 684</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1790.</num>
<heading> Military personnel citizenship processing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Using funds provided for operation and maintenance and notwithstanding <ref>section 2215 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Defense may reimburse the Secretary of Homeland Security for costs associated with the processing and adjudication by the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) of applications for naturalization described in sections 328(b)(4) and 329(b)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1439(b)(4)</ref> and 1440(b)(4)). Such reimbursements shall be deposited and remain available as provided by subsections (m) and (n) of section 286 of such Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1356</ref>). Such reimbursements shall be based on actual costs incurred by USCIS for processing applications for naturalization, and shall not exceed $7,500,000 per fiscal year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. A, title VIII, § 8070(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 822</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(22)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>MILITARY CHILD CARE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1791.</num>
<heading> Funding for military child care</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It is the policy of Congress that the amount of appropriated funds available during a fiscal year for operating expenses for military child development centers and programs shall be not less than 115 percent of the amount of child care fee receipts that are estimated to be received by the Department of Defense during that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for Allocations of Certain Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall be responsible for the allocation of Office of the Secretary of Defense level funds for military child development programs for children from birth through 12 years of age, and may not delegate such responsibility to the military departments.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 332</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 584</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3654</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 582</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 280</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1792.</num>
<heading> Child care employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Training</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations implementing a training program for child care employees. Those regulations shall apply uniformly among the military departments. Subject to paragraph (2), satisfactory completion of the training program shall be a condition of employment of any person as a child care employee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Under those regulations, the Secretary shall require that each child care employee complete the training program not later than six months after the date on which the employee is employed as a child care employee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The training program established under this subsection shall cover, at a minimum, training in the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Early childhood development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Activities and disciplinary techniques appropriate to children of different ages.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Child abuse prevention and detection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Cardiopulmonary resuscitation and other emergency medical procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training and Curriculum Specialists</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall require that at least one employee at each military child development center be a specialist in training and curriculum development. The Secretary shall ensure that such employees have appropriate credentials and experience.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The duties of such employees shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Special teaching activities at the center.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Daily oversight and instruction of other child care employees at the center.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Daily assistance in the preparation of lesson plans.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Assistance in the center’s child abuse prevention and detection program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Advising the director of the center on the performance of other child care employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each employee referred to in paragraph (1) shall be an employee in a competitive service position.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competitive Rates of Pay</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of providing military child development centers with a qualified and stable civilian workforce, employees at a military installation who are directly involved in providing child care and who are paid from nonappropriated funds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of entry-level employees, shall be paid a rate of pay competitive with the rates of pay paid to other equivalent non-Federal positions within the metropolitan statistical area or non-metropolitan statistical area (as the case may be) in which such Department employee’s position is located; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of any employee not covered by subparagraph (A), shall be paid a rate of pay competitive with the rates of pay paid to other employees with similar training, seniority, and experience within the metropolitan statistical area or non-metropolitan statistical area (as the case may be) in which such Department employee’s position is located.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), no employee shall receive a rate of pay under this subsection that is lower than the minimum hourly rate of pay applicable to civilian employees of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of determining the rates of pay under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall use the metropolitan and nonmetropolitan area occupational employment and wage estimates published monthly by the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competitive Service Position Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “competitive service position” means a position in the competitive service, as defined in <ref>section 2102(a)(1) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 332</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(34)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title XI, § 1106</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2142</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 583(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1911</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1793.</num>
<heading> Parent fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations establishing fees to be charged parents for the attendance of children at military child development centers. Those regulations shall be uniform for the military departments and shall require that, in the case of children who attend the centers on a regular basis, the fees shall be based on family income.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Local Waiver Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may provide authority to installation commanders, on a case-by-case basis, to establish fees for attendance of children at child development centers at rates lower than those prescribed under subsection (a) if the rates prescribed under subsection (a) are not competitive with rates at local non-military child development centers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Family Discount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a family with two or more children attending a child development center, the regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (a) may require that installations commanders charge a fee for attendance at the center of any child of the family after the first child of the family in amount equal to 85 percent of the amount of the fee otherwise chargeable for the attendance of such child at the center.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Child Care Employee Discount</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In order to support recruitment and retention initiatives, the Secretary of Defense shall charge reduced fees for the attendance, at a military child development center, of the children of a child care employee as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the first child, no fee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For each other child, a fee equal to or less than a fee discounted under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition of Concurrent Discounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A family may not receive discounts under subsections (c) and (d) concurrently.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 333</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 585(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3654</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 642</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2634</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VI, § 633</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1937</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1794.</num>
<heading> Child abuse prevention and safety at facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Child Abuse Task Force</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall maintain a special task force to respond to allegations of widespread child abuse at a military installation. The task force shall be composed of personnel from appropriate disciplines, including, where appropriate, medicine, psychology, and childhood development. In the case of such allegations, the task force shall provide assistance to the commander of the installation, and to parents at the installation, in helping them to deal with such allegations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Hotline</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall maintain a national telephone number for persons to use to report suspected child abuse or safety violations at a military child development center or family home day care site. The Secretary shall ensure that such reports may be made anonymously if so desired by the person making the report. The Secretary shall establish procedures for following up on complaints and information received over that number.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall publicize the existence of the number by means including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> posting it in public areas of military child development centers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing it to the parents and legal guardians of children who attend military child development centers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance From Local Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations requiring that, in a case of allegations of child abuse at a military child development center or family home day care site, the commander of the military installation or the head of the task force established under subsection (a) shall seek the assistance of local child protective authorities if such assistance is available.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations on safety and operating procedures at military child development centers. Those regulations shall apply uniformly among the military departments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspections</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall require that each military child development center be inspected not less often than four times a year. Each such inspection shall be unannounced. At least one inspection a year shall be carried out by a representative of the installation served by the center, and one inspection a year shall be carried out by a representative of the major command under which that installation operates.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Remedies for Violations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), any violation of a safety, health, or child welfare law or regulation (discovered at an inspection or otherwise) at a military child development center shall be remedied immediately.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a violation that is not life threatening, the commander of the major command under which the installation concerned operates may waive the requirement that the violation be remedied immediately for a period of up to 90 days beginning on the date of the discovery of the violation. If the violation is not remedied as of the end of that 90-day period, the military child development center shall be closed until the violation is remedied. The Secretary of the military department concerned may waive the preceding sentence and authorize the center to remain open in a case in which the violation cannot reasonably be remedied within that 90-day period or in which major facility reconstruction is required.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 333</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 584</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1912</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1795.</num>
<heading> Parent partnerships with child development centers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Parent Boards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall require that there be established at each military child development center a board of parents, to be composed of parents of children attending the center. The board shall meet periodically with staff of the center and the commander of the installation served by the center for the purpose of discussing problems and concerns. The board, together with the staff of the center, shall be responsible for coordinating the parent participation program described in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Parent Participation Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall require the establishment of a parent participation program at each military child development center. As part of such program, the Secretary of Defense may establish fees for attendance of children at such a center, in the case of parents who participate in the parent participation program at that center, at rates lower than the rates that otherwise apply.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 334</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1796.</num>
<heading> Subsidies for family home day care</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may use appropriated funds available for military child care purposes to provide assistance to family home day care providers so that family home day care services can be provided to members of the armed forces at a cost comparable to the cost of services provided by military child development centers. The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for the provision of such assistance.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 334</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1797.</num>
<heading> Early childhood education program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall require that all military child development centers meet standards of operation necessary for accreditation by an appropriate national early childhood programs accrediting body.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1798.</num>
<heading> Child care services and youth program services for dependents: financial assistance for providers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may provide financial assistance to an eligible civilian provider of child care services or youth program services that furnishes such services for members of the armed forces, survivors of members of the armed forces who die in combat-related incidents in the line of duty, and employees of the United States if the Secretary determines that providing such financial assistance—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is in the best interest of the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enables supplementation or expansion of furnishing of child care services or youth program services for military installations, while not supplanting or replacing such services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensures that the eligible provider is able to comply, and does comply, with the regulations, policies, and standards of the Department of Defense that are applicable to the furnishing of such services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Providers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A provider of child care services or youth program services is eligible for financial assistance under this section if the provider—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is licensed to provide those services under applicable State and local law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has previously provided such services for members of the armed forces or employees of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a family home day care provider; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is a provider of family child care services that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> otherwise provides federally funded or sponsored child development services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provides the services in a child development center owned and operated by a private, not-for-profit organization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provides before-school or after-school child care program in a public school facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> conducts an otherwise federally funded or federally sponsored school age child care or youth services program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> conducts a school age child care or youth services program that is owned and operated by a not-for-profit organization; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> is a provider of another category of child care services or youth services determined by the Secretary of Defense as appropriate for meeting the needs of members of the armed forces or employees of the Department of Defense.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To provide financial assistance under this subsection, the Secretary of Defense may use any funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 584(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 634</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2645</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VI, § 624</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1428</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1799.</num>
<heading> Child care services and youth program services for dependents: participation by children and youth otherwise ineligible</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may authorize participation in child care or youth programs of the Department of Defense, to the extent of the availability of space and services, by children and youth under the age of 19 who are not dependents of members of the armed forces or of employees of the Department of Defense and are not otherwise eligible for participation in those programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Authorization of participation in a program under subsection (a) shall be limited to situations in which that participation promotes the attainment of the objectives set forth in subsection (c), as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objectives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The objectives for authorizing participation in a program under subsection (a) are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To support the integration of children and youth of military families into civilian communities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To make more efficient use of Department of Defense facilities and resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To establish or support a partnership or consortium arrangement with schools and other youth services organizations serving children of members of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 584(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 634</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1800.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “military child development center” means a facility on a military installation (or on property under the jurisdiction of the commander of a military installation) at which child care services are provided for members of the armed forces or any other facility at which such child care services are provided that is operated by the Secretary of a military department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “family home day care” means home-based child care services that are provided for members of the armed forces by an individual who (A) is certified by the Secretary of the military department concerned as qualified to provide those services, and (B) provides those services on a regular basis for compensation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “child care employee” means a civilian employee of the Department of Defense who is employed to work in a military child development center (regardless of whether the employee is paid from appropriated funds or nonappropriated funds).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “child care fee receipts” means those nonappropriated funds that are derived from fees paid by members of the armed forces for child care services provided at military child development centers.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 335</ref>, § 1798; renumbered § 1800, <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 584(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 634</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>