<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 31—</num>
<heading>ENLISTMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter “enlistment” means original enlistment or reenlistment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Enlistment oath: who may administer</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enlistment Oath</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each person enlisting in an armed force shall take the following oath:<p class="indent1">“I, __________, do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I will support and defend the Constitution of the United States against all enemies, foreign and domestic; that I will bear true faith and allegiance to the same; and that I will obey the orders of the President of the United States and the orders of the officers appointed over me, according to regulations and the Uniform Code of Military Justice. So help me God.”</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Who May Administer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The oath may be taken before the President, the Vice-President, the Secretary of Defense, any commissioned officer, or any other person designated under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 17</ref>, § 501; <ref>Pub. L. 87–751, § 1</ref>, <date date="1962-10-05">Oct. 5, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 748</ref>; renumbered § 502, <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 753</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VI, § 653(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1462</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 595(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Enlistments: recruiting campaigns; compilation of directory information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recruiting Campaigns</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall conduct intensive recruiting campaigns to obtain enlistments in the Regular Army, Regular Navy, Regular Air Force, Regular Marine Corps, and Regular Coast Guard and the Space Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall act on a continuing basis to enhance the effectiveness of recruitment programs of the Department of Defense (including programs conducted jointly and programs conducted by the separate armed forces) through an aggressive program of advertising and market research targeted at prospective recruits for the armed forces and those who may influence prospective recruits. Subchapter I of chapter 35 of title 44 shall not apply to actions taken as part of that program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> PII regarding a prospective recruit collected or compiled under this subsection shall be kept confidential, and a person who has had access to such PII may not disclose the information except for purposes of this section or other purpose authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In the course of conducting a recruiting campaign, the Secretary concerned shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> notify a prospective recruit of data collection policies of the armed force concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> permit the prospective recruit to elect not to participate in such data collection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “PII” means personally identifiable information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compilation of Directory Information</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may collect and compile directory information pertaining to each student who is 17 years of age or older or in the eleventh grade (or its equivalent) or higher and who is enrolled in a secondary school in the United States or its territories, possessions, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may make directory information collected and compiled under this subsection available to the armed forces for military recruiting purposes. Such information may not be disclosed for any other purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Directory information pertaining to any person may not be maintained for more than 3 years after the date the information pertaining to such person is first collected and compiled under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Directory information collected and compiled under this subsection shall be confidential, and a person who has had access to such information may not disclose such information except for the purposes described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection. Regulations prescribed under this subsection shall be submitted to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives. Regulations prescribed by the Secretaries concerned to carry out this subsection shall be as uniform as practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as requiring, or authorizing the Secretary of Defense to require, that any educational institution furnish directory information to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access to Secondary Schools</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Each local educational agency receiving assistance under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall provide to military recruiters the same access to secondary school students as is provided generally to postsecondary educational institutions or to prospective employers of those students;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall provide to military recruiters access to career fairs or similar events upon a request made by military recruiters for military recruiting purposes; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shall, upon a request made by military recruiters for military recruiting purposes, provide, not later than 60 days after receiving such request, access to secondary school student names, addresses, electronic mail addresses (which shall be the electronic mail addresses provided by the school, if available), and telephone listings, notwithstanding subsection (a)(5) of section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1232g</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A local educational agency may not release a student’s name, address, electronic mail address, and telephone listing under subparagraph (A)(iii) without the prior written consent of a parent of the student if the student, or a parent of the student, has submitted a request to the local educational agency that the student’s information not be released for a purpose covered by that subparagraph without prior written parental consent. Each local educational agency shall notify parents of the rights provided under the preceding sentence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a local educational agency denies a request by the Department of Defense for recruiting access, the Secretary of Defense, in cooperation with the Secretary of the military department concerned, shall designate an officer in a grade not below the grade of colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain, or a senior executive of that military department to meet with representatives of that local educational agency in person, at the offices of that agency, for the purpose of arranging for recruiting access. The designated officer or senior executive shall seek to have that meeting within 120 days of the date of the denial of the request for recruiting access.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If, after a meeting under paragraph (2) with representatives of a local educational agency that has denied a request for recruiting access or (if the educational agency declines a request for the meeting) after the end of such 120-day period, the Secretary of Defense determines that the agency continues to deny recruiting access, the Secretary shall transmit to the chief executive of the State in which the agency is located a notification of the denial of recruiting access and a request for assistance in obtaining that access. The notification shall be transmitted within 60 days after the date of the determination. The Secretary shall provide to the Secretary of Education a copy of such notification and any other communication between the Secretary and that chief executive with respect to such access.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> If a local educational agency continues to deny recruiting access one year after the date of the transmittal of a notification regarding that agency under paragraph (3), the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall determine whether the agency denies recruiting access to at least two of the armed forces (other than the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> upon making an affirmative determination under subparagraph (A), shall transmit a notification of the denial of recruiting access to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the specified congressional committees;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Senators of the State in which the local educational agency is located; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the member of the House of Representatives who represents the district in which the local educational agency is located.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The requirements of this subsection do not apply to a private secondary school that maintains a religious objection to service in the armed forces and which objection is verifiable through the corporate or other organizational documents or materials of that school.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit an annual report to Congress not later than February 1 each calendar year, detailing each notification of denial of recruiting access issued under paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “local educational agency” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a local educational agency, within the meaning of that term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a private secondary school.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “recruiting access” means access requested as described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The term “senior executive” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 3132(a)(3) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> The term “specified congressional committees” means the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The term “member of the House of Representatives” includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 754</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–252, title XI, § 1114(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 749</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 571</ref>, title X, § 1067(1), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 622</ref>, 774; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, §§ 562, 563(a)–(c)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–131 to 1654A–133; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 544(a)</ref>, title X, § 1048(a)(5)(A), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1112</ref>, 1222; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 543</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1478</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(5)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2061</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(uuu)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2190</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 531(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2574</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 541</ref>, title XVII, § 1717(b)(1), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 264</ref>, 655.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Persons not qualified</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Insanity, Desertion, Felons, Etc</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person who is insane, intoxicated, or a deserter from an armed force, or who has been convicted of a felony, may be enlisted in any armed force. However, the Secretary concerned may authorize exceptions, in meritorious cases, for the enlistment of deserters and persons convicted of felonies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Citizenship or Residency</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A person may be enlisted in any armed force only if the person is one of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A national of the United States, as defined in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An alien who is lawfully admitted for permanent residence, as defined in section 101(a)(20) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(20)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> A person described in section 341 of one of the following compacts:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Compact of Free Association between the Federated States of Micronesia and the United States (<ref>section 201(a) of Public Law 108–188</ref> (<ref>117 Stat. 2784</ref>; <ref>48 U.S.C. 1921</ref> note)).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Compact of Free Association between the Republic of the Marshall Islands and the United States (<ref>section 201(b) of Public Law 108–188</ref> (<ref>117 Stat. 2823</ref>; <ref>48 U.S.C. 1921</ref> note)).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The Compact of Free Association between Palau and the United States (<ref>section 201 of Public Law 99–658</ref> (<ref>100 Stat. 3678</ref>; <ref>48 U.S.C. 1931</ref> note)).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), and subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary concerned may authorize the enlistment of a person not described in paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that such person possesses a critical skill or expertise—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that is vital to the national interest; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that the person will use in the primary daily duties of that person as a member of the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> No person who enlists under paragraph (2) may report to initial training until after the Secretary concerned has completed all required background investigations and security and suitability screening as determined by the Secretary of Defense regarding that person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A Secretary concerned may not authorize more than 1,000 enlistments under paragraph (2) per military department in a calendar year until after—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense submits to Congress written notice of the intent of that Secretary concerned to authorize more than 1,000 such enlistments in a calendar year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a period of 30 days has elapsed after the date on which Congress receives the notice.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 754</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 542(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3253</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1755</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 505.</num>
<heading> Regular components: qualifications, term, grade</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may accept original enlistments in the Regular Army, Regular Navy, Regular Air Force, Regular Marine Corps, or Regular Coast Guard, as the case may be, of qualified, effective, and able-bodied persons who are not less than seventeen years of age nor more than forty-two years of age. However, no person under eighteen years of age may be originally enlisted without the written consent of his parent or guardian, if he has a parent or guardian entitled to his custody and control.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A person is enlisted in the Regular Army, Regular Navy, Regular Air Force, Regular Marine Corps, or Regular Coast Guard in the grade or rating prescribed by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may accept original enlistments of persons for the duration of their minority or for a period of at least two but not more than eight years, in the Regular Army, Regular Navy, Regular Air Force, Regular Marine Corps, or Regular Coast Guard, as the case may be.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may accept a reenlistment in the Regular Army, Regular Navy, Regular Air Force, Regular Marine Corps, or Regular Coast Guard, as the case may be, for a period determined under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a member who has less than 10 years of service in the armed forces as of the day before the first day of the period for which reenlisted, the period for which the member reenlists shall be at least two years but not more than eight years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of a member who has at least 10 years of service in the armed forces as of the day before the first day of the period for which reenlisted, the Secretary concerned may accept a reenlistment for either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a specified period of at least two years but not more than eight years; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an unspecified period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> No enlisted member is entitled to be reenlisted for a period that would expire before the end of the member’s current enlistment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enlistments in the Space Force</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For enlistments in the Space Force, see sections 20301 and 20302 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 754</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–290</ref>, <date date="1974-05-24">May 24, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 173</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–485, title VIII, § 820(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-20">Oct. 20, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1627</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title X, § 1023</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 671</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 511</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2514</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 543, 544, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3253</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 531(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4449</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(5)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1717(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 655</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 506.</num>
<heading> Regular components: extension of enlistments during war</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An enlistment in the Regular Army, Regular Navy, Regular Air Force, Regular Marine Corps, Space Force, or Regular Coast Guard in effect at the beginning of a war, or entered into during a war, unless sooner terminated by the President, continues in effect until six months after the termination of that war.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 754</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1717(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 655</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 507.</num>
<heading> Extension of enlistment for members needing medical care or hospitalization</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An enlisted member of an armed force on active duty whose term of enlistment expires while he is suffering from disease or injury incident to service and not due to his misconduct, and who needs medical care or hospitalization, may be retained on active duty, with his consent, until he recovers to the extent that he is able to meet the physical requirements for reenlistment, or it is determined that recovery to that extent is impossible.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section does not prevent the retention in service, without his consent, of an enlisted member of an armed force under <ref>section 972 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 754</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 508.</num>
<heading> Reenlistment: qualifications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No person whose service during his last term of enlistment was not honest and faithful may be reenlisted in an armed force. However, the Secretary concerned may authorize the reenlistment in the armed force under his jurisdiction of such a person if his conduct after that service has been good.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A person discharged from a Regular component may be reenlisted in the Regular Army, Regular Navy, Regular Air Force, Regular Marine Corps, Space Force, or Regular Coast Guard, as the case may be, under such regulations as the Secretary concerned may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section does not deprive a person of any right to be reenlisted in the Regular Army, Regular Navy, Regular Air Force, Regular Marine Corps, Space Force, or Regular Coast Guard under any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 755</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(5)(C)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1717(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 655</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 509.</num>
<heading> Voluntary extension of enlistments: periods and benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary concerned may prescribe, the term of enlistment of a member of an armed force may be extended or reextended with his written consent for any period. However, the total of all such extensions of an enlistment may not exceed four years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When a member is discharged from an enlistment that has been extended under this section, he has the same rights, privileges, and benefits that he would have if discharged at the same time from an enlistment not so extended.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 755</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 510.</num>
<heading> Enlistment incentives for pursuit of skills to facilitate national service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enlistment Incentive Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out an enlistment incentive program in accordance with this section under which a person who is a National Call to Service participant shall be entitled to one of the incentives specified in subsection (e). The program shall be carried out during the period ending on <date date="2007-12-31">December 31, 2007</date>, and may be carried out after that date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Call to Service Participant</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “National Call to Service participant” means a person who has not previously served in the armed forces who enters into an original enlistment pursuant to a written agreement with the Secretary of a military department (in such form and manner as may be prescribed by that Secretary) under which the person agrees to perform a period of national service as specified in subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Service</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The total period of national service to which a National Call to Service participant is obligated under the agreement under this section shall be specified in the agreement. Under the agreement, the participant shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> upon completion of initial entry training (as prescribed by the Secretary of Defense), serve on active duty in a military occupational specialty designated by the Secretary of Defense under subsection (d) for a period of 15 months;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> upon completion of the period of active duty specified in paragraph (1) and without a break in service, serve either (A) an additional period of active duty as determined by the Secretary of Defense, or (B) a period of 24 months in an active status in the Selected Reserve or the Space Force; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> upon completion of the period of service specified in paragraph (2), and without a break in service, serve the remaining period of obligated service specified in the agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on active duty in the armed forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the Selected Reserve;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the Individual Ready Reserve;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in the Space Force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> in Americorps or another domestic national service program jointly designated by the Secretary of Defense and the head of such program for purposes of this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> in any combination of service referred to in subparagraphs (A) through (E) that is approved by the Secretary of the military department concerned pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense and specified in the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designated Military Occupational Specialties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall designate military occupational specialties for purposes of subsection (c)(1). Such military occupational specialties shall be military occupational specialties that, as determined by the Secretary, will facilitate pursuit of national service by National Call to Service participants and shall include military occupational specialties for enlistments for officer training and subsequent service as an officer, in cases in which the reason for the enlistment and entry into an agreement under subsection (b) is to enter an officer training program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incentives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The incentives specified in this subsection are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Payment of a bonus in the amount of $5,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Payment in an amount not to exceed $18,000 of outstanding principal and interest on qualifying student loans of the National Call to Service participant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Entitlement to an allowance for educational assistance at the monthly rate equal to the monthly rate payable for basic educational assistance allowances under <ref>section 3015(a)(1) of title 38</ref> for a total of 12 months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Entitlement to an allowance for educational assistance at the monthly rate equal to 50 percent of the monthly rate payable for basic educational assistance allowances under <ref>section 3015(b)(1) of title 38</ref> for a total of 36 months.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Election of Incentive</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A National Call to Service participant shall elect in the agreement under subsection (b) which incentive under subsection (e) to receive. An election under this subsection is irrevocable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of Bonus Amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Payment to a National Call to Service participant of the bonus elected by the National Call to Service participant under subsection (e)(1) shall be made in such time and manner as the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Payment of outstanding principal and interest on the qualifying student loans of a National Call to Service participant, as elected under subsection (e)(2), shall be made in such time and manner as the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Payment under this paragraph of the outstanding principal and interest on the qualifying student loans of a National Call to Service participant shall be made to the holder of such student loans, as identified by the National Call to Service participant to the Secretary of the military department concerned for purposes of such payment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Payment of a bonus or incentive in accordance with this subsection shall be made by the Secretary of the military department concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination With Montgomery GI Bill Benefits</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), a National Call to Service participant who elects an incentive under paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (e) is not entitled to additional educational assistance under chapter 1606 of this title or to basic educational assistance under subchapter II of chapter 30 of title 38.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If a National Call to Service participant meets all eligibility requirements specified in chapter 1606 of this title or chapter 30 of title 38 for entitlement to allowances for educational assistance under either such chapter, the participant may become eligible for allowances for educational assistance benefits under either such chapter up to the maximum allowance provided less the total amount of allowance paid under paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Educational assistance under paragraphs (3) or (4) of subsection (e) shall be provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs under an agreement to be entered into by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs. The agreements shall include administrative procedures to ensure the prompt and timely transfer of funds from the Secretary concerned to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the making of payments under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this section, the provisions of sections 503, 511, 3470, 3471, 3474, 3476, 3482(g), 3483, and 3485 of title 38 and the provisions of subchapters II and III of chapter 36 of such title (with the exception of sections 3686(a), 3687, and 3692) shall be applicable to the provision of educational assistance under this chapter. The term “eligible veteran” and the term “person”, as used in those provisions, shall be deemed for the purpose of the application of those provisions to this section to refer to a person eligible for educational assistance under paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (1), nothing in this section shall prohibit a National Call to Service participant who satisfies through service under subsection (c) the eligibility requirements for educational assistance under chapter 1606 of this title or basic educational assistance under chapter 30 of title 38 from an entitlement to such educational assistance under chapter 1606 of this title or basic educational assistance under chapter 30 of title 38, as the case may be.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A participant who made an election not to receive educational assistance under either such chapter at the applicable time specified under law or who was denied the opportunity to make an election may revoke that election or make an initial election, as the case may be, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary concerned may specify. A revocation or initial election under the preceding sentence is irrevocable.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The participant making a revocation or initial election under clause (i) shall be eligible for educational assistance under either such chapter at such time as the participant satisfies through service the applicable eligibility requirements under either such chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repayment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a National Call to Service participant who has entered into an agreement under subsection (b) and received or benefitted from an incentive under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (e) fails to complete the total period of service specified in the agreement, the National Call to Service participant shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Amounts for the payment of incentives under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (e) shall be derived from amounts available to the Secretary of the military department concerned for the payment of pay, allowances and other expenses of the members of the armed force concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts for the payment of incentives under paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (e) shall be derived from the Department of Defense Education Benefits Fund under <ref>section 2006 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments shall prescribe regulations for purposes of the program under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Americorps” means the Americorps program carried out under subtitle C of title I of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12571</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “qualifying student loan” means a loan, the proceeds of which were used to pay any part or all of the cost of attendance (as defined in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1087</ref><i>ll</i>) at an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary of a military department” includes, with respect to matters concerning the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 531(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2541</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 535(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 545</ref>, title VI, § 687(c)(1), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3254</ref>, 3333; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VI, § 618(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1426</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1717(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 655</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 511.</num>
<heading> College First Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of each military department may establish a program to increase the number of, and the level of the qualifications of, persons entering the armed forces as enlisted members by encouraging recruits to pursue higher education or vocational or technical training before entry into active service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delayed Entry With Allowance for Higher Education</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary concerned may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> exercise the authority under <ref>section 513 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to accept the enlistment of a person as a Reserve for service in the Selected Reserve or Individual Ready Reserve of a reserve component, or as a member of the Space Force, notwithstanding the scope of the authority under subsection (a) of that section, in the case of the Army National Guard of the United States or Air National Guard of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to authorize, notwithstanding the period limitation in subsection (b) of that section, a delay of the enlistment of any such person in a regular component under that subsection for the period during which the person is enrolled in, and pursuing a program of education at, an institution of higher education, or a program of vocational or technical training, on a full-time basis that is to be completed within the maximum period of delay determined for that person under subsection (c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> subject to paragraph (2) of subsection (d) and except as provided in paragraph (3) of that subsection, pay an allowance to a person accepted for enlistment under paragraph (1)(A) for each month of the period during which that person is enrolled in and pursuing a program described in paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum Period of Delay</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The period of delay authorized a person under paragraph (1)(B) of subsection (b) may not exceed the 30-month period beginning on the date of the person’s enlistment accepted under paragraph (1)(A) of such subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allowance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The monthly allowance paid under subsection (b)(2) shall be equal to the amount of the subsistence allowance provided for certain members of the Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps with the corresponding number of years of participation under <ref>section 209(a) of title 37</ref>. The Secretary concerned may supplement that stipend by an amount not to exceed $225 per month.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An allowance may not be paid to a person under this section for more than 24 months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A member of the Selected Reserve of a reserve component may be paid an allowance under this section only for months during which the member performs satisfactorily as a member of a unit of the reserve component that trains as prescribed in <ref>section 10147(a)(1) of this title</ref> or <ref>section 502(a) of title 32</ref>. Satisfactory performance shall be determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An allowance under this section is in addition to any other pay or allowance to which a member of a reserve component is entitled by reason of participation in the Ready Reserve of that component.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recoupment of Allowance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A person who, after receiving an allowance under this section, fails to complete the total period of service required of that person in connection with delayed entry authorized for the person under section 513 shall repay the United States the amount which bears the same ratio to the total amount of that allowance paid to the person as the unserved part of the total required period of service bears to the total period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An obligation to repay the United States imposed under paragraph (1) is for all purposes a debt owed to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A discharge of a person in bankruptcy under title 11 that is entered less than five years after the date on which the person was, or was to be, enlisted in the regular Army pursuant to the delayed entry authority under section 513 does not discharge that person from a debt arising under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may waive, in whole or in part, a debt arising under paragraph (1) in any case for which the Secretary determines that recovery would be against equity and good conscience or would be contrary to the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Pay and Bonuses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon enlisting in the regular component of the member’s armed force, a person who initially enlisted as a Reserve under this section may, at the discretion of the Secretary concerned, be eligible for all regular special pays, bonuses, education benefits, and loan repayment programs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 551(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1909</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1717(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 655</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 512.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12104]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 513.</num>
<heading> Enlistments: Delayed Entry Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A person with no prior military service who is qualified under <ref>section 505 of this title</ref> and applicable regulations for enlistment in a regular component of an armed force, or who is qualified under <ref>section 20301 of this title</ref> and applicable regulations for enlistment in the Space Force, may (except as provided in subsection (c)) be enlisted as a Reserve for service in the Army Reserve, Navy Reserve, Air Force Reserve, Marine Corps Reserve, or Coast Guard Reserve, or be enlisted as a member of the Space Force, for a term of not less than six years nor more than eight years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Unless sooner ordered to active duty under chapter 39 of this title or another provision of law, a person enlisted under subsection (a) shall, within 365 days after such enlistment, be discharged from the reserve component in which enlisted and immediately be enlisted in the regular component of an armed force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may extend the 365-day period described in paragraph (1) for any person for up to an additional 365 days if the Secretary determines that it is in the best interests of the armed force of which that person is a member to do so.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may extend by up to an additional 365 days the period of extension under paragraph (2) for a person who enlisted before <date date="2017-10-01">October 1, 2017</date>, under <ref>section 504(b)(2) of this title</ref> if the Secretary determines that the period of extension under this paragraph is required for the performance of adequate background and security reviews of that person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A person whose period of extension under paragraph (2) is extended under this paragraph shall undergo all security and suitability screening requirements and receive a favorable military security suitability determination before entering into service in a regular or reserve component. Screening priority shall be given to those persons who were enlisted for a military occupational specialty that requires specialized language or medical skills that are vital to the national interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The authority to make an extension under this paragraph shall expire one year after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018. The expiration of such authority shall not effect the validity of any extension made in accordance with this paragraph on or before that date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> During the period beginning on the date on which the person enlists under subsection (a) and ending on the date on which the person is enlisted in a regular component under this subsection, the person shall be in the Ready Reserve of the armed force concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A person who is under orders to report for induction into an armed force under the Military Selective Service Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.), except as provided in clause (ii) or (iii) of section 6(c)(2)(A) of that Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3806(c)(2)(A)</ref>), may not be enlisted under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> This section shall be carried out under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 501(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1435</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1484(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2514</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 572(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 623</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1081(b)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 526</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1717(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 655</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 514.</num>
<heading> Bounties prohibited; substitutes prohibited</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No bounty may be paid to induce any person to enlist in an armed force. A clothing allowance or enlistment bonus authorized by law is not a bounty for the purposes of this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> No person liable for active duty in an armed force under this subtitle may furnish a substitute for that active duty. No person may be enlisted or appointed in an armed force as a substitute for another person.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 19</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 515.</num>
<heading> Reenlistment after discharge as warrant officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person who has been discharged from a regular component of an armed force under section 1165 or 1166 of this title may, upon his request and in the discretion of the Secretary concerned, be enlisted in that armed force in the grade prescribed by the Secretary. However, a person discharged under <ref>section 1165 of this title</ref> may not be enlisted in a grade lower than the grade that he held immediately before appointment as a warrant officer.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 19</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 516.</num>
<heading> Effect upon enlisted status of acceptance of appointment as cadet or midshipman</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The enlistment or period of obligated service of an enlisted member of the armed forces who accepts an appointment as a cadet at the United States Military Academy, the United States Air Force Academy, or the United States Coast Guard Academy, or as a midshipman at the United States Naval Academy or in the Navy Reserve, may not be terminated because of the acceptance of that appointment. However, while serving as a cadet or midshipman at an Academy, he is entitled only to the pay, allowances, compensation, pensions, and other benefits provided by law for such a cadet or midshipman or, if he is a midshipman in the Navy Reserve, to the compensation and emoluments of a midshipman in the Navy Reserve.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If a person covered by subsection (a) is separated from service as a cadet or midshipman, or from service as a midshipman in the Navy Reserve, for any reason other than his appointment as a commissioned officer of a regular or reserve component of an armed force or in the Space Force, or because of a physical disability, he resumes his enlisted status and shall complete the period of service for which he was enlisted or for which he has an obligation, unless he is sooner discharged. In computing the unexpired part of an enlistment or period of obligated service for the purposes of this subsection, all service as a cadet or midshipman is counted as service under that enlistment or period of obligated service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(9)(A)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1439</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1717(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 655</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 517.</num>
<heading> Authorized enlisted end strength: members in pay grades E–8 and E–9</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The authorized end strength for enlisted members on active duty (other than for training) in an armed force in pay grades E–8 and E–9 as of the last day of a fiscal year may not be more than 3.0 percent and 1.25 percent, respectively, of the number of enlisted members of that armed force who are on active duty (other than for training). In computing the limitations prescribed in the preceding sentence, there shall be excluded enlisted members of an armed force on active duty as authorized under section 115(a)(1)(B) or 115(b) of this title, or excluded from counting for active duty end strengths under <ref>section 115(i) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(b)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IV, § 403(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3556</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whenever under <ref>section 527 of this title</ref> the President may suspend the operation of any provision of section 523, 525, or 526 of this title, the Secretary of Defense may suspend the operation of any provision of this section. Any such suspension shall, if not sooner ended, end in the manner specified in section 527 for a suspension under that section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 492</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–584, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-12-23">Dec. 23, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title V, § 503(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1107</ref>, 1108; <ref>Pub. L. 97–252, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title IV</ref>, §§ 413(a), 414(a)(2), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2517</ref>, 2518; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title IV, § 413(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 619</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title IV, § 413(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1083</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IV, § 413(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title IV, § 413(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1352</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IV, § 413(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 552(a)</ref>, title XVI, § 1662(a)(4), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2772</ref>, 2988; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title IV, § 407(a)</ref>, title X, § 1069(a)(2), <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1996</ref>, 2135; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title IV, § 421(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–95; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1069</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IV, § 416(f)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1868</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 89</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 518.</num>
<heading> Temporary enlistments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Temporary enlistments may be made only in the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, or Coast Guard, as the case may be, without specification of component.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 755</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(2)(A)(iii)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 519.</num>
<heading> Temporary enlistments: during war or emergency</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 505 of this title</ref> and except for enlistments as Reserves of an armed force—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> temporary enlistments in an armed force entered into in time of war or of emergency declared by Congress shall be for the duration of the war or emergency plus six months; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> only persons at least eighteen years of age and otherwise qualified under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary concerned are eligible for such enlistments.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 755</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 520.</num>
<heading> Limitation on enlistment and induction of persons whose score on the Armed Forces Qualification Test is below a prescribed level</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The number of persons originally enlisted or inducted to serve on active duty (other than active duty for training) in any armed force during any fiscal year whose score on the Armed Forces Qualification Test is at or above the tenth percentile and below the thirty-first percentile may not exceed 4 percent of the total number of persons originally enlisted or inducted to serve on active duty (other than active duty for training) in such armed force during such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon the request of the Secretary concerned, the Secretary of Defense may authorize an armed force to increase the limitation specified in paragraph (1) to not exceed 20 percent of the total number of persons originally enlisted or inducted to serve on active duty (other than active duty for training) in such armed force during such fiscal year. The Secretary of Defense shall notify the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than 30 days after using such authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A person who is not a high school graduate may not be accepted for enlistment in the armed forces unless the score of that person on the Armed Forces Qualification Test is at or above the thirty-first percentile; however, a person may not be denied enlistment in the armed forces solely because of his not having a high school diploma if his enlistment is needed to meet established strength requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–342, title III, § 302(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-08">Sept. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1082</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–579, § 9</ref>, <date date="1980-12-23">Dec. 23, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3368</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1104</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title XII, § 1268(3)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 542</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 264</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 520a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1076(g)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–282]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 520b.</num>
<heading> Applicants for enlistment: authority to use funds for the issue of authorized articles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense may be used for the issue of authorized articles to applicants for enlistment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1401(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2614</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1303(a)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 520c.</num>
<heading> Recruiting functions: provision of meals and refreshments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for recruitment of military personnel may be expended for small meals and refreshments during recruiting functions for the following persons:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Persons who have enlisted under the Delayed Entry Program authorized by <ref>section 513 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Persons who are objects of armed forces recruiting efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Persons whose assistance in recruiting efforts of the military departments is determined to be influential by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Members of the armed forces and Federal employees when attending recruiting functions in accordance with a requirement to do so.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Other persons whose presence at recruiting functions will contribute to recruiting efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 361(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2491</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 545</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1113</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(8)(A)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1596</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>