<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 773—</num>
<heading>DISPOSAL OF OBSOLETE OR SURPLUS MATERIAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7682.</num>
<heading> Obsolete or excess material: sale to National Council of Boy Scouts of America</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to regulations under <ref>section 121 of title 40</ref>, the Secretary of the Army, under such conditions as he may prescribe, may sell obsolete or excess material to the National Council of the Boy Scouts of America. Sales under this section shall be at fair value to the Department of the Army, including packing, handling, and transportation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 262</ref>, § 4682; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 512(19)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(25)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1297</ref>; renumbered § 7682, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7683.</num>
<heading> Excess non-automatic service rifles: loan or donation for funeral and other ceremonial purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Lend or Donate</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, may conditionally lend or donate excess M–1 rifles (not more than 15), slings, and cartridge belts to any eligible organization for use by that organization for funeral ceremonies of a member or former member of the armed forces, and for other ceremonial purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the rifles to be loaned or donated under paragraph (1) are to be used by the eligible organization for funeral ceremonies of a member or former member of the armed forces, the Secretary may issue and deliver the rifles, together with the necessary accoutrements and blank ammunition, without charge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> In order to meet the needs of an eligible organization with respect to performing funeral and other ceremonies, if the Secretary determines appropriate, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> loan or donate excess non-automatic service rifles to an eligible organization; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> authorize an eligible organization to retain non-automatic service rifles other than M–1 rifles.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to supersede any Federal law or regulation governing the use or ownership of firearms.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relief From Liability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may relieve an eligible organization to which materials are lent or donated under subsection (a), and the surety on its bond, from liability for loss or destruction of the material lent or donated, if there is conclusive evidence that the loss or destruction did not result from negligence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions on Loan or Donation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In lending or donating rifles under subsection (a), the Secretary shall impose such conditions on the use of the rifles as may be necessary to ensure security, safety, and accountability. The Secretary may impose such other conditions as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Organization Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “eligible organization” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a unit or other organization of honor guards recognized by the Secretary of the Army as honor guards for a national cemetery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a law enforcement agency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a local unit of any organization that, as determined by the Secretary of the Army, is a nationally recognized veterans’ organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 262</ref>, § 4683; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1602</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title III, § 381(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 582</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1935</ref>; renumbered § 7683, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7684.</num>
<heading> Surplus obsolete ordnance: sale to patriotic organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to regulations under <ref>section 121 of title 40</ref>, any branch, office, or officer designated by the Secretary of the Army may sell, without advertisement and at prices that he considers reasonable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> surplus obsolete small arms and ammunition and equipment for them, to any patriotic organization for military purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> surplus obsolete brass or bronze cannons, carriages, and cannon balls, for public parks, public buildings, and soldiers’ monuments.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 262</ref>, § 4684; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 512(19)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(26)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1297</ref>; renumbered § 7684, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7685.</num>
<heading> Obsolete ordnance: loan to educational institutions and State soldiers and sailors’ orphans’ homes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Upon the recommendation of the governor of the State concerned or Guam or the Virgin Islands, the Secretary of the Army, under regulations to be prescribed by him and without cost to the United States for transportation, may lend obsolete ordnance and ordnance stores to State, Guam, and the Virgin Islands educational institutions and to State soldiers and sailors’ orphans’ homes, for drill and instruction. However, no loan may be made under this subsection to an institution to which ordnance or ordnance stores may be issued under any law that was in effect on <date date="1906-06-30">June 30, 1906</date>, and is still in effect.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall require a bond from each institution or home to which property is lent under subsection (a), in double the value of the property lent, for the care and safekeeping of that property and, except for property properly expended, for its return when required.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 263</ref>, § 4685; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3441</ref>; renumbered § 7685, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7686.</num>
<heading> Obsolete ordnance: gift to State homes for soldiers and sailors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to regulations under <ref>section 121 of title 40</ref>, the Secretary of the Army may give not more than two obsolete bronze or iron cannons suitable for firing salutes to any home for soldiers or sailors established and maintained under State authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 263</ref>, § 4686; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 512(19)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(27)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1297</ref>; renumbered § 7686, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7687.</num>
<heading> Sale of excess, obsolete, or unserviceable ammunition and ammunition components</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Sell Outside DoD</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Army may sell to an eligible purchaser described in subsection (c) ammunition or ammunition components that are excess, obsolete, or unserviceable and have not been demilitarized if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the purchaser enters into an agreement, in advance, with the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to demilitarize the ammunition or components; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to reclaim, recycle, or reuse the component parts or materials; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary, or an official of the Department of the Army designated by the Secretary, approves the use of the ammunition or components proposed by the purchaser as being consistent with the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Method of Sale</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall use competitive procedures to sell ammunition and ammunition components under this section, except that the Secretary may use procedures other than competitive procedures in any case in which the Secretary determines that there is only one potential buyer of the items being offered for sale.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Purchasers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To be eligible to purchase excess, obsolete, or unserviceable ammunition or ammunition components under this section, the purchaser shall be a licensed manufacturer (as defined in <ref>section 921(a)(10) of title 18</ref>) that, as determined by the Secretary, has a capability to modify, reclaim, transport, and either store or sell the ammunition or ammunition components sought to be purchased.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Hold Harmless Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall require a purchaser of ammunition or ammunition components under this section to agree to hold harmless and indemnify the United States from any claim for damages for death, injury, or other loss resulting from a use of the ammunition or ammunition components, except in a case of willful misconduct or gross negligence of a representative of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Verification of Demilitarization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish procedures for ensuring that a purchaser of ammunition or ammunition components under this section demilitarizes the ammunition or ammunition components in accordance with any agreement to do so under subsection (a)(1). The procedures shall include onsite verification of demilitarization activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may accept ammunition, ammunition components, or ammunition demilitarization services as consideration for ammunition or ammunition components sold under this section. The fair market value of any such consideration shall be equal to or exceed the fair market value or, if higher, the sale price of the ammunition or ammunition components sold.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Arms Export Control Act</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the applicability of section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2778</ref>) to sales of ammunition or ammunition components on the United States Munitions List.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “excess, obsolete, or unserviceable”, with respect to ammunition or ammunition components, means that the ammunition or ammunition components are no longer necessary for war reserves or for support of training of the Army or production of ammunition or ammunition components.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “demilitarize”, with respect to ammunition or ammunition components—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means to destroy the military offensive or defensive advantages inherent in the ammunition or ammunition components; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes any mutilation, scrapping, melting, burning, or alteration that prevents the use of the ammunition or ammunition components for the military purposes for which the ammunition or ammunition components was designed or for a lethal purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1065(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1893</ref>, § 4687; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(30)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2399</ref>; renumbered § 7687, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7688.</num>
<heading> Armor-piercing ammunition and components: condition on disposal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Resale or Other Transfer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), whenever the Secretary of the Army carries out a disposal (by sale or otherwise) of armor-piercing ammunition, or a component of armor-piercing ammunition, the Secretary shall require as a condition of the disposal that the recipient agree in writing not to sell or otherwise transfer any of the ammunition (reconditioned or otherwise), or any armor-piercing component of that ammunition, to any purchaser in the United States other than a law enforcement or other governmental agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) does not apply to a transfer of a component of armor-piercing ammunition solely for the purpose of metal reclamation by means of a destructive process such as melting, crushing, or shredding.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Rule for Non-Armor-Piercing Components</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A component of the armor-piercing ammunition that is not itself armor-piercing and is not subjected to metal reclamation as described in subsection (b) may not be used as a component in the production of new or remanufactured armor-piercing ammunition other than for sale to a law enforcement or other governmental agency or for a government-to-government sale or commercial export to a foreign government under the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “armor-piercing ammunition” means a center-fire cartridge the military designation of which includes the term “armor penetrator” or “armor-piercing”, including a center-fire cartridge designated as armor-piercing incendiary (API) or armor-piercing incendiary-tracer (API–T).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, § 382(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–85, § 4688; renumbered § 7688, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7689.</num>
<heading> Transfer of material and equipment to the Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army is authorized to transfer, without payment, to the Architect of the Capitol, such material and equipment, not required by the Department of the Army, as the Architect may request for use at the Capitol power plant, the Capitol, and the Senate and House Office Buildings.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1294</ref>, § 4689; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(29)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2063</ref>; renumbered § 7689, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7690.</num>
<heading> Recyclable munitions materials: sale; use of proceeds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority for Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 2577 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the Army may carry out a program to sell recyclable munitions materials resulting from the demilitarization of conventional military munitions without regard to chapter 5 of title 40 and use any proceeds in accordance with subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Method of Sale</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall use competitive procedures to sell recyclable munitions materials under this section in a manner consistent with Federal procurement laws and regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proceeds</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Proceeds from the sale of recyclable munitions materials under this section shall be credited to an account that is specified as being for Army ammunition demilitarization from funds made available for the procurement of ammunition, to be available only for reclamation, recycling, and reuse of conventional military munitions (including research and development and equipment purchased for such purpose).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts credited under this subsection shall be available for obligation for the fiscal year during which the funds are so credited and for three subsequent fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out the program established under this section. Such regulations shall be consistent and in compliance with the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.) and the regulations implementing that Act.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title III, § 353(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2161</ref>, § 4690; renumbered § 7690, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>