<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 9—</num>
<heading>DEFENSE BUDGET MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 221.</num>
<heading> Future-years defense program: submission to Congress; consistency in budgeting</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress each year, not later than five days after the date on which the President’s budget is submitted to Congress that year under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, a future-years defense program (including associated annexes) reflecting the estimated expenditures and proposed appropriations included in that budget. Any such future-years defense program shall cover the fiscal year with respect to which the budget is submitted and at least the four succeeding fiscal years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that amounts described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2) for any fiscal year are consistent with amounts described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (2) for that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Amounts referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The amounts specified in program and budget information submitted to Congress by the Secretary in support of expenditure estimates and proposed appropriations in the budget submitted to Congress by the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref> for any fiscal year, as shown in the future-years defense program submitted pursuant to subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The total amounts of estimated expenditures and proposed appropriations necessary to support the programs, projects, and activities of the Department of Defense included pursuant to paragraph (5) of <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref> in the budget submitted to Congress under that section for any fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the inclusion in the future-years defense program of amounts for management contingencies, subject to the requirements of subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall make available to Congress, the Congressional Budget Office, the Comptroller General of the United States, and the Congressional Research Service each future-years defense program under this section as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> By making such program available electronically in the form of an unclassified electronic database.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> By delivering printed copies of such program to the congressional defense committees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the event inclusion of classified material in a future-years defense program would otherwise render the totality of the program classified for purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such program shall be made available to Congress in unclassified form, with such material attached as a classified annex; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such annex shall be submitted to the congressional defense committees, the Congressional Budget Office, the Comptroller General of the United States, and the Congressional Research Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Each future-years defense program under this subsection shall be accompanied by a certification by the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller), in the case of the Department of Defense, and the comptroller of each military department, in the case of such military department, that any information entered into the Standard Data Collection System of the Department of Defense, the Comptroller Information System, or any other data system, as applicable, for purposes of assembling such future-years defense program was accurate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1602(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1596</ref>, § 114a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1402(a)(1)</ref>–(3)(A), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1674</ref>; renumbered § 221 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1002(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2480</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1042(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1553</ref>, 1554.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 222.</num>
<heading> Future-years mission budget</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Future-Years Mission Budget</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress for each fiscal year a future-years mission budget for the military programs of the Department of Defense. That budget shall be submitted for any fiscal year with the future-years defense program submitted under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consistency With Future-Years Defense Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The future-years mission budget shall be consistent with the future-years defense program required under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>. In the future-years mission budget, the military programs of the Department of Defense shall be organized on the basis of major force programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Defense Budget Formats</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirement in subsection (a) is in addition to the requirements in any other provision of law regarding the format for the presentation regarding military programs of the Department of Defense in the budget submitted pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> for any fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1002(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2480</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1004</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 944(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 289</ref>, 290; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1595</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 222a.</num>
<heading> Unfunded priorities of the armed forces and combatant commands: annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 10 days after the date on which the budget of the President for a fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, each officer specified in subsection (b) shall submit to the Secretary of Defense and the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and to the congressional defense committees, a report on the unfunded priorities of the armed force or forces or combatant command under the jurisdiction or command of such officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The officers specified in this subsection are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chief of Staff of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chief of Naval Operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Chief of Staff of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Commandant of the Marine Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Chief of Space Operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The commanders of the combatant commands established under <ref>section 161 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Chief of the National Guard Bureau in the role assigned to that position in <ref>section 10502(c)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Elements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report under this subsection shall specify, for each unfunded priority covered by such report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A summary description of such priority, including the objectives outlined in the national defense strategy required under <ref>section 113(g) of this title</ref> and the National Military Strategy required under <ref>section 139(b) of this title</ref> to be advanced if such priority is funded (whether in whole or in part).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The additional amount of funds recommended in connection with the objectives under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Account information with respect to such priority, including the following (as applicable):</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Line Item Number (LIN) for applicable procurement accounts.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Program Element (PE) number for applicable research, development, test, and evaluation accounts.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Sub-activity group (SAG) for applicable operation and maintenance accounts.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A detailed assessment of each specific risk that would be reduced in executing the national defense strategy required under <ref>section 113(g) of this title</ref> and the National Military Strategy required under <ref>section 139(b) of this title</ref> if such priority is funded (whether in whole or in part).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The requirement to be addressed by the unfunded priority.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The reason why funding for the priority was not included in the budget of the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> A description of any funding provided for the requirement for the current and preceding fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> An assessment of the effect that providing funding for the priority would have on the future-years defense plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prioritization of priorities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report shall present the unfunded priorities covered by such report as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In overall order of urgency of priority according to the amount of risk reduced.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In overall order of urgency of priority among unfunded priorities (other than covered military construction projects).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In overall order of urgency of priority among covered military construction projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">National guard unfunded priorities.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The officer specified under subsection (b)(7) shall only include in a report submitted under subsection (a) such priorities that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> relate to equipping requirements in support of non-federalized National Guard responsibilities for the homeland defense or civil support missions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> except as provided in subparagraph (B), were not included in a report under this section submitted by an officer specified in subsection (b)(1) or (3) for any of five fiscal years preceding the fiscal year for which the report is submitted, on behalf of National Guard forces to address a warfighting requirement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The officer specified under subsection (b)(7) may include in a report submitted under subsection (a) an unfunded priority covered by subparagraph (A)(ii) if the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> determines that the inclusion such unfunded priority reasonably supports the priorities of the Department under the national defense strategy under <ref>section 113(g) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> submits to the congressional defense committees written notice of such determination.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prioritization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 10 days after the receipt of all of the reports referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report that prioritizes each specific unfunded priority across all unfunded priorities submitted by officers specified in (b) according to the risk reduced in executing the national defense strategy required under <ref>section 113(g) of this title</ref> and the National Military Strategy required under <ref>section 139(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “unfunded priority”, in the case of a fiscal year, means a program, activity, or mission requirement, including a covered military construction project, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is not funded in the budget of the President for the fiscal year as submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is necessary to fulfill a requirement associated with an operational or contingency plan of a combatant command or other validated requirement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> would have been recommended for funding through the budget referred to in subparagraph (1) by the officer submitting the report required by subsection (a) in connection with the budget if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> additional resources had been available for the budget to fund the program, activity, or mission requirement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the program, activity, or mission requirement has emerged since the budget was formulated.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered military construction project”, in connection with a fiscal year, means a military construction project that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is included in any fiscal year of the future-years defense program under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref> that is submitted in connection with the budget of the President for the fiscal year, and is executable in the fiscal year; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is considered by the commander of a combatant command referred to in subsection (b)(5) to be an urgent need, and is executable in the fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1064(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2408</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title X, § 1005</ref>, title XVII, § 1731(a)(12), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1573</ref>, 1813; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(10)</ref>, title X, §§ 1006, 1081(a)(12), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3823</ref>, 3838, 3871; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 384(b)</ref>, title X, § 1051, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2544</ref>, 2775; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1003</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 379</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 222b.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2199</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 222c.</num>
<heading> Armed forces: Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirements; Out-Year inventory numbers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At the same time each year that the budget for the fiscal year beginning in such year is submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, the chief of staff of each armed force (other than the Coast Guard) shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report setting forth for such armed force each of the following for such fiscal year, broken out as specified in subsection (c):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Out-Year inventory numbers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Delegation of Submittal Responsibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The responsibility of the chief of staff of an armed force in subsection (a) to submit a report may not be delegated outside the armed force concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presentation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement and Out-Year inventory numbers for an armed force for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (a) shall include specific inventory objective requirements for each variant of munitions with respect to each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Combat Requirement, broken out by operation plan (OPLAN).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Current Operation/Forward Presence Requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Strategic Readiness Requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Homeland Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Training and Testing Requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Total Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement, calculated in accordance with the implementation guidance described in subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Out-year worldwide inventory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Requirement for Protracted Warfare Scenarios, calculated by doubling the duration of each applicable operation plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation Guidance Used</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In submitting information pursuant to subsection (a) for a fiscal year, the chief of staff of each armed force shall describe and explain the munitions requirements process implementation guidance developed by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment and used by such armed force for the munitions requirements process for such armed force for that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The number of years required to meet the Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement at the rate requested for the fiscal year covered by the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The average rate of procurement during the three-year period preceding the date of the submission of the report, and the number of years required to meet the Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement at such three-year average rate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The additional amount of funding that would be required, for each fiscal year, to meet the Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement for each munition by the end of the period covered by the most recent future-years defense program submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “chief of staff”, with respect to the Marine Corps, means the Commandant of the Marine Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement” has the meaning given that term in and for purposes of Department of Defense Instruction 3000.04, or any successor instruction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1969</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title X, § 1006</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1574</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 222d.</num>
<heading> Annual report on industrial base constraints for munitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after the submission of all reports required under <ref>section 222c(a) of this title</ref>, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, in coordination with the service acquisition executive of each military department, shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report detailing the industrial base constraints for each munition identified in the Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements, broken down by munition:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Programmed purchase quantities per year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Average procurement unit cost per year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Contract type.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Current minimum sustaining rate of production per month and year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Current maximum rate of production per month and year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Expected date to meet the Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement in <ref>section 222c of this title</ref> under the programmed purchase quantities established for the period covered by the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> A description of industrial base constraints on increased production of each munition, including any supply chain weaknesses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> A description of investments or policy changes made by a defense contractor or by the United States Government to increase production, enable more efficient production, or mitigate significant loss of stability in potential production.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> A description of potential investments or policy changes identified by a defense contractor or the United States Government to increase munitions production, enable more efficient production, or mitigate significant loss of stability in potential production, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> direct investments in test and tooling equipment, workforce development, or improvements to existing production facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a pool of rotable critical components or subcomponents for munitions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> multiyear contracts or other contracting strategies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> direct investments in components, subcomponents, or raw materials commonly used across the industrial base;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> direct investments in additive manufacturing or expeditionary manufacturing capabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> direct investments in simplification of supply chains; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> direct investments in technologies or methods to enable increased scalability and reduced complexity of production processes for current or future munitions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> A list of each contract for a munition with a priority rating of “critical to national defense” (commonly referred to as a “DO-rated order”) or a priority rating of “highest national defense urgency” (commonly referred to as a “DX-rated order”) in the Defense Priorities and Allocation System pursuant to part 700 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> A prioritized list of munitions judged to have high value for export for which additional investments would be necessary to enable export, including a description of such investments required.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> A list of munitions subject to the requirements of chapter 2 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2761</ref> et seq.) relating to foreign military sales that are anticipated to be exported based on developments in the conflict in Ukraine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Munition Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “munition” has the meaning given by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 222e.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002017">1</ref></num>
<heading> Programs, projects, and activities that were internally changed in the submission of the President’s budget: annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Secretaries of the military departments and the officers of Department of Defense agencies and offices not under the control of a Secretary of a military department, shall submit to the congressional defense committees each year, not later than 30 days after the submission of the budget of the President for the fiscal year beginning in such year under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, a report that includes organized tabulations of programs, projects, and activities in research, development, test, and evaluation, procurement, and military construction the total obligational authority for which was changed in the current budget year proposal compared to the prior-year projection for the current year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The tabulations required under subsection (a) shall include, for each program, project, or activity that was internally changed, the following elements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whether the program, project, or activity was added, eliminated, or reduced and in which fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The appropriations sub-account.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The appropriate program element, line item number, or sub-activity group.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The program, project, or activity name.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The prior year enacted appropriation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The prior year projected current year budget.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The current year budget request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> If applicable, the amount reduced or saved by the current year elimination or reduction over the future years defense plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> A characterization of the change as a fact-of-life change, a prioritization change, a programmatic change, or a change due to congressional action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in machine readable, electronic form.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1002</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 378</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 222e.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002018">1</ref></num>
<heading> Unfunded priorities of the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering: annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 10 days after the date on which the budget of the President for a fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary of Defense, after coordinating with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the unfunded priorities of the Department of Defense related to activities for which the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering has authority.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Elements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (c), each report submitted under subsection (a) shall specify, for each unfunded priority covered by such report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A summary description of such priority, including the objectives to be achieved if such priority is funded (whether in whole or in part).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The additional amount of funds recommended in connection with the objectives under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Account information with respect to such priority, including the following (as applicable):</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Line Item Number (LIN) for applicable procurement accounts.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Program Element (PE) number for applicable research, development, test, and evaluation accounts.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prioritization of priorities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The report under subsection (a) shall present the unfunded priorities covered by such report in order of urgency of priority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of Priorities Covered in Other Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The report submitted under subsection (a) shall not include unfunded priorities or requirements covered in reports submitted under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> section 222a or 222b <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002019">2</ref> of this title; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> section 2806 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 (<ref>Public Law 115–91</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 222a</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Form of Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall be submitted in classified form, but may include an unclassified summary as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unfunded Priority Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “unfunded priority”, in the case of a fiscal year, means a program, activity, or mission requirement, that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is not funded in the budget of the President for the fiscal year as submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> would have been recommended for funding through that budget if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> additional resources had been available for the budget to fund the program, activity, or mission requirement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the program, activity, or mission requirement has emerged since the budget was formulated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of a military construction project, has reached 35 percent design.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 182</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1824</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 223.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2199</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 223a.</num>
<heading> Ballistic missile defense programs: procurement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget Justification Materials</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department of Defense budget for any fiscal year (as submitted with the budget of the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>), the Secretary of Defense shall specify, for each ballistic missile defense system element for which the Missile Defense Agency is engaged in planning for production and initial fielding, the following information:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The production rate capabilities of the production facilities planned to be used for production of that element.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The potential date of availability of that element for initial fielding.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The estimated date on which the administration of the acquisition of that element is to be transferred from the Director of the Missile Defense Agency to the Secretary of a military department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Future-Years Defense Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall include in the future-years defense program submitted to Congress each year under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref> an estimate of the amount necessary for procurement for each ballistic missile defense system element, together with a discussion of the underlying factors and reasoning justifying the estimate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance Criteria</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Missile Defense Agency shall include in the performance criteria prescribed for planned development phases of the ballistic missile defense system and its elements a description of the intended effectiveness of each such phase against foreign adversary capabilities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title II, § 223(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1420</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1060(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3502</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 224.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2199</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 225.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2199</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 226.</num>
<heading> Special operations forces: display of service-common and other support and enabling capabilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of each of the military departments shall include, in the budget materials submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> for fiscal year 2022 and any subsequent fiscal year, a budget justification display for each applicable appropriation showing service-common and other support and enabling capabilities for special operations forces requested by a military service or Defense Agency. Such budget justification displays shall include each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Details at the appropriation and line item level, including any amount for service-common support, acquisition support, training, operations, pay and allowances, base operations sustainment, and any other common services and support.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An identification of any change in the level or type of service-common support and enabling capabilities provided by each of the military services or Defense Agencies to special operations forces for the fiscal year covered by the budget justification display when compared to the preceding fiscal year, including the rationale for any such change and any mitigating actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An assessment of the specific effects that the budget justification display for the fiscal year covered by the display and any anticipated future manpower and force structure changes are likely to have on the ability of each of the military services to provide service-common support and enabling capabilities to special operations forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any other matters the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department determines are relevant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consolidated Budget Justification Display</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall include, in the budget materials submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, for fiscal year 2022 and any subsequent fiscal year, a consolidated budget justification display containing the same information as is required in the budget justification displays required under subsection (a). Such consolidated budget justification display may be provided as a summary by appropriation for each military department and a summary by appropriation for all Defense Agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service-common and Other Support and Enabling Capabilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “service-common and other support and enabling capabilities” means capabilities provided in support of special operations that are not reflected in Major Force Program–11 or designated as special operations forces-peculiar.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title X, § 1007(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1575</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1002</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 227.</num>
<heading> Budget justification for covered military unaccompanied housing Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Along with the budget for each fiscal year submitted by the President pursuant to <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, each Secretary of a military department shall include a consolidated budget justification display for the congressional defense committees that individually identifies—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the fiscal year covered by the budget, the total requested expenditure for Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization projects for covered military unaccompanied housing compared to the total expenditure required by such projects, disaggregated by military department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the total expenditure for Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization projects made during the fiscal year beginning two years before the fiscal year covered by the budget, disaggregated by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> military installation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the type of facility repaired or restored under such repair projects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number of such repair projects that were for sustainment or repair of a facility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the number of such repair projects that were for restoration or modernization of a facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “covered military unaccompanied housing” has the meaning given in <ref>section 2856 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The terms “facility” and “military installation” have the meanings given, respectively, in <ref>section 2801 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “repair project” has the meaning given in <ref>section 2811 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2253</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 228.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 995</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 229.</num>
<heading> Programs for combating terrorism: display of budget information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission With Annual Budget Justification Documents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress, as a part of the documentation that supports the President’s annual budget for the Department of Defense, a consolidated budget justification display, in classified and unclassified form, that includes all programs and activities of the Department of Defense combating terrorism program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Budget Display</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The budget display under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount requested, by appropriation and functional area, for each of the program elements, projects, and initiatives that support the Department of Defense combating terrorism program, with supporting narrative descriptions and rationale for the funding levels requested; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a summary, to the program element and project level of detail, of estimated expenditures for the current year, funds requested for the budget year, and budget estimates through the completion of the current future-years defense plan for the Department of Defense combating terrorism program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Explanation of Inconsistencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As part of the budget display under subsection (a) for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall identify and explain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any inconsistencies between (A) the information submitted under subsection (b) for that fiscal year, and (B) the information provided to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget in support of the annual report of the President to Congress on funding for executive branch counterterrorism and antiterrorism programs and activities for that fiscal year in accordance with section 1051(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998 (<ref>31 U.S.C. 1113</ref> note); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any inconsistencies between (A) the execution, during the previous fiscal year and the current fiscal year, of programs and activities of the Department of Defense combating terrorism program, and (B) the funding and specification for such programs and activities for those fiscal years in the manner provided by Congress (both in statutes and in relevant legislative history).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Department of Defense Combating Terrorism Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Department of Defense combating terrorism program” means the programs, projects, and activities of the Department of Defense related to combating terrorism inside and outside the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirement to submit a budget justification display under this section shall terminate on <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title IX, § 932(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 727</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1043(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1044</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 977</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1032</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1550</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 230.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2645</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 231.</num>
<heading> Budgeting for construction, maintenance, and modernization of naval vessels: annual plans and certifications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Naval Vessel Construction Plan and Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Navy shall include with the defense budget materials for a fiscal year each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A plan for the construction of naval vessels developed in accordance with this section for each of the following classes of ships:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Combatant and support vessels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Auxiliary vessels.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A certification by the Secretary that both the budget for that fiscal year and the future-years defense program submitted to Congress in relation to such budget under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref> provide for funding of the construction of naval vessels at a level that is sufficient for the procurement of the vessels provided for in the plan under paragraph (1) on the schedule provided in that plan, together with the views of the Chief of Naval Operations and Commandant of the Marine Corps on the budget.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The unaltered assessment of the Chief of Naval Operations and the Commandant of the Marine Corps of the plan required under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Naval Vessel Construction Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The annual naval vessel construction plan developed for a fiscal year for purposes of subsection (a)(1) shall be designed so that the naval vessel force provided for under that plan supports the national security strategy of the United States as set forth in the most recent national security strategy report of the President under section 108 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3043</ref>), except that, if at the time such plan is submitted with the defense budget materials for that fiscal year, a national security strategy report required under such section 108 has not been submitted to Congress as required by paragraph (2) or paragraph (3), if applicable, of subsection (a) of such section, then such annual plan shall be designed so that the naval vessel force provided for under that plan supports the ship force structure recommended in the report of the most recent national defense strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each such naval vessel construction plan shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A detailed program for the construction of combatant and support vessels for the Navy over the next 30 fiscal years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A detailed program for the construction of auxiliary vessels for the Navy over the next 30 fiscal years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A description of the necessary naval vessel force structure and capabilities to meet the requirements of the national security strategy of the United States or the most recent national defense strategy, whichever is applicable under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The estimated levels of annual funding by ship class in both graphical and tabular form necessary to carry out the program, together with a discussion of the procurement strategies on which such estimated levels of annual funding are based.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The estimated total cost of construction for each vessel used to determine estimated levels of annual funding under subparagraph (D).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The estimated operations and sustainment costs required to support the vessels delivered under the naval vessel construction plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The expected service life of each vessel in the naval vessel force provided for under the naval vessel construction plan, disaggregated by ship class, and the rationale for any changes to such expectations from the previous year’s plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> A certification by the appropriate Senior Technical Authority designated under <ref>section 8669b of this title</ref> of the expected service life of each vessel in the naval vessel force provided for under the naval vessel construction plan, disaggregated by ship class, and the rationale for any changes to such expectations from the previous year’s plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> For each battle force ship planned to be inactivated during the five-year period beginning on the date of the submittal of the report, a description of the planned disposition of each such ship following such inactivation and the potential gaps in warfighting capability that will result from such ship being removed from service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<chapeau> For any class of battle force ship for which the procurement of the final ship of the class is proposed in the relevant future-years defense program submitted under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> a description of the expected specific effects on the Navy shipbuilding industrial base of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the termination of the production program for the ship and the transition to a new or modified production program, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the termination of the production program for the ship without a new or modified production program to replace it; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of any such production program for which a replacement production program is proposed, a detailed schedule for the replacement production program with planned decision points, solicitations, and contract awards.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In developing annual naval vessel construction plans for purposes of subsection (a)(1), the Secretary of the Navy shall take into consideration the most recent biennial report on shipbuilder training and the defense industrial base required by <ref>section 8693 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment When Annual Naval Vessel Construction Plan Does Not Meet Force Structure Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the annual naval vessel construction plan for a fiscal year under subsection (b) does not result in a force structure or capabilities that meet the requirements identified in subsection (b)(2)(B), the Secretary shall include with the defense budget materials for that fiscal year an assessment of the extent of the strategic and operational risk to national security associated with the reduced force structure of naval vessels over the period of time that the required force structure or capabilities are not achieved. Such assessment shall include an analysis of whether the risks are acceptable, and plans to mitigate such risks. Such assessment shall be coordinated in advance with the commanders of the combatant commands and the Nuclear Weapons Council under <ref>section 179 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Plan for Maintenance and Modernization of Naval Vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the plan included under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary of Defense shall include with the defense budget materials for a fiscal year each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A plan for the maintenance and modernization of naval vessels that includes the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A forecast of the maintenance and modernization requirements for both the naval vessels in the inventory of the Navy and the vessels required to be delivered under the naval vessel construction plan under subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the initiatives of the Secretary of the Navy to ensure that activities key to facilitating the maintenance and modernization of naval vessels (including with respect to increasing workforce and industrial base capability and capacity, shipyard level-loading, and facility improvements) receive sufficient resourcing, and are including in appropriate planning, to facilitate the requirements specified in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A certification by the Secretary that both the budget for that fiscal year and the future-years defense program submitted to Congress in relation to such budget under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref> provide for funding for the maintenance and modernization of naval vessels at a level that is sufficient for such maintenance and modernization in accordance with the plan under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">CBO Evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the congressional defense committees receive the plan under subsection (a)(1), the Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall submit to such committees a report assessing the sufficiency of the estimated levels of annual funding included in such plan with respect to the budget submitted during the year in which the plan is submitted and the future-years defense program submitted under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Availability of Funds for Fiscal Years Without Plan and Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of Defense does not include with the defense budget materials for a fiscal year the plan and certification under subsection (a) and the plan and certification under subsection (d), the Secretary of Defense may not use more than 25 percent of the funds described in paragraph (2) during the fiscal year in which such materials are submitted until the date on which such plans and certifications are submitted to the congressional defense committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The funds described in this paragraph are funds made available to the Secretary of Defense for operation and maintenance, Defense-wide, for emergencies and extraordinary expenses, that remain available for obligation or expenditure as of the date on which the plan and certification under subsection (a) and the plan and certification under subsection (d) are required to be submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reduction in Battle Force Ships</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the plan and certification under subsection (a) for a fiscal year include a proposed reduction in the number of battle force ships proposed to be procured during that fiscal year or during the any of the subsequent nine fiscal years, as compared to the number of such ships proposed in the plan and certification for the preceding fiscal year for that fiscal year and the subsequent nine fiscal years, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the congressional defense committees, by not later than 15 days after the date of the submission of the plan and certification under subsection (a), a briefing that includes each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An identification of each specific ship for which funds are not requested in the budget for that fiscal year and an identification of any funds that were allocated to each such ship, for any prior fiscal year including funds for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> research, development, test, and evaluation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> advance procurement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> advanced construction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> economic order quantity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a shipyard is identified in relation to a ship identified under paragraph (1), the projected change in workload at the shipyard as a result of the reduction of the ship.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The projected change in the estimated value of any major subcontracted components or sequence critical material as a result of the reduction of the ship.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “budget”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the budget for that fiscal year that is submitted to Congress by the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “defense budget materials”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the materials submitted to Congress by the Secretary of Defense in support of the budget for that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “national defense strategy” means the review of the defense programs and policies of the United States that is carried out every four years under <ref>section 113(g) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “combatant and support vessel” means any commissioned ship built or armed for naval combat or any naval ship designed to provide support to combatant ships and other naval operations. Such term does not include patrol coastal ships, non-commissioned combatant craft specifically designed for combat roles, or ships that are designated for potential mobilization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “auxiliary vessel” means any ship designed to operate in the open ocean in a variety of sea states to provide general support to either combatant forces or shore based establishments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “expected service life” means the number of years a naval vessel is expected to be in service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1022(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2639</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1023(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1011(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1558</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1014(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1021</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 844</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1021, 1071(c)(2), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3486</ref>, 3508; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1021</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 965</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1021(d)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1011</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1947</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1021, 1081(a)(13), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3839</ref>, 3871; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1011(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1889</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 352(a)</ref>, title X, § 1021, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2533</ref>, 2763; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1015</ref>, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(3), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 382</ref>, 683; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title X, § 1021</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2052</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 231a.</num>
<heading> Budgeting for life-cycle costs of aircraft for the Army, Navy, and Air Force: annual plan and certification</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Aircraft Procurement Plan and Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the President submits to Congress the budget for a fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A plan for the procurement of the aircraft specified in subsection (b) for each of the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, and the Department of the Air Force developed in accordance with this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A certification by the Secretary that both the budget for such fiscal year and the future-years defense program submitted to Congress in relation to such budget under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref> provide for funding of the procurement of aircraft at a level that is sufficient for the procurement of the aircraft provided for in the plan under paragraph (1) on the schedule provided in the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Aircraft</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The aircraft specified in this subsection are the aircraft as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Fighter aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Attack aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Bomber aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Intertheater lift aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Intratheater lift aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Tanker aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Remotely piloted aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Rotary-wing aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Operational support and executive lift aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Any other major support aircraft designated by the Secretary of Defense for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Aircraft Procurement Plan</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The annual aircraft procurement plan developed for a fiscal year for purposes of subsection (a) should be designed so that the aviation force provided for under the plan is capable of supporting the national military strategy of the United States as set forth in the most recent National Defense Strategy submitted under <ref>section 113(g) of this title</ref> and the most recent National Military Strategy submitted under <ref>section 153(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each annual aircraft procurement plan shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A detailed program for the procurement of the aircraft specified in subsection (b) for each of the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, and the Department of the Air Force over the next 15 fiscal years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the aviation force structure necessary to meet the requirements of the national military strategy of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The estimated levels of annual investment funding necessary to carry out each aircraft program, together with a discussion of the procurement strategies on which such estimated levels of annual investment funding are based, set forth in aggregate for the Department of Defense and in aggregate for each military department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The estimated level of annual funding necessary to operate, maintain, sustain, and support each aircraft program throughout the life-cycle of the program, set forth in aggregate for the Department of Defense and in aggregate for each military department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> For each of the cost estimates required by subparagraphs (C) and (D)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of whether the cost estimate is derived from the cost estimate position of the military department concerned or from the cost estimate position of the Office of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the cost estimate position of the military department and the cost estimate position of the Office of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation differ by more than 5 percent for any aircraft program, an annotated cost estimate difference and sufficient rationale to explain the difference;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the confidence or certainty level associated with the cost estimate for each aircraft program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a certification that the calculations from which the cost estimate is derived are based on common cost categories used by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment for calculating the life-cycle cost of an aircraft program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> An assessment by the Secretary of Defense of the extent to which the combined aircraft forces of the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, and the Department of the Air Force meet the national security requirements of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For any cost estimate required by subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (2) for any aircraft program for which the Secretary is required to include in a report under <ref>section 4351 of this title</ref>, the source of the cost information used to prepare the annual aircraft plan shall be derived from the Selected Acquisition Report data that the Secretary plans to submit to the congressional defense committees in accordance with subsection (f) of that section for the year for which the annual aircraft procurement plan is prepared.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Each annual aircraft procurement plan shall be submitted in unclassified form, and shall contain a classified annex. A summary version of the unclassified report shall be made available to the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment When Aircraft Procurement Budget Is Insufficient to Meet Applicable Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the budget for any fiscal year provides for funding of the procurement of aircraft for the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, or the Department of the Air Force at a level that is not sufficient to sustain the aviation force structure specified in the aircraft procurement plan for such Department for that fiscal year under subsection (a), the Secretary shall include with the defense budget materials for that fiscal year an assessment that describes the funding shortfall and discusses the risks associated with the reduced force structure of aircraft that will result from funding aircraft procurement at such level. The assessment shall be coordinated in advance with the commanders of the combatant commands.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report on Aircraft Inventory</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As part of the annual plan and certification required to be submitted under this section, the Secretary shall include a report on the aircraft in the inventory of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report under paragraph (1) shall include for the year covered by such report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The total number of aircraft in the inventory.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The total number of the aircraft in the inventory that are active, stated in the following categories (with appropriate subcategories for mission aircraft, training aircraft, dedicated test aircraft, and other aircraft):</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Primary aircraft.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Backup aircraft.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Attrition and reconstitution reserve aircraft.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The total number of the aircraft in the inventory that are inactive, stated in the following categories:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Bailment aircraft.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Drone aircraft.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Aircraft for sale or other transfer to foreign governments.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Leased or loaned aircraft.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Aircraft for maintenance training.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Aircraft for reclamation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Aircraft in storage.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The aircraft inventory requirements approved by the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each report under paragraph (1) shall set forth each item specified in paragraph (2) separately for the regular component of each armed force and for each reserve component of each armed force and, for each such component, shall set forth each type, model, and series of aircraft provided for in the future-years defense program that covers the fiscal year for which the budget accompanying the plan, certification and report is submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “budget” means the budget of the President for a fiscal year as submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title I, § 151(a)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3437</ref>, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1919</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 232.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1081(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1960</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 233.</num>
<heading> Operation and maintenance budget presentation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identification of Baseline Amounts in O&amp;M Justification Documents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any case in which the amount requested in the President’s budget for a fiscal year for a Department of Defense operation and maintenance program, project, or activity is different from the amount appropriated for that program, project, or activity for the current year, the O&amp;M justification documents supporting that budget shall identify that appropriated amount and the difference between that amount and the amount requested in the budget, stated as an amount and as a percentage.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Navy for Ship Depot Maintenance and for Intermediate Ship Maintenance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the O&amp;M justification documents for the Navy for any fiscal year, amounts requested for ship depot maintenance and amounts requested for intermediate ship maintenance shall be identified and distinguished.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “O&amp;M justification documents” means Department of Defense budget justification documents with respect to accounts for operation and maintenance submitted to the congressional defense committees in support of the Department of Defense component of the President’s budget for any fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “President’s budget” means the budget of the President submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> for any fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “current year” means the fiscal year during which the President’s budget is submitted in any year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1003(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2035</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 233a.</num>
<heading> Annual report on force structure changes exhibit for the defense budget</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 10 days after the date on which the budget of the President for a fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on any major weapon systems proposed to be divested, re-prioritized, or retired in such budget.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Identification of each major weapon system the Secretary of Defense proposes to divest, re-prioritize, or retire in the period of five fiscal years following the date of the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Budget line-item details related to each major weapon system identified under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For each proposed divestment, re-prioritization, or retirement, an explanation of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the timeline for the divestment, re-prioritization, or retirement, including any factors that may affect such timelines positively or negatively;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any cost savings associated with the divestment, re-prioritization, or retirement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the rationale for the divestment, re-prioritization, or retirement, including a qualitative description of the risk associated with the divestment, re-prioritization, or retirement based on the most recent National Defense Strategy (as of the date of the report);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any critical dependencies with other program efforts that might affect the timeline for such divestment, reprioritization, or retirement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the expected disposition of the weapon system after divestment, re-prioritization or retirement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> identification of the system or systems that are expected to satisfy the military requirements that were fulfilled by the weapon system once the divestment, re-prioritization, or retirement of that weapon system is completed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the report required under subsection (a) is deconflicted with the report required under <ref>section 222e of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major Weapon System Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “major weapon system” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 3455(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title I, § 151</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 179</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 234.</num>
<heading> POW/MIA activities: display of budget information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission With Annual Budget Justification Documents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress, as a part of the defense budget materials for a fiscal year, a consolidated budget justification display, in classified and unclassified form, that covers all programs and activities of Department of Defense POW/MIA accounting and recovery organizations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Budget Display</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The budget display under subsection (a) for a fiscal year shall include for each such organization the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A statement of what percentage of the requirements originally requested by the organization in the budget review process that the budget requests funds for.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A summary of actual or estimated expenditures by that organization for the fiscal year during which the budget is submitted and for the fiscal year preceding that year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The amount in the budget for that organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A detailed explanation of the shortfalls, if any, in the funding of any requirement shown pursuant to paragraph (1), when compared to the amount shown pursuant to paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The budget estimate for that organization for the five fiscal years after the fiscal year for which the budget is submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Department of Defense POW/MIA Accounting and Recovery Organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “Department of Defense POW/MIA accounting and recovery organization” means any of the following (and any successor organization):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Defense Prisoner of War/Missing Personnel Office (DPMO).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Joint POW/MIA Accounting Command (JPAC).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Armed Forces DNA Identification Laboratory (AFDIL).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Life Sciences Equipment Laboratory (LSEL) of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Any other element of the Department of Defense the mission of which (as designated by the Secretary of Defense) involves the accounting for and recovery of members of the armed forces who are missing in action or prisoners of war or who are unaccounted for.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “defense budget materials”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the materials submitted to Congress by the Secretary of Defense in support of the budget for that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “budget”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the budget for that fiscal year that is submitted to Congress by the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 563(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 235.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 815(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1825</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 236.</num>
<heading> Personal protection equipment procurement: display of budget information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget Justification Display</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress, as a part of the defense budget materials for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2014, a consolidated budget justification display that covers all programs and activities associated with the procurement of personal protection equipment during the period covered by the future-years defense program submitted in that fiscal year under section 221.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Budget Display</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The consolidated budget justification display under subsection (a) for a fiscal year shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The amount for personal protection equipment included in both the base budget of the President and any overseas contingency operations budget of the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A brief description of each category of personal protection equipment for each military department planned to be procured and developed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For each category planned to be procured using funds made available for operation and maintenance (whether under the base budget or any overseas contingency operations budget)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the relevant appropriations account, budget activity, and subactivity group for the category; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the funding profile for the fiscal year as requested, including cost and quantities, and an estimate of projected investments or procurements for each of the subsequent five fiscal years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> For each category planned to be developed using funds made available for research, development, test, and evaluation (whether under the base budget or any overseas contingency operations budget)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the relevant appropriations account, program, project or activity; program element number, and line number; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the funding profile for the fiscal year as requested and an estimate of projected investments for each of the subsequent five fiscal years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The terms “budget” and “defense budget materials” have the meaning given those terms in <ref>section 234 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “category of personal protection equipment” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Body armor components.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Combat helmets.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Combat protective eyewear.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Other items as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title I, § 141(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 696</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 237.</num>
<heading> Embedded mental health providers of the reserve components: display of budget information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress, as a part of the documentation that supports the President’s annual budget for the Department of Defense, a budget justification display with respect to embedded mental health providers within each reserve component, including the amount requested for each such component.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VII, § 721(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 799</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 238.</num>
<heading> Cyber mission forces: program elements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget Justification Display</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress, as a part of the defense budget materials for fiscal year 2021 and each fiscal year thereafter, a budget justification display, in electronic and print formats, that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a major force program category for the five-year defense plan of the Department of Defense for the training, manning, and equipping of the cyber mission forces and the cyberspace operations forces; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> program elements for the cyber mission forces and the cyberspace operations forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may waive the requirement under subsection (a) for fiscal year 2021 if the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> determines the Secretary is unable to comply with such requirement for fiscal year 2021; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establishes a plan to implement the requirement for fiscal year 2022.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall provide the displays described in subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in electronic format not later than five days after the submission by the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref> of the budget; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in print format not later than 21 days after the submission by the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref> of the budget.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XVI, § 1631(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3637</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4080</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 239.</num>
<heading> National security space programs: major force program and budget assessment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Major Force Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a unified major force program for national security space programs pursuant to <ref>section 222(b) of this title</ref> to prioritize national security space activities in accordance with the requirements of the Department of Defense and national security.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget Assessment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after the date on which the President submits to Congress the budget for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the budget for national security space programs of the Department of Defense. The Secretary may include the report in the defense budget materials if the Secretary submits such materials to Congress by such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report on the budget for national security space programs of the Department of Defense under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> An overview of the budget, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a comparison between that budget, the previous budget, the most recent and prior future-years defense program submitted to Congress under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>, and the amounts appropriated for such programs during the previous fiscal year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the specific identification, as a budgetary line item, for the funding under such programs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An assessment of the budget, including significant changes, priorities, challenges, and risks.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any additional matters the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each report under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “budget”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the budget for that fiscal year that is submitted to Congress by the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “defense budget materials”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the materials submitted to Congress by the Secretary of Defense in support of the budget for that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1601(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1095</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVI, § 1605</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 239a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2199</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 239b.</num>
<heading> Certain intelligence-related programs: budget justification materials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Use of Program Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department of Defense budget for fiscal year 2021 and each fiscal year thereafter (as submitted with the budget of the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>), the Secretary of Defense may not include in any single program element both funds made available under the Military Intelligence Program and funds made available outside of the Military Intelligence Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “budget” has the meaning given that term in section 231(f) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002020">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “defense budget materials” has the meaning given that term in section 231(f) <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVI, § 1624(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 239c.</num>
<heading> Certain multiyear contracts for acquisition of property: budget justification materials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department of Defense budget for fiscal year 2023 and each fiscal year thereafter (as submitted with the budget of the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>), the Secretary of Defense shall include a proposal for any multiyear contract of the Department entered into under <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref> that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the head of an agency intends to cancel during the fiscal year; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with respect to which the head of an agency intends to effect a covered modification during the fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each proposal required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A detailed explanation of the rationale for the proposed cancellation or covered modification of the multiyear contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A detailed assessment of any expected termination costs associated with the proposed cancellation or covered modification of the multiyear contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An updated assessment of estimated savings of such cancellation or carrying out the multiyear contract as modified by such covered modification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An explanation of the proposed use of previously appropriated funds for advance procurement or procurement of property planned under the multiyear contract before such cancellation or covered modification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An assessment of expected impacts of the proposed cancellation or covered modification on the defense industrial base, including workload stability, loss of skilled labor, and reduced efficiencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “covered modification” means a modification that will result in a reduction in the quantity of end items to be procured.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “head of an agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Army;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Navy; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 811(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1822</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 811</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 239d.</num>
<heading> Budgeting for depot and ammunition production facility maintenance and repair: annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall include with the defense budget materials for each fiscal year a report regarding the maintenance and repair of covered facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report required under subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, the following (disaggregated by military department):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> With respect to each of the three fiscal years preceding the fiscal year covered by the defense budget materials with which the report is included, revenue data for that fiscal year for the maintenance, repair, and overhaul workload funded at all the depots of the military department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to the fiscal year covered by the defense budget materials with which the report is included and each of the two fiscal years prior, an identification of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The amount of appropriations budgeted for that fiscal year for depots, further disaggregated by the type of appropriation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The amount budgeted for that fiscal year for working-capital fund investments by the Secretary of the military department for the capital budgets of the covered depots of the military department, shown in total and further disaggregated by whether the investment relates to the efficiency of depot facilities, work environment, equipment, equipment (non-capital investment program), or processes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The total amount required to be invested by the Secretary of the military department for that fiscal year for the capital budgets of covered depots pursuant to <ref>section 2476(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A comparison of the budgeted amount identified under subparagraph (B) with the total required amount identified under subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> For each covered depot of the military department, of the total required amount identified under subparagraph (C), the percentage of such amount allocated, or projected to be allocated, to the covered depot for that fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For each covered facility of the military department, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Information on the average facility condition, average critical facility condition, restoration and maintenance project backlog, and average equipment age, including a description of any changes in such metrics from previous years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Information on the status of the implementation at the covered facility of the plans and strategies of the Department of Defense relating to covered facility improvement, including, as applicable, the implementation of the strategy required under section 359 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<ref>Public Law 116–92</ref>; <ref>133 Stat. 1323</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2460</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002021">1</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “ammunition production facility” means an ammunition organic industrial base production facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The terms “budget” and “defense budget materials” have the meaning given those terms in <ref>section 234 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “covered depot” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2476 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “covered facility” means a covered depot or an ammunition production facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 371</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2539</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 239e.</num>
<heading> Nuclear command, control, and communications: major force program and budget assessment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Major Force Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a unified major force program for nuclear command, control, and communications programs pursuant to <ref>section 222(b) of this title</ref> to prioritize such programs in accordance with the requirements of the Department of Defense and national security.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget Assessment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall include with the defense budget materials for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2030 a report on the budget for nuclear command, control, and communications programs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report on the budget for nuclear command, control, and communications programs of the Department under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> An overview of the budget, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a comparison between that budget, the previous budget, the most recent and prior future-years defense program submitted to Congress under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref> (such comparison shall exclude the responsibility for research and development of the continuing improvement of such nuclear command, control, and communications program), and the amounts appropriated for such nuclear command, control, and communications programs during the previous fiscal year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the specific identification, as a budgetary line item, for the funding under such programs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An assessment of the budget, including significant changes, priorities, challenges, and risks.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any additional matters the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each report under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “budget”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the budget for that fiscal year that is submitted to Congress by the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “defense budget materials”, with respect to a fiscal year, means the materials submitted to Congress by the Secretary of Defense in support of the budget for that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “nuclear command, control, and communications programs” means programs through which presidential authority and operational command and control of nuclear weapons is conducted, including programs that facilitate senior-level decisions on nuclear weapons employment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVI, § 1631</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 591</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>