<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 953—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES AIR FORCE ACADEMY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9431.</num>
<heading> Establishment; Superintendent; faculty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is in the Department of the Air Force an Air Force Academy (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “Academy”) for the instruction and preparation for military service of selected persons called “cadets”. The organization of the Academy shall be prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> There shall be at the Academy the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A Superintendent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A Dean of the Faculty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A Commandant of Cadets.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> 25 permanent professors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A chaplain.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A director of admissions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 561</ref>, § 9331; <ref>Pub. L. 85–600, § 1(19)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-06">Aug. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 523</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 514(10)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 515(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title V, § 523(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2410</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 533(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1658</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 529(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1471</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 545, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4466</ref>; renumbered § 9431, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 573</ref>, title IX, § 923(d)(7), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3644</ref>, 3814.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9432.</num>
<heading> Departments and professors: titles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Air Force may prescribe the titles of each of the departments of instruction and the professors of the Academy. However, the change of the title of a department or officer does not affect the status, rank, or eligibility for promotion or retirement of, or otherwise prejudice, a professor at the Academy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 562</ref>, § 9332; renumbered § 9432, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9433.</num>
<heading> Superintendent; faculty: appointment and detail</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Superintendent and the Commandant of Cadets of the Academy shall be detailed to those positions by the President from the officers of the Air Force or the Space Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The permanent professors of the Academy shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The director of admissions of the Academy shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall perform such duties as the Superintendent of the Academy may prescribe with the approval of the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 562</ref>, § 9333; <ref>Pub. L. 85–600, § 1(20)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-06">Aug. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 523</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 515(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1441</ref>; renumbered § 9433, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9433a.</num>
<heading> Superintendent: condition for detail to position</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As a condition for detail to the position of Superintendent of the Academy, an officer shall acknowledge that upon termination of that detail the officer shall be retired pursuant to <ref>section 9321(a) of this title</ref>, unless such retirement is waived under <ref>section 9321(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum Tour of Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer who is detailed to the position of Superintendent of the Academy shall be so detailed for a period of not less than three years. In any case in which an officer serving as Superintendent is reassigned or retires before having completed three years service as Superintendent, or otherwise leaves that position (other than due to death) without having completed three years service in that position, the Secretary of the Air Force shall submit to Congress notice that such officer left the position of Superintendent without having completed three years service in that position, together with a statement of the reasons why that officer did not complete three years service in that position.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 603</ref>, § 9333a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 541(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1903</ref>; renumbered § 9433a and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(a)(3), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9434.</num>
<heading> Command and supervision</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The immediate government of the Academy is under the Superintendent, who is also the commanding officer of the Academy and of the military post.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The permanent professors and the director of admissions exercise command only in the academic department of the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 562</ref>, § 9334; <ref>Pub. L. 85–600, § 1(21)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-06">Aug. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 524</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 515(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1441</ref>; renumbered § 9434, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9435.</num>
<heading> Dean of the Faculty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Dean of the Faculty is responsible to the Superintendent for developing and sustaining the curriculum and overseeing the faculty of the Academy. The qualifications, selection procedures, training, pay grade, and retention of the Dean shall be prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force, except that a person may not be appointed or assigned as Dean unless that person holds the highest academic degree in that person’s academic field. If a person appointed as the Dean is not an officer on active duty, the person shall be appointed as a member of the Senior Executive Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The retirement age of an officer appointed as Dean of the Faculty is that of a permanent professor of the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 562</ref>, § 9335; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 33(a)(46)(A)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1567</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V, § 508(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3867</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title V, § 521(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2409</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 533(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 605</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 529(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1471</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 542</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1904</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(qq)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2106</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 507(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1375</ref>; renumbered § 9435, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9436.</num>
<heading> Permanent professors; director of admissions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A permanent professor of the Academy who is the head of a department of instruction, or who has served as such a professor for more than six years, has the grade of colonel in the Air Force or the Space Force. However, a permanent professor appointed from the Regular Air Force or the Space Force has the grade of colonel after the date when such person completes six years of service as a professor, or after the date on which such person would have been promoted had such person been selected for promotion from among officers in the promotion zone, whichever is earlier. All other permanent professors have the grade of lieutenant colonel in the Air Force or the Space Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A person appointed as director of admissions of the Academy has the regular grade of lieutenant colonel in the Air Force or the grade of lieutenant colonel in the Space Force, and, after such person has served six years as director of admissions, has the regular grade of colonel in the Air Force or the grade of lieutenant colonel in the Space Force. However, a person appointed from the Regular Air Force has the regular grade of colonel and a person appointed from the Space Force has the grade of colonel in the Space Force after the date when such person completes six years of service as director of admissions, or after the date on which such person would have been promoted had such person been selected for promotion from among officers in the promotion zone, whichever is earlier.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 562</ref>, § 9336; <ref>Pub. L. 85–600, § 1(22)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-06">Aug. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 524</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 33(a)(46)(B)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1567</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title II, § 218(b)</ref>, title V, § 504(24), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2886</ref>, 2917; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 533(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2528</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 515(a)(4)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 529(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1472</ref>; renumbered § 9436, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1721(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 666</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9438.</num>
<heading> Civilian faculty: number; compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force may employ as many civilians as professors, instructors, and lecturers at the Academy as the Secretary considers necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The compensation of persons employed under this section is as prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Air Force may, notwithstanding the provisions of subchapter V of chapter 55 of title 5 or section 6101 of such title, prescribe for persons employed under this section the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The work schedule, including hours of work and tours of duty, set forth with such specificity and other characteristics as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any premium pay or compensatory time off for hours of work or tours of duty in excess of the regularly scheduled hours or tours of duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 533(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1658</ref>, § 9338; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title XI, § 1107(c)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 778</ref>; renumbered § 9438, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9441.</num>
<heading> Faculty and other officers: leaves of absence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Superintendent of the Academy may grant a leave of absence for the period of the suspension of the ordinary academic studies, without deduction of pay or allowances, to a professor, assistant professor, instructor, or other officer of the Academy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 563</ref>, § 9341; renumbered § 9441, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9441a.</num>
<heading> Cadets: appointment by the President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Cadets at the Academy shall be appointed by the President alone. An appointment is conditional until the cadet is admitted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–60, title II, § 203(c)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-14">Oct. 14, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1006</ref>, § 9341a; renumbered § 9441a, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9442.</num>
<heading> Cadets: appointment; numbers, territorial distribution</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The authorized strength of cadets of the Academy (determined for any year as of the day before the last day of the academic year) is 4,400 or such lower number as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force under subsection (j). Subject to that limitation, cadets are selected as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 65 cadets selected in order of merit as established by competitive examination from the children of members of the armed forces who were killed in action or died of, or have a service-connected disability rated at not less than 100 per centum resulting from wounds or injuries received or diseases contracted in, or preexisting injury or disease aggravated by, active service, children of members who are in a “missing status” as defined in <ref>section 551(2) of title 37</ref>, and children of civilian employees who are in “missing status” as defined in <ref>section 5561(5) of title 5</ref>. The determination of the Department of Veterans Affairs as to service connection of the cause of death or disability, and the percentage at which the disability is rated, is binding upon the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Five cadets nominated at large by the Vice President or, if there is no Vice President, by the President pro tempore of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Ten cadets from each State, five of whom are nominated by each Senator from that State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Five cadets from each congressional district, nominated by the Representative from the district.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Five cadets from the District of Columbia, nominated by the Delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Four cadets from the Virgin Islands, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Six cadets from Puerto Rico, five of whom are nominated by the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico and one who is a native of Puerto Rico nominated by the Governor of Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Five cadets from Guam, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from Guam.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Three cadets from American Samoa, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from American Samoa.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Three cadets from the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from the commonwealth.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each Senator, Representative, and Delegate in Congress, including the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico, is entitled to nominate 15 persons <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002180">1</ref> for each vacancy that is available to him under this section. Nominees may be submitted without ranking or with a principal candidate and 9 ranked or unranked alternates. Qualified nominees not selected for appointment under this subsection shall be considered qualified alternates for the purposes of selection under other provisions of this chapter. When a nominee of a Senator, Representative, or Delegate is selected for appointment as a cadet, the Senator, Representative, or Delegate shall be notified at least 48 hours before the official notification or announcement of the appointment is made.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In addition, there may be appointed each year at the Academy cadets as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> one hundred selected by the President from the children of members of an armed force who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are on active duty (other than for training) and who have served continuously on active duty for at least eight years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are, or who died while they were, retired with pay or granted retired or retainer pay;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> are serving as members of reserve components, or the Space Force, and are credited with at least eight years of service computed under <ref>section 12733 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> would be, or who died while they would have been, entitled to retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title except for not having attained 60 years of age;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">however, a person who is eligible for selection under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) may not be selected under this paragraph.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 85 nominated by the Secretary of the Air Force from enlisted members of the Regular Air Force or the Space Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> 85 nominated by the Secretary of the Air Force from enlisted members of reserve components of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> 20 nominated by the Secretary of the Air Force, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, from the honor graduates of schools designated as honor schools by the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, or the Department of the Air Force, and from members of the Air Force Reserve Officers’ Training Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> 200 <sup>1</sup> selected by the Secretary of the Air Force in order of merit (prescribed pursuant to <ref>section 9443 of this title</ref>) from qualified alternates nominated by persons named in paragraphs (3) through (10) of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The President may also appoint as cadets at the Academy children of persons who have been awarded the Medal of Honor for acts performed while in the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Superintendent may nominate for appointment each year 50 persons from the country at large. Persons nominated under this paragraph may not displace any appointment authorized under paragraphs (2) through (9) of subsection (a) and may not cause the total strength of cadets to exceed the authorized number.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If the annual quota of cadets under subsection (b)(1), (2), or (3) is not filled, the Secretary may fill the vacancies by nominating for appointment other candidates from any of these sources who were found best qualified on examination for admission and not otherwise nominated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Each candidate for admission nominated under paragraphs (3) through (9) of subsection (a) must be domiciled in the State, or in the congressional district, from which he is nominated, or in the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, or the Virgin Islands, if nominated from one of those places.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Air Force may limit the number of cadets authorized to be appointed under this section to the number that can be adequately accommodated at the Academy as determined by the Secretary after consulting with the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, subject to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Cadets chargeable to each nominating authority named in subsection (a)(3) or (4) may not be limited to less than four.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary limits the number of appointments under subsection (a)(3) or (4), appointments under subsection (b)(1)–(4) are limited as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 27 appointments under subsection (b)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 27 appointments under subsection (b)(2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 27 appointments under subsection (b)(3); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> 13 appointments under subsection (b)(4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary limits the number of appointments under subsection (b)(5), appointments under subsection (b)(2)–(4) are limited as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 27 appointments under subsection (b)(2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 27 appointments under subsection (b)(3); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 13 appointments under subsection (b)(4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The limitations provided for in this subsection do not affect the operation of subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The Superintendent shall furnish to any Member of Congress, upon the written request of such Member, the name of the Congressman or other nominating authority responsible for the nomination of any named or identified person for appointment to the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> For purposes of the limitation in subsection (a) establishing the aggregate authorized strength of cadets, the Secretary of the Air Force may for any year permit a variance in that limitation by not more than one percent. In applying that limitation, and any such variance, the last day of an academic year shall be considered to be graduation day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Beginning with the 2003–2004 academic year, the Secretary of the Air Force may prescribe annual increases in the cadet strength limit in effect under subsection (a). For any academic year, any such increase shall be by no more than 100 cadets or such lesser number as applies under paragraph (3) for that year. Such annual increases may be prescribed until the cadet strength limit is 4,400.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any increase in the cadet strength limit under paragraph (1) with respect to an academic year shall be prescribed not later than the date on which the budget of the President is submitted to Congress under sections 1105 of title 31 for the fiscal year beginning in the same year as the year in which that academic year begins. Whenever the Secretary prescribes such an increase, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a notice in writing of the increase. The notice shall state the amount of the increase in the cadet strength limit and the new cadet strength limit, as so increased, and the amount of the increase in Senior Air Force Reserve Officers’ Training Corps enrollment under each of sections 2104 and 2107 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The amount of an increase under paragraph (1) in the cadet strength limit for an academic year may not exceed the increase (if any) for the preceding academic year in the total number of cadets enrolled in the Air Force Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program under chapter 103 of this title who have entered into an agreement under section 2104 or 2107 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “cadet strength limit” means the authorized maximum strength of cadets of the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 563</ref>, § 9342; <ref>Pub. L. 87–663, § 1(5)</ref>, (6), <date date="1962-09-14">Sept. 14, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–276, § 4(1)</ref>, <date date="1964-03-03">Mar. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–650, § 1(1)</ref>–(3), (5), <date date="1966-10-13">Oct. 13, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 896</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–374</ref>, <date date="1968-07-05">July 5, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–623, § 2(8)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–405, title II, § 204(c)</ref>, <date date="1970-09-22">Sept. 22, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 852</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–365, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1972-08-07">Aug. 7, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 505</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–171, § 3(1)</ref>–(4), <date date="1973-11-29">Nov. 29, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 690</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–106, title VIII, § 803(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-07">Oct. 7, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 538</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 514(11)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–600, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–60, title II, § 203(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-14">Oct. 14, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1006</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title X, § 1005(a)(3)</ref>, (b)(3), <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 660</ref>, 661; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1602</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 532(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 531</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1657</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1674(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 532(c)</ref>, title XV, § 1502(a)(1), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 315</ref>, 502; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(62)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1903</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 531(b)(3)</ref>, title X, § 1067(1), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 602</ref>, 774; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 531(c)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–110; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 532(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2546</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 524(c)</ref>, title X, § 1031(a)(58), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1464</ref>, 1603; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(38)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2400</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–229, title VII, § 718(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 869</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 540(c), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4454</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 527(c)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2288</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(42)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 556(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 825</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 566(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2139</ref>; renumbered § 9442 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(a)(3), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>, 1840; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(10)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 552(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 561(c), 562(c), title XVII, § 1721(c)(2), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 273</ref>, 274, 666.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9442a.</num>
<heading> Cadets: nomination in event of death, resignation, or expulsion from office of Member of Congress otherwise authorized to nominate</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senators</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the event a Senator does not submit all nominations for cadets allocated to such Senator for an academic year in accordance with <ref>section 9442(a)(3) of this title</ref>, due to death, resignation from office, or expulsion from office, and the date of the swearing-in of the Senator’s successor as Senator occurs after the date of the deadline for submittal of nominations for cadets for the academic year, the nominations for cadets for such academic year, otherwise authorized to be made by the Senator pursuant to such section, may be made instead by the other Senator from the State of such Representative.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Representatives</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the event a Representative does not submit all nominations for cadets allocated to such Representative for an academic year in accordance with <ref>section 9442(a)(4) of this title</ref>, due to death, resignation from office, or expulsion from office, and the date of the swearing-in of the Representative’s successor as Representative occurs after the date of the deadline for submittal of nominations for cadets for the academic year, the nominations for cadets for such academic year, otherwise authorized to be made by the Representative pursuant to such section, may be made instead by the Senators from the State of such Representative, with such nominations divided equally among such Senators and any remainder going to the senior Senator from the State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The nomination of a cadet by a Member of Congress pursuant to this section shall not be construed to permanently reallocate nominations under <ref>section 9442 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 553(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1737</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9443.</num>
<heading> Cadets: appointment; to bring to full strength</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If it is determined that, upon the admission of a new class to the Academy, the number of cadets at the Academy will be below the authorized number, the Secretary of the Air Force may fill the vacancies by nominating additional cadets from qualified candidates designated as alternates and from other qualified candidates who competed for nomination and are recommended and found qualified by the Academy Board. At least three-fourths of those nominated under this section shall be selected from qualified alternates nominated by the persons named in paragraphs (2) through (8) of <ref>section 9442(a) of this title</ref>, and the remainder from qualified candidates holding competitive nominations under any other provision of law. An appointment under this section is an additional appointment and is not in place of an appointment otherwise authorized by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 564</ref>, § 9343; <ref>Pub. L. 88–276, § 4(2)</ref>, <date date="1964-03-03">Mar. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 46</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–171, § 3(5)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-29">Nov. 29, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 691</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(2)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1563</ref>, 1564; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(43)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1955</ref>; renumbered § 9443 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(a)(3), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9446.</num>
<heading> Cadets: requirements for admission</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> To be eligible for admission to the Academy a candidate must be at least 17 years of age and must not have passed his twenty-third birthday on July 1 of the year in which he enters the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> To be admitted to the Academy, an appointee must show, by an examination held under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force, that he is qualified in the subjects prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A candidate designated as a principal or an alternate for appointment as a cadet shall appear for physical examination at a time and place designated by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> To be admitted to the Academy, an appointee must take and subscribe to an oath prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force. If a candidate for admission refuses to take and subscribe to the prescribed oath, his appointment is terminated.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 565</ref>, § 9346; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 47</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 555(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2527</ref>; renumbered § 9446, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9447.</num>
<heading> Cadets; nominees: effect of redistricting of States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If as a result of redistricting a State the domicile of a cadet, or a nominee, nominated by a Representative falls within a congressional district other than that from which he was nominated, he is charged to the district in which his domicile so falls. For this purpose, the number of cadets otherwise authorized for that district is increased to include him. However, the number as so increased is reduced by one if he fails to become a cadet or when he is finally separated from the Academy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 565</ref>, § 9347, renumbered § 9447, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9448.</num>
<heading> Cadets: service obligation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Each cadet shall sign an agreement with respect to the cadet’s length of service in the armed forces. The agreement shall provide that the cadet agrees to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> That the cadet will complete the course of instruction at the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> That upon graduation from the Academy the cadet—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> will accept an appointment, if tendered, as a commissioned officer of the Regular Air Force or the Space Force; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will serve on active duty for at least five years immediately after such appointment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> That if an appointment described in paragraph (2) is not tendered or if the cadet is permitted to resign as a regular officer, or to terminate the officer’s order to sustained duty in the Space Force before completion of the commissioned service obligation of the cadet, the cadet—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> will accept an appointment as a commissioned officer as a Reserve in the Air Force for service in the Air Force Reserve or will accept further assignment in a space force active status; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> will remain in that reserve component, or the Space Force, until completion of the commissioned service obligation of the cadet.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> That if an appointment described in paragraph (2) or (3) is tendered and the cadet participates in a program under <ref>section 2121 of this title</ref>, the cadet will fulfill any unserved obligation incurred under this section on active duty, regardless of the type of appointment held, upon completion of, and in addition to, any service obligation incurred under <ref>section 2123 of this title</ref> for participation in such program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> That the cadet may not obtain employment as a professional athlete until two years after the cadet graduates from the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (4), the Secretary of the Air Force may transfer to the Air Force Reserve, and may order to active duty for such period of time as the Secretary prescribes (but not to exceed four years), a cadet who breaches an agreement under subsection (a). The period of time for which a cadet is ordered to active duty under this paragraph may be determined without regard to <ref>section 651(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A cadet who is transferred to the Air Force Reserve under paragraph (1) shall be transferred in an appropriate enlisted grade or rating, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the purposes of paragraph (1), a cadet shall be considered to have breached an agreement under subsection (a) if the cadet is separated from the Academy under circumstances which the Secretary determines constitute a breach by the cadet of the cadet’s agreement to complete the course of instruction at the Academy and accept an appointment as a commissioned officer upon graduation from the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Each academic year, the Secretary of the Air Force may transfer not more than three cadets, who obtain employment in violation of paragraph (5) of subsection (a), to the Selected Reserve of the Air Force. Each cadet so transferred shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> serve as a commissioned officer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in an appropriate grade or rating, determined by the Secretary of the Air Force; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for a period, determined by the Secretary of the Air Force, not longer than 10 years; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> while so serving, participate in efforts to recruit and retain members of the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Air Force shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Those regulations shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> standards for determining what constitutes, for the purpose of subsection (b), a breach of an agreement under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> that a cadet who obtains employment as a professional athlete—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in violation of paragraph (5) of subsection (a) has breached an agreement under such subsection unless such cadet receives a transfer under paragraph (4) of subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at least two years after the cadet graduates from the Academy has not breached an agreement under subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> procedures for determining whether such a breach has occurred; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> standards for determining the period of time for which a person may be ordered to serve on active duty under subsection(b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “commissioned service obligation”, with respect to a cadet, means the period beginning on the date of the cadet’s appointment as a commissioned officer and ending on the sixth anniversary of such appointment or, at the discretion of the Secretary of Defense, any later date up to the eighth anniversary of such appointment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to a cadet who is not a citizen or national of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a cadet who is a minor and who has parents or a guardian, the cadet may sign the agreement required by subsection (a) only with the consent of a parent or guardian.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> A cadet or former cadet who does not fulfill each term of the agreement as specified under subsection (a), or an alternative obligation imposed under subsection (b), shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 565</ref>, § 9348; <ref>Pub. L. 88–276, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-03-03">Mar. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–647, title III, § 301(25)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1073</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V</ref>, §§ 541(c), 542(d), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 512(c)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 511(d)</ref>, title XVI, § 1622(e)(5), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1439</ref>, 1605; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 531(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI, § 687(c)(11)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3335</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(29)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 554(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4221</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 543(c)</ref>, title VI, § 618(a)(1)(M), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1396</ref>, 1426; renumbered § 9448, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 554(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1388</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(11)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 553(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1721(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 666</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 557(c)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9449.</num>
<heading> Cadets: organization; service; instruction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A cadet shall perform duties at such places and of such type as the President may direct.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The course of instruction at the Academy is four years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force shall so arrange the course of studies at the Academy that cadets are not required to pursue their studies on Sunday.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 566</ref>, § 9349; renumbered § 9449, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(12)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9450.</num>
<heading> Cadets: clothing and equipment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force may prescribe the amount to be credited to a cadet, upon original admission to the Academy, for the cost of his initial issue of clothing and equipment. That amount shall be deducted from his pay. If a cadet is discharged before graduation while owing the United States for pay advanced for the purchase of required clothing and equipment, he shall turn in so much of his clothing and equipment of a distinctive military nature as is necessary to repay the amount advanced. If the value of the clothing and equipment turned in does not cover the amount owed, the indebtedness shall be canceled.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, uniforms and equipment shall be furnished to a cadet at the Academy upon his request.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 566</ref>, § 9350; renumbered § 9450, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9451.</num>
<heading> Cadets: deficiencies in conduct or studies; effect of failure on successor</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A cadet who is reported as deficient in conduct or studies and recommended to be discharged from the Academy may not, unless recommended by the Academy Board, be returned or reappointed to the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any cadet who fails to pass a required examination because he is deficient in any one subject of instruction is entitled to a reexamination of equal scope and difficulty in that subject, if he applies in writing to the Superintendent within 10 days after he is officially notified of his failure. The reexamination shall be held within 60 days after the date of his application. If the cadet passes the reexamination and is otherwise qualified, he shall be readmitted to the Academy. If he fails, he may not have another examination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The failure of a member of a graduating class to complete the course with his class does not delay the admission of his successor.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 566</ref>, § 9351; renumbered § 9451, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9452.</num>
<heading> Cadets: hazing</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the approval of the Secretary of the Air Force, the Superintendent of the Academy shall issue regulations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> defining hazing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> designed to prevent that practice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prescribing dismissal, suspension, or other adequate punishment for violations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If a cadet who is charged with violating a regulation issued under subsection (a), the penalty for which is or may be dismissal from the Academy, requests in writing a trial by a general court-martial, he may not be dismissed for that offense except under sentence of such a court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A cadet dismissed from the Academy for hazing may not be reappointed as a cadet, and is ineligible for appointment as a commissioned officer in a regular component of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps, or in the Space Force, until two years after the graduation of his class.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 566</ref>, § 9352; renumbered § 9452, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(13)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1721(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 667</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9453.</num>
<heading> Cadets: degree and commission on graduation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Superintendent of the Academy may, under such conditions as the Secretary of the Air Force may prescribe, confer the degree of bachelor of science upon graduates of the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a cadet who completes the prescribed course of instruction may, upon graduation, be appointed a second lieutenant in the Regular Air Force under <ref>section 531 of this title</ref> or a second lieutenant in the Space Force under section 531 or 20201 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 567</ref>, § 9353; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861</ref>, §§ 1(201), 33(a)(43), <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1541</ref>, 1567; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 504(25)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2917</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 542(d)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1743</ref>; renumbered § 9453, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(14)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3815</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1721(c)(5)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 667</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9454.</num>
<heading> Buildings and grounds: buildings for religious worship</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Air Force may authorize any denomination, sect, or religious body to erect a building for religious worship at the Air Force Academy, if its erection will not interfere with the use of the reservation for military purposes and will be without expense to the United States. Such a building shall be removed, or its location changed, without compensation for it and without expense to the United States, by the denomination, sect, or religious body that erected it, whenever in the opinion of the Secretary public or military necessity so requires.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 567</ref>, § 9354; renumbered § 9454, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9455.</num>
<heading> Board of Visitors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A Board of Visitors to the Academy is constituted annually of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the chair of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, or the designee of such chair;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the ranking member of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, or the designee of the ranking member;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> two other members of the Senate designated by the Majority Leader of the Senate, one of whom is a member of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> two other members of the Senate designated by the Minority Leader of the Senate, one of whom is a member of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the chair of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, or the designee of such chair;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the ranking member of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, or the designee of the ranking member;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> two other members of the House of Representatives designated by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, one of whom is a member of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> one other member of the House of Representatives designated by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> six persons designated by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The persons designated by the President serve for three years each except that any member whose term of office has expired shall continue to serve until his successor is designated by the President. The President shall designate persons each year to succeed the members designated by the President whose terms expire that year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> At least two of the members designated by the President shall be graduates of the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a member of the Board dies or resigns or is terminated as a member of the Board under paragraph (2), a successor shall be designated for the unexpired portion of the term by the official who designated the member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If a member of the Board fails to attend two successive Board meetings, except in a case in which an absence is approved in advance, for good cause, by the Board chairman, such failure shall be grounds for termination from membership on the Board. A person designated for membership on the Board shall be provided notice of the provisions of this paragraph at the time of such designation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Termination of membership on the Board under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of the Board who is not a member of Congress, may be made by the Board chairman; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of the Board who is a member of Congress, may be made only by the official who designated the member.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> When a member of the Board is subject to termination from membership on the Board under subparagraph (A), the Board chairman shall notify the official who designated the member. Upon receipt of such a notification with respect to a member of the Board who is a member of Congress, the official who designated the member shall take such action as that official considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Board shall visit the Academy annually. With the approval of the Secretary of the Air Force, the Board or its members may make other visits to the Academy in connection with the duties of the Board or to consult with the Superintendent of the Academy. Board members shall have access to the Academy grounds and the cadets, faculty, staff, and other personnel of the Academy for the purposes of the duties of the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Board shall inquire into the morale, discipline, and social climate, the curriculum, instruction, physical equipment, fiscal affairs, academic methods, and other matters relating to the Academy that the Board decides to consider.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force and the Superintendent of the Academy shall provide the Board candid and complete disclosure, consistent with applicable laws concerning disclosure of information, with respect to institutional problems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Board shall recommend appropriate action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Board shall prepare a semiannual report containing its views and recommendations pertaining to the Academy, based on its meeting since the last such report and any other considerations it determines relevant. Each such report shall be submitted concurrently to the Secretary of Defense, through the Secretary of the Air Force, and to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Upon approval by the Secretary, the Board may call in advisers for consultation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> While performing duties as a member of the Board, each member of the Board and each adviser shall be reimbursed under Government travel regulations for travel expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A majority of the members of the Board may call an official meeting of the Board once per year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A member may attend such meeting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in person, at the Academy; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> remotely, at the election of such member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 567</ref>, § 9355; <ref>Pub. L. 96–579, § 13(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-23">Dec. 23, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1061(e)(2)</ref>, title XV, § 1502(a)(12), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 443</ref>, 503; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 543</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1904</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(39)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2400</ref>; renumbered § 9455 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 593</ref>, title VIII, § 806(a)(3), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1789</ref>, 1832; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 554(c), 555(c), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1738</ref>, 1739; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 558(c)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1899</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9456.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of guarantees with gifts for major projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary of the Air Force may accept from a donor or donors a qualified guarantee for the completion of a major project for the benefit of the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Obligation Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of a qualified guarantee accepted under this section shall be considered as contract authority to provide obligation authority for purposes of Federal fiscal and contractual requirements. Funds available for a project for which such a guarantee has been accepted may be obligated and expended for the project without regard to whether the total amount of the funds and other resources available for the project (not taking into account the amount of the guarantee) is sufficient to pay for completion of the project.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Proposed Acceptance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may not accept a qualified guarantee under this section for the completion of a major project until after the expiration of 30 days following the date upon which a report of the facts concerning the proposed guarantee is submitted to Congress or, if earlier, the expiration of 14 days following the date on which a copy of the report is provided in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Commingling of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may not enter into any contract or other transaction involving the use of a qualified guarantee and appropriated funds in the same contract or transaction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major project</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “major project” means a project for the purchase or other procurement of real or personal property, or for the construction, renovation, or repair of real or personal property, the total cost of which is, or is estimated to be, at least $1,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified guarantee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “qualified guarantee”, with respect to a major project, means a guarantee that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is made by one or more persons in connection with a donation, specifically for the project, of a total amount in cash or securities that, as determined by the Secretary of the Air Force, is sufficient to defray a substantial portion of the total cost of the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is made to facilitate or expedite the completion of the project in reasonable anticipation that other donors will contribute sufficient funds or other resources in amounts sufficient to pay for completion of the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is set forth as a written agreement that provides for the donor to furnish in cash or securities, in addition to the donor’s other gift or gifts for the project, any additional amount that may become necessary for paying the cost of completing the project by reason of a failure to obtain from other donors or sources funds or other resources in amounts sufficient to pay the cost of completing the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> is accompanied by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an irrevocable and unconditional standby letter of credit for the benefit of the Academy that is in the amount of the guarantee and is issued by a major United States commercial bank; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a qualified account control agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified account control agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “qualified account control agreement”, with respect to a guarantee of a donor, means an agreement among the donor, the Secretary of the Air Force, and a major United States investment management firm that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensures the availability of sufficient funds or other financial resources to pay the amount guaranteed during the period of the guarantee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides for the perfection of a security interest in the assets of the account for the United States for the benefit of the Academy with the highest priority available for liens and security interests under applicable law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> requires the donor to maintain in an account with the investment management firm assets having a total value that is not less than 130 percent of the amount guaranteed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> requires the investment management firm, at any time that the value of the account is less than the value required to be maintained under subparagraph (C), to liquidate any noncash assets in the account and reinvest the proceeds in Treasury bills issued under <ref>section 3104 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major united states commercial bank</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “major United States commercial bank” means a commercial bank that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is an insured bank (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1813</ref>));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is headquartered in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has net assets in a total amount considered by the Secretary of the Air Force to qualify the bank as a major bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major united states investment management firm</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “major United States investment management firm” means any broker, dealer, investment adviser, or provider of investment supervisory services (as defined in section 3 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78c</ref>) or section 202 of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 80b–2</ref>)) or a major United States commercial bank that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is headquartered in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> holds for the account of others investment assets in a total amount considered by the Secretary of the Air Force to qualify the firm as a major investment management firm.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2871(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 875</ref>, § 9356; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1087(a)(17)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–291; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(59)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1603</ref>; renumbered § 9456, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9457.</num>
<heading> Grants for faculty research for scientific, literary, and educational purposes: acceptance; authorized grantees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Research Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may authorize the Superintendent of the Academy to accept qualifying research grants under this section. Any such grant may only be accepted if the work under the grant is to be carried out by a professor or instructor of the Academy for a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifying Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A qualifying research grant under this section is a grant that is awarded on a competitive basis by an entity referred to in subsection (c) for a research project with a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Entities From Which Grants May be Accepted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A grant may be accepted under this section only from a corporation, fund, foundation, educational institution, or similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific, literary, or educational purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration of Grant Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish an account for administering funds received as research grants under this section. The Superintendent shall use the funds in the account in accordance with applicable regulations and the terms and conditions of the grants received.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Related Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the Academy may be used to pay expenses incurred by the Academy in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, award of a qualifying research grant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1063(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2131</ref>, § 9357; renumbered § 9457, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9459.</num>
<heading> Mixed-funded athletic and recreational extracurricular programs: authority to manage appropriated funds in same manner as nonappropriated funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of an Academy mixed-funded athletic or recreational extracurricular program, the Secretary of the Air Force may designate funds appropriated to the Department of the Air Force and available for that program to be treated as nonappropriated funds and expended for that program in accordance with laws applicable to the expenditure of nonappropriated funds. Appropriated funds so designated shall be considered to be nonappropriated funds for all purposes and shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “Academy mixed-funded athletic or recreational extracurricular program” means an athletic or recreational extracurricular program of the Academy to which each of the following applies:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The program is not considered a morale, welfare, or recreation program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The program is supported through appropriated funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The program is supported by a nonappropriated fund instrumentality.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The program is not a private organization and is not operated by a private organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 544(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1907</ref>, § 9359; renumbered § 9459, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9460.</num>
<heading> Cadets: charges and fees for attendance; limitation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), no charge or fee for tuition, room, or board for attendance at the Academy may be imposed unless the charge or fee is specifically authorized by a law enacted after <date date="1994-10-05">October 5, 1994</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibition specified in subsection (a) does not apply with respect to any item or service provided to cadets for which a charge or fee is imposed as of <date date="1994-10-05">October 5, 1994</date>. The Secretary of Defense shall notify Congress of any change made by the Academy in the amount of a charge or fee authorized under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 545(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1908</ref>, § 9360; renumbered § 9460, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9461.</num>
<heading> Policy on sexual harassment and sexual violence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under guidance prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Air Force shall direct the Superintendent of the Academy to prescribe a policy on sexual harassment and sexual violence applicable to the cadets and other personnel of the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matters to Be Specified in Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The policy on sexual harassment and sexual violence prescribed under this section shall include specification of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Programs to promote awareness of the incidence of rape, acquaintance rape, and other sexual offenses of a criminal nature that involve cadets or other Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Procedures that a cadet should follow in the case of an occurrence of sexual harassment or sexual violence, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the cadet chooses to report an occurrence of sexual harassment or sexual violence, a specification of the person or persons to whom the alleged offense should be reported and the options for confidential reporting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a specification of any other person whom the victim should contact; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> procedures on the preservation of evidence potentially necessary for proof of criminal sexual assault.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Procedures for disciplinary action in cases of alleged criminal sexual assault involving a cadet or other Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any other sanction authorized to be imposed in a substantiated case of sexual harassment or sexual violence involving a cadet or other Academy personnel in rape, acquaintance rape, or any other criminal sexual offense, whether forcible or nonforcible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Required training on the policy for all cadets and other Academy personnel, including the specific training required for personnel who process allegations of sexual harassment or sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Assessment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, through the Secretary of the Air Force, shall direct the Superintendent to conduct at the Academy during each Academy program year an assessment, to be administered by the Department of Defense, to determine the effectiveness of the policies, training, and procedures of the Academy with respect to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For the assessment at the Academy under paragraph (1) with respect to an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year, the Secretary of the Air Force shall conduct a survey, to be administered by the Department of Defense, of Academy personnel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to measure—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual violence events, on or off the Academy reservation, that have been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual violence events, on or off the Academy reservation, that have not been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to assess the perceptions of Academy personnel of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the policies, training, and procedures on sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the enforcement of such policies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the incidence of sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other issues relating to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may postpone the conduct of an assessment under this subsection if the Secretary determines that conducting such assessment is not practicable due to a war or national emergency declared by the President or Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that an assessment postponed under subparagraph (A) is conducted as soon as practicable after the end of the period of war or national emergency concerned, or earlier if the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall notify Congress of a determination under subparagraph (A) not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary makes such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force shall direct the Superintendent of the Academy to submit to the Secretary a report on sexual harassment and sexual violence involving cadets or other personnel at the Academy for each Academy program year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, for the Academy program year covered by the report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The number of sexual assaults, rapes, and other sexual offenses involving cadets or other Academy personnel that have been reported to Academy officials during the program year and, of those reported cases, the number that have been substantiated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The policies, procedures, and processes implemented by the Secretary of the Air Force and the leadership of the Academy in response to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving cadets or other Academy personnel during the program year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A plan for the actions that are to be taken in the following Academy program year regarding prevention of and response to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving cadets or other Academy personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each report under paragraph (1) for an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year shall include the results of the survey conducted in that program year under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force shall transmit to the Secretary of Defense, and to the Board of Visitors of the Academy, each report received by the Secretary under this subsection, together with the Secretary’s comments on the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall transmit each such report, together with the Secretary’s comments on the report, to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration of Request for Transfer of a Cadet Who Is the Victim of a Sexual Assault or Related Offense</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force shall provide for timely consideration of and action on a request submitted by a cadet appointed to the United States Air Force Academy who is the victim of an alleged sexual assault or other offense covered by section 920, 920c, or 930 of this title (article 120, 120c, or 130 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice) for transfer to another military service academy or to enroll in a Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program affiliated with another institution of higher education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Air Force shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection, within guidelines provided by the Secretary of Defense that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide that the Superintendent of the United States Air Force Academy shall ensure that any cadet who has been appointed to the United States Air Force Academy and who is a victim of an alleged sexual assault or other offense referred to in paragraph (1), is informed of the right to request a transfer pursuant to this section, and that any formal request submitted by a cadet is processed as expeditiously as practicable through the chain of command for review and action by the Superintendent;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> direct the Superintendent of the United States Air Force Academy, in coordination with the Superintendent of the military service academy to which the cadet requests to transfer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to take action on a request for transfer under this subsection not later than 72 hours after receiving the formal request from the cadet;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to approve such request for transfer unless there are exceptional circumstances that require denial of the request; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> upon approval of such request, to take all necessary and appropriate action to effectuate the transfer of the cadet to the military service academy concerned as expeditiously as possible; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> direct the Superintendent of the United States Air Force Academy, in coordination with the Secretary of the military department that sponsors the Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program at the institution of higher education to which the cadet requests to transfer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to take action on a request for transfer under this subsection not later than 72 hours after receiving the formal request from the cadet;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> subject to the cadet’s acceptance for admission to the institution of higher education to which the cadet wishes to transfer, to approve such request for transfer unless there are exceptional circumstances that require denial of the application; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to take all necessary and appropriate action to effectuate the cadet’s enrollment in the institution of higher education to which the cadet wishes to transfer and to process the cadet for participation in the relevant Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program as expeditiously as possible.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Superintendent of the United States Air Force Academy denies a request for transfer under this subsection, the cadet may request review of the denial by the Secretary of the Air Force, who shall take action on such request not later than 72 hours after receipt of the formal request for review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall ensure that all records of any request, determination, transfer, or other action under this subsection remain confidential, consistent with applicable law and regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A cadet who transfers under this subsection may retain the cadet’s appointment to the United States Air Force Academy or may be appointed to the military service academy to which the cadet transfers without regard to the limitations and requirements set forth in sections 7442, 8454, and 9442 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2203</ref>, § 9361; renumbered § 9461, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 555(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1390</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 552(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3632</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9462.</num>
<heading> Support of athletic programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Corporation for Support Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force may, in accordance with the laws of the State of incorporation, establish a corporation (in this section referred to as the “corporation”) to support the athletic programs of the Academy. All stock of the corporation shall be owned by the United States and held in the name of and voted by the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The corporation shall operate exclusively for charitable, educational, and civic purposes to support the athletic programs of the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Corporate Organization</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The corporation shall be organized and operated—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as a nonprofit corporation under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in accordance with this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> pursuant to the laws of the State of incorporation, its articles of incorporation, and its bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Corporate Board of Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The members of the board of directors of the corporation shall serve without compensation as members of the board, except for reasonable travel and other related expenses for attendance at meetings of the board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force may authorize military and civilian personnel of the Department of the Air Force under <ref>section 1033 of this title</ref> to serve, in their official capacities, as members of the board of directors of the corporation, but such personnel shall not hold more than one-third of the directorships.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfers From Nonappropriated Fund Operation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may, subject to the acceptance of the corporation, transfer to the corporation all title to and ownership of the assets and liabilities of the Air Force nonappropriated fund instrumentality whose functions include providing support for the athletic programs of the Academy, including bank accounts and financial reserves in its accounts, equipment, supplies, and other personal property, but excluding any interest in real property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Support.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support received from the corporation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary of the Air Force may accept from the corporation funds, supplies, equipment, and services for the support of the athletic programs of the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funds received from other sources</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may charge fees for the support of the athletic programs of the Academy. The Secretary may accept and retain fees for services and other benefits provided incident to the operation of its athletic programs, including fees from the National Collegiate Athletic Association, fees from athletic conferences, game guarantees from other educational institutions, fees for ticketing or licensing, and other consideration provided incidental to the execution of the athletic programs of the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure that contributions accepted under this subsection do not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Department of the Air Force, any of its employees, or any member of the armed forces to carry out any responsibility or duty in a fair and objective manner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the Department of the Air Force, or any individual involved in such a program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Leases and Licenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may, in accordance with <ref>section 2667 of this title</ref>, enter into leases or licenses with the corporation for the purpose of supporting the athletic programs of the Academy. Consideration provided under such a lease or license may be provided in the form of funds, supplies, equipment, and services for the support of the athletic programs of the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may provide support services to the corporation without charge while the corporation conducts its support activities at the Academy. In this paragraph, the term “support services” includes utilities, office furnishings and equipment, communications services, records staging and archiving, audio and video support, and security systems in conjunction with the leasing or licensing of property. Any such support services may only be provided without any liability of the United States to the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracts and Cooperative Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with the corporation for the purpose of supporting the athletic programs of the Academy. Notwithstanding <ref>section 3201(e) of this title</ref>, the Secretary may enter such contracts or cooperative agreements on a sole source basis pursuant to <ref>section 3204(a)(5) of this title</ref>. Notwithstanding chapter 63 of title 31, a cooperative agreement under this section may be used to acquire property, services, or travel for the direct benefit or use of the athletic programs of the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Trademarks and Service Marks.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Licensing, marketing, and sponsorship agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agreement under subsection (g) may, consistent with <ref>section 2260 of this title</ref> (other than subsection (d) of such section), authorize the corporation to enter into licensing, marketing, and sponsorship agreements relating to trademarks and service marks identifying the Academy, subject to the approval of the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No licensing, marketing, or sponsorship agreement may be entered into under paragraph (1) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such agreement would reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Department of the Air Force, any of its employees, or any member of the armed forces to carry out any responsibility or duty in a fair and objective manner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that the use of the trademark or service mark would compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the Department of the Air Force, or any individual involved in such a program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention and Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any funds received under this section may be retained for use in support of the athletic programs of the Academy and shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 528(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2289</ref>, § 9362; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 554</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3377</ref>; renumbered § 9462, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(15)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3815</ref>, 4294.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>