<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 322—</num>
<heading>MAJOR SYSTEMS AND MAJOR DEFENSE ACQUISITION PROGRAMS GENERALLY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>MANAGEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4211.</num>
<heading> Acquisition strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition Strategy Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be an acquisition strategy for each major defense acquisition program and each major system approved by a milestone decision authority.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsible Official</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each acquisition strategy required by subsection (a), the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, or the milestone decision authority, when the milestone decision authority is the service acquisition executive of the military department that is managing the program, is responsible for issuing and maintaining the requirements for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the content of the strategy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the review and approval process for the strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In issuing requirements for the content of an acquisition strategy for a major defense acquisition program or major system, the Under Secretary, or the milestone decision authority, when the milestone decision authority is the service acquisition executive of the military department that is managing the program, shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the strategy clearly describes the proposed top-level business and technical management approach for the program or system, in sufficient detail to allow the milestone decision authority to assess the viability of the proposed approach, the method of implementing laws and policies, and program objectives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the strategy contains a clear explanation of how the strategy is designed to be implemented with available resources, such as time, funding, and management capacity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the strategy is tailored to address program requirements and constraints; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the strategy considers the items listed in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each strategy shall, where appropriate, consider the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An approach that delivers required capability in increments, each depending on available mature technology, and that recognizes up front the need for future capability improvements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Acquisition approach, including industrial base considerations in accordance with <ref>section 4820 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Risk management, including such methods as competitive prototyping at the system, subsystem, or component level.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Business strategy, including measures to ensure competition at the system and subsystem level throughout the life-cycle of the program or system in accordance with <ref>section 4324 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> Contracting strategy, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> contract type and how the type selected relates to level of program risk in each acquisition phase;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> how the plans for the program or system to reduce risk enable the use of fixed-price elements in subsequent contracts and the timing of the use of those fixed price elements;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> market research; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> consideration of small business participation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Intellectual property strategy in accordance with sections 3771 through 3775 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> International involvement, including foreign military sales and cooperative opportunities, in accordance with <ref>section 2350a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Multiyear procurement in accordance with <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Integration of current intelligence assessments into the acquisition process.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Requirements related to logistics, maintenance, and sustainment in accordance with sections 2464 and 2466 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The milestone decision authority shall review and approve, as appropriate, the acquisition strategy for a major defense acquisition program or major system at each of the following times:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Milestone A approval.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The decision to release the request for proposals for development of the program or system.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Milestone B approval.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Each subsequent milestone.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Review of any decision to enter into full-rate production.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> When there has been—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a significant change to the cost of the program or system;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a critical change to the cost of the program or system;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a significant change to the schedule of the program or system; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a significant change to the performance of the program or system.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Any other time considered relevant by the milestone decision authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the milestone decision authority revises an acquisition strategy for a program or system because of a change described in paragraph (1)(F), the milestone decision authority shall provide notice of the revision to the congressional defense committees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Milestone A approval” means a decision to enter into technology maturation and risk reduction pursuant to guidance prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for the management of Department of Defense acquisition programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Milestone B approval” has the meaning provided in <ref>section 4172(e)(7) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “milestone decision authority”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major system, means the official within the Department of Defense designated with the overall responsibility and authority for acquisition decisions for the program or system, including authority to approve entry of the program or system into the next phase of the acquisition process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “management capacity”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major system, means the capacity to manage the program or system through the use of highly qualified organizations and personnel with appropriate experience, knowledge, and skills.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “significant change to the cost”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major system, means a significant cost growth threshold, as that term is defined in <ref>section 4371(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “critical change to the cost”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major system, means a critical cost growth threshold, as that term is defined in <ref>section 4371(a)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “significant change to the schedule”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major system, means any schedule delay greater than six months in a reported event.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 821(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 897</ref>, § 2431a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 848</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(39)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(70)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1551</ref>; renumbered § 4211 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4253</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(s)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2149</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(39)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4212.</num>
<heading> Risk management and mitigation in major defense acquisition programs and major systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the initial acquisition strategy (required under <ref>section 4211 of this title</ref>) approved by the milestone decision authority and any subsequent revisions include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A comprehensive approach for managing and mitigating risk (including technical, cost, and schedule risk) during each of the following periods or when determined appropriate by the milestone decision authority:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The period preceding engineering manufacturing development, or its equivalent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The period preceding initial production.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The period preceding full-rate production.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An identification of the major sources of risk in each of the periods listed in paragraph (1) to improve programmatic decisionmaking and appropriately minimize and manage program concurrency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approach to Manage and Mitigate Risks</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The comprehensive approach to manage and mitigate risk included in the acquisition strategy for purposes of subsection (a)(1) shall, at a minimum, include consideration of risk mitigation techniques such as the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Prototyping (including prototyping at the system, subsystem, or component level and competitive prototyping, where appropriate) and, if prototyping at either the system, subsystem, or component level is not used, an explanation of why it is not appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Modeling and simulation, the areas that modeling and simulation will assess, and identification of the need for development of any new modeling and simulation tools in order to support the comprehensive strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Technology demonstrations and decision points for disciplined transition of planned technologies into programs or the selection of alternative technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Multiple design approaches.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Alternative designs, including any designs that meet requirements but do so with reduced performance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Phasing of program activities or related technology development efforts in order to address high-risk areas as early as feasible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Manufacturability and industrial base availability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Independent risk element assessments by outside subject matter experts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Schedule and funding margins for identified risks.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preference for Prototyping</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To the maximum extent practicable and consistent with the economical use of available financial resources, the milestone decision authority for each major defense acquisition program shall ensure that the acquisition strategy for the program provides for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the production of competitive prototypes at the system or subsystem level before Milestone B approval; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the production of competitive prototypes is not practicable, the production of single prototypes at the system or subsystem level.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Concurrency Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “concurrency” means, with respect to an acquisition strategy, the combination or overlap of program phases or activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 822(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 900</ref>, § 2431b; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2417</ref>; renumbered § 4212 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4214.</num>
<heading> Baseline description</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Baseline Description Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department shall establish a baseline description for each major defense acquisition program and for each designated major subprogram under the program under the jurisdiction of such Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The baseline shall include sufficient parameters to describe the cost estimate (referred to as the “Baseline Estimate” in sections 4371 through 4375 of this title), schedule, performance, supportability, and any other factor of such major defense acquisition program or designated major subprogram.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding Limit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No amount appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Defense for carrying out a major defense acquisition program or any designated major subprogram under the program may be obligated after the program or subprogram enters system development and demonstration without an approved baseline description unless such obligation is specifically approved by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Schedule</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A baseline description for a major defense acquisition program or any designated major subprogram under the program shall be prepared under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> before the program or subprogram enters system development and demonstration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> before the program or subprogram enters production and deployment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> before the program or subprogram enters full rate production.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Original Baseline Estimate</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In this subpart, the term “original Baseline Estimate”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or any designated major subprogram under the program, means the baseline description established with respect to the program or subprogram under subsection (a) prepared before the program or subprogram enters system development and demonstration, or at program or subprogram initiation, whichever occurs later, without adjustment or revision (except as provided in paragraph (2)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An adjustment or revision of the original baseline description of a major defense acquisition program or any designated major subprogram under the program may be treated as the original Baseline Estimate for the program or subprogram for purposes of this chapter only if the percentage increase in the program acquisition unit cost or procurement unit cost under such adjustment or revision exceeds the critical cost growth threshold for the program or subprogram under sections 4371 through 4375 of this title, as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned under <ref>section 4374 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the event of an adjustment or revision of the original baseline description of a major defense acquisition program or any designated major subprogram under the program, the Secretary of Defense shall include in the next Selected Acquisition Report to be submitted under <ref>section 4351 of this title</ref> after such adjustment or revision a notification to the congressional defense committees of such adjustment or revision, together with the reasons for such adjustment or revision.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations governing the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The content of baseline descriptions under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The submission to the Secretary of the military department concerned and the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment by the program manager for a program for which there is an approved baseline description (or in the case of a major defense acquisition program with one or more designated major subprograms, approved baseline descriptions for such subprograms) under this section of reports of deviations from any such baseline description of the cost, schedule, performance, supportability, or any other factor of the program or subprogram.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Procedures for review of such deviation reports within the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Procedures for submission to, and approval by, the Secretary of Defense of revised baseline descriptions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title X, § 904(a)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–82</ref>, 1783–133, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title X, § 904(a)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–82</ref>, 3341–133, § 2435; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IX</ref>, formerly title IV, § 904(a)(1), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3912</ref>, renumbered title IX, <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 273</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 280</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VIII, § 803(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1125</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 848</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1233</ref>(<i>l</i>)(4), <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2058</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VIII, § 811(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1207(b)</ref>, title XIV, § 1484(k)(11), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1665</ref>, 1719; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title III, § 3005(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3330</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VIII, § 821(d)</ref>, title X, § 1048(b)(2), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1182</ref>, 1225; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VIII, § 802(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2315</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 811(d), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4524</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(71)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1551</ref>; renumbered § 4214 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4254</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(6)(C)(i), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>CONTRACTING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4231.</num>
<heading> Major systems: determination of quantity for low-rate initial production</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of Quantities To Be Procured for Low-Rate Initial Production</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In the course of the development of a major system, the determination of what quantity of articles of that system should be procured for low-rate initial production (including the quantity to be procured for preproduction verification articles) shall be made—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> when the milestone B decision with respect to that system is made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by the official of the Department of Defense who makes that decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “milestone B decision” means the decision to approve the system development and demonstration of a major system by the official of the Department of Defense designated to have the authority to make that decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any increase from a quantity determined under paragraph (1) may only be made with the approval of the official making the determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The quantity of articles of a major system that may be procured for low-rate initial production may not be less than one operationally configured production unit unless another quantity is established at the milestone B decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall include a statement of the quantity determined under paragraph (1) in the first SAR submitted with respect to the program concerned after that quantity is determined. If the quantity exceeds 10 percent of the total number of articles to be produced, as determined at the milestone B decision with respect to that system, the Secretary shall include in the statement the reasons for such quantity. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “SAR” means a Selected Acquisition Report submitted under <ref>section 4351 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Low-Rate Initial Production of Weapon Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (c), low-rate initial production with respect to a new system is production of the system in the minimum quantity necessary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide production-configured or representative articles for operational tests pursuant to <ref>section 4171 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to establish an initial production base for the system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to permit an orderly increase in the production rate for the system sufficient to lead to full-rate production upon the successful completion of operational testing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Low-Rate Initial Production of Naval Vessel and Satellite Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to naval vessel programs and military satellite programs, low-rate initial production is production of items at the minimum quantity and rate that (1) preserves the mobilization production base for that system, and (2) is feasible, as determined pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VIII, § 803(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1487</ref>, § 2400; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title III, § 3015</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3332</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1062(d)</ref>, div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(b)(13), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 444</ref>, 673; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VIII, § 821(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1182</ref>; renumbered § 4231 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4254</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(6)(C)(ii), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4232.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on use of lowest price technically acceptable source selection process</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Department of Defense shall not use a lowest price technically acceptable source selection process for the engineering and manufacturing development contract of a major defense acquisition program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lowest price technically acceptable source selection process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “lowest price technically acceptable source selection process” has the meaning given that term in part 15 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Engineering and manufacturing development contract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “engineering and manufacturing development contract” means a prime contract for the engineering and manufacturing development of a major defense acquisition program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 832(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1468</ref>, § 2442; renumbered § 4232 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4236.</num>
<heading> Negotiation of price for technical data before development, production, or sustainment of major weapon systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the Department of Defense, before selecting a contractor for the engineering and manufacturing development of a major weapon system, production of a major weapon system, or sustainment of a major weapon system, negotiates a price for technical data to be delivered under a contract for such development, production, or sustainment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 835(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1471</ref>, § 2439; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 867</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1901</ref>; renumbered § 4236, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>MILESTONES FOR MAJOR DEFENSE ACQUISITION PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4251.</num>
<heading> Major defense acquisition programs: factors to be considered before Milestone A approval</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before granting Milestone A approval for a major defense acquisition program or a major subprogram, the milestone decision authority for the program or subprogram shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information about the program or subprogram is sufficient to warrant entry of the program or subprogram into the risk reduction phase;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the cost, schedule, technical feasibility, and performance trade-offs that have been made with regard to the program do not overly constrain future trade space; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> there are sound plans for progression of the program or subprogram to the development phase.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors to Be Considered for Milestone a Approval</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A major defense acquisition program or subprogram may not receive Milestone A approval or otherwise be initiated prior to Milestone B approval until the milestone decision authority confirms that the following factors were considered in the decision to grant Milestone A approval:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The program or subprogram fulfills an approved requirements document.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The program or subprogram has conducted appropriate market research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> With respect to any identified areas of risk, there is a plan to reduce the risk.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Planning for sustainment has been addressed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An analysis of alternatives has been performed consistent with study guidance developed by the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation, or in lieu of an analysis of alternatives, early experimentation with a combatant commander has been conducted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A life cycle cost estimate for the program or subprogram has been submitted by the component and that the level of resources required to complete the technology maturation and risk reduction phase of the program is sufficient for successful program execution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The program or subprogram meets any other considerations the milestone decision authority considers relevant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Written Record of a Milestone Decision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The milestone decision authority shall issue a written record of a milestone decision at the time that Milestone A approval is granted. The record shall confirm compliance with subsection (b) and specifically state that the milestone decision authority considered the factors described in such subsection prior to the decision to grant milestone approval. The milestone decision authority shall retain records of the basis for the milestone decision.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Submissions to Congress on Milestone A.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 15 days after granting Milestone A approval for a major defense acquisition program, the milestone decision authority for the program shall provide to the congressional defense committees and, in the case of intelligence or intelligence-related activities, the congressional intelligence committees a written record of the milestone decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At the request of any of the congressional defense committees or, in the case of intelligence or intelligence-related activities, the congressional intelligence committees, the milestone decision authority shall submit to the committee an explanation of the basis for the decision to grant Milestone A approval with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major subprogram, and make available all underlying documentation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “requirements document” means any capabilities requirement document approved by the Joint Requirements Oversight Council that establishes the need for a materiel approach to resolve a capability gap.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Milestone A approval” means a decision to enter into technology maturation and risk reduction pursuant to guidance prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for the management of Department of Defense acquisition programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Milestone B approval” has the meaning provided that term in <ref>section 4172(e)(7) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “milestone decision authority”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or a major subprogram, means the official within the Department of Defense designated with the overall responsibility and authority for acquisition decisions for the program or subprogram, including authority to approve entry of the program or subprogram into the next phase of the acquisition process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “congressional intelligence committees” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 437(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 943(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 288</ref>, § 2366b; renumbered § 2366a and amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 813(b), (e)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4527</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–23, title I, § 101(d)(3)</ref>, title II, §§ 201(e), 204(a), (b), <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1710</ref>, 1720, 1723; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 814(b)</ref>, title X, § 1075(b)(33), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4266</ref>, 4370; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 801(a)</ref>, (e)(1), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1482</ref>, 1483; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title III, § 322(e)(1)</ref>, title X, § 1076(a)(10), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1695</ref>, 1948; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 823(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(b), 807(d), 808(a), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2259</ref>, 2262; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 831(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1857</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(44)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1814</ref>; renumbered § 4251 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4254</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4252.</num>
<heading> Major defense acquisition programs: factors to be considered before Milestone B approval</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before granting Milestone B approval for a major defense acquisition program or major subprogram, the milestone decision authority for the program or subprogram shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information about the program or subprogram is sufficient to warrant entry of the program or subprogram into the engineering and manufacturing development phase;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> appropriate trade-offs among cost, schedule, technical feasibility, and performance objectives have been made to ensure that the program or subprogram is affordable when considering the per-unit cost and the total life-cycle cost, and the Secretary of the military department concerned and the Chief of the armed force concerned concur with these trade-offs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> there are sound plans for progression of the program or subprogram to the production phase.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Factors to Be Considered for Milestone B Approval</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A major defense acquisition program or major subprogram may not receive Milestone B approval until the milestone decision authority confirms the following factors were considered in the decision to grant Milestone B approval:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The program or subprogram has received a preliminary design review and a formal post-preliminary design review or an equivalent assessment was conducted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The technology in the program or subprogram has been demonstrated in a relevant environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The program or subprogram is affordable when considering the ability of the Department of Defense to accomplish the program’s or subprogram’s general mission using alternative systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Reasonable lifecycle cost and schedule estimates have been developed to execute, with the concurrence of the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation, the plan under the program or subprogram.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The estimated procurement unit cost for the program or subprogram and the estimated date for initial operational capability for the baseline description for the program or subprogram (under <ref>section 4214 of this title</ref>) have been established.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Funding is expected to be available to execute the product development and production plan for the program or subprogram, consistent with the estimates described in paragraph (4) for the program or subprogram.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Appropriate market research has been conducted prior to technology development, including market research of commercial products, commercial services, and nondevelopmental items (as defined in <ref>section 110 of title 41</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The Department of Defense has completed an analysis of alternatives with respect to the program or subprogram, or in lieu of an analysis of alternatives, early experimentation with a combatant commander has been conducted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The Joint Requirements Oversight Council has accomplished its duties with respect to the program or subprogram pursuant to <ref>section 181(b) of this title</ref>, including an analysis of the operational requirements for the program or subprogram.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Life-cycle sustainment planning has identified and evaluated relevant sustainment cost elements, factors, risks, and gaps that are likely to drive readiness of the system as well as operating and supporting costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> An estimate has been made of the requirements for core logistics capabilities and the associated sustaining workloads required to support such requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The program or subprogram complies with all relevant policies, regulations, and directives of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Appropriate actions are planned for the acquisition of technical data required to support the program or subprogram.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> The program or subprogram has an approved life cycle sustainment plan required under <ref>section 4324(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> In the case of a naval vessel program or subprogram, such program or subprogram is in compliance with the requirements of <ref>section 8669b of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Written Record of Milestone Decision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The milestone decision authority shall issue a written record of decision at the time that Milestone B approval is granted. The record shall confirm compliance with subsection (b) and specifically state that the milestone decision authority considered the factors described in subsection (b) prior to the decision to grant milestone approval. The milestone decision authority shall retain records of the basis for the milestone decision.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Changes to Basis for Milestone Approval</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The program manager for a major defense acquisition program that has received a written record of the milestone decision under subsection (c) shall immediately notify the milestone decision authority of any changes to the program or a designated major subprogram of such program that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> alter the substantive basis for the decision of the milestone decision authority relating to any component of such decision specified in subsection (b); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> otherwise cause the program or subprogram to deviate significantly from the material provided to the milestone decision authority in support of such decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon receipt of information under paragraph (1), the milestone decision authority may rescind Milestone B approval if the milestone decision authority determines that such approval is no longer valid.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Submissions to Congress on Milestone B.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 15 days after granting Milestone B approval for a major defense acquisition program or major subprogram, the milestone decision authority for the program or subprogram shall provide to the congressional defense committees and, in the case of intelligence or intelligence-related activities, the congressional intelligence committees a written record of the milestone decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional information</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> At the request of any of the congressional defense committees or, in the case of intelligence or intelligence-related activities, the congressional intelligence committees, the milestone decision authority shall submit to the committee an explanation of the basis for the decision to grant Milestone B approval with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major subprogram, or further information or underlying documentation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The explanation or additional information shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “milestone decision authority”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means the official within the Department of Defense designated with the overall responsibility and authority for acquisition decisions for the program, including authority to approve entry of the program into the next phase of the acquisition process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Milestone B approval” has the meaning provided that term in <ref>section 4172(e)(7) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “core logistics capabilities” means the core logistics capabilities identified under <ref>section 2464(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “congressional intelligence committees” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 437(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “written record of milestone decision”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or a major subprogram, means a document signed by the milestone decision authority that formalizes approved entry of the program or subprogram into the next phase of the acquisition process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VIII, § 801(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3366</ref>, § 2366a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VIII, § 805</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VIII, § 812</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 219</ref>; renumbered § 2366b, <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 813(a), (b), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4527</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–23, title I, § 101(d)(4)</ref>, title II, §§ 201(f), 205(a), <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1710</ref>, 1720, 1724; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 813(d)(1), 814(c), title IX, § 901(j)(4), title X, § 1075(k)(1), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4265</ref>, 4266, 4324, 4378; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 801(b), (e)(2), 819(b), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1483</ref>, 1484, 1501; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title III, § 322(e)(2)</ref>, title IX, § 904(e)(2), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1695</ref>, 1867; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 821(a), 822(a), title X, § 1091(b)(1), <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 809</ref>, 876; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 824(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 903</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 805(a)(3), 807(e), 808(b), 843, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2255</ref>, 2262, 2263, 2290; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 835(b)(1), 838(a)(1), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1471</ref>, 1474; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 831(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1857</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 833</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1494</ref>; renumbered § 4252 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 802(b)</ref>, title XVIII, §§ 1847(d)(2), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3732</ref>, 4255, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(6)(C)(iii), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 807</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4253.</num>
<heading> Major defense acquisition programs: submissions to Congress on Milestone C</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Brief Summary Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 15 days after granting Milestone C approval for a major defense acquisition program, the milestone decision authority for the program shall provide to the congressional defense committees and, in the case of intelligence or intelligence-related activities, the congressional intelligence committees a brief summary report that contains the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The estimated cost and schedule for the program established by the military department concerned, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the dollar values estimated for the program acquisition unit cost, average procurement unit cost, and total life-cycle cost; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the planned dates for initial operational test and evaluation and initial operational capability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The independent estimated cost for the program established pursuant to <ref>section 3221(b)(6) of this title</ref>, and any independent estimated schedule for the program, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the dollar values estimated for the program acquisition unit cost, average procurement unit cost, and total life-cycle cost; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the planned dates for initial operational test and evaluation and initial operational capability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A summary of any production, manufacturing, and fielding risks associated with the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An assessment of the sufficiency of the developmental test and evaluation completed, including the use of automated data analytics or modeling and simulation tools and methodologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At the request of any of the congressional defense committees or, in the case of intelligence or intelligence-related activities, the congressional intelligence committees, the milestone decision authority shall submit to the committee further information or underlying documentation for the information in a brief summary report submitted under subsection (a), including the independent cost and schedule estimates and the independent technical risk assessments referred to in that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Intelligence Committees Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “congressional intelligence committees” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 437(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 808(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2265</ref>, § 2366c; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 838(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1474</ref>; renumbered § 4253 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>ADDITIONAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE SPECIFICALLY TO MAJOR DEFENSE ACQUISITION PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4271.</num>
<heading> Program cost, fielding, and performance goals in planning major defense acquisition programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Cost and Fielding Targets</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Before funds are obligated for technology development, systems development, or production of a major defense acquisition program, the designated milestone decision authority for the program shall ensure, by establishing the goals described in paragraph (2), that the program will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be affordable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> incorporate program planning that anticipates the evolution of capabilities to meet changing threats, technology insertion, and interoperability; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> be fielded when needed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The goals described in this paragraph are goals for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the procurement unit cost and sustainment cost (referred to in this section as the “program cost targets”);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date for initial operational capability (referred to in this section as the “fielding target”); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> technology maturation, prototyping, and a modular open system approach to evolve system capabilities and improve interoperability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “procurement unit cost” has the meaning provided in <ref>section 4351(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “initial capabilities document” has the meaning provided in <ref>section 4251(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2260</ref>, § 2448a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 831(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1857</ref>; renumbered § 4271 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(6)(C)(iv), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4272.</num>
<heading> Independent technical risk assessments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to a major defense acquisition program, the Secretary of Defense shall conduct or approve independent technical risk assessments before any decision to grant Milestone B approval for the program pursuant to <ref>section 4252 of this title</ref>, any decision to enter into low-rate initial production or full-rate production, or at any other time considered appropriate by the Secretary, that includes the identification of any critical technologies or manufacturing processes that have not been successfully demonstrated in a relevant environment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall issue guidance and a framework for the conduct, execution, and approval of independent technical risk assessments.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2261</ref>, § 2448b; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(73)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1552</ref>; renumbered § 4272 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4273.</num>
<heading> Performance assessments and root cause analyses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Senior Official Responsibility for Performance Assessments and Root Cause Analyses</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall designate a senior official in the Office of the Secretary of Defense as the principal official of the Department of Defense responsible for conducting and overseeing performance assessments and root cause analyses for major defense acquisition programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No program execution responsibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that the senior official designated under paragraph (1) is not responsible for program execution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Staff and resources</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall assign to the senior official designated under paragraph (1) appropriate staff and resources necessary to carry out the senior official’s function under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The senior official designated under subsection (a) shall be responsible for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Carrying out performance assessments of major defense acquisition programs in accordance with the requirements of subsection (c) periodically or when requested by the Secretary of Defense, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, the Secretary of a military department, or the head of a Defense Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Conducting root cause analyses for major defense acquisition programs in accordance with the requirements of subsection (d) when required by <ref>section 4376(a)(1) of this title</ref>, or when requested by the Secretary of Defense, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, the Secretary of a military department, or the head of a Defense Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Issuing policies, procedures, and guidance governing the conduct of performance assessments and root cause analyses by the military departments and the Defense Agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Evaluating the utility of performance metrics used to measure the cost, schedule, and performance of major defense acquisition programs, and making such recommendations to the Secretary of Defense as the official considers appropriate to improve such metrics.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Advising acquisition officials on performance issues regarding a major defense acquisition program that may arise—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> before certification under sections 4376 and 4377 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> before entry into full-rate production; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the course of consideration of any decision to request authorization of a multiyear procurement contract for the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance Assessments</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section, a performance assessment with respect to a major defense acquisition program is an evaluation of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The cost, schedule, and performance of the program, relative to current metrics, including performance requirements and baseline descriptions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The extent to which the level of program cost, schedule, and performance predicted relative to such metrics is likely to result in the timely delivery of a level of capability to the warfighter that is consistent with the level of resources to be expended and provides superior value to alternative approaches that may be available to meet the same military requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Root Cause Analyses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section and sections 4376 and 4377 of this title, a root cause analysis with respect to a major defense acquisition program is an assessment of the underlying cause or causes of shortcomings in cost, schedule, or performance of the program, including the role, if any, of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> unrealistic performance expectations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> unrealistic baseline estimates for cost or schedule;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> immature technologies or excessive manufacturing or integration risk;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> unanticipated design, engineering, manufacturing, or technology integration issues arising during program performance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> changes in procurement quantities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> inadequate program funding or funding instability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> poor performance by government or contractor personnel responsible for program management; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> any other matters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support of Applicable Capabilities and Expertise</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the senior official designated under subsection (a) has the support of other Department of Defense officials with relevant capabilities and expertise needed to carry out the requirements of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title IX, § 901(d)</ref>, (k)(1)(F), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4321</ref>, 4325, § 2438; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(27)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1077(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 998</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(72)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1551</ref>; renumbered § 4273 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(16)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2134</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(34)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 685</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(44)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 4274.</num>
<heading> Omitted]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>CONTRACTORS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4292.</num>
<heading> Contracts: limitations on lead system integrators</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), no entity performing lead system integrator functions in the acquisition of a major system by the Department of Defense may have any direct financial interest in the development or construction of any individual system or element of any system of systems.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An entity described in subsection (a) may have a direct financial interest in the development or construction of an individual system or element of a system of systems if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of Defense certifies to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the entity was selected by the Department of Defense as a contractor to develop or construct the system or element concerned through the use of competitive procedures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Department took appropriate steps to prevent any organizational conflict of interest in the selection process; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the entity was selected by a subcontractor to serve as a lower-tier subcontractor, through a process over which the entity exercised no control.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude an entity described in subsection (a) from performing work necessary to integrate two or more individual systems or elements of a system of systems with each other.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2315</ref>, § 2410p; renumbered § 4292, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4293.</num>
<heading> Major defense acquisition programs: incentive program for contractors to purchase capital assets manufactured in United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Incentive Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall plan and establish an incentive program in accordance with this section for contractors to purchase capital assets manufactured in the United States in part with funds available to the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense Industrial Capabilities Fund May Be Used</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may use the Defense Industrial Capabilities Fund, established under section 814 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2004, for incentive payments under the program established under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability to Major Defense Acquisition Program Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The incentive program shall apply to contracts for the procurement of a major defense acquisition program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall provide consideration in source selection in any request for proposals for a major defense acquisition program for offerors with eligible capital assets.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 822(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1546</ref>, § 2436; renumbered § 4293, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>