<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 937—</num>
<heading>DECORATIONS AND AWARDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9271.</num>
<heading> Medal of honor: award</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may award, and present in the name of Congress, a medal of honor of appropriate design, with ribbons and appurtenances, to a person who, while a member of the Air Force or the Space Force, distinguishes himself conspicuously by gallantry and intrepidity at the risk of his life above and beyond the call of duty—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> while engaged in an action against an enemy of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> while engaged in military operations involving conflict with an opposing foreign force; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> while serving with friendly foreign forces engaged in an armed conflict against an opposing armed force in which the United States is not a belligerent party.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 540</ref>, § 8741; <ref>Pub. L. 88–77, § 3(1)</ref>, <date date="1963-07-25">July 25, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 94</ref>; renumbered § 9271, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(c)(12)(A)(i)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9272.</num>
<heading> Air Force cross: award</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may award an Air Force cross of appropriate design, with ribbons and appurtenances, to a person who, while serving in any capacity with the Air Force or the Space Force, distinguishes himself by extraordinary heroism not justifying the award of a medal of honor—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> while engaged in an action against an enemy of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> while engaged in military operations involving conflict with an opposing foreign force; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> while serving with friendly foreign forces engaged in an armed conflict against an opposing armed force in which the United States is not a belligerent party.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 540</ref>, § 8742; <ref>Pub. L. 86–593, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-06">July 6, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 331</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–77, § 3(2)</ref>, <date date="1963-07-25">July 25, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 94</ref>; renumbered § 9272, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(c)(12)(A)(ii)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9273.</num>
<heading> Distinguished-service medal: award</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may award a distinguished-service medal of appropriate design and a ribbon, together with a rosette or other device to be worn in place thereof, to a person who, while serving in any capacity with the Air Force or the Space Force, distinguishes himself by exceptionally meritorious service to the United States in a duty of great responsibility.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 540</ref>, § 8743; renumbered § 9273, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(c)(12)(A)(iii)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9274.</num>
<heading> Medal of honor; Air Force cross; distinguished-service medal: limitations on award</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No more than one Air Force Cross or distinguished-service medal may be awarded to a person. However, for each succeeding act that would otherwise justify the award of such a medal or cross, the President may award a suitable bar or other device to be worn as he directs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (c), no medal of honor, Air Force cross, distinguished-service medal, or device in place thereof, may be awarded to a person unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the award is made within five years after the date of the act justifying the award;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a statement setting forth the distinguished service and recommending official recognition of it was made within three years after the distinguished service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> it appears from records of the Department of the Air Force that the person is entitled to the award.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary of the Air Force determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a statement setting forth the distinguished service and recommending official recognition of it was made and supported by sufficient evidence within three years after the distinguished service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> no award was made, because the statement was lost or through inadvertence the recommendation was not acted on;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">a medal of honor, Air Force cross, distinguished-service medal, or device in place thereof, as the case may be, may be awarded to the person concerned within two years after the date of that determination.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 540</ref>, § 8744; <ref>Pub. L. 86–582, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-05">July 5, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 320</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–593, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-06">July 6, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 331</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 561(c), 562(b), <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 766</ref>; renumbered § 9274, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 582(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1412</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9275.</num>
<heading> Medal of honor; Air Force cross; distinguished-service medal: delegation of power to award</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may delegate his authority to award the medal of honor, Air Force cross, and distinguished-service medal, to a commanding general of a separate air force or higher unit in the field, or to an equivalent commander of a separate space force or higher unit in the field.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 541</ref>, § 8745; <ref>Pub. L. 86–593, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-06">July 6, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 332</ref>; renumbered § 9275, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(c)(12)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9276.</num>
<heading> Silver star: award</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may award a silver star of appropriate design, with ribbons and appurtenances, to a person who, while serving in any capacity with the Air Force or the Space Force, is cited for gallantry in action that does not warrant a medal of honor or Air Force cross—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> while engaged in an action against an enemy of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> while engaged in military operations involving conflict with an opposing foreign force; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> while serving with friendly foreign forces engaged in an armed conflict against an opposing armed force in which the United States is not a belligerent party.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 541</ref>, § 8746; <ref>Pub. L. 88–77, § 3(3)</ref>, <date date="1963-07-25">July 25, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 95</ref>; renumbered § 9276, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(c)(12)(A)(iv)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9277.</num>
<heading> Medal of honor; Air Force cross; distinguished-service cross; distinguished-service medal; silver star: replacement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any medal of honor, Air Force cross, distinguished-service cross, distinguished-service medal, or silver star, or any bar, ribbon, rosette, or other device issued for wear with or in place of any of them, that is stolen, lost, or destroyed, or becomes unfit for use, without fault or neglect of the person to whom it was awarded, shall be replaced without charge.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 541</ref>, § 8747; <ref>Pub. L. 86–593, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-06">July 6, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 332</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 553(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1116</ref>; renumbered § 9277, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9278.</num>
<heading> Medal of honor; Air Force cross; distinguished-service cross; distinguished-service medal; silver star: availability of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Air Force may spend, from any appropriation for contingent expenses of the Department of the Air Force, amounts necessary to provide medals and devices under sections 9271, 9272, 9273, 9274, 9276, 9277, and 9282 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 541</ref>, § 8748; <ref>Pub. L. 86–593, § 1(5)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-06">July 6, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 332</ref>; renumbered § 9278 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(b)(11), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9279.</num>
<heading> Distinguished flying cross: award; limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President may award a distinguished flying cross of appropriate design with accompanying ribbon to any person who, while serving in any capacity with the Air Force or Space Force, distinguishes himself by heroism or extraordinary achievement while participating in an aerial or space flight.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Not more than one distinguished flying cross may be awarded to a person. However, for each succeeding act that would otherwise justify the award of such a cross, the President may award a suitable bar or other device to be worn as he directs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 541</ref>, § 8749; renumbered § 9279, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 582(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 521(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1882</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9280.</num>
<heading> Airman’s Medal: award; limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President may award a decoration called the “Airman’s Medal”, of appropriate design with accompanying ribbon, to any person who, while serving in any capacity with the Air Force or Space Force, distinguishes himself by heroism not involving actual conflict with an enemy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authority in paragraph (1) includes authority to award the medal to a member of the Ready Reserve who was not in a duty status defined in <ref>section 101(d) of this title</ref> when the member distinguished himself by heroism.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Not more than one Airman’s Medal may be awarded to a person. However, for each succeeding act that would otherwise justify the award of such a medal, the President may award a suitable bar or other device to be worn as he directs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 542</ref>, § 8750; <ref>Pub. L. 86–593, § 1(6)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-06">July 6, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 332</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 574(c)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1758</ref>; renumbered § 9280, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 521(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1882</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9281.</num>
<heading> Service medals: issue; replacement; availability of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force shall procure, and issue without charge to any person entitled thereto, any service medal authorized for members of the Air Force or the Space Force after <date date="1947-09-26">September 26, 1947</date>, and any ribbon, clasp, star, or similar device prescribed as a part of that medal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, any medal or other device issued under subsection (a) that is lost, destroyed, or becomes unfit for use without fault or neglect of the owner, may be replaced at cost. However, if the owner is a member of the Air Force or the Space Force, the medal or device may be replaced without charge.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may spend, from any appropriation for the support of the Air Force or the Space Force, amounts necessary to provide medals and devices under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 542</ref>, § 8751; renumbered § 9281, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(c)(12)(A)(v)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9282.</num>
<heading> Medals: posthumous award and presentation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If a person dies before the award of a medal of honor, distinguished-service cross, distinguished-service medal, distinguished flying cross, or device in place thereof, to which he is entitled, the award may be made and the medal or device presented to his representative, as designated by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If a person dies before an authorized service medal or device prescribed as a part thereof is presented to him under <ref>section 9281 of this title</ref>, it shall be presented to his family.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 542</ref>, § 8752; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 33(a)(23)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1565</ref>; renumbered § 9282 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(b)(11), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9284.</num>
<heading> Medal of honor: duplicate medal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person awarded a medal of honor shall, upon written application of that person, be issued, without charge, one duplicate medal of honor with ribbons and appurtenances. Such duplicate medal of honor shall be marked, in such manner as the Secretary of the Air Force may determine, as a duplicate or for display purposes only.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 553(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1116</ref>, § 8754; renumbered § 9284, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9285.</num>
<heading> Medal of honor: presentation of Medal of Honor Flag</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall provide for the presentation of the Medal of Honor Flag designated under <ref>section 903 of title 36</ref> to each person to whom a medal of honor is awarded under <ref>section 9271 of this title</ref>. Presentation of the flag shall be made at the same time as the presentation of the medal under section 9271 or 9282(a) of this title. In the case of a posthumous presentation of the medal, the flag shall be presented to the person to whom the medal is presented.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–248, title VIII, § 8143(c)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2002-10-23">Oct. 23, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1570</ref>, § 8755; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1062(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2650</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 555(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2217</ref>; renumbered § 9285 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(b)(11), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9286.</num>
<heading> Korea Defense Service Medal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force shall issue a campaign medal, to be known as the Korea Defense Service Medal, to each person who while a member of the Air Force or the Space Force served in the Republic of Korea or the waters adjacent thereto during the KDSM eligibility period and met the service requirements for the award of that medal prescribed under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “KDSM eligibility period” means the period beginning on <date date="1954-07-28">July 28, 1954</date>, and ending on such date after the date of the enactment of this section as may be determined by the Secretary of Defense to be appropriate for terminating eligibility for the Korea Defense Service Medal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force shall prescribe service requirements for eligibility for the Korea Defense Service Medal. Those requirements shall not be more stringent than the service requirements for award of the Armed Forces Expeditionary Medal for instances in which the award of that medal is authorized.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 543(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2550</ref>, § 8755; renumbered § 8756, <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(33)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2063</ref>; renumbered § 9286, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(c)(12)(A)(vi)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>