<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 857—</num>
<heading>RETIREMENT OF CIVILIAN MEMBERS OF THE TEACHING STAFFS OF THE UNITED STATES NAVAL ACADEMY AND UNITED STATES NAVAL POSTGRADUATE SCHOOL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8581.</num>
<heading> Civilian member: definition; exceptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In this chapter, the term “civilian member” means a civilian member of the teaching staff of the United States Naval Academy or the United States Naval Postgraduate School. It includes the Provost and Chief Academic Officer, senior professors, professors, associate professors, assistant professors, chief instructors, assistant chief instructors, and instructors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This chapter does not apply to any civilian member who was employed at the Naval Academy or the Postgraduate School on <date date="1936-01-16">January 16, 1936</date>, and who did not elect to participate in the benefits provided by the <ref>Act of January 16, 1936, ch. 3</ref> (<ref>49 Stat. 1092</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This chapter does not apply to any person who was a civilian member after <date date="1956-09-30">September 30, 1956</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 438</ref>, § 7081; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(149)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1513</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(e)(8)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1605</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 557(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1916</ref>; renumbered § 8581, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(45)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8582.</num>
<heading> Deferred annuity policy required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each civilian member, as a part of his contract of employment, shall carry, during his employment, a deferred annuity policy, having no cash surrender or loan provision, in a joint-stock life insurance corporation that is incorporated under the laws of a State and has a charter restriction that its business must be conducted without profit to its stockholders.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 439</ref>, § 7082; renumbered § 8582, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8583.</num>
<heading> Annuity premium to be paid by monthly installments; government reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each civilian member shall make a monthly allotment in an amount equal to 10 percent of his monthly basic salary toward the purchase of his deferred annuity policy. For each month the allotment is in force, the pay account of the civilian member shall be credited monthly from appropriations made for this purpose with an additional amount equal to 5 percent of his monthly basic salary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 439</ref>, § 7083; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 39</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1120</ref>; renumbered § 8583, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8584.</num>
<heading> Age of retirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A civilian member may be retired at any time after his sixty-fifth birthday, and shall be retired by June 30 following that birthday. However, in any special case the Secretary of the Navy may defer the retirement of a member until a date not later than the member’s seventieth birthday.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 439</ref>, § 7084; renumbered § 8584, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8585.</num>
<heading> Computation of life annuity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each civilian member who retires under <ref>section 8584 of this title</ref> is entitled to a life annuity computed by multiplying his average annual compensation during any five consecutive years of allowable service, at his option, by his number of years of service, not exceeding 35, and dividing the product by 70. The retirement annuity payable to a retired civilian member under a policy required by <ref>section 8582 of this title</ref> is counted as part of the retirement annuity provided in this section. Any difference between the amount received by the retired civilian member under his annuity policy and the total annual amount to which he is entitled under this section shall be paid to him by the Secretary of the Navy from appropriations made for this purpose.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 439</ref>, § 7085; renumbered § 8585 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(c)(1), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8586.</num>
<heading> Physical disability retirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each civilian member who has served not less than five years, and who, before reaching the age of 65, becomes totally disabled for useful and efficient service in his position, by reason of disease or injury not due to his own vicious habits, intemperance, or willful misconduct shall, upon his application or upon the request of the Secretary of the Navy, be retired with a life annuity computed under <ref>section 8585 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The amount that the Secretary shall pay annually under this section is the difference between the total amount to which the retired member is entitled under subsection (a) and the immediate life annuity to which he is entitled at the time of his disability retirement under the annuity policy required by <ref>section 8582 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Each civilian member retired under this section, unless the disability for which he was retired is permanent in character, shall be examined by a board of medical officers designated by the Superintendent of the Naval Academy or of the Postgraduate School, as appropriate, one year after his retirement and annually thereafter, until he becomes 65 years of age.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Payments by the Secretary under this section shall be terminated if the retired civilian member is found to be sufficiently recovered for useful and efficient service in his former position and is offered reemployment in that position by the Superintendent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If a civilian member retired under this section is later reemployed by the United States, the payments by the Secretary shall be terminated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Each civilian member retired under this section who is reemployed as a civilian member of the teaching staff of the Naval Academy or the Naval Postgraduate School shall, upon his later retirement, be paid annually by the Secretary the difference between the total annual amount computed under <ref>section 8585 of this title</ref> and the immediate life annuity which the total premiums paid on his annuity contracts would buy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> No person may receive payments from the Secretary of the Navy under this chapter and, for the same period of time, compensation under chapter 81 of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 439</ref>, § 7086; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 40</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1120</ref>; renumbered § 8586 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(c)(1), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8587.</num>
<heading> Election of annuity for self and beneficiary</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> At the time of his retirement, a civilian member retiring under this chapter may elect to receive instead of the amount payable annually by the Secretary of the Navy under section 8585 or 8586 of this title a reduced annuity for his life and an annuity payable after his death to his beneficiary in either—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an amount equal to his reduced annuity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an amount equal to 50 percent of his reduced annuity.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The annuities payable to principal and beneficiary, under either election, shall be in amounts that have, on the date of the retirement of the civilian member, a combined actuarial value equal to the actuarial value of the annuity payable by the Secretary under section 8585 or 8586 of this title, as determined under actuarial tables prepared by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If the civilian member elects to take a reduced annuity under this section, he shall, at the time of his retirement, designate the beneficiary in writing and file the designation with the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The annuity payable under this section to the beneficiary of a deceased civilian member shall be terminated upon the death of the beneficiary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 440</ref>, § 7087; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(45)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1298</ref>; renumbered § 8587 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 807(c)(1), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8588.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 441</ref>, § 7088; renumbered § 8588, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>