<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 757—</num>
<heading>SCHOOLS AND CAMPS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7481.</num>
<heading> Establishment: purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army may maintain schools and camps for the military instruction and training of persons selected, upon their application, from warrant officers and enlisted members of the Army and civilians, to qualify them for appointment as reserve officers, or enlistment as reserve noncommissioned officers, for service in the Army Reserve.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 249</ref>, § 4411; renumbered § 7481, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7482.</num>
<heading> Operation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In maintaining schools and camps established under <ref>section 7481 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the Army may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prescribe the periods during which they will be operated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prescribe regulations for their administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prescribe the courses to be taught;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> detail members of the Regular Army to designated duties relating to the camps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> use necessary supplies and transportation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> furnish uniforms, subsistence, and medical attendance and supplies to persons attending the camps; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> authorize necessary expenditures from proper Army funds for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> water;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> fuel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> light;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> temporary structures, except barracks and officers’ quarters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> screening;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> damages resulting from field exercises;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> expenses incident to theoretical winter instruction of trainees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> other expenses incident to maintaining the camps.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 249</ref>, § 4412; renumbered § 7482 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 808(c)(2), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7483.</num>
<heading> Transportation and subsistence during travel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> There may be furnished to a person attending a school or camp established under <ref>section 7481 of this title</ref>, for travel to and from that school or camp—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> transportation and subsistence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> transportation in kind and a subsistence allowance of one cent a mile; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a travel allowance of five cents a mile.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The travel allowance for the return trip may be paid in advance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, distance is computed by the shortest usually traveled route, within such territorial limits as the Secretary of the Army may prescribe, from the authorized starting point to the school or camp and return.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 250</ref>, § 4413; renumbered § 7483 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 808(c)(2), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7484.</num>
<heading> Quartermaster and ordnance property: sales</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army may sell to a person attending a school or camp established under <ref>section 7481 of this title</ref> quartermaster and ordnance property necessary for his proper equipment. Sales under this section shall be for cash.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 250</ref>, § 4414; renumbered § 7484 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 808(c)(2), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7486.</num>
<heading> Academy of Health Sciences: admission of civilians in physician assistant training program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Army may, pursuant to an agreement entered into with an accredited institution of higher education—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> permit students of the institution to attend the didactic portion of the physician assistant training program conducted by the Army Medical Department at the Academy of Health Sciences at Fort Sam Houston, Texas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> accept from the institution academic services to support the physician assistant training program at the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreement for Exchange of Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agreement entered into with an institution of higher education under this section shall require the institution, in exchange for services provided under paragraph (1) of subsection (a), to provide academic services described in paragraph (2) of such subsection that the Secretary and authorized representatives of the institution consider appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection of Students</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In consultation with the authorized representatives of the institution of higher education concerned, the Secretary shall prescribe the qualifications and methods of selection for students of the institution to receive instruction at the Academy under this section. The qualifications shall be comparable to those generally required for admission to the physician assistant training program at the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rules of Attendance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as the Secretary determines necessary, a student who receives instruction at the Academy under this section shall be subject to the same regulations governing attendance, discipline, discharge, and dismissal as apply to other persons attending the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> That the Army Medical Department, in carrying out an agreement under this section, does not incur costs in excess of the costs that the department would incur to obtain, by means other than the agreement, academic services that are comparable to those provided by the institution pursuant to the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> That attendance of civilian students at the Academy under this section does not cause a decrease in the number of members of the armed forces enrolled in the physician assistant training program at the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VII, § 741(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1816</ref>, § 4416; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(19)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2645</ref>; renumbered § 7486, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7487.</num>
<heading> United States Army War College: acceptance of grants for faculty research for scientific, literary, and educational purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Research Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Army may authorize the Commandant of the United States Army War College to accept qualifying research grants. Any such grant may only be accepted if the work under the grant is to be carried out by a professor or instructor of the College for a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifying Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A qualifying research grant under this section is a grant that is awarded on a competitive basis by an entity referred to in subsection (c) for a research project with a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Entities From Which Grants May Be Accepted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A grant may be accepted under this section only from a corporation, fund, foundation, educational institution, or similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific, literary, or educational purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration of Grant Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall establish an account for administering funds received as research grants under this section. The Commandant shall use the funds in the account in accordance with applicable provisions of the regulations and the terms and condition of the grants received.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Related Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the Army War College may be used to pay expenses incurred by the College in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, the award of qualifying research grants.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 522(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3240</ref>, § 4417; renumbered § 7487, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>