<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 141—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS RELATING TO PROPERTY</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 2381.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3247]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2382.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVI, § 1671(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2084</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2383.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4508]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2384.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4753]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2384a.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3242]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2385.</num>
<heading> Arms and ammunition: immunity from taxation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax on the sale or transfer of firearms, pistols, revolvers, shells, or cartridges may be imposed on such articles when bought with funds appropriated for a military department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 137</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2386.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3793]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2387.</num>
<heading> Contract working dogs: requirement to transfer animals to 341st Training Squadron after service life</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each contract entered into by the Secretary of Defense for the provision of a contract working dog shall require, and shall contain a contract term, that the dog be transferred to the 341st Training Squadron and assigned for veterinary screening and care in accordance with <ref>section 2583 of this title</ref> after the service life of the dog has terminated as described in subsection (b) for reclassification as a military animal and placement for adoption in accordance with such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service Life</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The service life of a contract working dog has terminated and the dog is available for transfer to the 341st Training Squadron pursuant to a contract under subsection (a) only if the contracting officer concerned has determined that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the final contractual obligation of the dog preceding such transfer is with the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the dog cannot be used by another department or agency of the Federal Government due to age, injury, or performance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract Working Dog</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “contract working dog” means a dog—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that performs a service for the Department of Defense pursuant to a contract; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that is trained and kenneled by an entity that provides such a dog pursuant to such a contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title III, § 342(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2082</ref>, § 2410r; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title III, § 372(f)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1331</ref>; renumbered § 2387, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1882(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2388.</num>
<heading> Security clearances for facilities of certain companies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the senior management official of a covered company does not have a security clearance, the Secretary of Defense may grant a security clearance to a facility of such company only if the following criteria are met:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The company has appointed a senior officer, director, or employee of the company who has a security clearance at the level of the security clearance of the facility to act as the senior management official of the company with respect to such facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any senior management official, senior officer, or director of the company who does not have such a security clearance will not have access to any classified information, including with respect to such facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The company has certified to the Secretary that the senior officer, director, or employee appointed under paragraph (1) has the authority to act on behalf of the company with respect to such facility independent of any senior management official, senior officer, or director described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The facility meets all of the requirements to be granted a security clearance other than any requirement relating to the senior management official of the company having an appropriate security clearance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Company</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “covered company” means a company that has entered into a contract or agreement with the Department of Defense, assists the Department, or requires a facility to process classified information.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1732</ref>, § 2410s; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(23)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1984</ref>; renumbered § 2388, <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1882(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2389.</num>
<heading> Ensuring safety regarding insensitive munitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that insensitive munitions under development or procurement are safe throughout development and fielding when subject to unplanned stimuli.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VIII, § 834(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1191</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2390.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on the sale of certain defense articles from the stocks of the Department of Defense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), the sale outside the Department of Defense of any defense article designated or otherwise classified as Prepositioned Material Configured to Unit Sets, as decrement stock, or as Prepositioned War Reserve Stocks for United States Forces is prohibited.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “decrement stock” means such stock as is needed to bring the armed forces from a peacetime level of readiness to a combat level of readiness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The President may authorize the sale outside the Department of Defense of a defense article described in subsection (a) if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> he determines that there is an international crisis affecting the national security of the United States and the sale of such article is in the best interests of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> he reports to the Congress not later than 60 days after the transfer of such article a plan for the prompt replenishment of the stocks of such article and the planned budget request to begin implementation of that plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall preclude the sale of stocks which have been designated for replacement, substitution, or elimination or which have been designated for sale to provide funds to procure higher priority stocks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall preclude the transfer or sale of equipment to other members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–485, title VIII, § 815(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-20">Oct. 20, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1625</ref>, § 975; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; renumbered § 2390, <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1604</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2391.</num>
<heading> Military base reuse studies and community planning assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reuse Studies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned publicly announces that a military installation is a candidate for closure or that a final decision has been made to close a military installation and the Secretary of Defense determines, because of the location, facilities, or other particular characteristics of the installation, that the installation may be suitable for some specific Federal, State, or local use potentially beneficial to the Nation, the Secretary of Defense may conduct such studies, including the preparation of an environmental impact statement in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.), in connection with such installation and such potential use as may be necessary to provide information sufficient to make sound conclusions and recommendations regarding the possible use of the installation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adjustment and Diversification Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement funds available under Federal programs administered by agencies other than the Department of Defense in order to assist State and local governments in planning community adjustments and economic diversification required (A) by the proposed or actual establishment, realignment, or closure of a military installation, (B) by the cancellation or termination of a Department of Defense contract or the failure to proceed with an approved major weapon system program, (C) by a publicly announced planned major reduction in Department of Defense spending that would directly and adversely affect a community, (D) by the encroachment of a civilian community on a military installation, (E) by threats to military installation resilience, or (F) by the closure or the significantly reduced operations of a defense facility as the result of the merger, acquisition, or consolidation of the defense contractor operating the defense facility, if the Secretary determines that an action described in clause (A), (B), (C), or (F) is likely to have a direct and significantly adverse consequence on the affected community or, in the case of an action described in clause (D) or (E), if the Secretary determines that either the encroachment of the civilian community or threats to military installation resilience is likely to impair the continued operational utility of the military installation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of the establishment or expansion of a military installation, assistance may be made under paragraph (1) only if (A) community impact assistance or special impact assistance is not otherwise available, and (B) the establishment or expansion involves the assignment to the installation of (i) more than 2,000 military, civilian, and contractor Department of Defense personnel, or (ii) more military, civilian, and contractor Department of Defense personnel than the number equal to 10 percent of the number of persons employed in counties or independent municipalities within fifteen miles of the installation, whichever is lesser.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of a publicly announced planned reduction in Department of Defense spending, the closure or realignment of a military installation, the cancellation or termination of a Department of Defense contract, or the failure to proceed with a previously approved major defense acquisition program, assistance may be made under paragraph (1) only if the reduction, closure or realignment, cancellation or termination, or failure will have a direct and significant adverse impact on a community or its residents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a State or local government eligible for assistance under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense may also make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement other Federal funds in order to assist the State or local government to carry out a community adjustment and economic diversification program (including State industrial extension or modernization efforts to facilitate the economic diversification of defense contractors and subcontractors) in addition to planning such a program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall establish criteria for the selection of community adjustment and economic diversification programs to receive assistance under subparagraph (A). Such criteria shall include a requirement that the State or local government agree—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to provide not less than 10 percent of the funding for the program from non-Federal sources;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to provide business planning and market exploration services under the program to defense contractors and subcontractors that seek modernization or diversification assistance; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to provide training, counseling, and placement services for members of the armed forces and dislocated defense workers.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall carry out this paragraph in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may also make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement other Federal funds in order to assist a State or local government in planning community adjustments and economic diversification even though the State or local government is not currently eligible for assistance under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that a substantial portion of the economic activity or population of the geographic area to be subject to the advance planning is dependent on defense expenditures.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may also make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement other Federal funds in order to assist a State or local government in enhancing its capacities—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to assist communities, businesses, and workers adversely affected by an action described in paragraph (1);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to support local adjustment and diversification initiatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to stimulate cooperation between statewide and local adjustment and diversification efforts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> to support public infrastructure projects and services that enhance the capabilities and resilience of the defense industrial base and the defense industrial base workers, if the Secretary determines such support will improve operations of the Department of Defense.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may also make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement other Federal funds in order to assist a State or local government in enhancing the capabilities of the government to support efforts of the Department of Defense to privatize, contract for, or diversify the performance of military family support services in cases in which the capability of the Department to provide such services is adversely affected by an action described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may also make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement other Federal funds, in order to assist a State or local government in planning, enhancing infrastructure, and implementing measures and projects (to include resilience measures and projects involving the protection, restoration, and maintenance of natural features) that, as determined by the Secretary of Defense, will contribute to maintaining or improving military installation resilience or will prevent or mitigate encroachment that could affect operations of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Funds provided to State and local governments and regional organizations under this section may be used as part or all of any required non-Federal contribution to a Federal grant-in-aid program for the purposes stated in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent practicable, the Secretary of Defense shall inform a State or local government applying for assistance under this subsection of the approval or rejection by the Secretary of the application for such assistance as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Before the end of the 7-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary receives the application, in the case of an application for a planning grant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Before the end of the 30-day period beginning on such date, in the case of an application for assistance to carry out a community adjustments and economic diversifications program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In attempting to complete consideration of applications within the time period specified in paragraph (7), the Secretary of Defense shall give priority to those applications requesting assistance for a community described in subsection (f)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If an application under paragraph (7) is rejected by the Secretary, the Secretary shall promptly inform the State or local government of the reasons for the rejection of the application.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Research and Technical Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may make grants to, or conclude cooperative agreements or enter into contracts with, another Federal agency, a State or local government, or any private entity to conduct research and provide technical assistance in support of activities under this section or Executive Order 12788 (57 Fed. Reg. 2213), as amended by section 33 of Executive Order 13286 (68 Fed. Reg. 10625) and Executive Order 13378 (70 Fed. Reg. 28413).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense Community Infrastructure Program</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement funds available under Federal programs administered by agencies other than the Department of Defense to assist State governments, local governments, and not-for-profit, member-owned utility services to address deficiencies in community infrastructure supportive of a military installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall establish criteria for the selection of community infrastructure projects to receive assistance under this subsection, including selection of community infrastructure projects in the following order of priority:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Projects that will enhance military value at a military installation, taking into consideration the military value criteria originally developed by the Secretary in compliance with the amendment made by section 3002 of the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2002 (division B of <ref>Public Law 107–107</ref>; <ref>115 Stat. 1344</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Projects that will contribute to the training of cadets enrolled in an independent Reserve Officer Training Corps program at a covered educational institution.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Projects that will enhance military installation resilience, as defined in <ref>section 101 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Projects that will enhance military family quality of life at a military installation, taking into consideration subsection (e)(4)(C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The criteria established for the selection of community infrastructure projects to receive assistance under this subsection shall include a requirement that, except as provided in subparagraph (B), the recipient of such assistance agrees to contribute not less than 30 percent of the funding for the community infrastructure project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If a proposed community infrastructure project will be carried out in a rural area or the Secretary of Defense determines that a proposed community infrastructure project is advantageous for reasons related to national security, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall not penalize a State or local government for offering to make a contribution of 30 percent or less of the funding for the community infrastructure project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may reduce the requirement for a State or local government contribution to 30 percent or less or waive the cost-sharing requirement entirely.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In selecting community infrastructure projects to receive assistance under this subsection, the Secretary shall consider infrastructure improvements identified in the report on strategic seaports required by section 3515 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<ref>Public Law 116–92</ref>; <ref>133 Stat. 1985</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for assistance under paragraph (1) may remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The terms “military installation” and “realignment” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 2687 of this title</ref>. For purposes of paragraphs (1)(D) and (E) and (5)(D) of subsection (b) and subsection (d), the term “military installation” includes a military facility owned and operated by any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands, even though the facility is not under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, if the Secretary of Defense determines that the military facility is subject to significant use for training by the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “defense facility” means any private facility producing goods or services pursuant to a defense contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The terms “community adjustment” and “economic diversification” include the development of feasibility studies and business plans for market diversification within a community adversely affected by an action described in clause (A), (B), (C), or (E) of subsection (b)(1) by adversely affected businesses and labor organizations located in the community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “community infrastructure” means a project or facility described in subparagraph (B) that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is located off of a military installation or on property under the jurisdiction of a Secretary of a military department that is subject to a real estate agreement (including a lease or easement); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> is—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> owned by a State or local government; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a not-for-profit, member-owned utility service.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A project or facility described in this subparagraph is any of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Any transportation project.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A school, hospital, police, fire, emergency response, or other community support facility.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A water, waste-water, telecommunications, electric, gas, or other utility infrastructure project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> For the purposes of determining whether proposed community infrastructure will enhance quality of life, the Secretary of Defense shall consider the impact of the community infrastructure on alleviating installation commuter workforce issues and the benefit of schools or other local infrastructure located off of a military installation that will support members of the armed forces and their dependents residing in the community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “rural area” means a city, town, or unincorporated area that has a population of not more than 100,000 inhabitants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered educational institution” means a college or university that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a part B institution, as defined in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1061</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an 1890 Institution, as defined in section 2 of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 7601</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not affiliated with a consortium; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> located at least 40 miles from a major military installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance Subject to Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary of Defense to make grants under this section in any fiscal year is subject to the availability of appropriations for that purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 912(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1122</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–115, title VIII, § 808</ref>, <date date="1983-10-11">Oct. 11, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 789</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2805</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. D, title XLI, § 4102(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1851</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(j)(3)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(28)</ref>, div. D, title XLIII, § 4301(a)–(c), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2500</ref>, 2696, 2697; <ref>Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 202(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 101</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. B, title XXIX, § 2913</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1925</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XI</ref>, §§ 1122(a), 1123(a), (b), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2870</ref>, 2871; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2814</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2790</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2822</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1997</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2645</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2832</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2861, 2862, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2823(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4730</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVII, § 2712(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2145</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2805(f), 2861, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2263</ref>, 2282; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2862</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1899</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2882</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2862–2864, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3010</ref>, 3011; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2801</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 743</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2802, 2842, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2247</ref>, 2263.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2392.</num>
<heading> Process for strategic basing actions for the Department of the Air Force</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programmatic Basing Decisions Prohibited</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force (or a designee) shall not make any basing decision during the resource allocation plan or program objective memorandum process.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quarterly Briefings</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and quarterly thereafter, the Secretary of the Air Force (or a designee) shall brief the congressional defense committees on the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Strategic basing actions approved by the strategic basing panel for review by the strategic basing executive steering group during the quarter covered by the briefing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For each strategic basing action not covered by a previous briefing, a description of the criteria for selection of candidate location for each such strategic basing action and how each criterion will be applied to the candidate locations to determine preferred location.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Updates regarding candidate locations, preferred locations, and the final location selected for each strategic basing action covered by the briefing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any strategic basing actions with projected decision dates that will occur before the next scheduled briefing under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Briefings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon request by either the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives or of the Senate, the Secretary of the Air Force (or a designee) shall provide to such Committee a briefing on the information described in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Post-briefing Changes</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Air Force (or a designee) shall notify the congressional defense committees, not later than seven days after the effective date of a change, if such change is a change—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to the selection criteria or the application of selection criteria, that would result in a different decision than briefed under subsection (b) regarding the enterprise definition, identified candidate locations, or identified preferred location; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the governance process used to oversee a strategic basing action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Overseas Strategic Basing Actions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to a strategic basing action relating to a military installation located outside of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or Guam, a notification required under this section may be provided in a classified form.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the terms “enterprise definition”, “program objective memorandum process”, “resource allocation plan”, “strategic basing action”, “strategic basing executive steering group”, and “strategic basing panel” have the meanings given, respectively, under the Department of the Air Force Instruction 10–503 (issued <date date="2023-06-12">June 12, 2023</date>, as in effect on <date date="2024-11-01">November 1, 2024</date>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2803(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2393.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4654]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2394.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2922a]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2394a.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2922b]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2395.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3132]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2396.</num>
<heading> Advances for payments for compliance with foreign laws, rent in foreign countries, tuition, public utility services, and pay and supplies of armed forces of friendly foreign countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An advance under an appropriation to the Department of Defense may be made to pay for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> compliance with laws and ministerial regulations of a foreign country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> rent in a foreign country for periods of time determined by local custom;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> tuition; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> public service utilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, or by the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service of the Navy, an officer of an armed force of the United States accountable for public money may advance amounts to a disbursing official of a friendly foreign country or members of an armed force of a friendly foreign country for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pay and allowances to members of the armed force of that country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> necessary supplies and services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An advance may be made under this subsection only if the President has made an agreement with the foreign country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> requiring reimbursement to the United States for amounts advanced;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> requiring the appropriate authority of the country to advance amounts reciprocally to members of the armed forces of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> containing any other provision the President considers necessary to carry out this subsection and to safeguard the interests of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(b)(4)(B)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1053</ref>, § 2395; renumbered § 2396 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(28)(B)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1014(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1875</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 2397 to 2397c.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLIII, § 4304(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 664</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2398.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2922c]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2398a.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2922d]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2399.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4171]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2400.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4231]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2401.</num>
<heading> Transferred]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2401a.</num>
<heading> Transferred]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2402.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4655]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2403.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VIII, § 847(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1845</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2404.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2922e]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2405.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VIII, § 810(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1839</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2406.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title II, § 2201(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3318</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2407.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2350b]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2408.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4656]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2409.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4701]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2409a.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4702]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3862]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410a.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3133]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410b.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3845]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410c.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2922f]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410d.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3903]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410e.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title II, § 2301(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3321</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410f.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4658]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410g.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4603]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410h.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 1747]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410i.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4659]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410j.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4703]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410k.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4704]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410l.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4509]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410m.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3863]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410n.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3905]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410o.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3551]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410p.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4292]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410q.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2922i]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410r.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2387]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2410s.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2388]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>