<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 947—</num>
<heading>CIVILIAN EMPLOYEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9371.</num>
<heading> Air University and Space Delta 13: civilian faculty members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Secretary</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may employ as many civilians as professors, instructors, and lecturers at a school of the Air University or of the Space Delta 13 as the Secretary considers necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation of Faculty Members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The compensation of persons employed under this section shall be as prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application to Certain Faculty Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), this section shall apply with respect to persons who are selected by the Secretary for employment as professors, instructors, and lecturers at a school of the Air University or of the Space Delta 13 after <date date="1990-02-27">February 27, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply with respect to professors, instructors, and lecturers employed at a school of the Air University or of the Space Delta 13 if the duration of the principal course of instruction offered at that school is less than 10 months.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XI, § 1124(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1559</ref>, § 9021; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1070(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2856</ref>; renumbered § 9371, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(16)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XI, § 1117(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9375.</num>
<heading> Production of supplies and munitions: hours and pay of laborers and mechanics</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During a national emergency declared by the President, the regular working hours of laborers and mechanics of the Department of the Air Force producing military supplies or munitions are 8 hours a day or 40 hours a week. However, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force these hours may be exceeded. Each laborer or mechanic who works more than 40 hours in a workweek shall be paid at a rate not less than one and one-half times the regular hourly rate for each hour in excess of 40.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 558</ref>, § 9025; renumbered § 9375, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(16)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9377.</num>
<heading> Civilian special agents of the Office of Special Investigations: authority to execute warrants and make arrests</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may authorize any Department of the Air Force civilian employee described in subsection (b) to have the same authority to execute and serve warrants and other processes issued under the authority of the United States and to make arrests without a warrant as may be authorized under <ref>section 1585a of this title</ref> for special agents of the Defense Criminal Investigative Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agents To Have Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) applies to any employee of the Department of the Air Force who is a special agent of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations (or a successor to that office) whose duties include conducting, supervising, or coordinating investigations of criminal activity in programs and operations of the Department of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines for Exercise of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided under subsection (a) shall be exercised in accordance with guidelines prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force and approved by the Secretary of Defense and the Attorney General and any other applicable guidelines prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force, the Secretary of Defense, or the Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 554(c)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–127, § 9027; renumbered § 9377, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(b)(16)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>