<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 711—</num>
<heading>STRENGTH</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7101.</num>
<heading> Officers on active duty: minimum strength based on requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army shall ensure that the strength at the end of each fiscal year of officers on active duty is sufficient to enable the Army to meet at least that percentage of the programmed manpower structure for officers for the active component of the Army that is provided for in the most recent Defense Planning Guidance issued by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The number of officers on active duty shall be counted for purposes of this section in the same manner as applies under <ref>section 115(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “programmed manpower structure” means the aggregation of billets describing the full manpower requirements for units and organizations in the programmed force structure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “programmed force structure” means the set of units and organizations that exist in the current year and that is planned to exist in each future year under the then-current Future-Years Defense Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 505(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 295</ref>, § 3201; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(37)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1954</ref>; renumbered § 7101, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7102.</num>
<heading> Congressional notification of significant Army force structure changes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (c), the Secretary of the Army shall submit to the congressional defense committees written notification of any decision to make a significant change to Army force structure prior to implementing or announcing such change.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A notification required under subsection (a) shall include each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The justification for the planned change.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of the details of the planned change and timing for implementation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A description of the operational implications of the planned change.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The estimated costs of such change.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The notification requirement under subsection (a) shall not apply if the Secretary of Defense certifies to the congressional defense committees in advance that the planned Army force structure change must be implemented immediately for reasons of military urgency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Significant Change to Army Force Structure</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “significant change to Army force structure” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a change in the number, type, or component of brigade-level organizations or higher-echelon headquarters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a change in the number or component of theater-level capabilities, such as a multi-domain task force, Terminal High Altitude Area Defense, long range fires unit, or headquarters; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a permanent or temporary activation or inactivation of an experimental unit or brigade-size or higher task force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1044(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1904</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7110.</num>
<heading> Regular Army: strength in grade; general officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to <ref>section 526 of this title</ref>, the authorized strength of the Regular Army in general officers on the active-duty list is 75/10,000 of the authorized strength of the Regular Army in commissioned officers on the active-duty list.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The authorized strength of each of the following branches—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> each corps of the Army Medical Department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Chaplains;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">in general officers on the active-duty list of the Regular Army is 5/1,000 of the authorized strength of the branch concerned in commissioned officers on the active-duty list of the Regular Army. Not more than one-half of the authorized strength in general officers in such a branch may be in a regular grade above brigadier general.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> When the application of the percentages and ratios specified in this section results in a fraction, a fraction of one-half or more is counted as one, and a fraction of less than one-half is disregarded.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 174</ref>, § 3210; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(66)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1463</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–603, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-24">Sept. 24, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 846</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–329</ref>, <date date="1968-06-04">June 4, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 502(5)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2909</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 128</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(20)(A)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1473</ref>; renumbered § 7110, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>