<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 801—</num>
<heading>DEFINITIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8001.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this subtitle:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Navy” means the United States Navy. It includes the Regular Navy, the Fleet Reserve, and the Navy Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Marine Corps” means the United States Marine Corps. It includes the Regular Marine Corps, the Fleet Marine Corps Reserve, and the Marine Corps Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “member of the naval service” means a person appointed or enlisted in, or inducted or conscripted into, the Navy or the Marine Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “enlisted member” means a member of the naval service serving in an enlisted grade or rating. It excludes, unless otherwise specified, a member who holds a permanent enlisted grade and a temporary appointment in a commissioned or warrant officer grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “officer” means a member of the naval service serving in a commissioned or warrant officer grade. It includes, unless otherwise specified, a member who holds a permanent enlisted grade and a temporary appointment in a commissioned or warrant officer grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “commissioned officer” means a member of the naval service serving in a grade above warrant officer, W–1. It includes, unless otherwise specified, a member who holds a permanent enlisted grade or the permanent grade of warrant officer, W–1, and a temporary appointment in a grade above warrant officer, W–1.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “warrant officer” means a member of the naval service serving in a warrant officer grade. It includes, unless otherwise specified, a member who holds a permanent enlisted grade and a temporary appointment in a warrant officer grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “officer restricted in the performance of duty” means an officer of the Navy designated for engineering duty, aeronautical engineering duty, special duty, or limited duty, or an officer of the Marine Corps designated for limited duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this subtitle, a member of the naval service who holds a temporary appointment in a grade higher than his permanent grade is considered, unless otherwise specified, to be serving in the higher grade.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 276</ref>, § 5001; <ref>Pub. L. 87–123, § 5(1)</ref>, <date date="1961-08-03">Aug. 3, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 264</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title III, § 371</ref>, title V, § 513(2), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2903</ref>, 2931; <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3233</ref>; renumbered § 8001, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>