<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1211—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL GUARD MEMBERS IN FEDERAL SERVICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12401.</num>
<heading> Army and Air National Guard of the United States: status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Army National Guard of the United States and the Air National Guard of the United States are not in active Federal service except when ordered thereto under law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12402.</num>
<heading> Army and Air National Guard of the United States: commissioned officers; duty in National Guard Bureau</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President may, with their consent, order commissioned officers of the Army National Guard of the United States and the Air National Guard of the United States to active duty in the National Guard Bureau.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The number of officers of the Army National Guard of the United States in grades below brigadier general who are ordered to active duty in the National Guard Bureau may not be more than 40 percent of the number of officers of the Army authorized for duty in that Bureau and, to the extent practicable, shall not exceed 40 percent of the number of officers of the Army serving in that Bureau in any grade below brigadier general.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The number of officers of the Air National Guard of the United States in grades below brigadier general who are ordered to active duty in the National Guard Bureau may not be more than 40 percent of the number of officers of the Air Force authorized for duty in that Bureau and, to the extent practicable, shall not exceed 40 percent of the number of officers of the Air Force serving in that Bureau in any grade below brigadier general.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2993</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(18)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12403.</num>
<heading> Army and Air National Guard of the United States: members; status in which ordered into Federal service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Army National Guard of the United States ordered to active duty shall be ordered to duty as Reserves of the Army. Members of the Air National Guard of the United States ordered to active duty shall be ordered to duty as Reserves of the Air Force.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2993</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(18)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12404.</num>
<heading> Army and Air National Guard of the United States: mobilization; maintenance of organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During an initial mobilization, the organization of a unit of the Army National Guard of the United States or of the Air National Guard of the United States ordered into active Federal service shall, so far as practicable, be maintained as it existed on the date of the order to duty.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2993</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(18)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12405.</num>
<heading> National Guard in Federal service: status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the National Guard called into Federal service are, from the time when they are required to respond to the call, subject to the laws and regulations governing the Army or the Air Force, as the case may be, except those applicable only to members of the Regular Army or Regular Air Force, as the case may be.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12406.</num>
<heading> National Guard in Federal service: call</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States, or any of the Commonwealths or possessions, is invaded or is in danger of invasion by a foreign nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> there is a rebellion or danger of a rebellion against the authority of the Government of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the President is unable with the regular forces to execute the laws of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the President may call into Federal service members and units of the National Guard of any State in such numbers as he considers necessary to repel the invasion, suppress the rebellion, or execute those laws. Orders for these purposes shall be issued through the governors of the States or, in the case of the District of Columbia, through the commanding general of the National Guard of the District of Columbia.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2994</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3440</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12407.</num>
<heading> National Guard in Federal service: period of service; apportionment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whenever the President calls the National Guard of a State into Federal service, he may specify in the call the period of the service. Members and units called shall serve inside or outside the territory of the United States during the term specified, unless sooner relieved by the President. However, no member of the National Guard may be kept in Federal service beyond the term of his commission or enlistment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When the National Guard of a State is called into Federal service with the National Guard of another State, the President may apportion the total number called from the Army National Guard or from the Air National Guard, as the case may be, on the basis of the populations of the States affected by the call.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2994</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(19)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12408.</num>
<heading> National Guard in Federal service: physical examination</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the President, each member of the National Guard called into Federal service under section 12301(a), 12302, or 12304 of this title shall be examined as to physical fitness, without further commission or enlistment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Immediately before such a member is mustered out of Federal service, he shall be examined as to physical fitness. The record of this examination shall be retained by the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2994</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 523</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2517</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>