<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 244—</num>
<heading>UNDEFINITIZED CONTRACTUAL ACTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3371.</num>
<heading> Undefinitized contractual actions: required description of anticipated effect on military department requirements if use of undefinitized contractual action results in delay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of an agency may not enter into an undefinitized contractual action unless the request to the head of the agency for authorization of the contractual action includes a description of the anticipated effect on requirements of the military department concerned if a delay is incurred for purposes of determining contractual terms, specifications, and price before performance is begun under the contractual action.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1819(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3372.</num>
<heading> Undefinitized contractual actions: requirements and limitations relating to definitization of contractual terms, specifications, and price</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Contractual Action to Provide Time for Definitization of Contractual Terms, Specifications, and Price; Limitations on Obligation of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms for time for definitization to be included in contractual action</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A contracting officer of the Department of Defense may not enter into an undefinitized contractual action unless the contractual action provides for agreement upon contractual terms, specifications, and price by the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date on which the contractor submits a qualifying proposal to definitize the contractual terms, specifications, and price; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the amount of funds obligated under the contractual action is equal to more than 50 percent of the negotiated overall ceiling price for the contractual action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation on obligation of funds before definitization.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">50 percent limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the contracting officer for an undefinitized contractual action may not obligate with respect to such contractual action an amount that is equal to more than 50 percent of the negotiated overall ceiling price until the contractual terms, specifications, and price are definitized for such contractual action.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">75 percent limitation when contractor submits qualifying proposal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a contractor submits a qualifying proposal (as defined in <ref>section 3377(b) of this title</ref>) to definitize an undefinitized contractual action before an amount equal to more than 50 percent of the negotiated overall ceiling price is obligated on such action, the contracting officer for such action may not obligate with respect to such contractual action an amount that is equal to more than 75 percent of the negotiated overall ceiling price until the contractual terms, specifications, and price are definitized for such contractual action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of an agency may waive the provisions of this subsection with respect to a contract of that agency if that head of an agency determines that the waiver is necessary in order to support any of the following operations:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A humanitarian or peacekeeping operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability with respect to purchase of initial spares</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection does not apply to an undefinitized contractual action for the purchase of initial spares.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Unilateral Definitization by Contracting Officer.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With respect to any undefinitized contractual action with a value greater than $50,000,000, if agreement is not reached on contractual terms, specifications, and price within the period or by the date provided in subsection (a)(1), the contracting officer may not unilaterally definitize those terms, specifications, or price over the objection of the contractor until—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the service acquisition executive for the military department that awarded the contract, or the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment if the contract was awarded by a Defense Agency or other component of the Department of Defense, approves the definitization in writing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the contracting officer provides a copy of the written approval to the contractor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a period of 30 calendar days has elapsed after the written approval is provided to the contractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of unilateral definitization of a contract as a final decision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A unilateral definitization by a contracting officer shall be considered a final decision under chapter 71 of title 41, and a contractor may appeal this decision to the Armed Services Board of Contract Appeals or the United States Court of Federal Claims.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Foreign Military Contracts.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading> 180<inline class="small-caps">-day requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a contracting officer of the Department of Defense may not enter into an undefinitized contractual action for a foreign military sale unless the contractual action provides for agreement upon contractual terms, specifications, and price by the end of the 180-day period described in subsection (a)(1)(A).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirement under paragraph (1) may be waived in accordance with subsection (a)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1819(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4189</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3373.</num>
<heading> Undefinitized contractual actions: limitation on inclusion of non-urgent requirements and on modification of scope</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusion of Non-Urgent Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Requirements for spare parts and support equipment that are not needed on an urgent basis may not be included in an undefinitized contractual action for spare parts and support equipment that are needed on an urgent basis unless the head of the agency approves such inclusion as being—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> good business practice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Modification of Scope</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The scope of an undefinitized contractual action under which performance has begun may not be modified unless the head of the agency approves such modification as being—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> good business practice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1819(a)</ref>, (d), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4189</ref>, 4190.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3374.</num>
<heading> Undefinitized contractual actions: allowable profit</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allowed Profit to Reflect Certain Reduced Cost Risks of Contractor</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of an agency shall ensure that the profit allowed on an undefinitized contractual action for which the final price is negotiated after a substantial portion of the performance required is completed reflects—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the possible reduced cost risk of the contractor with respect to costs incurred during performance of the contract before the final price is negotiated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the reduced cost risk of the contractor with respect to costs incurred during performance of the remaining portion of the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Date as of Which Contractor Cost Risk to Be Determined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a contractor submits a qualifying proposal to definitize an undefinitized contractual action and the contracting officer for such action definitizes the contract after the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date on which the contractor submitted the qualifying proposal, the head of the agency concerned shall ensure that the profit allowed on the contract accurately reflects the cost risk of the contractor as such risk existed on the date the contractor submitted the qualifying proposal.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1819(a)</ref>, (e), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4189</ref>, 4190.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3375.</num>
<heading> Undefinitized contractual actions: time limit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No undefinitized contractual action may extend beyond 90 days without a written determination by the Secretary of the military department concerned, the head of the Defense Agency concerned, the commander of the combatant command concerned, or the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment (as applicable) that it is in the best interests of the military department, the Defense Agency, the combatant command, or the Department of Defense, respectively, to continue the action.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1819(a)</ref>, (f), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4189</ref>, 4190.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3377.</num>
<heading> Inapplicability to Coast Guard and National Aeronautics and Space Administration; definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This chapter does not apply to the Coast Guard or the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “undefinitized contractual action” means a new procurement action entered into by the head of an agency for which the contractual terms, specifications, or price are not agreed upon before performance is begun under the action. Such term does not include contractual actions with respect to the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Purchases in an amount not in excess of the amount of the simplified acquisition threshold.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Special access programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Congressionally mandated long-lead procurement contracts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “qualifying proposal” means a proposal that contains sufficient information to enable the Department of Defense to conduct a meaningful audit of the information contained in the proposal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1819(a)</ref>, (g), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4189</ref>, 4191.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>