<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 8—</num>
<heading>DEFENSE AGENCIES AND DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE FIELD ACTIVITIES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>COMMON SUPPLY AND SERVICE ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 191.</num>
<heading> Secretary of Defense: authority to provide for common performance of supply or service activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the Secretary of Defense determines such action would be more effective, economical, or efficient, the Secretary may provide for the performance of a supply or service activity that is common to more than one military department by a single agency of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Common Supply or Service Agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any agency of the Department of Defense established under subsection (a) (or under the second sentence of <ref>section 125(d) of this title</ref> (as in effect before <date date="1986-10-01">October 1, 1986</date>)) for the performance of a supply or service activity referred to in such subsection shall be designated as a Defense Agency or a Department of Defense Field Activity.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title III, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1019</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 192.</num>
<heading> Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities: oversight by the Secretary of Defense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Overall Supervision</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall assign responsibility for the overall supervision of each Defense Agency and Department of Defense Field Activity designated under <ref>section 191(b) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to a civilian officer within the Office of the Secretary of Defense listed in <ref>section 131(b) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An official assigned such a responsibility with respect to a Defense Agency or Department of Defense Field Activity shall advise the Secretary of Defense on the extent to which the program recommendations and budget proposals of such agency or activity conform with the requirements of the military departments and of the unified and specified combatant commands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This subsection does not apply to the Defense Intelligence Agency or the National Security Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program and Budget Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish procedures to ensure that there is full and effective review of the program recommendations and budget proposals of each Defense Agency and Department of Defense Field Activity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Periodic Review</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Not later than <date date="2020-01-01">January 1, 2020</date>, and periodically (but not less frequently than every four years) thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall conduct a review of the efficiency and effectiveness of each Defense Agency and Department of Defense Field Activity. Each review shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be conducted in coordination with other ongoing efforts in connection with business enterprise reform.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> As part of each review under this paragraph, the Secretary shall identify each activity of an Agency or Activity that is substantially similar to, or duplicative of, an activity carried out by another organization or element of the Department of Defense, or is not being performed to an adequate level to meet Department needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> For purposes of conducting reviews under this paragraph, the Secretary shall develop internal guidance that defines requirements for such reviews and provides clear direction for conducting and recording the results of reviews.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Not later than 90 days after the completion of a review under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report that sets forth the results of the review.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The report on a review under this paragraph shall, based on the results of the review, include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> A list of each Defense Agency and Department of Defense Field Activity that the Secretary has determined—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> operates efficiently and effectively; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> does not carry out any function that is substantially similar to, or duplicative of, a function carried out by another organization or element of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to each Agency or Activity not included on the list under clause (i), a plan, aimed at better meeting Department needs, for—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> rationalizing the functions within such Agency or Activity; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> transferring some or all of the functions of such Agency or Activity to another organization or element of the Department.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Recommendations for functions, if any, currently conducted separately by the military departments that should be consolidated into an Agency or Activity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) shall apply to the National Security Agency as determined appropriate by the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence. The Secretary shall establish procedures under which information required for review of the National Security Agency shall be obtained.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Rule for Defense Commissary Agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the results of any periodic review under subsection (c) with regard to the Defense Commissary Agency, the Secretary of Defense may not transfer to the Secretary of a military department the responsibility to manage and fund the provision of services and supplies provided by the Defense Commissary Agency unless the transfer of the management and funding responsibility is specifically authorized by a law enacted after <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may not terminate a Defense Agency or Department of Defense Field Activity until 30 days after the date on which the Secretary submits to the congressional defense committees a report setting forth the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notice of the intent of the Secretary to terminate the Agency or Activity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such recommendations for legislative action as the Secretary considers appropriate in connection with the termination of the Agency or Activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title III, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1020</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title III, § 361(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1984</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title III, § 371</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX</ref>, §§ 904(c), 931(a)(1), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 274</ref>, 285; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title IX, § 901(n)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3469</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(b)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title IX, § 923</ref>, title X, § 1081(f)(1)(A)(i), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1930</ref>, 1986; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3871</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title IX, § 901(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 193.</num>
<heading> Combat support agencies: oversight</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Combat Readiness</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Periodically (and not less often than every two years), the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff shall submit to the Secretary of Defense and the congressional defense committees a report on the combat support agencies. Each such report shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a determination with respect to the responsiveness and readiness of each such agency to support operating forces in the event of a war or threat to national security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any recommendations that the Chairman considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In preparing each such report, the Chairman shall review the plans of each such agency with respect to its support of operating forces in the event of a war or threat to national security. After consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments and the commanders of the unified and specified combatant commands, as appropriate, the Chairman may, with the approval of the Secretary of Defense, take steps to provide for any revision of those plans that the Chairman considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation in Joint Training Exercises</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Chairman shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide for the participation of the combat support agencies in joint training exercises to the extent necessary to ensure that those agencies are capable of performing their support missions with respect to a war or threat to national security; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assess the performance in joint training exercises of each such agency and, in accordance with guidelines established by the Secretary of Defense, take steps to provide for any change that the Chairman considers appropriate to improve that performance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Readiness Reporting System</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chairman shall develop, in consultation with the director of each combat support agency, a uniform system for reporting to the Secretary of Defense, the commanders of the unified and specified combatant commands, and the Secretaries of the military departments concerning the readiness of each such agency to perform with respect to a war or threat to national security.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of National Security Agency and National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall apply to the National Security Agency and the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, but only with respect to combat support functions that the agencies perform for the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary, after consulting with the Director of National Intelligence, shall establish policies and procedures with respect to the application of subsections (a), (b), and (c) to the National Security Agency and the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Combat Support Capabilities of DIA, NSA, and NGA</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, shall develop and implement, as they may determine to be necessary, policies and programs to correct such deficiencies as the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and other officials of the Department of Defense may identify in the capabilities of the Defense Intelligence Agency, the National Security Agency, and the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency to accomplish assigned missions in support of military combat operations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Combat Support Agency</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “combat support agency” means any of the following Defense Agencies:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Defense Information Systems Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Defense Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Defense Logistics Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Any other Defense Agency designated as a combat support agency by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title III, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1020</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2683</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title IX, § 907</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2354</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 932(a)(1), (2), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(c)(10)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1082</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 871</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 194.</num>
<heading> Limitations on personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cap on Headquarters Management Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total number of members of the armed forces and civilian employees assigned or detailed to permanent duty in the management headquarters activities or management headquarters support activities in the Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities may not exceed the number that is the number of such members and employees assigned or detailed to such duty on <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cap on Other Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total number of members of the armed forces and civilian employees assigned or detailed to permanent duty in the Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities, other than members and employees assigned to management headquarters activities or management headquarters support activities, may not exceed the number that is the number of such members and employees assigned or detailed to such duty on <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition Against Certain Actions to Exceed Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The limitations in subsections (a) and (b) may not be exceeded by re­categorizing or redefining duties, functions, offices, or organizations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of NSA</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The National Security Agency shall be excluded in computing and maintaining the limitations required by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The limitations in this section do not apply—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in time of war; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> during a national emergency declared by the President or Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the terms “management headquarters activities” and “management headquarters support activities” have the meanings given those terms in Department of Defense Instruction 5100.73, titled “Major DoD Headquarters Activities”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title III, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1021</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XIII, § 1314(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1605</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title IX, § 906</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 818</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 195.</num>
<heading> Defense Automated Printing Service: applicability of Federal printing requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Defense Automated Printing Service shall comply fully with the requirements of <ref>section 501 of title 44</ref> relating to the production and procurement of printing, binding, and blank-book work.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 383(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1711</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 196.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4173]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 197.</num>
<heading> Defense Logistics Agency: fees charged for logistics information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may charge fees for providing information in the Federal Logistics Information System through Defense Logistics Information Services to a department or agency of the executive branch outside the Department of Defense, or to a State, a political subdivision of a State, or any person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The fee or fees prescribed under subsection (a) shall be such amount or amounts as the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate for recovering the costs of providing information as described in such subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention of Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Fees collected under this section shall be credited to the appropriation available for Defense Logistics Information Services for the fiscal year in which collected, shall be merged with other sums in such appropriation, and shall be available for the same purposes and period as the appropriation with which merged.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense Logistics Information Services Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Defense Logistics Information Services” means the organization within the Defense Logistics Agency that is known as Defense Logistics Information Services.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1010(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2038</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 198.</num>
<heading> Office of Local Defense Community Cooperation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is in the Department of Defense an Office of Local Defense Community Cooperation (in this section referred to as the “Office”). The Secretary shall designate the Office as a Department of Defense Field Activity pursuant to section 191, effective as of the date of the enactment of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<ref>Public Law 116–283</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Office shall be headed by the Director of the Office of Local Defense Community Cooperation, who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Defense from among civilian employees of the Federal Government or private individuals who have the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Experience in the interagency in the Executive Branch.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Experience in the administration and management of Federal grants programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Office shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> serve as the office in the Department of Defense with primary responsibility for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing assistance to States, counties, municipalities, regions, and other communities to foster cooperation with military installations to enhance the military mission, achieve facility and infrastructure savings and reduced operating costs, address encroachment and compatible land use issues, support military families, and increase military, civilian, and industrial readiness and resiliency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing adjustment and diversification assistance to State and local governments under <ref>section 2391(b) of this title</ref> to achieve the objectives described in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate the provision of such assistance with other organizations and elements of the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide support to the Economic Adjustment Committee established under Executive Order No. 12788 (57 Fed. Reg. 2213; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2391</ref> note) or any successor to such Committee; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> carry out such other activities as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than June 1 each year, the Director of the Office of Local Defense Community Cooperation shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the activities of the Office during the preceding year, including the assistance provided pursuant to subsection (c)(1) during such year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 905(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3798</ref>, § 146; renumbered § 198 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1868</ref>, 1869.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS DEFENSE AGENCY MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 201.</num>
<heading> Certain intelligence officials: consultation and concurrence regarding appointments; evaluation of performance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation Regarding Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before submitting a recommendation to the President regarding the appointment of an individual to the position of Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency, the Secretary of Defense shall consult with the Director of National Intelligence regarding the recommendation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Concurrence in Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the event of a vacancy in a position referred to in paragraph (2), before appointing an individual to fill the vacancy or recommending to the President an individual to be nominated to fill the vacancy, the Secretary of Defense shall obtain the concurrence of the Director of National Intelligence as provided in section 106(b) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3041(b)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) applies to the following positions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Security Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Reconnaissance Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance Evaluations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director of National Intelligence shall provide annually to the Secretary of Defense, for the Secretary’s consideration, an evaluation of the performance of the individuals holding the positions referred to in paragraph (2) in fulfilling their respective responsibilities with regard to the National Intelligence Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The positions referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Security Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Reconnaissance Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title IX, § 922(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1453</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1103(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2676</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)(4)</ref>, (5), (c)(2), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 932(a)(3)–(5), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(c)(10)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3508</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 202.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–107, title V, § 503(c)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-20">Nov. 20, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2262</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 203.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2102</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 204.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 3848]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 205.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2199</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>