<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 7—</num>
<heading>BOARDS, COUNCILS, AND COMMITTEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 171.</num>
<heading> Armed Forces Policy Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> There is in the Department of Defense an Armed Forces Policy Council consisting of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense, as Chairman, with the power of decision;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Deputy Secretary of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Army;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Navy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Air Force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the Chief of Staff of the Army;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> the Chief of Naval Operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> the Chief of Staff of the Air Force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> the Commandant of the Marine Corps; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> the Chief of Space Operations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Armed Forces Policy Council shall advise the Secretary of Defense on matters of broad policy relating to the armed forces and shall consider and report on such other matters as the Secretary of Defense may direct.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 8</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–599, § 9(c)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-06">Aug. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–596, § 5</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1318</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–140, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-21">Oct. 21, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1173</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title XII, § 1213</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title X, § 903(e)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–82</ref>, 1783–133, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title X, § 903(e)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–82</ref>, 3341–133; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IX</ref>, formerly title IV, § 903(e), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3912</ref>, renumbered title IX, <ref>Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(6)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3822</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 171a.</num>
<heading> Council on Oversight of the National Leadership Command, Control, and Communications System</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is within the Department of Defense a council to be known as the “Council on Oversight of the National Leadership Command, Control, and Communications System” (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The members of the Council shall be as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Commander of the United States Strategic Command.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Director of the National Security Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Director of the White House Military Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Such other officers of the Department of Defense as the Secretary may designate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Co-Chair</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall be co-chaired by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment and the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Council shall be responsible for oversight of the command, control, and communications system for the national leadership of the United States, including nuclear command, control, and communications, and including with respect to the integrated tactical warning and attack assessment systems, processes, and enablers, and continuity of the governmental functions of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out the responsibility for oversight of the command, control, and communications system as specified in paragraph (1), the Council shall be responsible for the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Oversight of performance assessments (including interoperability).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Vulnerability identification and mitigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Architecture development (including space system architectures and associated user terminals and ground segments).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Resource prioritization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Such other responsibilities as the Secretary of Defense shall specify for purposes of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>During the period preceding <date date="2021-01-31">January 31, 2021</date>, at the same time each year that the budget of the President is submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, and from time to time after such period at the discretion of the Council, the Council shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the activities of the Council. Each report shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A description and assessment of the activities of the Council during the previous fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of the activities proposed to be undertaken by the Council during the period covered by the current future-years defense program under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any changes to the requirements of the command, control, and communications system for the national leadership of the United States made during the previous year, along with an explanation for why the changes were made and a description of the effects of the changes to the capability of the system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A breakdown of each program element in such budget that relates to the system, including how such program element relates to the operation and sustainment, research and development, procurement, or other activity of the system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An assessment of the threats and vulnerabilities described in the reports and assessments collected under subsection (f) during the previous year, including any plans to address such threats and vulnerabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> An assessment of the readiness of the command, control, and communications system for the national leadership of the United States and of each layer of the system, as that layer relates to nuclear command, control, and communications.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collection of Assessments on Certain Threats</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall collect and assess (consistent with the provision of classified information and intelligence sources and methods) all reports and assessments otherwise conducted by the intelligence community (as defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</ref>)) regarding foreign threats, including cyber threats, to the command, control, and communications system for the national leadership of the United States and the vulnerabilities of such system to such threats.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget and Funding Matters</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 30 days after the President submits to Congress the budget for a fiscal year under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, the Commander of the United States Strategic Command shall submit to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff an assessment of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whether such budget allows the Federal Government to meet the required capabilities of the command, control, and communications system for the national leadership of the United States during the fiscal year covered by the budget and the four subsequent fiscal years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the Commander determines that such budget does not allow the Federal Government to meet such required capabilities, a description of the steps being taken to meet such required capabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff receives the assessment of the Commander of the United States Strategic Command under paragraph (1), the Chairman shall submit to the congressional defense committees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such assessment as it was submitted to the Chairman; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any comments of the Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If a House of Congress adopts a bill authorizing or appropriating funds for the activities of the command, control, and communications system for the national leadership of the United States that, as determined by the Council, provides insufficient funds for such activities for the period covered by such bill, the Council shall notify the congressional defense committees of the determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports on Space Architecture Development</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not less than 90 days before each of the dates on which a system described in paragraph (2) achieves Milestone A or Milestone B approval, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report prepared by the Council detailing the implications of any changes to the architecture of such a system with respect to the systems, capabilities, and programs covered under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A system described in this paragraph is any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Advanced extremely high frequency satellites.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The space-based infrared system.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The integrated tactical warning and attack assessment system and its command and control system.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The enhanced polar system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the terms “Milestone A approval” and “Milestone B approval” have the meanings given such terms in sections 4172(e) and 4251(d) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of Reduction of Certain Warning Time</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Defense for any fiscal year may be used to change any command, control, and communications system described in subsection (d)(1) in a manner that reduces the warning time provided to the national leadership of the United States with respect to a warning of a strategic missile attack on the United States unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense notifies the congressional defense committees of such proposed change and reduction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a period of one year elapses following the date of such notification.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than <date date="2017-03-01">March 1, 2017</date>, and each year thereafter, the Council shall determine whether the integrated tactical warning and attack assessment system and its command and control system have met all warfighter requirements for operational availability, survivability, and endurability. If the Council determines that such systems have not met such requirements, the Secretary of Defense and the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff shall jointly submit to the congressional defense committees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an explanation for such negative determination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the mitigations that are in place or being put in place as a result of such negative determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the plan of the Secretary and the Chairman to ensure that the Council is able to make a positive determination in the following year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Status of Acquisition Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> On a quarterly basis, each program manager of a covered acquisition program shall transmit to the co-chairs of the Council, acting through the senior steering group of the Council, a report that identifies—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the covered acquisition program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the requirements of the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the development timeline of the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the status of the program, including whether the program is delayed and, if so, whether such delay will result in a program schedule delay.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than seven days after the end of each semiannual period, the co-chairs of the Council shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report that identifies, with respect to the reports transmitted to the Council under paragraph (1) for the two quarters in such period—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each covered acquisition program that is delayed more than 180 days; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any covered acquisition program that should have been included in such reports but was excluded, and the reasons for such exclusion.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “covered acquisition program” means each acquisition program of the Department of Defense that materially contributes to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the nuclear command, control, and communications systems of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the continuity of government systems of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Leadership of the United States Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “national leadership of the United States” means the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Vice President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Such other civilian officials of the United States Government as the President shall designate for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1052(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 859</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1651</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XVI, § 1661</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2613</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(13)</ref>, title XVI, § 1654(a)(1), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1595</ref>, 1758; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1661</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(10)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1845(c)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3871</ref>, 4247; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII</ref>, §§ 1701(b)(14), 1702(a)(1), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2134</ref>, 2155; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1636(c), 1672(a), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2940</ref>, 2959.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 172.</num>
<heading> Explosive safety board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, acting through a joint board that includes members selected by the Secretaries of the military departments, composed of military officers designated as the chair and voting members of the board for each military department, and other civilian officers and employees of the Department of Defense, as necessary, shall provide oversight on storage and transportation of supplies of ammunition and components thereof for use of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, and Coast Guard, with particular regard to keeping those supplies properly dispersed and stored and to preventing hazardous conditions from arising to endanger life and property inside or outside of storage reservations. When the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Department of the Navy, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall appoint an officer of the Coast Guard to serve as a voting member of the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Oversight by Secretaries of the Military Departments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretaries of the military departments shall provide research, development, test, evaluation, and manufacturing oversight for energetic materials supporting military requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities of Chair</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (h), the chair of the explosive safety board shall carry out the following responsibilities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To act as the principal executive representative and advisor of the Secretary on explosive and chemical agent safety matters related to Department of Defense military munitions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To perform the hazard classification approval duties assigned to the chair.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To preside over meetings of the explosive safety board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To direct the staff of the explosive safety board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To perform other functions relating to explosives safety management, as directed by the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Sustainment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> To provide impartial and objective advice related to explosives safety management to the Secretary of Defense and the heads of the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> To serve as the principal representative and advisor of the Department of Defense on matters relating to explosives safety management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> To provide assistance and advice to the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment and the Deputy Director of Land Warfare and Munitions in munitions acquisition oversight and technology advancement for Department of Defense military munitions, especially in the areas of explosives and chemical agent safety and demilitarization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> To provide assistance and advice to the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Logistics and Material Readiness in sustainment oversight of Department of Defense military munitions, especially in the areas of explosives and chemical agent safety, storage, transportation, and demilitarization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> To develop and recommend issuances to define the functions of the explosive safety board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> To establish joint hazard classification procedures with covered components of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> To make recommendations to the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment with respect to explosives and chemical agent safety tenets and requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> To conduct oversight of Department of Defense explosive safety management programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> To carry out such other responsibilities as the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities of Executive Director and Civilian Members</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The executive director and civilian members of the explosive safety board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide assistance to the chair in carrying out the responsibilities specified in subsection (c); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> carry out such other responsibilities as the chair determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The explosive safety board shall meet not less frequently than quarterly.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The chair shall submit to the congressional defense committees an annual report describing the activities conducted at the meetings of the board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusive Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The explosive safety board shall have exclusive responsibility within the Department of Defense for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> recommending new and updated explosive and chemical agent safety regulations and standards to the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy Installations and Environment for submittal to the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> acting as the primary forum for coordination among covered components of the Department on all matters related to explosive safety management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Components</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the covered components of the Department are each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Office of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Office of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and the Joint Staff, the Combatant Commands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Office of the Inspector General of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Defense Agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Department of Defense field activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> All other organizational entities within the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Explosives Used by Space Launch Vehicles</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall delegate to the Secretary of the Air Force, who may further delegate to the Commanders of the Space Launch Deltas, the responsibilities under subsection (c) with respect to explosives used by space launch vehicles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “launch vehicle” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 50902(11) of title 51</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 8</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title IX, § 909</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2621</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1361</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title III, § 351</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1730</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, title IX, § 924(b)(2)(A)(ii), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3542</ref>, 3821; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVI, § 1601(a)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(2), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 583</ref>, 683.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 173.</num>
<heading> Advisory personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may establish such advisory committees and employ such part-time advisers as he considers necessary for the performance of his functions and those of the agencies under his control.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A person who serves as a member of a committee may not be paid for that service while holding another position or office under the United States for which he receives compensation. Other members and part-time advisers shall (except as otherwise specifically authorized by law) serve without compensation for such service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 8</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1061(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 443</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 174.</num>
<heading> Advisory personnel: research and development</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of each military department may establish such advisory committees and panels as are necessary for the research and development activities of his department and may employ such part-time advisers as he considers necessary to carry out those activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A person who serves as a member of such a committee or panel may not be paid for that service while holding another position or office under the United States for which he receives compensation. Other members and part-time advisers shall (except as otherwise specifically authorized by law) serve without compensation for such service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned may delegate any authority under this section to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Under Secretary of his department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an Assistant Secretary of his department; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the chief, and one assistant to the chief, of any technical service, bureau, or office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1061(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 443</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 175.</num>
<heading> Reserve Forces Policy Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is in the Office of the Secretary of Defense a Reserve Forces Policy Board. The functions, membership, and organization of that board are set forth in <ref>section 10301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–168, § 2(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="1967-12-01">Dec. 1, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title XII, § 1212(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIII, § 1306</ref>, title XIV, § 1405(4), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2613</ref>, 2622; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 21</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2870</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 531(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 921</ref>, title XVI, § 1661(b)(3), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2829</ref>, 2981.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 176.</num>
<heading> Armed Forces Institute of Pathology</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is in the Department of Defense an Institute to be known as the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Institute”), which has the responsibilities, functions, authority, and relationships set forth in this section. The Institute shall be a joint entity of the three military departments, subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Institute shall consist of a Board of Governors, a Director, two Deputy Directors, and a staff of such professional, technical, and clerical personnel as may be required.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Board of Governors shall consist of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs, who shall serve as chairman of the Board of Governors, the Assistant Secretary of Health and Human Services for Health, the Surgeons General of the Army, Navy, and Air Force, the Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and a former Director of the Institute, as designated by the Secretary of Defense, or the designee of any of the foregoing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Director and the Deputy Directors shall be appointed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out the provisions of this section, the Institute is authorized to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contract with the American Registry of Pathology (established under <ref>section 177 of this title</ref>) for cooperative enterprises in medical research, consultation, and education between the Institute and the civilian medical profession under such conditions as may be agreed upon between the Board of Governors and the American Registry of Pathology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make available at no cost to the American Registry of Pathology such space, facilities, equipment, and support services within the Institute as the Board of Governors deems necessary for the accomplishment of their mutual cooperative enterprises; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> contract with the American Registry of Pathology for the services of such professional, technical, or clerical personnel as are necessary to fulfill their cooperative enterprises.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No contract may be entered into under paragraph (1) which obligates the Institute to make outlays in advance of the enactment of budget authority for such outlays.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Director is authorized, with the approval of the Board of Governors, to enter into agreements with the American Registry of Pathology for the services at any time of not more than six distinguished pathologists or scientists of demonstrated ability and experience for the purpose of enhancing the activities of the Institute in education, consultation, and research. Such pathologists or scientists may be appointed by the Director to administrative positions within the components or subcomponents of the Institute and may be authorized by the Director to exercise any or all professional duties within the Institute, notwithstanding any other provision of law. The Secretary of Defense, on a case-by-case basis, may waive the limitation on the number of distinguished pathologists or scientists with whom agreements may be entered into under this subsection if the Secretary determines that such waiver is in the best interest of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to prescribe the organization, functions, and responsibilities of the Institute.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–361, title VIII, § 811(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-07-14">July 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 933</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(6)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2920</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1602</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VII, § 733</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1697</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IX, § 903(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 177.</num>
<heading> American Registry of Pathology</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be established a nonprofit corporation to be known as the American Registry of Pathology which shall not for any purpose be an agency or establishment of the United States Government. The American Registry of Pathology shall be subject to the provisions of this section and, to the extent not inconsistent with this section, to the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act (D.C. Code, sec. 29–501 et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The American Registry of Pathology shall have a Board of Members (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Board”) consisting of not less than eleven individuals who are representatives of the professional societies and organizations that support the activities of the American Registry of Pathology, of whom one shall be elected annually by the Board to serve as chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The American Registry of Pathology shall have a Director, who shall be appointed by the Board, and such other officers as may be named and appointed by the Board. Such officers shall be compensated at rates fixed by the Board and shall serve at the pleasure of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The members of the initial Board shall serve as incorporators and shall take whatever actions are necessary to establish under the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act the corporation authorized by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term of office of each member of the Board shall be four years, except that (A) any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term, (B) the terms of office of members first taking office shall begin on the date of incorporation and shall expire, as designated at the time of their appointment and to the maximum extent practicable, one fourth at the end of one year, one fourth at the end of two years, one fourth at the end of three years, and one fourth at the end of four years, and (C) a member whose term has expired may serve until his successor has qualified. No member shall be eligible to serve more than two consecutive terms of four years each.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Any vacancy in the Board shall not affect its powers, but such vacancy shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In order to carry out the purposes of this section, the American Registry of Pathology is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enter into contracts with public and private organizations for the writing, editing, printing, and publishing of fascicles of tumor pathology, atlases, and other material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> accept gifts and grants from and enter into contracts with individuals, private foundations, professional societies, institutions, and governmental agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enter into agreements with professional societies for the establishment and maintenance of Registries of Pathology; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> serve as a focus for the interchange between military and civilian pathology and encourage the participation of medical, dental, and veterinary sciences in pathology for the mutual benefit of military and civilian medicine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> In the performance of the functions set forth in subsection (b), the American Registry of Pathology is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enter into such other contracts, leases, cooperative agreements, or other transactions as the Board deems appropriate to conduct the activities of the American Registry of Pathology; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> charge such fees for professional services as the Board deems reasonable and appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The American Registry of Pathology may transmit annually to its Board and supporting organizations referred to in subsection (a)(2) a comprehensive and detailed report of its operations, activities, and accomplishments.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–361, title VIII, § 811(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-07-14">July 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 934</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(5)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 585</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1768</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 178.</num>
<heading> The Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be established a nonprofit corporation to be known as the Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Foundation”) which shall not for any purpose be an agency or instrumentality of the United States Government. The Foundation shall be subject to the provisions of this section and, to the extent not inconsistent with this section, the Corporations and Associations Articles of the State of Maryland.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> It shall be the purpose of the Foundation (1) to carry out medical research and education projects under cooperative arrangements with the Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences, (2) to serve as a focus for the interchange between military and civilian medical personnel, and (3) to encourage the participation of the medical, dental, nursing, veterinary, and other biomedical sciences in the work of the Foundation for the mutual benefit of military and civilian medicine.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Foundation shall have a Council of Directors (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Council”) composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Chairmen and ranking minority members of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives (or their designees from the membership of such committees), who shall be ex officio members,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Dean of the Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences, who shall be an ex officio member, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> six members, each of whom shall be appointed at the expiration of the term of a member appointed under this subparagraph, as provided for in paragraph (2), by the members currently serving on the Council pursuant to this subparagraph and paragraph (2), including the member whose expiring term is so being filled by such appointment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term of office of each member of the Council appointed under clause (C) of paragraph (1) shall be four years, except that any person appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Council shall elect a chairman from among its members.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Foundation shall have an Executive Director who shall be appointed by the Council and shall serve at the pleasure of the Council. The Executive Director shall be responsible for the day-to-day operations of the Foundation and shall have such specific duties and responsibilities as the Council shall prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The rate of compensation of the Executive Director shall be fixed by the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The initial members of the Council shall serve as incorporators and take whatever actions as are necessary to establish under the Corporations and Associations Articles of the State of Maryland the corporation authorized by subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Any vacancy in the Council shall not affect its powers, but shall be filled in the same manner in which the original designation or appointment was made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> In order to carry out the purposes of this section, the Foundation is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enter into contracts with, accept grants from, and make grants to the Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences for the purpose of carrying out cooperative enterprises in medical research, medical consultation, and medical education, including contracts for provision of such personnel and services as may be necessary to carry out such cooperative enterprises;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enter into contracts with public and private organizations for the writing, editing, printing, and publishing of books and other material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> take such action as may be necessary to obtain patents and licenses for devices and procedures developed by the Foundation and its employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> accept, hold, administer, invest, and spend any gift, devise, or bequest of real or personal property made to the Foundation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> enter into contracts with individuals, public or private organizations, professional societies, and government agencies for the purpose of carrying out the functions of the Foundation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> enter into such other contracts, leases, cooperative agreements, and other transactions as the Executive Director considers appropriate to conduct the activities of the Foundation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> charge such fees for professional services furnished by the Foundation as the Executive Director determines reasonable and appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> A person who is a full-time or part-time employee of the Foundation may not be an employee (full-time or part-time) of the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Council shall transmit to the President annually, and at such other times as the Council considers desirable, a report on the operations, activities, and accomplishments of the Foundation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–36, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-05-27">May 27, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 200</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–132, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-10-17">Oct. 17, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 849</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VII, § 726(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1480</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VII, § 739</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VII, § 733(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179.</num>
<heading> Nuclear Weapons Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment; Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is a Nuclear Weapons Council (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Council”) operated as a joint activity of the Department of Defense and the Department of Energy. The membership of the Council is comprised of the following officers of those departments:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary for Nuclear Security of the Department of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Commander of the United States Strategic Command.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairman; Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Chairman of the Council shall be the member designated under subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A meeting of the Council shall be chaired by the Under Secretary for Nuclear Security of the Department of Energy whenever the matter under consideration is within the primary responsibility or concern of the Department of Energy, as determined by majority vote of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Council shall meet not less often than once every three months. To the extent possible, not later than seven days before a meeting, the Chairman shall disseminate to each member of the Council the agenda and documents for such meeting.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Staff and Administrative Services; Staff Director</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy shall enter into an agreement with the Council to furnish necessary staff and administrative services to the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Nuclear Deterrence, Chemical, and Biological Defense Policy and Programs shall be the Staff Director of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Whenever the position of Assistant Secretary of Defense for Nuclear Deterrence, Chemical, and Biological Defense Policy and Programs has been vacant a period of more than 6 months, the Secretary of Energy shall designate a qualified individual to serve as acting staff director of the Council until the position of Assistant Secretary is filled.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An individual designated under subparagraph (A) shall possess substantial technical and policy experience relevant to the management and oversight of nuclear weapons programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall be responsible for the following matters:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Preparing the annual Nuclear Weapons Stockpile Memorandum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Developing nuclear weapons stockpiles options and the costs of such options and alternatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Coordinating and approving programming and budget matters pertaining to nuclear weapons programs between the Department of Defense and the Department of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Identifying various options for cost-effective schedules for nuclear weapons production.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Considering safety, security, and control issues for existing weapons and for proposed new weapon program starts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Ensuring that adequate consideration is given to design, performance, and cost tradeoffs for all proposed new nuclear weapons programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Providing specific guidance regarding priorities for research on nuclear weapons and priorities among activities, including production, surveillance, research, construction, and any other programs within the National Nuclear Security Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Coordinating and approving activities conducted by the Department of Energy for the study, development, production, and retirement of nuclear warheads, including concept definition studies, feasibility studies, engineering development, hardware component fabrication, warhead production, and warhead retirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Reviewing proposed capabilities, and, in coordination with the Joint Requirements Oversight Council, establishing and validating performance requirements (as defined in <ref>section 181(h) of this title</ref>), for nuclear warhead programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to nuclear warheads—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reviewing military requirements, performance requirements, and planned delivery schedules to evaluate whether such requirements and schedules create significant risks to cost, schedules, or other matters regarding production, surveillance, research, and other programs relating to nuclear weapons within the National Nuclear Security Administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if any such risk exists, proposing and analyzing adjustments to such requirements and schedules.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Preparing comments on annual proposals for budget levels for research on nuclear weapons and transmitting those comments to the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy before the preparation of the annual budget requests by the Secretaries of those departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Coordinating and approving the annual budget proposals of the National Nuclear Security Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Coordinating risk management efforts between the Department of Defense and the National Nuclear Security Administration relating to the nuclear weapons stockpile, the nuclear security enterprise (as defined in section 4002 of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 2501</ref>)), and the delivery platforms for nuclear weapons, including with respect to identifying and analyzing risks and proposing actions to mitigate risks.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report on Difficulties Relating to Safety or Reliability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall submit to Congress a report on any analysis conducted by the Council with respect to difficulties at nuclear weapons laboratories or nuclear weapons production plants that have significant bearing on confidence in the safety or reliability of nuclear weapons or nuclear weapon types.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget and Funding Matters</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Council shall annually review the plans and budget of the National Nuclear Security Administration and assess whether such plans and budget meet the current and projected requirements relating to nuclear weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Council shall review each budget request transmitted by the Secretary of Energy to the Council under section 4717 of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 2757</ref>) and make a determination under subparagraph (B) regarding the adequacy of each such request. Not later than 30 days after making such a determination, the Council shall notify the congressional defense committees that such a determination has been made.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> If the Council determines that a budget request for a fiscal year transmitted to the Council under section 4717 of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 2757</ref>) is inadequate, in whole or in part, to implement the objectives of the Department of Defense with respect to nuclear weapons for that fiscal year, the Council shall submit to the Secretary of Energy a written description of funding levels and specific initiatives that would, in the determination of the Council, make the budget request adequate to implement those objectives.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If the Council determines that a budget request for a fiscal year transmitted to the Council under section 4717 of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 2757</ref>) is adequate to implement the objectives described in clause (i) for that fiscal year, the Council shall submit to the Secretary of Energy a written statement confirming the adequacy of the request.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The Council shall maintain a record of each description submitted under clause (i) and each statement submitted under clause (ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 30 days after the President submits to Congress the budget for a fiscal year under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, the Council shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report containing the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The results of the assessment conducted under paragraph (1) with respect to that budget.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> An evaluation of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> whether the funding requested for the National Nuclear Security Administration in such budget—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> enables the Administrator for Nuclear Security to meet requirements relating to nuclear weapons for such fiscal year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is adequate to implement the objectives of the Department of Defense with respect to nuclear weapons for that fiscal year; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> whether the plans and budget reviewed under paragraph (1) will enable the Administrator to meet—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the requirements to produce war reserve plutonium pits under section 4219(a) of such Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 2538a(a)</ref>); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any other requirements under Federal law.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> If the evaluation under subparagraph (B)(ii) determines that the plans and budget reviewed under paragraph (1) will not enable the Administrator to meet the requirements to produce war reserve plutonium pits under section 4219(a) of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 2538a(a)</ref>)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an explanation for why the plans and budget will not enable the Administrator to meet such requirements; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> proposed alternative plans, budget, or requirements by the Council to meet such requirements.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If a member of the Council does not concur in any assessment or evaluation under this subsection, the report or other information required to be submitted to the congressional defense committees regarding such assessment or evaluation shall include a written explanation from the non-concurring member describing the reasons for the member’s nonconcurrence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 30 days after the President submits to Congress the budget for a fiscal year under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, the Commander of the United States Strategic Command shall submit to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff an assessment of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> whether such budget allows the Federal Government to meet the nuclear stockpile and stockpile stewardship program requirements during the fiscal year covered by the budget and the four subsequent fiscal years; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the Commander determines that such budget does not allow the Federal Government to meet such requirements, a description of the steps being taken to meet such requirements.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff receives the assessment of the Commander of the United States Strategic Command under subparagraph (A), the Chairman shall submit to the congressional defense committees—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such assessment as it was submitted to the Chairman; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any comments of the Chairman.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “budget” has the meaning given that term in section 231(f) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002011">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Semiannual Updates on Council Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than February 1 and August 1 of each year, the Council shall provide to the congressional defense committees a semiannual update including, with respect to the six-month period preceding the update—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the dates on which the Council met and the members who attended each meeting; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> except as provided by paragraph (2), a summary of any decisions made by the Council pursuant to subsection (d) at each such meeting and the rationale for and options that informed such decisions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Council shall not be required to include in a semiannual update under paragraph (1) the matters described in subparagraph (B) of that paragraph with respect to decisions of the Council relating to the budget of the President for a fiscal year if the budget for that fiscal year has not been submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> as of the date of the semiannual update.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Council may provide a semiannual update under paragraph (1) either in the form of a briefing or a written report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. C, title I, § 3137(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4065</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XII, § 1231(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1160</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1233(h)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2058</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. C, title XXXI, § 3133</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. C, title XXXI, § 3152</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3090</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IX, § 904(b)(1)</ref>, title XV, § 1502(a)(7), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 403</ref>, 502; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, div. C, title XXXI, § 3163(a), (c), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>, 944; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [div. C, title XXXI, § 3152(a)]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–464; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLII, § 4213(c)</ref>, formerly <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXI, § 3159(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2842</ref>, renumbered <ref>§ 4213(c) of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(14)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1760</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2025</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title IX, § 901(j)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4324</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1039</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1053, 1091(a)(3), <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 861</ref>, 875; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XVI, § 1641</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3648</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 997</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(14)</ref>, title XVI, § 1653, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1595</ref>, 1758; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVI, § 1661</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2152</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1663</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1631(a), 1632(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4056</ref>, 4057; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XVI, § 1633(a)</ref>, (b), (d), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2935</ref>, 2936, 2938; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2171</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 180.</num>
<heading> Service academy athletic programs: review board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Independent Review Board</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall appoint a board to review the administration of the athletics programs of the United States Military Academy, the United States Naval Academy, and the United States Air Force Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Composition of Board</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall appoint the members of the board from among distinguished administrators of institutions of higher education, members of Congress, members of the Boards of Visitors of the academies, and other experts in collegiate athletics programs. The Superintendents of the three academies shall be members of the board. The Secretary shall designate one member of the board, other than a Superintendent of an academy, as Chairman.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The board shall, on an annual basis—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> review all aspects of the athletics programs of the United States Military Academy, the United States Naval Academy, and the United States Air Force Academy, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the policies relating to the administration of such programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the appropriateness of the balance between the emphasis placed by each academy on athletics and the emphasis placed by such academy on academic pursuits; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the extent to which all athletes in all sports are treated equitably under the athletics program of each academy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> determine ways in which the administration of the athletics programs at the academies can serve as models for the administration of athletics programs at civilian institutions of higher education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each member of the board who is not an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for Executive Schedule Level IV under <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref>, for each day (including travel time) during which such member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the board. Members of the board who are officers or employees of the United States shall serve without compensation in addition to that received for their services as officers or employees of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The members of the board shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 513(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1360</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1087(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–290.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 181.</num>
<heading> Joint Requirements Oversight Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a Joint Requirements Oversight Council in the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mission</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to other matters assigned to it by the President or Secretary of Defense, the Joint Requirements Oversight Council shall assist the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assessing joint military capabilities, and identifying, approving, and prioritizing gaps in such capabilities, to meet applicable requirements in the national defense strategy under <ref>section 113(g) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> increasing awareness of global trends, threats, and adversary capabilities to address gaps in joint military capabilities and validate joint requirements developed by the military departments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> reviewing and validating whether a capability proposed by an armed force, Defense Agency, or other entity of the Department of Defense fulfills a gap in joint military capabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> establishing and approving joint performance requirements that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure interoperability, where appropriate, between and among joint military capabilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are necessary, as designated by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, to fulfill capability gaps of more than one armed force, Defense Agency, or other entity of the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> reviewing performance requirements for any existing or proposed capability that the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff determines should be reviewed by the Council;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> identifying new joint military capabilities based on advances in technology and concepts of operation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> identifying alternatives to any acquisition program that meets approved joint military capability requirements for the purposes of sections 4251(b), 4252(a)(4), and 4375(b) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Composition.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Joint Requirements Oversight Council is composed of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, who is the Chair of the Council and is the principal adviser to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff for making recommendations about joint military capabilities or joint performance requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An Army officer in the grade of general.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A Navy officer in the grade of admiral.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> An Air Force officer in the grade of general.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A Marine Corps officer in the grade of general.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A Space Force officer in the grade of general.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection of members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of the Council under subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), and (E) of paragraph (1) shall be selected by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, after consultation with the Secretary of Defense, from officers in the grade of general or admiral, as the case may be, who are recommended for selection by the Secretary of the military department concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In making any recommendation to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff as described in paragraph (1)(A), the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff shall provide the Chairman any dissenting view of members of the Council under paragraph (1) with respect to such recommendation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Advisors.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following officials of the Department of Defense shall serve as advisors to the Joint Requirements Oversight Council on matters within their authority and expertise:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering who shall serve as the Chief Technical Advisor to the Council and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall provide assistance in evaluating the technical feasibility of requirements under development; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall identify options for expanding or generating new requirements based on opportunities provided by new or emerging technologies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Director of Operational Test and Evaluation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The commander of a combatant command when matters related to the area of responsibility or functions of that command are under consideration by the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Input from combatant commands</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall seek and consider input from the commanders of the combatant commands in carrying out its mission under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Input from chiefs of staff</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall seek, and strongly consider, the views of the Chiefs of Staff of the armed forces, in their roles as customers of the acquisition system, on matters pertaining to a capability proposed by an armed force, Defense Agency, or other entity of the Department of Defense under subsection (b)(2) and joint performance requirements pursuant to subsection (b)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Input from vice chief of the national guard bureau</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall seek, and strongly consider, the views of the Vice Chief of the National Guard Bureau regarding non-Federalized National Guard capabilities in support of homeland defense and civil support missions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance Requirements as Responsibility of Armed Forces</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of Staff of an armed force is responsible for all performance requirements for that armed force and, except for performance requirements specified in subsections (b)(4) and (b)(5), such performance requirements do not need to be validated by the Joint Requirements Oversight Council.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Analytic Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that analytical organizations within the Department of Defense, such as the Office of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation, provide resources and expertise in operations research, systems analysis, and cost estimation to the Joint Requirements Oversight Council to assist the Council in performing the mission in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Oversight Information to Congressional Defense Committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, in the case of a recommendation by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to the Secretary that is approved by the Secretary, oversight information with respect to such recommendation that is produced as a result of the activities of the Joint Requirements Oversight Council is made available in a timely fashion to the congressional defense committees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “joint military capabilities” means the collective capabilities across the joint force, including both joint and force-specific capabilities, that are available to conduct military operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “performance requirement” means a performance attribute of a particular system considered critical or essential to the development of an effective military capability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “joint performance requirement” means a performance requirement that is critical or essential to ensure interoperability or fulfill a capability gap of more than one armed force, Defense Agency, or other entity of the Department of Defense, or impacts the joint force in other ways such as logistics.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “oversight information” means information and materials comprising analysis and justification that are prepared to support a recommendation that is made to, and approved by, the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IX, § 905(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 403</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title IX, § 908</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2621</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1043(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1610</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 942(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 287</ref>, 288; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 813(d)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4527</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–23, title I</ref>, §§ 101(d)(1), 105(a), title II, § 201(b), <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1709</ref>, 1717, 1719; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 841</ref>, title X, § 1075(b)(8), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4281</ref>, 4369; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title IX, § 951(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1891</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 802(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 879</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 925(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1595</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 831(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1857</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(7)</ref>, title XVI, § 1621(e)(1)(A)(v), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1543</ref>, 1733; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX</ref>, §§ 906, 924(b)(9), title XVIII, § 1850(m), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3799</ref>, 3822, 4271; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title IX, § 903(a)</ref>, title XVII, § 1702(a)(2), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1869</ref>, 2155; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 521(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1880</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 182.</num>
<heading> Center for Excellence in Disaster Management and Humanitarian Assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may operate a Center for Excellence in Disaster Management and Humanitarian Assistance (in this section referred to as the “Center”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Missions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Center shall be used to provide and facilitate education, training, and research in civil-military operations, particularly operations that require international disaster management and humanitarian assistance and operations that require coordination between the Department of Defense and other agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Center shall be used to make available high-quality disaster management and humanitarian assistance in response to disasters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Center shall be used to provide and facilitate education, training, interagency coordination, and research on the following additional matters:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Management of the consequences of nuclear, biological, and chemical events.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Management of the consequences of terrorism.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Appropriate roles for the reserve components in the management of such consequences and in disaster management and humanitarian assistance in response to natural disasters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Meeting requirements for information in connection with regional and global disasters, including the use of advanced communications technology as a virtual library.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Tropical medicine, particularly in relation to the medical readiness requirements of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Center shall develop a repository of disaster risk indicators for the Asia-Pacific region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Center shall perform such other missions as the Secretary of Defense may specify.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joint Operation With Educational Institution Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may enter into an agreement with appropriate officials of an institution of higher education to provide for joint operation of the Center. Any such agreement shall provide for the institution to furnish necessary administrative services for the Center, including administration and allocation of funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Donations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of Defense may accept, on behalf of the Center, donations to be used to defray the costs of the Center or to enhance the operation of the Center. Such donations may be accepted from any agency of the Federal Government, any State or local government, any foreign government, any foundation or other charitable organization (including any that is organized or operates under the laws of a foreign country), or any other private source in the United States or a foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may not accept a donation under paragraph (1) if the acceptance of the donation would compromise or appear to compromise—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the ability of the Department of Defense, any employee of the Department, or members of the armed forces, to carry out any responsibility or duty of the Department in a fair and objective manner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the integrity of any program of the Department of Defense or of any person involved in such a program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe written guidance setting forth the criteria to be used in determining whether or not the acceptance of a foreign donation would have a result described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Funds accepted by the Secretary under paragraph (1) as a donation on behalf of the Center shall be credited to appropriations available to the Department of Defense for the Center. Funds so credited shall be merged with the appropriations to which credited and shall be available for the Center for the same purposes and the same period as the appropriations with which merged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 382(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1709</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 182a.</num>
<heading> Center for Excellence in Environmental Security</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may operate a Center for Excellence in Environmental Security (in this section referred to as the “Center”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Missions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Center shall be used to provide and facilitate education, training, and research in civil-military operations, particularly operations that require international assistance and operations that require coordination between the Department of Defense and other Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Center shall be used to provide and facilitate education, training, interagency coordination, and research on the following additional matters:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Management of the consequences of environmental insecurity with respect to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> access to water, food, and energy;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> related health matters; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> matters relating to when, how, and why environmental stresses to human safety, health, water, energy, and food will cascade to economic, social, political, or national security events.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Appropriate roles for the reserve components in response to environmental insecurity resulting from natural disasters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Meeting requirements for information in connection with regional and global disasters, including through the use of advanced communications technology as a virtual library.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Center shall perform such other missions as the Secretary of Defense may specify.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To assist the Center in carrying out the missions under this subsection, upon request of the Center, the head of any Federal agency may grant to the Center access to the data, archives, and other physical resources (including facilities) of that agency, and may detail any personnel of that agency to the Center, for the purpose of enabling the development of global environmental indicators.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joint Operation With Educational Institution Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may enter into an agreement with appropriate officials of an institution of higher education to provide for the operation of the Center. Any such agreement shall provide for the institution to furnish necessary administrative services for the Center, including by directly providing such services or providing the funds for such services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Donations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of Defense may accept, on behalf of the Center, donations to be used to defray the costs of the Center or to enhance the operation of the Center. Such donations may be accepted from any agency of the Federal Government, any State or local government, any foreign government, any foundation or other charitable organization (including any that is organized or operates under the laws of a foreign country), or any other private source in the United States or a foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may not accept a donation under paragraph (1) if the acceptance of the donation would compromise or appear to compromise—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the ability of the Department of Defense, any employee of the Department, or any member of the armed forces, to carry out any responsibility or duty of the Department or the armed forces in a fair and objective manner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the integrity of any program of the Department of Defense or of any person involved in such a program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe written guidance setting forth the criteria to be used in determining whether or not the acceptance of a foreign donation under paragraph (1) would have a result described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Funds accepted by the Secretary under paragraph (1) as a donation on behalf of the Center shall be credited to appropriations available to the Department of Defense for the Center. Funds so credited shall be merged with the appropriations to which credited and shall be available for the Center for the same purposes and the same period as the appropriations with which merged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 183.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense Board of Actuaries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be in the Department of Defense a Department of Defense Board of Actuaries (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Board”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Board shall consist of three members who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Defense from among qualified professional actuaries who are members of the Society of Actuaries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The members of the Board shall serve for a term of 15 years, except that a member of the Board appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the end of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall only serve until the end of such term. A member may serve after the end of the member’s term until the member’s successor takes office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A member of the Board may be removed by the Secretary of Defense only for misconduct or failure to perform functions vested in the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A member of the Board who is not an employee of the United States is entitled to receive pay at the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay of the highest rate of basic pay then currently being paid under the General Schedule of subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 for each day the member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the Board and is entitled to travel expenses, including a per diem allowance, in accordance with section 5703 of that title in connection with such duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board shall have the following duties:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To review valuations of the Department of Defense Military Retirement Fund in accordance with <ref>section 1465(c) of this title</ref> and submit to the President and Congress, not less often than once every four years, a report on the status of that Fund, including such recommendations for modifications to the funding or amortization of that Fund as the Board considers appropriate and necessary to maintain that Fund on a sound actuarial basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To review valuations of the Department of Defense Education Benefits Fund in accordance with <ref>section 2006(e) of this title</ref> and make recommendations to the President and Congress on such modifications to the funding or amortization of that Fund as the Board considers appropriate to maintain that Fund on a sound actuarial basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To review valuations of such other funds as the Secretary of Defense shall specify for purposes of this section and make recommendations to the President and Congress on such modifications to the funding or amortization of such funds as the Board considers appropriate to maintain such funds on a sound actuarial basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the Board has access to such records regarding the funds referred to in subsection (c) as the Board shall require to determine the actuarial status of such funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Board shall submit to the Secretary of Defense on an annual basis a report on the actuarial status of each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Department of Defense Military Retirement Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Department of Defense Education Benefits Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Each other fund specified by Secretary under subsection (c)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Board shall also furnish its advice and opinion on matters referred to it by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 906(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 275</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 183a.</num>
<heading> Military Aviation and Installation Assurance Clearinghouse for review of mission obstructions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish a Military Aviation and Installation Assurance Siting Clearinghouse (in this section referred to as the “Clearinghouse”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Clearinghouse shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> organized under the authority, direction, and control of an Assistant Secretary of Defense designated by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assigned such personnel and resources as the Secretary considers appropriate to carry out this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Clearinghouse shall coordinate Department of Defense review of applications for energy projects or antenna structure projects filed with the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to <ref>section 44718 of title 49</ref> and received by the Department of Defense from the Secretary of Transportation. In performing such coordination, the Clearinghouse shall provide procedures to ensure affected local military installations are consulted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Clearinghouse shall accelerate the development of planning tools necessary to determine the acceptability to the Department of Defense of proposals included in an application for an energy project or antenna structure project submitted pursuant to such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Clearinghouse shall perform such other functions as the Secretary of Defense assigns.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of Proposed Actions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 75 days after receiving from the Secretary of Transportation a proper application for an energy project or antenna structure project under <ref>section 44718 of title 49</ref> that may have an adverse impact on military operations and readiness, the Clearinghouse shall conduct a preliminary review of such application. The review shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assess the likely scope, duration, and level of risk of any adverse impact of such energy project or antenna structure project on military operations and readiness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify any feasible and affordable actions that could be taken by the Department, the developer of such energy project or antenna structure project, or others to mitigate the adverse impact and to minimize risks to national security while allowing the energy project or antenna structure project to proceed with development.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If the Clearinghouse finds under paragraph (1) that an energy project or antenna structure project will have an adverse impact on military operations and readiness, the Clearinghouse shall issue to the applicant a notice of presumed risk that describes the concerns identified by the Department in the preliminary review and requests a discussion of possible mitigation actions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> After the Clearinghouse issues a notice under subparagraph (A) with respect to an energy project or antenna structure project, the parties should seek to identify feasible and affordable actions that can be taken by the Department, the developer of such energy project or antenna structure project, or others to mitigate any adverse impact on military operations and readiness.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A notice of presumed risk issued under subparagraph (A) is a preliminary assessment only and does not represent a formal objection pursuant to subsection (e). Discussions of possible mitigation actions under such subparagraph could favorably resolve any concerns identified in the notice of presumed risk.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> At the same time that the Clearinghouse issues to the applicant a notice of presumed risk under paragraph (2), the Clearinghouse shall provide the same notice to the governor of the State in which the project is located and request that the governor provide the Clearinghouse any comments the governor believes of relevance to the application. The Clearinghouse shall ensure that a governor has at least 30 days after the date on which the governor receives the notice of presumed risk to provide any such comments and shall provide detailed information and other information necessary to ensure that the governor can fully understand the nature of the presumed risk. The Secretary of Defense shall consider the comments of the governor in the Secretary’s evaluation of whether the project presents an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States and shall include the comments with the finding provided to the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to <ref>section 44718(f) of title 49</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If, after issuing the notices of presumed risk required by paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary of Defense later concludes for any reason that the energy project or antenna structure project will not have an adverse impact on military readiness, the Clearinghouse shall notify the applicant and the governor in writing of that conclusion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Clearinghouse shall develop, in coordination with other departments and agencies of the Federal Government, an integrated review process to ensure timely notification and consideration of energy projects or antenna structure projects filed with the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to <ref>section 44718 of title 49</ref> that may have an adverse impact on military operations and readiness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Clearinghouse shall establish procedures for the Department of Defense for the coordinated consideration of and response to a request for a review received from another Federal agency, a State government, an Indian tribal government, a local government, a landowner, or the developer of an energy project or antenna structure project, including guidance to personnel at each military installation in the United States on how to initiate such procedures and ensure a coordinated Department response.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Clearinghouse shall develop procedures for conducting early outreach to parties carrying out energy projects or antenna structure projects that could have an adverse impact on military operations and readiness and to clearly communicate to such parties actions being taken by the Department of Defense under this section. The procedures shall provide for filing by such parties of a project area and preliminary project layout at least one year before expected construction of any project proposed within a military training route or within line-of-sight of any air route surveillance radar, airport surveillance radar, or wide area surveillance over-the-horizon radar operated or used by the Department of Defense in order to provide adequate time for analysis and negotiation of mitigation options. Material marked as proprietary or competition sensitive by a party filing for this preliminary review shall be protected from public release by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> If, in reviewing an application for an energy project or antenna structure project pursuant to paragraph (1), the Clearinghouse finds no adverse impact on military operations under <ref>section 44718(b)(1) of title 49</ref>, the Clearinghouse shall communicate to the Secretary of Transportation in writing, not later than five business days after making such finding, the following: “No Part 77 concerns, national security review ongoing.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Comprehensive Review</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall develop a comprehensive strategy for addressing the impacts upon the military of projects filed with the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to <ref>section 44718 of title 49</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In developing the strategy required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assess the magnitude of interference posed by projects filed with the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to <ref>section 44718 of title 49</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> solely for the purpose of informing preliminary reviews under subsection (c)(1) and early outreach efforts under subsection (c)(5), identify distinct geographic areas selected as proposed locations for projects filed, or for projects that are reasonably expected to be filed in the near future, with the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to <ref>section 44718 of title 49</ref> where the Secretary of Defense can demonstrate such projects could have an adverse impact on military operations and readiness, including military training routes or any active intercontinental ballistic missile launch facility or control center, and categorize the risk of adverse impact in such areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> develop procedures for the initial identification of such geographic areas identified under subparagraph (B), to include a process to provide notice and seek public comment prior to making a final designation of the geographic areas, including maps of the area and the basis for identification;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> develop procedures to periodically review and modify, consistent with the notice and public comment process under subparagraph (C), geographic areas identified under subparagraph (B) and to solicit and identify additional geographic areas as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> at the conclusion of the notice and public comment period conducted under subparagraph (C), make a final finding on the designation of a geographic area of concern or delegate the authority to make such finding to the Deputy Secretary of Defense, an Under Secretary of Defense, a Deputy Under Secretary of Defense, or, in the case of a geographic area of concern related to an active intercontinental ballistic missile launch facility or control center, the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> specifically identify feasible and affordable long-term actions that may be taken to mitigate adverse impacts of projects filed, or which may be filed in the future, with the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to <ref>section 44718 of title 49</ref>, on military operations and readiness, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> investment priorities of the Department of Defense with respect to research and development;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> modifications to military operations to accommodate applications for such projects;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> recommended upgrades or modifications to existing systems or procedures by the Department of Defense;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> acquisition of new systems by the Department and other departments and agencies of the Federal Government and timelines for fielding such new systems; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> modifications to the projects for which such applications are filed with the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to <ref>section 44718 of title 49</ref>, including changes in size, location, or technology.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The governor of a State may recommend to the Secretary of Defense additional geographical areas of concern within that State. Any such recommendation shall be submitted for notice and comment pursuant to paragraph (2)(C).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Clearinghouse shall make access to data reflecting geographic areas identified under subparagraph (B) of paragraph (2) and reviewed and modified under subparagraph (C) of such paragraph available online.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Department of Defense Finding of Unacceptable Risk</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may not object to an energy project or antenna structure project filed with the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to <ref>section 44718 of title 49</ref>, except in a case in which the Secretary of Defense determines, after giving full consideration to mitigation actions identified pursuant to this section, that such project, in isolation or cumulatively with other projects, would result in an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In the case of any energy project or antenna structure project with proposed structures more than 200 feet above ground level located within two nautical miles of the geographic center of an active intercontinental ballistic missile launch facility or control center, the Secretary of Defense shall issue a finding of unacceptable risk to national security for such project if the mitigation actions identified pursuant to this section do not include removal of all such proposed structures from such project after receiving notice of presumed risk from the Clearinghouse under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Clause (i) does not apply to structures approved before the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 or to structures that are re-powered with updated technology in the same location as previously approved structures.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any finding of unacceptable risk to national security by the Secretary of Defense under this paragraph shall be transmitted to the Secretary of Transportation for inclusion in the report required under <ref>section 44718(b)(2) of title 49</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after making a finding of unacceptable risk under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on such finding and the basis for such finding. Such report shall include an explanation of the operational impact that led to the finding, a discussion of the mitigation options considered, and an explanation of why the mitigation options were not feasible or did not resolve the conflict. The report may include a classified annex. Unclassified reports shall also be provided to the project proponent. The Secretary of Defense may provide public notice through the Federal Register of the finding.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall notify the appropriate State agency of a finding made under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may only delegate the responsibility for making a finding of unacceptable risk under paragraph (1) to the Deputy Secretary of Defense, an Under Secretary of Defense, or a Deputy Under Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Clearinghouse shall develop procedures for making a finding of unacceptable risk, including with respect to how to implement cumulative effects analysis. Such procedures shall be subject to public comment prior to finalization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Accept Contributions of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense is authorized to request and accept a voluntary contribution of funds from an applicant for an energy project or antenna structure project. Amounts so accepted shall remain available until expended for the purpose of offsetting the cost of measures undertaken by the Secretary of Defense to mitigate adverse impacts of such a project on military operations and readiness or to conduct studies of potential measures to mitigate such impacts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Department of Defense Hazard Assessment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An action taken pursuant to this section shall not be considered to be a substitute for any assessment or determination required of the Secretary of Transportation under <ref>section 44718 of title 49</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “adverse impact on military operations and readiness” means any adverse impact upon military operations and readiness, including flight operations, research, development, testing, and evaluation, and training, that is demonstrable and is likely to impair or degrade the ability of the armed forces to perform their warfighting missions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “antenna structure project”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means a project to construct a structure located within two nautical miles of the geographic center of any intercontinental ballistic missile launch facility or control center that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is constructed or used to transmit radio energy or that is constructed or used for the primary purpose of supporting antennas to transmit or receive radio energy (or both), and any antennas and other appurtenances mounted on the structure, from the time construction of the supporting structure begins until such time as the supporting structure is dismantled; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for which notification is required to be made to the Federal Aviation Administration pursuant to processes already established by law; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any structure constructed before the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024, including any such structure which is upgraded, repaired, or otherwise modified after such date of enactment as long as such upgrade, repair, or modification has not increased the height of such structure; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any project in support of or required by an intercontinental ballistic missile launch facility or control center, or any other such project that has been approved by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Defense’s designee for use on the same military installation at which such facility or control center is located.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “intercontinental ballistic missile launch facility or control center” means such facilities or control centers located at the Francis E. Warren Air Force Base; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002012">1</ref> the Malmstrom Air Force Base, and the Minot Air Force Base, and their respective missile fields.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “energy project” means a project that provides for the generation or transmission of electrical energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “governor”, with respect to a State, means the chief executive officer of the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “landowner” means a person that owns a fee interest in real property on which a proposed energy project or antenna structure project is planned to be located.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “military installation” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2801(c)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “military readiness” includes any training or operation that could be related to combat readiness, including testing and evaluation activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “military training route” means a training route developed as part of the Military Training Route Program, carried out jointly by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Secretary of Defense, for use by the armed forces for the purpose of conducting low-altitude, high-speed military training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The term “State” means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, and American Samoa.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> The term “unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States” means the construction, alteration, establishment, or expansion, or the proposed construction, alteration, establishment, or expansion, of a structure or sanitary landfill, that the Secretary of Defense can demonstrate would—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> endanger safety in air commerce directly related to the activities of the Department of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> interfere with the efficient use of the navigable airspace directly related to the activities of the Department of Defense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> significantly impair or degrade the capability of the Department of Defense to conduct training, research, development, testing, and evaluation, and operations or to maintain military readiness.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title III, § 311(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1343</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 311, 312, 371, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1303</ref>, 1329; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3513</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 371(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1663</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 361, 362, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 231</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 184.</num>
<heading> Civilian Protection Center of Excellence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall operate the Civilian Protection Center of Excellence. The purpose of the Center shall be to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve as the focal point for matters related to civilian casualties and other forms of civilian harm resulting from military operations involving the United States Armed Forces; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> institutionalize and advance knowledge, practices, and tools for preventing, mitigating, and responding to civilian harm.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Center shall be used to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop standardized civilian-harm operational reporting and data management processes to improve data collection, sharing, and learning across the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop, recommend, and review guidance, and the implementation of guidance, on how the Department responds to civilian harm;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop recommended guidance for addressing civilian harm across the full spectrum of armed conflict and for use in doctrine and operational plans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> recommend training and exercises for the prevention and investigation of civilian harm;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> develop a repository of civilian casualty and civilian harm information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> capture lessons learned from assessments and investigations of civilian casualty incidents and supporting institutionalization of such lessons learned within policy, doctrine, training, exercises, and tactics, techniques, and procedures of the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> support the coordination and synchronization of efforts across combatant commands, the Department of State, and other relevant United States Government departments and agencies to prevent, mitigate, and respond to incidents of civilian harm;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> engage with nongovernmental organizations and civilian casualty experts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> perform such other functions as the Secretary of Defense may specify.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees, and make publicly available on an appropriate website of the Department, an annual report on the activities of the Center.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title X, § 1082(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2799</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 185.</num>
<heading> Joint Safety Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established, within the Office of the Deputy Secretary of Defense, a Joint Safety Council (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership; Appointment; Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Council shall be composed of voting members as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Director of Safety for each military department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An employee of the Department of Defense who is a career member of the Senior Executive Service and has a demonstrated record of success in the implementation of programs within the Department of Defense (as determined by the Deputy Secretary of Defense), appointed by the Deputy Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> One member of the armed forces or civilian employee from each military department, appointed by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> During periods in which the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Department of the Navy, an officer of the Coast Guard, appointed by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Such additional members as may be determined by the Deputy Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Each member of the Council shall serve at the will of the official who appointed that member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any vacancy on the Council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Members of the Council may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairperson and Vice Chairperson</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, or the designee of the Secretary, shall select one of the members of the Council who is a member of the armed forces to serve as the Chairperson of the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Chairperson shall serve for a term of two years and shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> serving as the Director of Safety for the Department of Defense;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> serving as principal advisor to the Secretary of Defense regarding military safety and related regulations and policy reforms, including issues regarding maintenance, supply chains, personnel management, and training;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> overseeing all duties and activities of the Council, including the conduct of military safety studies and the issuance of safety guidance to the military departments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> working with, and advising, the Secretaries of the military departments through appointed safety chiefs to implement standardized safety guidance across the military departments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> submitting to the Secretary of Defense and Congress an annual report reviewing the compliance of each military department with the guidance described in clause (iv);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> advising Congress on issues relating to military safety and reforms; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> overseeing coordination with other Federal agencies, including the Federal Aviation Administration, to inform military aviation safety guidance and reforms.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The individual appointed under subsection (b)(1)(B) shall serve as the Vice Chairperson. The Vice Chairperson shall report to the Chairperson and shall serve as Chairperson in the absence of the Chairperson.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall carry out the following responsibilities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (e), issuing, publishing, and updating regulations related to joint safety, including regulations on the reporting and investigation of mishaps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to mishap data—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establishing uniform data collection standards and a repository, that is accessible Department-wide, of data for mishaps in the Department of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reviewing the compliance of each military department in adopting and using the uniform data collection standards established under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> reviewing mishap data to assess, identify, and prioritize risk mitigation efforts and safety improvement efforts across the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to non-mishap data—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establishing standards and requirements for the collection of aircraft, equipment, simulator, airfield, range, pilot, and operator data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establishing standards and requirements for the collection of ground vehicle equipment and crew data; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> establishing requirements for each military department to collect and analyze any waivers issued relating to pilot or operator qualifications or standards.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Reviewing and assessing civil and commercial aviation safety programs and practices to determine the suitability of such programs and practices for implementation in the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Establishing, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, a requirement for each military department to implement an aviation safety management system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Establishing, in consultation with the heads of appropriate Federal departments and agencies, a requirement for each military department to implement a separate safety management program for ground vehicles and ships.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> Ensuring each military department has in place, for the safety management system and program described in paragraphs (5) and (6), respectively, of that military department—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a resolution plan that identifies specific corrective and preventative actions to address the causes of mishaps; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an implementation plan for such system and program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Reviewing the proposal of each military department for the safety management system and program described in paragraphs (5) and (6), respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Reviewing the implementation of such systems by each military department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Ensuring each military department has in place a system to monitor the implementation of recommendations made in safety and legal investigation reports of mishap incidents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Not later than one year after the initial identification of corrective and preventative actions by a military department pursuant to a resolution plan under paragraph (7)(A), and periodically thereafter, reviewing and validating each such identified corrective and preventative action to ensure the action is effective.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Ensuring any related change in methods, tactics, or procedures necessary for the conduct of such identified corrective and preventative actions have been implemented.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Oversight</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The decisions and recommendations of the Council are subject to review and approval by the Deputy Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Staff</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Council may appoint staff in accordance with <ref>section 3101 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Council may accept persons on detail from within the Department of Defense and from other Federal departments or agencies on a reimbursable or non-reimbursable basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contract Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council may enter into contracts for the acquisition of administrative supplies, equipment, and personnel services for use by the Council, to the extent that funds are available for such purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procurement of Temporary and Intermittent Services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chairperson may procure temporary and intermittent services under <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref> at rates for individuals which do not exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Data Collection</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under regulations issued by the Secretary of Defense, the Council shall have access to Department of Defense databases necessary to carry out its responsibilities, including causal factors to be used for mishap reduction purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Under regulations issued by the Secretary of Defense, the Council may enter into agreements with the Federal Aviation Administration, the National Transportation Safety Board, and any other Federal agency regarding the sharing of safety data.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Data collected by the Council pursuant to this subsection may include privileged safety information that is protected from disclosure or discovery to any person.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall meet quarterly and at the call of the Chairperson.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chairperson of the Council shall submit to the congressional defense committees biannual reports on the activities of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than December 31 of each year, the Deputy Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees an annual report containing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a summary of the goals and priorities of the Deputy Secretary for the year following the date of the submission of the report with respect to the activities of the Council;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment by the Deputy Secretary of the activities of the Council carried out during the year preceding the date of such submission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> for the year covered by the report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> releasable information regarding any mishap that occurred during such year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an identification of any corrective or preventative action implemented pursuant to a recommendation made in a safety or legal investigation report of such a mishap.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Biannual Briefings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than March 31 and December 31 of each year, the Chairperson of the Council shall provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on the contents of the report required to be submitted under subsection (k)(1) that covers the six-month period preceding the date of the briefing.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 372(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1664</ref>, § 184; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 381, 383, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2542</ref>, 2544; renumbered § 185 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 363</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title III, § 331</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1854</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 186.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title IX, § 901(c)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3463</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 187.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XIV, § 1411(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2869</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 188.</num>
<heading> Interagency Council on the Strategic Capability of the National Laboratories</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is an Interagency Council on the Strategic Capability of the National Laboratories (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The membership of the Council is comprised of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Homeland Security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Administrator for Nuclear Security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Such other officials as the President considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Structure and Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may determine the chair, structure, staff, and procedures of the Council.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall be responsible for the following matters:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Identifying and considering the science, technology, and engineering capabilities of the national laboratories that could be leveraged by each participating agency to support national security missions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Reviewing and assessing the adequacy of the national security science, technology, and engineering capabilities of the national laboratories for supporting national security missions throughout the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Establishing and overseeing means of ensuring that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> capabilities identified by the Council under paragraph (1) are sustained to an appropriate level; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> each participating agency provides the appropriate level of institutional support to sustain such capabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In accordance with acquisition rules regarding federally funded research and development centers, establishing criteria for when each participating agency should seek to use the services of the national laboratories, including the identification of appropriate mission areas and capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Making recommendations to the President and Congress regarding regulatory or statutory changes needed to better support—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the strategic capabilities of the national laboratories; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use of such laboratories by each participating agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Other actions the Council considers appropriate with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the sustainment of the national laboratories; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use of the strategic capabilities of such laboratories.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Streamlined Process</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With respect to the participating agency for which a member of the Council is the head of, each member of the Council shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish processes to streamline the consideration and approval of procuring the services of the national laboratories on appropriate matters; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that such processes are used in accordance with the criteria established under subsection (d)(4).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “participating agency” means a department or agency of the Federal Government that is represented on the Council by a member under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “national laboratories” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each national security laboratory (as defined in section 3281(1) of the National Nuclear Security Administration Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 2471(1)</ref>)); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> each national laboratory of the Department of Energy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1040(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1928</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 189.</num>
<heading> Communications Security Review and Advisory Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be in the Department of Defense a Communications Security Review and Advisory Board (in this section referred to as the “Board”) to review and assess the communications security, cryptographic modernization, and related key management activities of the Department and provide advice to the Secretary with respect to such activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall determine the number of members of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense shall serve as chairman of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall appoint officers in the grade of general or admiral and civilian employees of the Department of Defense in the Senior Executive Service to serve as members of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> monitor the overall communications security, cryptographic modernization, and key management efforts of the Department, including activities under major defense acquisition programs (as defined in <ref>section 4201 of this title</ref>), by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> requiring each Chief Information Officer of each military department to report the communications security activities of the military department to the Board;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> tracking compliance of each military department with respect to communications security modernization efforts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> validating lifecycle communications security modernization plans for major defense acquisition programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> validate the need to replace cryptographic equipment based on the expiration dates of the equipment and evaluate the risks of continuing to use cryptographic equipment after such expiration dates;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> convene in-depth program reviews for specific cryptographic modernization developments with respect to validating requirements and identifying programmatic risks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop a long-term roadmap for communications security to identify potential issues and ensure synchronization with major planning documents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> advise the Secretary on the cryptographic posture of the Department, including budgetary recommendations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of Certain Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Board shall not include the consideration of programs funded under the National Intelligence Program (as defined in section 3(6) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003(6)</ref>)) in carrying out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title II, § 261(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 724</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(f)(4)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3510</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1846(i)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4252</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 190.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 810(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1487</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>