<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 159—</num>
<heading>REAL PROPERTY; RELATED PERSONAL PROPERTY; AND LEASE OF NON-EXCESS PROPERTY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2661.</num>
<heading> Miscellaneous administrative provisions relating to real property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Operation and Maintenance Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Appropriations for operation and maintenance of the active forces shall be available for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The repair of facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The installation of equipment in public and private plants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leasing and Road Maintenance Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of each military department may provide for the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The leasing of buildings and facilities (including the payment of rentals for special purpose space at the seat of Government). Rental for such leases may be paid in advance in connection with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the conduct of field exercises and maneuvers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the administration of the Act of <date date="1942-07-09">July 9, 1942</date> (<ref>43 U.S.C. 315q</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The maintenance of defense access roads which are certified to the Secretary of Transportation as important to the national defense under the provisions of <ref>section 210 of title 23</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Naming Department of Defense Real Property After Member of Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Real property under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may not be named after, or otherwise officially identified by the name of, any individual who is a Member of Congress at the time the property is so named or identified.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “Member of Congress” includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “real property” includes structures, buildings, or other infrastructure of a military installation, roadways and defense access roads, and any other area on the grounds of a military installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Pentagon Reservation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this chapter, the terms “Secretary concerned” and “Secretary of a military department” include the Secretary of Defense with respect to the Pentagon Reservation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–370, § 1</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3), <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 849</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821(a)(1)</ref>, (e)(1), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2129</ref>, 2130; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821(d)</ref>, (e), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2863(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1701</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2661a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(31)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1296</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2662.</num>
<heading> Real property transactions: reports to congressional committees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Notice and Wait Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of a military department or, with respect to a Defense Agency, the Secretary of Defense may not enter into any of the following listed transactions by or for the use of that department until the Secretary concerned submits a report, subject to paragraph (3), to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An acquisition of fee title to any real property, if the estimated price is more than $750,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A lease of any real property to the United States, if the estimated annual rental is more than $750,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A lease, license, or easement of real property owned by the United States (other than a lease or license entered into under <ref>section 2667(g) of this title</ref>), if the estimated annual fair market rental value of the property is more than $750,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A transfer of real property owned by the United States to another Federal agency or another military department or to a State, if the estimated value is more than $750,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A report of excess real property owned by the United States to a disposal agency, if the estimated value is more than $750,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Any termination or modification by either the grantor or grantee of an existing license or permit of real property owned by the United States to a military department, under which substantial investments have been or are proposed to be made in connection with the use of the property by the military department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Any transaction or contract action that results in, or includes, the acquisition or use by, or the lease or license to, the United States of real property, if the estimated annual rental or cost for the use of the real property is more than $750,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Any transaction or contract action for the provision and operation of energy production facilities on real property under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of a military department, as authorized by <ref>section 2922a(a)(2) of this title</ref>, if the term of the transaction or contract exceeds 20 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a transaction covered by subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) is part of a project, the report shall include a summary of the general plan for that project, including an estimate of the total cost of the lands to be acquired or leases to be made, as well as the certification described in paragraph (5). The report required by this subsection concerning any report of excess real property described in subparagraph (E) of paragraph (1) shall contain a certification by the Secretary concerned that he has considered the feasibility of exchanging such property for other real property authorized to be acquired for military purposes and has determined that the property proposed to be declared excess is not suitable for such purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary concerned to enter into a transaction described in paragraph (1) commences only after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the first day of the first month beginning on or after the date on which the report containing the facts concerning such transaction, and all other such proposed transactions for that month, is provided in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The report for a month under this subsection may not be submitted later than the first day of that month.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (2), the certification described in this paragraph with respect to an acquisition or lease of real property is a certification that the Secretary concerned—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> evaluated the feasibility of using space in property under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense to satisfy the purposes of the acquisition or lease; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> determined that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> space in property under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense is not reasonably available to be used to satisfy the purposes of the acquisition or lease;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> acquiring the property or entering into the lease would be more cost-effective than the use of the Department of Defense property; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the use of the Department of Defense property would interfere with the ongoing military mission of the property.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Reporting Requirements Regarding Leases of Real Property Owned by the United States</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of a proposed lease, license, or easement of real property owned by the United States covered by paragraph (1)(C) of subsection (a), the Secretary concerned shall comply with the notice-and-wait requirements of paragraph (3) of such subsection before—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> issuing a contract solicitation or other lease offering with regard to the transaction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing public notice regarding any meeting to discuss a proposed contract solicitation with regard to the transaction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The report under paragraph (3) of subsection (a) shall include the following with regard to a proposed transaction covered by paragraph (1)(C) of such subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of the proposed transaction, including the proposed duration of the lease, license, or easement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the authorities to be used in entering into the transaction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A statement of the scored cost of the entire transaction, determined using the scoring criteria of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A determination that the property involved in the transaction is not excess property, as required by <ref>section 2667(a)(3) of this title</ref>, including the basis for the determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A determination that the proposed transaction is directly compatible with the mission of the military installation or Defense Agency at which the property is located and a description of the anticipated long-term use of the property at the conclusion of the lease or license.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A description of the requirements or conditions within the contract solicitation or other lease offering for the person making the offer to address taxation issues, including payments-in-lieu-of taxes, and other development issues related to local municipalities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> If the proposed lease involves a project related to energy production, a certification by the Secretary of Defense that the project, as it will be specified in the contract solicitation or other lease offering, is consistent with the Department of Defense performance goals and plan required by <ref>section 2911 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned may not enter into the actual lease or license with respect to property for which the information required by paragraph (2) was submitted in a report under subsection (a)(3) unless the Secretary again complies with the notice-and-wait requirements of such subsection. The subsequent report shall include the following with regard to the proposed transaction:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A cross reference to the prior report that contained the information submitted under paragraph (2) with respect to the transaction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the differences between the information submitted under paragraph (2) and the information regarding the transaction being submitted in the subsequent report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A description of the payment to be required in connection with the lease, license, or easement, including a description of any in-kind consideration that will be accepted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A description of any community support facility or provision of community support services under the lease, license, or easement, regardless of whether the facility will be operated by a covered entity (as defined in <ref>section 2667(d) of this title</ref>) or the lessee or the services will be provided by a covered entity or the lessee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A description of the competitive procedures used to select the lessee or, in the case of a lease involving the public benefit exception authorized by <ref>section 2667(h)(2) of this title</ref>, a description of the public benefit to be served by the lease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Excepted Projects</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply to real property for water resource development projects of the Corps of Engineers, or to leases of Government-owned real property for agricultural or grazing purposes or to any real property acquisition specifically authorized in a Military Construction Authorization Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statements of Compliance in Transaction Instruments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A statement in an instrument of conveyance, including a lease, that the requirements of this section have been met, or that the conveyance is not subject to this section, is conclusive.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports on Transactions Involving Intelligence Components</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever a transaction covered by this section is made by or on behalf of an intelligence component of the Department of Defense or involves real property used by such a component, any report under this section with respect to the transaction that is submitted to the congressional committees named in subsection (a) shall be submitted concurrently to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions for Transactions for War and Certain Emergency and Other Operations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The reporting requirement set forth in subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to a real property transaction otherwise covered by that subsection if the Secretary concerned determines that the transaction is made as a result of any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A declaration of war.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A declaration of a national emergency by the President pursuant to the National Emergencies Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A declaration of an emergency or major disaster pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The use of the militia or the armed forces after a proclamation to disperse under <ref>section 254 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The reporting requirement set forth in subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to a real property transaction otherwise covered by that subsection if the Secretary concerned determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an event listed in paragraph (1) is imminent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the transaction is necessary for purposes of preparation for such event.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after entering into a real property transaction covered by paragraph (1) or (2), the Secretary concerned shall submit to the committees named in subsection (a) a report on the transaction. The report shall set forth any facts or information which would otherwise have been submitted in a report on the transaction under subsection (a), but for the operation of paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary Concerned Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Secretary concerned” includes, with respect to Defense Agencies, the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–70, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 142</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–500, title V, § 511(1)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-08">June 8, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 186</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–624, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 411</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–145, title VII, § 707(5)</ref>, <date date="1971-10-27">Oct. 27, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–545, title VII, § 709</ref>, <date date="1972-10-25">Oct. 25, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–552, title VI, § 610</ref>, <date date="1974-12-27">Dec. 27, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–107, title VI, § 607(5)</ref>, (6), <date date="1975-10-07">Oct. 7, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–431, title VI, § 614</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–418, title VIII, § 805</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2803</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1311(6)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1670</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–496, title IV, § 403(a)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3185</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(23)</ref>, div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(b)(21), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 505</ref>, 673; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2204</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–416; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(27)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(22)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2062</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(a)</ref>–(f), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4461</ref>, 4462; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1686</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2152</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(45)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, §§ 2811(a), 2812, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1596</ref>, 1848, 1849.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2663.</num>
<heading> Land acquisition authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition of Land by Condemnation for Certain Military Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to subsection (f), the Secretary of a military department may have proceedings brought in the name of the United States, in a court of proper jurisdiction, to acquire by condemnation any interest in land, including temporary use, needed for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the site, construction, or operation of fortifications, coast defenses, or military training camps;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the construction and operation of plants for the production of nitrate and other compounds, and the manufacture of explosives or other munitions of war; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the development and transmission of power for the operation of plants under subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In time of war or when war is imminent, the United States may, immediately upon the filing of a petition for condemnation under paragraph (1), take and use the land to the extent of the interest sought to be acquired.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition by Purchase in Lieu of Condemnation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the military department concerned may contract for or buy any interest in land, including temporary use, needed for any purpose named in subsection (a), as soon as the owner fixes a price for it and the Secretary considers that price to be reasonable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition of Low-Cost Interests in Land</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of a military department may acquire any interest in land that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines is needed in the interest of national defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not cost more than $4,000,000, exclusive of administrative costs and the amounts of any deficiency judgments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of a military department may acquire any interest in land that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines is needed solely to correct a deficiency that is life-threatening, health-threatening, or safety-threatening; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not cost more than $1,500,000, exclusive of administrative costs and the amounts of any deficiency judgments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This subsection does not apply to the acquisition, as a part of the same project, of more than one parcel of land unless the parcels are noncontiguous, or, if contiguous, unless the total cost is not more than $750,000, in the case of an acquisition under paragraph (1), or $1,500,000, in the case of an acquisition under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Appropriations available to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance or construction may be used for the acquisition of land or interests in land under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition of Interests in Land When Need Is Urgent</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of a military department may acquire any interest in land in any case in which the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the acquisition is needed in the interest of national defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the acquisition is required to maintain the operational integrity of a military installation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> considerations of urgency do not permit the delay necessary to include the required acquisition in an annual Military Construction Authorization Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than 10 days after the date on which the Secretary of a military department determines to acquire an interest in land under the authority of this subsection, the Secretary shall submit, in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>, to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a notice containing a description of the property and interest to be acquired and the reasons for the acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Appropriations available for military construction may be used for the purposes of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Survey Authority; Acquisition Methods</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Authority provided the Secretary of a military department by law to acquire an interest in real property (including a temporary interest) includes authority—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to make surveys; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to acquire the interest in real property by gift, purchase, exchange of real property owned by the United States, or otherwise.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advance Notice of Use of Condemnation</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Before commencing any legal proceeding to acquire any interest in land under subsection (a), including acquisition for temporary use, by condemnation, eminent domain, or seizure, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pursue, to the maximum extent practicable, all other available options for the acquisition or use of the land, such as the purchase of an easement or the execution of a land exchange; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> submit to the congressional defense committees a report containing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of the land to be acquired;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a certification that negotiations with the owner or owners of the land occurred, and that the Secretary tendered consideration in an amount equal to the fair market value of the land, as determined by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an explanation of the other approaches considered for acquiring use of the land, the reasons for the acquisition of the land, and the reasons why alternative acquisition strategies are inadequate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may have proceedings brought in the name of the United States to acquire the land after the end of the 21-day period beginning on the date on which the report is received by the committees in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception to Advance Notice Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of a military department determines that the use of condemnation, eminent domain, or seizure to acquire an interest in land is required under subsection (a) to satisfy a requirement vital to national security, and that any delay would be detrimental to national security or the protection of health, safety, or the environment, the Secretary may have proceedings brought in the name of the United States to acquire the land in advance of submitting the report required by subsection (f)(1)(B). However, the Secretary shall submit the report not later than seven days after commencement of the legal proceedings with respect to the land.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Land Acquisition Options in Advance of Military Construction Projects</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department may acquire an option on a parcel of real property before or after its acquisition is authorized by law, if the Secretary considers it suitable and likely to be needed for a military project of the military department under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> As consideration for an option acquired under paragraph (1), the Secretary may pay, from funds available to the military department under the jurisdiction of the Secretary for real property activities, an amount that is not more than 12 percent of the appraised fair market value of the property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 33(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1565</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2822(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 544</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(g)(6)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1848</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2804(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2664.</num>
<heading> Limitations on real property acquisition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization for Acquisition Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No military department may acquire real property not owned by the United States unless the acquisition is expressly authorized by law. The foregoing limitation shall not apply to the acceptance by a military department of real property acquired under the authority of the Administrator of General Services to acquire property by the exchange of Government property pursuant to subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commissions on Land Purchase Contracts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The maximum amount payable as a commission on a contract for the purchase of land from funds appropriated for the Department of Defense is two percent of the purchase price.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cost Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the cost authorized for a land acquisition project may be increased by not more than 25 percent of the amount appropriated for the project by Congress or 200 percent of the amount specified by law as the maximum amount for a minor military construction project, whichever is lesser, if the Secretary concerned determines (A) that such an increase is required for the sole purpose of meeting unusual variations in cost, and (B) that such variations in cost could not have been reasonably anticipated at the time the project was originally approved by Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Until subsection (d) is complied with, a land acquisition project may not be placed under contract if, based upon the agreed price for the land or, in the case of land to be acquired by condemnation, the amount to be deposited with the court as just compensation for the land—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the scope of the acquisition, as approved by Congress, is proposed to be reduced by more than 25 percent; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the agreed price for the land or, in the case of land to be acquired by condemnation, the amount to be deposited with the court as just compensation for the land, exceeds the amount appropriated for the project by more than (i) 25 percent, or (ii) 200 percent of the amount specified by law as the maximum amount for a minor military construction project, whichever is lesser.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The limitations on reduction in scope or increase in cost of a land acquisition in subsection (c) do not apply if the reduction in scope or the increase in cost, as the case may be, is approved by the Secretary concerned and a notification of the facts relating to the proposed reduced scope or increased cost (including a statement of the reasons therefor) is submitted by the Secretary concerned to the congressional defense committees. A contract for the acquisition may then be awarded only after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date the notification is received by the committees in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of Judgements and Settlements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned shall promptly pay any deficiency judgment against the United States awarded by a court in an action for condemnation of any interest in land or resulting from a final settlement of an action for condemnation of any interest in land. Payments under this subsection may be made from funds available to the Secretary concerned for military construction projects and without regard to the limitations of subsections (c) and (d).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(51)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1460</ref>, § 2676; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–166, title VI, § 608(2)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-29">Nov. 29, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 682</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–214, § 5</ref>, <date date="1982-07-12">July 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–407, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="1984-08-28">Aug. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1519</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIII, § 1343(a)(17)(A)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3993</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2870(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1562</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(14)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1062(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2650</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(30)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1600</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2061</ref>; renumbered § 2664 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821(a)(10)</ref>, (b)–(d), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(45)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3846</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(d)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1848</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2665.</num>
<heading> Sale of certain interests in land; logs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President, through an executive department, may sell to any person or foreign government any interest in land that is acquired for the production of lumber or timber products, except land under the control of the Department of the Army or the Department of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The President, through an executive department, may sell to any person or foreign government any forest products produced on land owned or leased by a military department or the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Sales under subsection (a) or (b) shall be at prices determined by the President acting through the selling agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Appropriations of the Department of Defense may be reimbursed for all costs of production of forest products pursuant to this section from amounts received as proceeds from the sale of any such property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each State in which is located a military installation or facility from which forest products are sold in a fiscal year is entitled at the end of such year to an amount equal to 40 percent of (A) the amount received by the United States during such year as proceeds from the sale of forest products produced on such installation or facility, less (B) the amount of reimbursement of appropriations of the Department of Defense under subsection (d) during such year attributable to such installation or facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The amount paid to a State pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be expended as the State legislature may prescribe for the benefit of the public schools and public roads of the county or counties in which the military installation or facility is situated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In a case in which a military installation or facility is located in more than one State or county, the amount paid pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be distributed in a manner proportional to the area of such installation or facility in each State or county.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> There is in the Treasury a reserve account administered by the Secretary of Defense for the purposes of this section. Balances in the account may be used for costs of the military departments—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for improvements of forest lands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for unanticipated contingencies in the administration of forest lands and the production of forest products for which other sources of funds are not available in a timely manner; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for natural resources management that implements approved plans and agreements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> There shall be deposited into the reserve account the total amount received by the United States as proceeds from the sale of forest products sold under subsections (a) and (b) less—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reimbursements of appropriations made under subsection (d), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> payments made to States under subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The reserve account may not exceed $4,000,000 on December 31 of any calendar year. Unobligated balances exceeding $4,000,000 on that date shall be deposited into the United States Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 149</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–82, title VI, § 610</ref>, <date date="1977-08-01">Aug. 1, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 378</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(91)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2928</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–31, § 12(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-06">Aug. 6, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–99, title IX, § 910(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-23">Dec. 23, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1386</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(33)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–407, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-08-28">Aug. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1522</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–561, § 4</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1056(c)(6)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2666.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2129</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2667.</num>
<heading> Leases: non-excess property of military departments and Defense Agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lease Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whenever the Secretary concerned considers it advantageous to the United States, the Secretary concerned may lease to such lessee and upon such terms as the Secretary concerned considers will promote the national defense or to be in the public interest, real or personal property that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is under the control of the Secretary concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is not for the time needed for public use; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is not excess property, as defined by <ref>section 102 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions on Leases</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A lease under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may not be for more than five years, unless the Secretary concerned determines that a lease for a longer period will promote the national defense or be in the public interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may give the lessee the first right to buy the property if the lease is revoked to allow the United States to sell the property under any other provision of law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall permit the Secretary to revoke the lease at any time, unless he determines that the omission of such a provision will promote the national defense or be in the public interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall provide for the payment (in cash or in kind) by the lessee of consideration in an amount that is not less than the fair market value of the lease interest, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> may provide, notwithstanding <ref>section 1302 of title 40</ref> or any other provision of law, for the alteration, repair, or improvement, by the lessee, of the property leased as the payment of part or all of the consideration for the lease;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> except as otherwise provided in subsection (d), shall require the lessee to provide the covered entities specified in paragraph (1) of that subsection the right to establish and operate a community support facility or provide community support services, or seek equitable compensation for morale, welfare, and recreation programs of the Department of Defense in lieu of the operation of such a facility or the provision of such services, if the Secretary determines that the lessee will provide merchandise or services in direct competition with covered entities through the lease;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> may not provide for a leaseback by the Secretary concerned with an annual payment in excess of $500,000, or otherwise commit the Secretary concerned or the Department of Defense to annual payments in excess of such amount; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> shall provide that any facilities constructed on the property may be constructed using commercial standards in a manner that provides force protection safeguards appropriate to the activities conducted in, and the location of, such facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Types of In-Kind Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to any in-kind consideration accepted under subsection (b)(5), in-kind consideration accepted with respect to a lease under this section may include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Maintenance, protection, alteration, repair, improvement, or restoration (including environmental restoration) of property or facilities under the control of the Secretary concerned, whether or not needed for the functionality of the property or facility leased.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Construction of new facilities for the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Provision of facilities for use by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Provision or payment of utility services for the Secretary concerned, which shall prioritize energy resilience in the event of commercial grid outages.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Provision of real property maintenance services for the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Provision of such other services relating to activities that will occur on the leased property as the Secretary concerned considers appropriate, which may include industrial process optimization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Refurbishment of existing industrial plant equipment on the leased property.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Removal and replacement of industrial plant equipment on the leased property that is at or near end-of-life.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Provision of new industrial plant equipment on the leased property (including new technology), installation of such equipment, and maintenance of such equipment, but only if the title to such equipment passes to the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In-kind consideration under paragraph (1) may be accepted at any property or facilities under the control of the Secretary concerned that are selected for that purpose by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Sections 2662 and 2802 of this title shall not apply to any new facilities whose construction is accepted as in-kind consideration under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Community Support Facilities and Community Support Services Under Lease; Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection and subsection (b)(6), the term “covered entity” means each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Army and Air Force Exchange Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Navy Exchange Service Command.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Marine Corps exchanges.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Defense Commissary Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The revenue-generating nonappropriated fund activities of the Department of Defense conducted for the morale, welfare, and recreation of members of the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned may waive the requirement in subsection (b)(6) with respect to a lease if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the lease is entered into under subsection (g); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that the waiver is in the best interests of the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall submit, in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>, to the congressional defense committees a notice of each waiver under paragraph (2), including the reasons for the waiver.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The covered entities shall exercise the right provided in subsection (b)(6) with respect to a lease, if at all, not later than 90 days after receiving notice from the Secretary concerned regarding the opportunity to exercise such right with respect to the lease. The Secretary may, at the discretion of the Secretary, extend the period under this paragraph for the exercise of the right with respect to a lease for such additional period as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe in regulations uniform procedures and criteria for the evaluation of proposals for enhanced use leases involving the operation of community support facilities or the provision of community support services by either a lessee under this section or a covered entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deposit and Use of Proceeds</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall deposit in a special account in the Treasury established for that Secretary the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> All money rentals received pursuant to leases entered into by that Secretary under this section.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> All proceeds received pursuant to the granting of easements by that Secretary under <ref>section 2668 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> All proceeds received by that Secretary from authorizing the temporary use of other property under the control of that Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Subparagraph (A) does not apply to the following proceeds:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Amounts paid for utilities and services furnished lessees by the Secretary concerned pursuant to leases entered into under this section.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Money rentals referred to in paragraph (3), (4), or (5).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to subparagraphs (D) and (E), the proceeds deposited in the special account established for the Secretary concerned shall be available to the Secretary, in such amounts as provided in appropriation Acts, for the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Maintenance, protection, alteration, repair, improvement, or restoration (including environmental restoration) of property or facilities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Construction or acquisition of new facilities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Lease of facilities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Payment of utility services.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Real property maintenance services.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Administrative expenses incurred by the Secretary concerned under this section and for easements under <ref>section 2668 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> At least 50 percent of the proceeds deposited in the special account established for the Secretary concerned shall be available for activities described in subparagraph (C) only at the military installation or Defense Agency location where the proceeds were derived.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> If the proceeds deposited in the special account established for the Secretary concerned are derived from activities associated with a military museum, the proceeds shall be available for activities described in subparagraph (C) only at that museum.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Payments for utilities and services furnished lessees pursuant to leases entered into under this section shall be credited to the appropriation account or working capital fund from which the cost of furnishing the utilities and services was paid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Money rentals received by the United States directly from a lease under this section for agricultural or grazing purposes of lands under the control of the Secretary concerned (other than lands acquired by the United States for flood control or navigation purposes or any related purpose, including the development of hydroelectric power) may be retained and spent by the Secretary concerned in such amounts as the Secretary considers necessary to cover the administrative expenses of leasing for such purposes and to cover the financing of multiple-land use management programs at any installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Money rentals received by the United States from a lease under subsection (g) at a military installation approved for closure or realignment under a base closure law shall be deposited into the Department of Defense Base Closure Account established under section 2906(a) of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (part A of title XXIX of <ref>Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Lessee Interest in Property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The interest of a lessee of property leased under this section may be taxed by State or local governments. A lease under this section shall provide that, if and to the extent that the leased property is later made taxable by State or local governments under an Act of Congress, the lease shall be renegotiated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special Rules for Base Closure and Realignment Property</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41 (to the extent those provisions are inconsistent with this subsection) or subsection (a)(2) of this section, pending the final disposition of real property and personal property located at a military installation to be closed or realigned under a base closure law, the Secretary concerned may lease the property to any individual or entity under this subsection if the Secretary determines that such a lease would facilitate State or local economic adjustment efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding subsection (b)(4), the Secretary concerned may accept consideration in an amount that is less than the fair market value of the lease interest if the Secretary concerned determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a public interest will be served as a result of the lease; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the fair market value of the lease is (i) unobtainable, or (ii) not compatible with such public benefit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Before entering into any lease under this subsection, the Secretary shall consult with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency in order to determine whether the environmental condition of the property proposed for leasing is such that the lease of the property is advisable. The Secretary and the Administrator shall enter into a memorandum of understanding setting forth procedures for carrying out the determinations under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.), the scope of any environmental impact analysis necessary to support an interim lease of property under this subsection shall be limited to the environmental consequences of activities authorized under the proposed lease and the cumulative impacts of other past, present, and reasonably foreseeable future actions during the period of the proposed lease.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Interim leases entered into under this subsection shall be deemed not to prejudice the final disposal decision with respect to the property, even if final disposal of the property is delayed until completion of the term of the interim lease. An interim lease under this subsection shall not be entered into without prior consultation with the redevelopment authority concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall not apply to an interim lease under this subsection if authorized activities under the lease would—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> significantly affect the quality of the human environment; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> irreversibly alter the environment in a way that would preclude any reasonable disposal alternative of the property concerned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competitive Procedures for Selection of Certain Lessees; Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a proposed lease under subsection (a) involves only personal property, the lease term exceeds one year, or the fair market value of the lease interest exceeds $100,000, as determined by the Secretary concerned, the Secretary shall use competitive procedures to select the lessee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) does not apply if the Secretary concerned determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a public interest will be served as a result of the lease; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use of competitive procedures for the selection of certain lessees is unobtainable or not compatible with the public benefit served under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) does not apply to a renewal or extension of a lease by the Secretary of the Navy with a selected institution for operation of a ship within the University National Oceanographic Laboratory System if, under the lease, each of the following applies:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Use of the ship is restricted to federally supported research programs and to non-Federal uses under specific conditions with approval by the Secretary of the Navy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Because of the anticipated value to the Navy of the oceanographic research and training that will result from the ship’s operation, no monetary lease payments are required from the lessee under the initial lease or under any renewal or extension.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The lessee is required to maintain the ship in a good state of repair, readiness, and efficient operating condition, conform to all applicable regulatory requirements, and assume full responsibility for the safety of the ship, its crew, and scientific personnel aboard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) does not apply to a renewal, extension, or succeeding lease by the Secretary concerned with a financial institution selected in accordance with the Department of Defense Financial Management Regulation providing for the selection of financial institutions to operate on military installations if each of the following applies:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The on-base financial institution was selected before the date of the enactment of this paragraph or competitive procedures are used for the selection of any new financial institutions.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A current and binding operating agreement is in place between the installation commander and the selected on-base financial institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The renewal, extension, or succeeding lease shall terminate upon the termination of the operating agreement described in subparagraph (A)(ii) associated with that lease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “administrative expenses” means only those expenses related to assessing, negotiating, executing, and managing lease and easement transactions. The term does not include any Government personnel costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “community support facility” includes an ancillary supporting facility (as that term is defined in <ref>section 2871(1) of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “community support services” includes revenue-generating food, recreational, lodging support services, and resale operations and other retail facilities and services intended to support a community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “military installation” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 2687 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Secretary concerned” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of a military department, with respect to matters concerning that military department; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense, with respect to matters concerning the Defense Agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of Certain Lands</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply to oil, mineral, or phosphate lands.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leases for Education</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (b)(4), the Secretary concerned may accept consideration in an amount that is less than the fair market value of the lease, if the lease is to a local education agency or an elementary or secondary school (as those terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 7801</ref>)).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 150</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–107, title VI, § 607(7)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-07">Oct. 7, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–412, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1258</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(92)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2928</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(34)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–321, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2806</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1787</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2862</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1559</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2851</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. B, title XXIX, § 2906</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1920</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(1)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, §§ 2831(a), 2832, 2833, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 502</ref>, 558, 559; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 361(b)(2)</ref>, title X, § 1061(a)–(c)(1), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1701</ref>, 1891; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2208</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812(a)–(e)]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–416 to 1654A–418; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1013</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(12)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(18)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2645</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1043(b)(15)</ref>, (c)(3), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1611</ref>, 1612; <ref>Pub. L. 108–178, § 4(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-15">Dec. 15, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2641</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VI, § 662</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2831, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2263</ref>, 2480; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1063(c)(13)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2823, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 323</ref>, 544; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2812(a)–(d), (f)(1), 2831, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4725</ref>, 4726, 4728, 4732; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(26)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(44)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3846</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(41)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, §§ 2811(g)–2813(a), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4371</ref>, 4463; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVII, § 2712(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2145</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 1014</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2814</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(46)</ref>, (47), div. B, title XXVIII, §§ 2811(e), 2835, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1596</ref>, 1597, 1848, 1859; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2802(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2261</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2844</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2667a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–417, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4727</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2668.</num>
<heading> Easements for rights-of-way</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Types of Easements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the Secretary of a military department finds that it will not be against the public interest, the Secretary may grant, upon such terms as the Secretary considers advisable, easements for rights-of-way over, in, and upon public lands permanently withdrawn or reserved for the use of that department, and other lands under the Secretary’s control for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> railroad tracks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> gas, water, sewer, and oil pipe lines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> substations for electric power transmission lines and pumping stations for gas, water, sewer, and oil pipe lines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> canals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> ditches;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> flumes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> tunnels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> dams and reservoirs in connection with fish and wildlife programs, fish hatcheries, and other improvements relating to fish-culture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> roads and streets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> poles and lines for the transmission or distribution of electric power;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> poles and lines for the transmission or distribution of communications signals (including telephone and telegraph signals);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> structures and facilities for the transmission, reception, and relay of such signals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> any other purpose that the Secretary considers advisable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Size of Easement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No easement granted under this section may include more land than is necessary for the easement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the military department concerned may terminate all or part of any easement granted under this section for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> failure to comply with the terms of the grant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> nonuse for a two-year period; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> abandonment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to Department of the Interior</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Copies of instruments granting easements over public lands under this section shall be furnished to the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disposition of Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsections (c) and (e) of <ref>section 2667 of this title</ref> shall apply with respect to in-kind consideration and proceeds received by the Secretary of a military department in connection with an easement granted under this section in the same manner as such subsections apply to in-kind consideration and money rentals received pursuant to leases entered into by that Secretary under such section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 150</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(38)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2624</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2861</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2804</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812(f)(1)]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–418; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2822(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2474</ref>, 2475; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1063(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2668a.</num>
<heading> Easements: granting restrictive easements in connection with land conveyances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Include Restrictive Easement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In connection with the conveyance of real property by the Secretary concerned under any provision of law, the Secretary concerned may grant an easement to an entity specified in subsection (b) restricting future uses of the conveyed real property for a conservation purpose consistent with section 170(h)(4)(A)(iv) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 170(h)(4)(A)(iv)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Recipients</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An easement under subsection (a) may be granted only to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a State or local government; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a qualified organization, as that term is defined in section 170(h) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 170(h)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Use of Easement Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An easement under subsection (a) may not be granted unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the proposed recipient of the easement consents to the receipt of the easement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary concerned determines that the easement is in the public interest and the conservation purpose to be promoted by the easement cannot be effectively achieved through the application of State law by the State or a local government without the grant of restrictive easements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the jurisdiction that encompasses the property to be subject to the easement authorizes the grant of restrictive easements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Secretary can give or assign to a third party the responsibility for monitoring and enforcing easements granted under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Easements granted under this section shall be without consideration from the recipient.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acreage Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No easement granted under this section may include more land than is necessary for the easement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Terms and Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The grant of an easement under this section shall be subject to such additional terms and conditions as the Secretary concerned considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2823(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2475</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2669.</num>
<heading> Transfer of land and facilities to support contracts with federally funded research and development centers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lease of Land, Facilities, and Improvements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department may lease, for no consideration, land, facilities, infrastructure, and improvements to a covered FFRDC if the lease is to further the purposes of a contract between the Department of Defense and the covered FFRDC.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A lease entered into under paragraph (1) shall terminate on the earlier of the following dates:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The date that is 50 years after the date on which the Secretary enters into the lease.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The date of the termination or non-renewal of the contract between the Department of Defense and the covered FFRDC related to the lease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conveyance of Facilities and Improvements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department may convey, for no consideration, ownership of facilities and improvements located on land leased to a covered FFRDC to further the purposes of a contract between the Department of Defense and the covered FFRDC.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The ownership of any facilities and improvements conveyed by the Secretary of a military department or any improvements made to the leased land by the covered FFRDC under this subsection shall, as determined by the Secretary of a military department, revert or transfer to the United States upon the termination or non-renewal of the underlying land lease.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any facilities and improvements conveyed by the Secretary of a military department shall be demolished by the covered FFDRC as determined by such Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A lease entered into under this section may provide that any facilities constructed on the leased land may be constructed using commercial standards in a manner that provides force protection safeguards appropriate to the activities conducted in, and the location of, such facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of Certain Property Management Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The conveyance or lease of property or facilities, improvements, and infrastructure under this section shall not be subject to the following provisions of law:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2667 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>Section 1302 of title 40</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Section 501 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 11411</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Sections 2662 and 2802 of this title shall not apply to any improvements or facilities constructed by the covered FFRDC on land leased or conveyed to a covered FFRDC described in subsection (a) or (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competitive Procedures for Selection of Certain Lessees; Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a proposed lease under this section is with respect to a covered FFRDC, the use of competitive procedures for the selection of the lessee is not required and the provisions of chapter 33 of title 41, United States Code, or chapter 221 of title 10, United States Code, and the related provisions of the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall not apply.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered FFRDC Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “covered FFRDC” means a federally funded research and development center that is sponsored by, and has entered into a contract with, the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2831(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3002</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2670.</num>
<heading> Use of facilities by private organizations; use as polling places</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use by Red Cross</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under such conditions as he may prescribe, the Secretary of any military department may issue a revocable license to the American National Red Cross to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> erect and maintain, on any military installation under his jurisdiction, buildings for the storage of supplies; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use, for the storage of supplies, buildings erected by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Supplies stored in buildings erected or used under this subsection are available to aid the civilian population in a serious national disaster.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Certain Facilities as Polling Places</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding chapter 29 of title 18 (including sections 592 and 593 of such title) or any other provision of law, the Secretary of Defense or Secretary of a military department may not (except as provided in paragraph (3)) prohibit the designation or use of a qualifying facility under the jurisdiction of the Secretary as an official polling place for local, State, or Federal elections.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A Department of Defense facility is a qualifying facility for purposes of this subsection if as of <date date="2000-12-31">December 31, 2000</date>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the facility is designated as an official polling place by a State or local election official; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the facility has been used as such an official polling place since <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The limitation in paragraph (1) may be waived by the Secretary of Defense or Secretary of the military department concerned with respect to a particular Department of Defense facility if the Secretary of Defense or Secretary concerned determines that local security conditions require prohibition of the designation or use of that facility as an official polling place for any election.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Space and Equipment by Veterans Service Organizations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon certification to the Secretary concerned by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary concerned shall allow accredited, paid, full-time representatives of the organizations named in <ref>section 5902 of title 38</ref>, or of other organizations recognized by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, to function on military installations under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned that are on land and from which persons are discharged or released from active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The commanding officer of a military installation allowing representatives to function on the installation under paragraph (1) shall allow the representatives to use available space and equipment at the installation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This subsection does not authorize the violation of measures of military security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XVI, § 1607(a)</ref>–(b)(2), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1279</ref>, 1280; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821(c)(1)</ref>, (e)(2), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2129</ref>, 2130.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2671.</num>
<heading> Military reservations and facilities: hunting, fishing, and trapping</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Requirements for Hunting, Fishing, and Trapping</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall, with respect to each military installation or facility under the jurisdiction of any military department in a State—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require that all hunting, fishing, and trapping at that installation or facility be in accordance with the fish and game laws of the State in which it is located;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require that an appropriate license for hunting, fishing, or trapping on that installation or facility be obtained, except that with respect to members of the armed forces, such a license may be required only if the State authorizes the issuance of a license to a member on active duty for a period of more than thirty days at an installation or facility within that State, without regard to residence requirements, and upon terms otherwise not less favorable than the terms upon which such a license is issued to residents of that State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop, subject to safety requirements and military security, and in cooperation with the Governor (or his designee) of the State in which the installation or facility is located, procedures under which designated fish and game or conservation officials of that State may, at such time and under such conditions as may be agreed upon, have full access to that installation or facility to effect measures for the management, conservation, and harvesting of fish and game resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive or otherwise modify the fish and game laws of a State otherwise applicable under subsection (a)(1) to hunting, fishing, or trapping at a military installation or facility if the Secretary determines that the application of such laws to such hunting, fishing, or trapping without modification could result in undesirable consequences for public health or safety at the installation or facility. The authority to waive such laws includes the authority to extend, but not reduce, the specified season for certain hunting, fishing, or trapping. The Secretary may not waive the requirements under subsection (a)(2) regarding a license for such hunting, fishing, or trapping or any fee imposed by a State to obtain such a license.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the Secretary determines that a waiver of fish and game laws of a State is appropriate under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide written notification to the appropriate State officials stating the reasons for, and extent of, the waiver. The notification shall be provided at least 30 days before implementation of the waiver.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Violations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whoever is guilty of an act or omission which violates a requirement prescribed under subsection (a)(1) or (2), which act or omission would be punishable if committed or omitted within the jurisdiction of the State in which the installation or facility is located, by the laws thereof in effect at the time of that act or omission, is guilty of a like offense and is subject to a like punishment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relation to Treaty Rights</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not modify any rights granted by the treaty or otherwise to any Indian tribe or to the members thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–337, § 4(1)</ref>, <date date="1958-02-28">Feb. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 29</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(42)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4371</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2672.</num>
<heading> Protection of buildings, grounds, property, and persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary of Defense Responsibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall protect the buildings, grounds, and property that are under the jurisdiction, custody, or control of the Department of Defense and the persons on that property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Officers and Agents</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may designate military or civilian personnel of the Department of Defense as officers and agents to perform the functions of the Secretary under subsection (a), including, with regard to civilian officers and agents, duty in areas outside the property specified in that subsection to the extent necessary to protect that property and persons on that property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A designation under paragraph (1) may be made by individual, by position, by installation, or by such other category of personnel as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In making a designation under paragraph (1) with respect to any category of personnel, the Secretary shall specify each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The personnel or positions to be included in the category.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The authorities provided for in subsection (c) that may be exercised by personnel in that category.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of civilian personnel in that category—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the authorities provided for in subsection (c), if any, that are authorized to be exercised outside the property specified in subsection (a); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with respect to the exercise of any such authorities outside the property specified in subsection (a), the circumstances under which coordination with law enforcement officials outside of the Department of Defense should be sought in advance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may make a designation under paragraph (1) only if the Secretary determines, with respect to the category of personnel to be covered by that designation, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the exercise of each specific authority provided for in subsection (c) to be delegated to that category of personnel is necessary for the performance of the duties of the personnel in that category and such duties cannot be performed as effectively without such authorities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the necessary and proper training for the authorities to be exercised is available to the personnel in that category.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (i) and to the extent specifically authorized by the Secretary of Defense, while engaged in the performance of official duties pursuant to this section, an officer or agent designated under subsection (b) may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enforce Federal laws and regulations for the protection of persons and property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> carry firearms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> make arrests—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> without a warrant for any offense against the United States committed in the presence of the officer or agent; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if the officer or agent has reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing a felony;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> serve warrants and subpoenas issued under the authority of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> conduct investigations, on and off the property in question, of offenses that may have been committed against property under the jurisdiction, custody, or control of the Department of Defense or persons on such property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations, including traffic regulations, necessary for the protection and administration of property under the jurisdiction, custody, or control of the Department of Defense and persons on that property. The regulations may include reasonable penalties, within the limits prescribed in paragraph (2), for violations of the regulations. The regulations shall be posted and remain posted in a conspicuous place on the property to which they apply.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person violating a regulation prescribed under this subsection shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 30 days, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Delegation of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary of Defense under subsections (b), (c), and (d) may be exercised only by the Secretary or the Deputy Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disposition of Persons Arrested</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who is arrested pursuant to authority exercised under subsection (b) may not be held in a military confinement facility, other than in the case of a person who is subject to chapter 47 of this title (the Uniform Code of Military Justice).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Facilities and Services of Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In implementing this section, when the Secretary of Defense determines it to be economical and in the public interest, the Secretary may utilize the facilities and services of Federal, State, Indian tribal, and local law enforcement agencies, with the consent of those agencies, and may reimburse those agencies for the use of their facilities and services. Such services of State, Indian tribal, and local law enforcement, including application of their powers of law enforcement, may be provided notwithstanding that the property is subject to the legislative jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority Outside Federal Property</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the protection of property under the jurisdiction, custody, or control of the Department of Defense and persons on that property, the Secretary of Defense may enter into agreements with Federal agencies and with State, Indian tribal, and local governments to obtain authority for civilian officers and agents designated under this section to enforce Federal laws and State, Indian tribal, and local laws concurrently with other Federal law enforcement officers and with State, Indian tribal, and local law enforcement officers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attorney General Approval</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The powers granted pursuant to subsection (c) to officers and agents designated under subsection (b) shall be exercised in accordance with guidelines approved by the Attorney General. Such guidelines may include specification of the geographical extent of property outside of the property specified in subsection (a) within which those powers may be exercised.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation With Regard to Other Federal Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide for the protection of facilities (including the buildings, grounds, and properties of the General Services Administration) that are under the jurisdiction, custody, or control, in whole or in part, of a Federal agency other than the Department of Defense and that are located off of a military installation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperation With Local Law Enforcement Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before authorizing civilian officers and agents to perform duty in areas outside the property specified in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall consult with, and is encouraged to enter into agreements with, local law enforcement agencies exercising jurisdiction over such areas for the purposes of avoiding conflicts of jurisdiction, promoting notification of planned law enforcement actions, and otherwise facilitating productive working relationships.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Statutory Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to preclude or limit the authority of any Federal law enforcement agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to restrict the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security under the Homeland Security Act of 2002 or of the Administrator of General Services, including the authority to promulgate regulations affecting property under the custody and control of that Secretary or the Administrator, respectively;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to expand or limit section 21 of the Internal Security Act of 1950 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 797</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to affect chapter 47 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to restrict any other authority of the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to restrict the authority of the Director of the National Security Agency under section 11 of the National Security Agency Act of 1959 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3609</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2672a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3513</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2673.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2130</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2674.</num>
<heading> Operation and control of Pentagon Reservation and defense facilities in National Capital Region</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pentagon Reservation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense has jurisdiction, custody, and control over, and responsibility for, the operation, maintenance, and management of the Pentagon Reservation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Law Enforcement Authorities and Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall protect the buildings, grounds, and property located in the National Capital Region that are occupied by, or under the jurisdiction, custody, or control of, the Department of Defense, and the persons on that property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may designate military or civilian personnel to perform law enforcement functions and military, civilian, or contract personnel to perform security functions for such buildings, grounds, property, and persons, including, with regard to civilian personnel designated under this section, duty in areas outside the property referred to in paragraph (1) to the extent necessary to protect that property and persons on that property. Subject to the authorization of the Secretary, any such military or civilian personnel so designated may exercise the authorities listed in paragraphs (1) through (5) of <ref>section 2672(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The powers granted under paragraph (2) to military and civilian personnel designated under that paragraph shall be exercised in accordance with guidelines prescribed by the Secretary and approved by the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> preclude or limit the authority of any Defense Criminal Investigative Organization or any other Federal law enforcement agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> restrict the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security under the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref>6 U.S.C. 101</ref> et seq.) or the authority of the Administrator of General Services, including the authority to promulgate regulations affecting property under the custody and control of that Secretary or the Administrator, respectively;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> expand or limit section 21 of the Internal Security Act of 1950 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 797</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> affect chapter 47 of this title (the Uniform Code of Military Justice);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> restrict any other authority of the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> restrict the authority of the Director of the National Security Agency under section 11 of the National Security Agency Act of 1959 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3609</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For positions for which the permanent duty station is the Pentagon Reservation, the Secretary, in his sole and exclusive discretion, may without regard to the pay provisions of title 5, fix the rates of basic pay for such positions occupied by civilian law enforcement and security personnel appointed under the authority of this section so as to place such personnel on a comparable basis with personnel of other similar Federal law enforcement and security organizations within the vicinity of the Pentagon Reservation, not to exceed the basic pay for personnel performing similar duties in the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division or the United States Park Police, whichever is greater.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations and Enforcement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prescribe such rules and regulations as the Secretary considers appropriate to ensure the safe, efficient, and secure operation of the Pentagon Reservation, including rules and regulations necessary to govern the operation and parking of motor vehicles on the Pentagon Reservation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person who violates a rule or regulation prescribed under this subsection is liable to the United States for a civil penalty of not more than $1,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any person who willfully violates any rule or regulation prescribed pursuant to this subsection commits a Class B misdemeanor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Charge for Provision of Certain Services and Facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may establish rates and collect charges for space, services, protection, maintenance, construction, repairs, alterations, or facilities provided at the Pentagon Reservation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pentagon Reservation Maintenance Revolving Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund to be known as the Pentagon Reservation Maintenance Revolving Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Fund”). There shall be deposited into the Fund funds collected by the Secretary for space and services and other items provided an organization or entity using any facility or land on the Pentagon Reservation pursuant to subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraphs (3) and (4), monies deposited into the Fund shall be available, without fiscal year limitation, for expenditure for real property management, operation, protection, construction, repair, alteration and related activities for the Pentagon Reservation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the cost of a construction or alteration activity proposed to be financed in whole or in part using monies from the Fund will exceed the limitation specified in <ref>section 2805 of this title</ref> for a comparable unspecified minor military construction project, the activity shall be subject to authorization as provided by <ref>section 2802 of this title</ref> before monies from the Fund are obligated for the activity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the authority of the Secretary to use monies from the Fund to support construction or alteration activities at the Pentagon Reservation expires on <date date="2012-09-30">September 30, 2012</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the date specified in subparagraph (A), the Secretary may use monies from the Fund after that date to support construction or alteration activities at the Pentagon Reservation within the limits specified in <ref>section 2805 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Pentagon Reservation” means the Pentagon, the Mark Center Campus, and the Raven Rock Mountain Complex.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “National Capital Region” means the geographic area located within the boundaries of (A) the District of Columbia, (B) Montgomery and Prince Georges Counties in the State of Maryland, (C) Arlington, Fairfax, Loudoun, and Prince William Counties and the City of Alexandria in the Commonwealth of Virginia, and (D) all cities and other units of government within the geographic areas of such District, Counties, and City.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Pentagon” means that area of land (consisting of approximately 227 acres) and improvements thereon, including parking areas, located in Arlington County, Virginia, containing the Pentagon Office Building and its supporting facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “Mark Center Campus” means that area of land (consisting of approximately 16 acres) and improvements thereon, including parking areas, located in Alexandria, Virginia, and known on the day before the date of the enactment of this paragraph as the Fort Belvoir Mark Center Campus.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “Raven Rock Mountain Complex” means that area of land (consisting of approximately 720 acres) and improvements thereon, including parking areas, at the Raven Rock Mountain Complex and its supporting facilities located in Maryland and Pennsylvania.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2804(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1784</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(18)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2864, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1473</ref>, 1561; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(24)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 505</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 369(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XI, § 1101</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 933</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1581</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2802</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4458</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1686</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 952(a)</ref>, (b), div. B, title XXVIII, § 2829E, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2374</ref>, 2375, 2733; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(d)(16)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1600</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2675.</num>
<heading> Leases: foreign countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lease Authority; Duration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may acquire by lease in foreign countries structures and real property relating to structures that are needed for military purposes other than for military family housing. A lease under this section may be for a period of up to 10 years, or 15 years in the case of a lease in Korea, and the rental for each yearly period may be paid from funds appropriated to that military department for that year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Appropriations available to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance or construction may be used for the acquisition of interests in land under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(51)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1460</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 91–511, title VI, § 608</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–107, title VI, § 607(10)</ref>, (11), <date date="1975-10-07">Oct. 7, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 567</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–82, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-01">Aug. 1, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 371</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–356, title V, § 503(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-09-08">Sept. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 579</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–125, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-11-26">Nov. 26, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 940</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–418, title V, § 504(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–99, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="1981-12-23">Dec. 23, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1374</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–214, § 8</ref>, <date date="1982-07-12">July 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 174</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(40)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2624</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1322(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1671</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2804(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2130</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2824</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2476</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2676.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2664]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2677.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2822(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 544</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2678.</num>
<heading> Feral horses and burros: removal from military installations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When feral horses or burros are found on an installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of a military department, the Secretary may use helicopters and motorized equipment for their removal.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1481(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2679.</num>
<heading> Installation-support services: intergovernmental support agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law governing the award of Federal Government contracts for goods and services, the Secretary concerned may enter into an intergovernmental support agreement, on a sole source basis, with a State, local, or tribal government to provide, receive, or share installation-support services if the Secretary determines that the agreement will serve the best interests of the department by enhancing mission effectiveness or creating efficiencies or economies of scale, including by reducing costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An intergovernmental support agreement under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may be for a term not to exceed ten years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may use, for installation-support services provided by a State, local, or tribal government, wage grades normally paid by that State, local, or tribal government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An intergovernmental support agreement under paragraph (1) may only be used when the Secretary concerned or the State, local, or tribal government, as the case may be, providing the installation-support services already provides such services for its own use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any contract for the provision of installation-support services awarded by the Federal Government or a State, local, or tribal government pursuant to an intergovernmental support agreement provided in subsection (a) shall be awarded on a competitive basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect on First Responder Arrangements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided by this section and limitations on the use of that authority are not intended to revoke, preclude, or otherwise interfere with existing or proposed mutual-aid agreements relating to police or fire protection services or other similar first responder agreements or arrangements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds available to the Secretary concerned for operation and maintenance may be used to pay for such installation-support services. The costs of agreements under this section for any fiscal year may be paid using annual appropriations made available for that year. Funds received by the Secretary as reimbursement for providing installation-support services pursuant to such an agreement shall be credited to the appropriation or account charged with providing installation support.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect on OMB Circular A-</inline>76.—</heading>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall ensure that intergovernmental support agreements authorized by this section are not used to circumvent the requirements of Office of Management and Budget Circular A-76 regarding public-private competitions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program for Use of Cost Savings Realized</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each Secretary concerned shall conduct a pilot program under which the Secretary will make available to the commander of each military installation for which cost savings are realized as a result of an intergovernmental support agreement entered into under this section an amount equal to not less than 25 percent of the amount of such cost savings for that military installation for a fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts made available to an installation commander under paragraph (1) shall be used solely to address sustainment restoration and modernization requirements that have been approved by the major subordinate command or equivalent component.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to each military installation for which amounts are made available to the installation commander under paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned shall certify, not less frequently than annually for each fiscal year of the pilot program, to the congressional defense committees the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The name of the installation and the amount of the cost savings achieved at the installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The source and type of intergovernmental support agreement that achieved the cost savings.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The amount of the cost savings made available to the installation commander under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The sustainment restoration and modernization purposes for which the amount made available under paragraph (1) were used.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The authority to conduct the pilot program shall expire <date date="2025-09-30">September 30, 2025</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “installation-support services” means those services, supplies, resources, and support typically provided by a local government for its own needs and without regard to whether such services, supplies, resources, and support are provided to its residents generally, except that the term does not include security guard or fire-fighting functions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “local government” includes a county, parish, municipality, city, town, township, local public authority, school district, special district, and any agency or instrumentality of a local government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealths of Puerto Rico and the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the United States Virgin Islands, and any agency or instrumentality of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “intergovernmental support agreement” means a legal instrument reflecting a relationship between the Secretary concerned and a State, local, or tribal government that contains such terms and conditions as the Secretary concerned considers appropriate for the purposes of this section and necessary to protect the interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title III, § 331(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1696</ref>, § 2336; renumbered § 2679 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3346</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(9)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1001</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1849</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(26)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1985</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2861(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2845</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2264</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2680.</num>
<heading> Minimum capital investment for facilities sustainment, restoration, and modernization for military departments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum Investment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Beginning in fiscal year 2027, and each fiscal year thereafter, each Secretary of a military department shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> calculate (in accordance with subsection (b)) the cumulative plant replacement value of the total inventory of facilities on each military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> invest in the budget for facilities sustainment, restoration, and modernization of that military department, a total amount equal to not less than the percentage specified in subsection (c) of the cumulative plant replacement value described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In making any calculation pursuant to paragraph (1) of subsection (a), each Secretary of a military department shall exclude any facility under the jurisdiction of such Secretary that is scheduled for demolition during the two-year period beginning after the date of such calculation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Percentage Specified</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The percentage of the specified in this subsection is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for fiscal year 2027, 1.75 percent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for fiscal year 2028, 2.5 percent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for fiscal year 2029, 3.25 percent; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> for fiscal year 2030 and each subsequent fiscal year, 4 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As part of the annual budget submission of the President under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, each Secretary of each military department shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a certification to the congressional defense committees that the military department is in compliance with this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a list of facilities under the jurisdiction of that Secretary, disaggregated by military installation and location, that are scheduled for demolition during the two-year period beginning after the date of the submission of such budget, which shall include cost and schedule estimates.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Plant Replacement Value Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “plant replacement value” means, with respect to a facility, the cost to replace such facility using construction costs (including labor and materials) and standards (including methodologies and codes) in effect as of the date such cost is calculated.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2841(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2681.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 4175]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2682.</num>
<heading> Facilities for defense agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maintenance and Repair</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (c), the maintenance and repair of a real property facility for an activity or agency of the Department of Defense (other than a military department) financed from appropriations for military functions of the Department of Defense will be accomplished by or through a military department designated by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (c), a real property facility under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense which is used by an activity or agency of the Department of Defense (other than a military department) shall be under the jurisdiction of a military department designated by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Facilities for Intelligence Collection or for Special Operations Abroad</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) if necessary to provide security for authorized intelligence collection or special operations activities abroad undertaken by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than 48 hours after using the waiver authority under paragraph (1) for any facility for intelligence collection conducted under the authorities of the Department of Defense or special operations activity, the Secretary of Defense shall submit, in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>, to the appropriate congressional committees a notice of the use of the authority, including the justification for the waiver and the estimated cost of the project for which the waiver applies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> With respect to a waiver regarding special operations activities, the congressional defense committees.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to a waiver regarding intelligence collection conducted under the authorities of the Department of Defense—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the congressional defense committees; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The waiver authority provided by paragraph (1) expires <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 88–174, title VI, § 609(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1963-11-07">Nov. 7, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 329</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–214, § 10(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1982-07-12">July 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title IX, § 926</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1541</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1632</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1111</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(f)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1848</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2683.</num>
<heading> Relinquishment of legislative jurisdiction; minimum drinking age on military installations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary concerned may, whenever he considers it desirable, relinquish to a State, or to a Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, all or part of the legislative jurisdiction of the United States over lands or interests under his control in that State, Commonwealth, territory, or possession. Relinquishment of legislative jurisdiction under this section may be accomplished (1) by filing with the Governor (or, if none exists, with the chief executive officer) of the State, Commonwealth, territory, or possession concerned a notice of relinquishment to take effect upon acceptance thereof, or (2) as the laws of the State, Commonwealth, territory, or possession may otherwise provide.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The authority granted by subsection (a) is in addition to and not instead of that granted by any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary concerned shall establish and enforce as the minimum drinking age on a military installation located in a State the age established by the law of that State as the State minimum drinking age.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of a military installation located—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in more than one State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in one State but within 50 miles of another State or Mexico or Canada,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary concerned may establish and enforce as the minimum drinking age on that military installation the lowest applicable age.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> In subparagraph (A), the term “lowest applicable age” means the lowest minimum drinking age established by the law—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of a State in which a military installation is located; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> of a State or jurisdiction of Mexico or Canada that is within 50 miles of such military installation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The commanding officer of a military installation may waive the requirement of paragraph (1) if such commanding officer determines that the exemption is justified by special circumstances.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall define by regulations what constitute special circumstances for the purposes of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “State” includes the District of Columbia.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “minimum drinking age” means the minimum age or ages established for persons who may purchase, possess, or consume alcoholic beverages.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–511, title VI, § 613(1)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1226</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 92–545, title VIII, § 707</ref>, <date date="1972-10-25">Oct. 25, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–283, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-05-14">May 14, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 141</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1224(a)</ref>, (b)(1), (c)(1), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 728</ref>, 729; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIII, § 1343(a)(18)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3993</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–526, title I, § 106(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2625</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2684.</num>
<heading> Cooperative agreements for management of cultural resources</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may enter into a cooperative agreement with a State or local government or other entity for the preservation, management, maintenance, and improvement of cultural resources located on a site authorized by subsection (b) and for the conduct of research regarding the cultural resources. Activities under the cooperative agreement shall be subject to the availability of funds to carry out the cooperative agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Cultural Resources Sites</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To be covered by a cooperative agreement under subsection (a), cultural resources must be located—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on a military installation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on a site outside of a military installation, but only if the cooperative agreement will directly relieve or eliminate current or anticipated restrictions that would or might restrict, impede, or otherwise interfere, whether directly or indirectly, with current or anticipated military training, testing, or operations on a military installation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of Other Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Section 1535 and chapter 63 of title 31 shall not apply to a cooperative agreement entered into under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cultural Resource Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “cultural resource” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A building, structure, site, district, or object eligible for or included in the National Register of Historic Places maintained under <ref>section 302101 of title 54</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Cultural items, as that term is defined in section 2(3) of the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 3001(3)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An archaeological resource, as that term is defined in section 3(1) of the Archaeological Resources Protection Act of 1979 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 470bb(1)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An archaeological artifact collection and associated records covered by <ref>section 79 of title 36</ref>, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An Indian sacred site, as defined in section 1(b)(iii) of Executive Order No. 13007.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2862(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2804</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(58)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1903</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2824</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3264</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1001</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2684a.</num>
<heading> Agreements to limit encroachments and other constraints on military training, testing, and operations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreements Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may enter into an agreement with an eligible entity or entities described in subsection (b) to address the use or development of real property in the vicinity of, or ecologically related to, a military installation, as well as a State-owned National Guard installation, or military airspace for purposes of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> limiting any development or use of the property that would be incompatible with the mission of the installation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> preserving habitat on the property in a manner that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is compatible with environmental requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may eliminate or relieve current or anticipated environmental restrictions that would or might otherwise restrict, impede, or otherwise interfere, whether directly or indirectly, with current or anticipated military training, testing, or operations on the installation;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> maintaining or improving military installation resilience; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> protecting Clear Zone Areas from use or encroachment that is incompatible with the mission of the installation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Entities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section, an eligible entity is any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A State or political subdivision of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A private entity that has as its stated principal organizational purpose or goal the conservation, restoration, or preservation of land and natural resources, or a similar purpose or goal, as determined by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Coordinate</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In entering into an agreement under subsection (a) or undertaking a project under such agreement, the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department, as the case may be, may coordinate with any other covered official with an interest in the activities proposed to be undertaken under such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “covered official” means a Secretary concerned, the Director of the Army National Guard, or the Director of the Air National Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of Certain Contract Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding chapter 63 of title 31, an agreement under this section that is a cooperative agreement or a grant may be used to acquire property or services for the direct benefit or use of the United States Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition and Acceptance of Property and Interests</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An agreement with an eligible entity or entities under this section shall provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the acquisition by an eligible entity or entities of all right, title, and interest in and to any real property, or any lesser interest in the property, as may be appropriate for purposes of this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the sharing by the United States and an eligible entity or entities of the acquisition costs in accordance with paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Property or interests may not be acquired pursuant to the agreement unless the owner of the property or interests consents to the acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> An agreement with an eligible entity under this section may provide for the management of natural resources on, and the monitoring and enforcement of any right, title, real property in which the Secretary concerned acquires any right, title, or interest in accordance with this subsection and for the payment by the United States of all or a portion of the costs of such natural resource management and monitoring and enforcement if the Secretary concerned determines that there is a demonstrated need to preserve or restore habitat for the purpose described in subsection (a)(2). Any such payment by the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may be paid in a lump sum and include an amount intended to cover the future costs of natural resource management and monitoring and enforcement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may be placed by the eligible entity in an interest-bearing account, and any interest shall be applied for the same purposes as the principal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall determine the appropriate portion of the acquisition costs to be borne by the United States in the sharing of acquisition costs of real property, or an interest in real property, under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In lieu of or in addition to making a monetary contribution toward the cost of acquiring a parcel of real property, or an interest therein, pursuant to an agreement under this section, the Secretary concerned may convey, using the authority provided by <ref>section 2869 of this title</ref>, real property described in paragraph (2) of subsection (a) of such section, subject to the limitation in paragraph (3) of such subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The portion of acquisition costs borne by the United States under subparagraph (A), either through the contribution of funds or excess real property, or both, may not exceed an amount equal to, at the discretion of the Secretary concerned—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the fair market value of any property or interest in property to be transferred to the United States upon the request of the Secretary concerned under paragraph (5); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the cumulative fair market value of all properties or interests to be transferred to the United States under paragraph (5) pursuant to an agreement under subsection (a).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> The portion of acquisition costs borne by the United States under subparagraph (A) may exceed the amount determined under subparagraph (C), but only if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary concerned submits, in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>, a notice to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives containing—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a certification by the Secretary that the military value to the United States of the property or interest to be acquired justifies a payment in excess of the fair market value of the property or interest; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a description of the military value to be obtained; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the contribution toward the acquisition costs of the property or interest is not made until at least 10 days after the date on which the notice is submitted under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> The contribution of an entity or entities to the acquisition costs of real property, or an interest in real property, under paragraph (1)(B) may include, with the approval of the Secretary concerned, the following or any combination of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The provision of funds, including funds received by such entity or entities from a Federal agency outside the Department of Defense or a State or local government in connection with a Federal, State, or local program.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The provision of in-kind services, including services related to the acquisition or maintenance of such real property or interest in real property.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The exchange or donation of real property or any interest in real property.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The agreement shall require the entity or entities to transfer to the United States, upon the request of the Secretary concerned, all or a portion of the property or interest acquired under the agreement or a lesser interest therein. No such requirement need be included in the agreement if the property or interest is being transferred to a State or another Federal agency, or the agreement requires it to be subsequently transferred to a State or another Federal agency, and the Secretary concerned determines that the laws and regulations applicable to the future use of such property or interest provide adequate assurance that the property concerned will be developed and used in a manner appropriate for purposes of this section. The Secretary shall limit such transfer request to the minimum property or interests necessary to ensure that the property concerned is developed and used in a manner appropriate for purposes of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), if all or a portion of the property or interest acquired under the agreement is initially or subsequently transferred to a State or another Federal agency, before that State or other Federal agency may declare the property or interest in excess to its needs or propose to exchange the property or interest, the State or other Federal agency shall give the Secretary concerned reasonable advance notice of its intent. If the Secretary concerned determines it necessary to preserve the purposes of this section, the Secretary concerned may request that administrative jurisdiction over the property be transferred to the Secretary concerned at no cost, and, upon such a request being made, the administrative jurisdiction over the property shall be transferred accordingly. If the Secretary concerned does not make such a request within a reasonable time period, all such rights of the Secretary concerned to request transfer of the property or interest shall remain available to the Secretary concerned with respect to future transfers or exchanges of the property or interest and shall bind all subsequent transferees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may accept on behalf of the United States any property or interest to be transferred to the United States under the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> For purposes of the acceptance of property or interests under the agreement, the Secretary concerned may accept an appraisal or title documents prepared or adopted by a non-Federal entity as satisfying the applicable requirements of section 301 of the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4651</ref>) or <ref>section 3111 of title 40</ref>, if the Secretary concerned finds that the appraisal or title documents substantially comply with the requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition of Water Rights</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary concerned to enter into an agreement under this section for the acquisition of real property (or an interest therein) includes the authority to support the purchase of water rights from any available source when necessary to support or protect the mission of a military installation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Terms and Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned may require such additional terms and conditions in an agreement under this section as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than March 1 each year, the Secretary of Defense shall, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments and the Director of the Department of Defense Test Resource Management Center, submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the projects undertaken under agreements under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each report under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of the status of the projects undertaken under agreements under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An assessment of the effectiveness of such projects, and other actions taken pursuant to this section, as part of a long-term strategy to ensure the sustainability of military test and training ranges, military installations, and associated airspace.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An evaluation of the methodology and criteria used to select, and to establish priorities, for projects undertaken under agreements under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A description of any sharing of costs by the United States and eligible entities under subsection (e) during the preceding year, including a description of each agreement under this section providing for the sharing of such costs and a statement of the eligible entity or entities with which the United States is sharing such costs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Information concerning the activities undertaken pursuant to the Sentinel Landscapes Partnership under <ref>section 2693 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Such recommendations as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate for legislative or administrative action in order to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of actions taken pursuant to agreements under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interagency Cooperation in Conservation and Resilience Programs to Avoid or Reduce Adverse Impacts on Military Installation Resilience and Military Readiness Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In order to facilitate interagency cooperation and enhance the effectiveness of actions that will protect the environment, military installation resilience, and military readiness, the recipient of funds provided pursuant to an agreement under this section or under the Sikes Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 670</ref> et seq.) may, with regard to the lands and waters within the scope of the agreement, use such funds to satisfy any matching funds or cost-sharing requirement of any conservation or resilience program of any Federal agency notwithstanding any limitation of such program on the source of matching or cost-sharing funds.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), funds authorized to be appropriated for operation and maintenance of the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, Space Force, or Defense-wide activities may be used to enter into agreements under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a military installation operated primarily with funds authorized to be appropriated for research, development, test, and evaluation, funds authorized to be appropriated for the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, Space Force, or Defense-wide activities for research, development, test, and evaluation may be used to enter into agreements under this section with respect to the installation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Funds obligated to carry out an agreement under this section shall be available for use with regard to any property in the geographic scope specified in the agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at the time the funds are obligated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any subsequent modification to the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary concerned” means the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Clear Zone Area” means an area immediately beyond the end of the runway of an airfield that is needed to ensure the safe and unrestricted passage of aircraft in and over the area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2705</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2822</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3513</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(g)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2473</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2825</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(27)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(43)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4371</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title III, § 312(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(f)(23)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(g)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1848</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title III, § 312(i)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2827(b)(1), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1711</ref>, 2270; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 312(a)–(b)(2), (c), 315(b), title IX, § 924(b)(33), title X, § 1081(d)(12), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3513–3515</ref>, 3826, 3874; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 317(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 311(c)(1), 314, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 215</ref>, 216.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2685.</num>
<heading> Adjustment of or surcharge on selling prices in commissary stores to provide funds for construction and improvement of commissary store facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adjustment or Surcharge Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Defense may, for the purposes of this section, provide for an adjustment of, or surcharge on, sales prices of goods and services sold in commissary store facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use for Construction, Repair, Improvement, and Maintenance</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may use the proceeds from the adjustments or surcharges authorized by subsection (a) only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to acquire (including acquisition by lease), construct, convert, expand, improve, repair, maintain, and equip the physical infrastructure of commissary stores and central product processing facilities of the defense commissary system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to cover environmental evaluation and construction costs related to activities described in paragraph (1), including costs for surveys, administration, overhead, planning, and design.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In paragraph (1), the term “physical infrastructure” includes real property, utilities, and equipment (installed and free standing and including computer equipment), necessary to provide a complete and usable commissary store or central product processing facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Advance Obligation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, may obligate anticipated proceeds from the adjustments or surcharges authorized by subsection (a) for any use specified in subsection (b) or (d), without regard to fiscal year limitations, if the Secretary determines that such obligation is necessary to carry out any use of such adjustments or surcharges specified in subsection (b) or (d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperation With Nonappropriated Fund Instrumentalities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may authorize a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the United States to enter into a contract for construction of a shopping mall or similar facility for a commissary store and one or more nonappropriated fund instrumentality activities. The Secretary may use the proceeds of adjustments or surcharges authorized by subsection (a) to reimburse the nonappropriated fund instrumentality for the portion of the cost of the contract that is attributable to construction of the commissary store or to pay the contractor directly for that portion of such cost.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In paragraph (1), the term “construction”, with respect to a facility, includes acquisition, conversion, expansion, installation, or other improvement of the facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Sources of Funds for Construction and Improvements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Revenues received by the Secretary of Defense from the following sources or activities of commissary store facilities shall be available for the purposes set forth in subsections (b), (c), and (d):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Sale of recyclable materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Sale of excess and surplus property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> License fees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Royalties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Fees paid by sources of products in order to obtain favorable display of the products for resale, known as business related management fees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–552, title VI, § 611</ref>, <date date="1974-12-27">Dec. 27, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1765</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–82, title VI, § 614</ref>, <date date="1977-08-01">Aug. 1, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 380</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–321, title VIII, § 804</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2851</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3072</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 374</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1707</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, § 333(a), (b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–60.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2686.</num>
<heading> Utilities and services: sale; expansion and extension of systems and facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Under such regulations and for such periods and at such prices as he may prescribe, the Secretary concerned or his designee may sell or contract to sell to purchasers within or in the immediate vicinity of an activity of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, or Coast Guard, as the case may be, any of the following utilities and related services, if it is determined that they are not available from another local source and that the sale is in the interest of national defense or in the public interest:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Electric power.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Steam.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Compressed air.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Water.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Sewage and garbage disposal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Natural, manufactured, or mixed gas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Ice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Mechanical refrigeration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Telephone service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Proceeds of sales under subsection (a) shall be credited to the appropriation currently available for the supply of that utility or service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> To meet local needs the Secretary concerned may make minor expansions and extensions of any distributing system or facility within an activity through which a utility or service is furnished under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 141</ref>, § 2481; <ref>Pub. L. 86–156</ref>, <date date="1959-08-14">Aug. 14, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 338</ref>; renumbered § 2686, <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 371(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(2)(A)(viii)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2687.</num>
<heading> Base closures and realignments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no action may be taken to effect or implement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the closure of any military installation at which at least 300 civilian personnel are authorized to be employed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any realignment with respect to any military installation referred to in paragraph (1) involving a reduction by more than 1,000, or by more than 50 percent, in the number of civilian personnel authorized to be employed at such military installation at the time the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned notifies the Congress under subsection (b) of the Secretary’s plan to close or realign such installation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any construction, conversion, or rehabilitation at any military facility other than a military installation referred to in clause (1) or (2) which will or may be required as a result of the relocation of civilian personnel to such facility by reason of any closure or realignment to which clause (1) or (2) applies,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">unless and until the provisions of subsection (b) are complied with.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> No action described in subsection (a) with respect to the closure of, or a realignment with respect to, any military installation referred to in such subsection may be taken unless and until—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned notifies the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, as part of an annual request for authorization of appropriations to such Committees, of the proposed closing or realignment and submits with the notification—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the fiscal, local economic, budgetary, environmental, strategic, and operational consequences of such closure or realignment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the criteria used to consider and recommend military installations for such closure or realignment, which shall include at a minimum consideration of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the ability of the infrastructure (including transportation infrastructure) of both the existing and receiving communities to support forces, missions, and personnel as a result of such closure or realignment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the costs associated with community transportation infrastructure improvements as part of the evaluation of cost savings or return on investment of such closure or realignment; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a period of 30 legislative days or 60 calendar days, whichever is longer, expires following the day on which the notice and evaluation referred to in clause (1) have been submitted to such committees, during which period no irrevocable action may be taken to effect or implement the decision.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> No action described in subsection (a) with respect to the closure of, or realignment with respect to, any military installation referred to in such subsection may be taken within five years after the date on which a decision is made to reduce the civilian personnel thresholds below the levels prescribed in such subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply to the closure of a military installation, or a realignment with respect to a military installation, if the President certifies to the Congress that such closure or realignment must be implemented for reasons of national security or a military emergency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> After the expiration of the period of time provided for in subsection (b)(2) with respect to the closure or realignment of a military installation, funds which would otherwise be available to the Secretary to effect the closure or realignment of that installation may be used by him for such purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section restricts the authority of the Secretary to obtain architectural and engineering services under <ref>section 2807 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned determines, pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.), that a significant transportation impact will occur as a result of an action described in subsection (a), the action may not be taken unless and until the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> analyzes the adequacy of transportation infrastructure at and in the vicinity of each military installation that would be impacted by the action;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> concludes consultation with the Secretary of Transportation with regard to such impact;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> analyzes the impact of the action on local businesses, neighborhoods, and local governments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> includes in the notification required by subsection (b)(1) a description of how the Secretary intends to remediate the significant transportation impact.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “military installation” means a base, camp, post, station, yard, center, homeport facility for any ship, or other activity under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, including any leased facility, which is located within any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or Guam. Such term does not include any facility used primarily for civil works, rivers and harbors projects, or flood control projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “civilian personnel” means direct-hire, permanent civilian employees of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “realignment” includes any action which both reduces and relocates functions and civilian personnel positions, but does not include a reduction in force resulting from workload adjustments, reduced personnel or funding levels, skill imbalances, or other similar causes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “legislative day” means a day on which either House of Congress is in session.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–82, title VI, § 612(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-01">Aug. 1, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 379</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–356, title VIII, § 805</ref>, <date date="1978-09-08">Sept. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 586</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–214, § 10(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1982-07-12">July 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(41)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2624</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 716</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XII, § 1231(17)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1161</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. B, title XXIX, § 2911</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1819</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2823(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4730</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVII, § 2704</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1682</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(33)</ref>, div. B, title XXVII, § 2712(a), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1954</ref>, 2144.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2687a.</num>
<heading> Overseas base closures and realignments and status of United States overseas military locations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report on Status of Overseas Closures and Realignments and Overseas Military Locations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> At the same time that the budget is submitted under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref> for a fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the status of overseas base closure and realignment actions undertaken as part of a global defense posture realignment strategy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the status of overseas military locations, whether such a location is designated as an enduring location or contingency location.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> To satisfy the reporting requirement specified in paragraph (1)(B), a report under paragraph (1) shall contain the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A list of overseas military locations. For any overseas military location established during the previous fiscal year, the reasons for the establishment of the overseas military location.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the strategic goal and operational requirements supported by each overseas military location.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A list of each construction or facility improvement project carried out by the Department of Defense regardless of the funding source, and each construction or facility improvement project accepted as a payment-in-kind, at overseas military locations during the previous fiscal year if the construction or facility improvement project was not specifically authorized in a Military Construction Authorization Act or congressional notice of the construction or facility improvement project was not provided by another means. Each construction or facility improvement project on the list shall be delineated by project location, project title or description, project cost, including costs covered by the host country, and authority used to undertake the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> For each overseas military location first designated as an enduring location in one of the previous two required reports, a list of required construction and facility improvement projects anticipated to be carried out by the Department of Defense directly or through the acceptance of payments-in-kind during the fiscal year in which the report is submitted and the next four fiscal years. Each construction or facility improvement project on the list shall be delineated by project location, project title or description, estimated project cost, including costs anticipated to be covered by the host country, and authority to be used to undertake the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> An overview of any annual lease or access costs to the United States for each overseas military location designated as an enduring location.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A description of any plans to transition an existing contingency overseas military location to an enduring overseas military location, or to upgrade or downgrade the designation of an existing enduring or contingency overseas military location, during the fiscal year in which the report is submitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> A list of any overseas military locations that, during the previous fiscal year, were transferred to the control of security forces of the host country or another military force, closed, or for any other reason no longer used by the armed forces, including a summary of any costs associated with the transfer or closure of the overseas military location.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> A summary of any force protection risks identified for cooperative security locations and contingency locations, the actions proposed to mitigate such risks, and the resourcing and implementation plan to implement the mitigation actions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Such other such matters related to overseas military locations as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The term “overseas military location” covers both enduring locations and contingency locations established outside the United States.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> An enduring location is primarily characterized either by the presence of permanently assigned United States forces with robust infrastructure and quality of life amenities to support that presence, by the sustained presence of allocated United States forces with infrastructure and quality of life amenities consistent with that presence, or by the periodic presence of allocated United States forces with little or no permanent United States military presence or controlled infrastructure. Enduring locations include main operating bases, forward operating sites, and cooperative security locations.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A contingency location refers to a location outside of the United States that is not covered by subparagraph (B), but that is used by United States forces to support and sustain operations during named and unnamed contingency operations or other operations as directed by appropriate authority and is categorized by mission life-cycle requirements as initial, temporary, or semi-permanent.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The term “construction or facility improvement project” includes any construction, development, conversion, or extension of a building, structure, or other improvement to real property carried out at an overseas military location, whether to satisfy temporary or permanent requirements, and any acquisition of land for an overseas military location.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The term does not include repairs to a building, structure, or other improvement to real property, unless the building, structure, or other improvement cannot effectively be used for its designated functional purpose in the absence of the repairs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prepare the report under paragraph (1) in coordination with the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy and the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A report under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex as necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Department of Defense Overseas Military Facility Investment Recovery Account</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (c), amounts paid to the United States, pursuant to any treaty, status of forces agreement, or other international agreement to which the United States is a party, for the residual value of real property or improvements to real property used by civilian or military personnel of the Department of Defense shall be deposited into the Department of Defense Overseas Military Facility Investment Recovery Account.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Money deposited in the Department of Defense Overseas Military Facility Investment Recovery Account shall be available to the Secretary of Defense for payment, as provided in appropriation Acts, of costs incurred by the Department of Defense in connection with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> military construction, facility maintenance and repair, and environmental restoration at military installations in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> military construction, facility maintenance and repair, and compliance with applicable environmental laws at military installations outside the United States at which the Secretary anticipates the United States will have an enduring presence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Funds in the Department of Defense Overseas Facility Investment Recovery Account shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Not later than December 1 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report detailing all expenditures made from the Department of Defense Overseas Facility Investment Recovery Account during the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Amounts Corresponding to the Value of Property Purchased With Nonappropriated Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a payment referred to in subsection (b)(1) for the residual value of real property or improvements at an overseas military facility, the portion of the payment that is equal to the depreciated value of the investment made with nonappropriated funds shall be deposited in the reserve account established under section 204(b)(7)(C) of the Defense Authorization Amendments and Base Closure and Realignment Act (<ref>Public Law 100–526</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note). The Secretary of Defense may use amounts in the account (in such an aggregate amount as is provided in advance by appropriation Acts) for the purpose of acquiring, constructing, or improving commissary stores and nonappropriated fund instrumentalities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">OMB Review of Proposed Overseas Basing Settlements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may not enter into an agreement of settlement with a host country regarding the release to the host country of improvements made by the United States to facilities at an installation located in the host country until 30 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the proposed settlement to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget. The prohibition set forth in the preceding sentence shall apply only to agreements of settlement for improvements having a value in excess of $10,000,000. The Director shall evaluate the overall equity of the proposed settlement. In evaluating the proposed settlement, the Director shall consider such factors as the extent of the United States capital investment in the improvements being released to the host country, the depreciation of the improvements, the condition of the improvements, and any applicable requirements for environmental remediation or restoration at the installation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on each proposed agreement of settlement that was not submitted by the Secretary to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget in the previous year under paragraph (1) because the fair market value of the improvements to be released pursuant to the proposed agreement did not exceed $10,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Oversight of Use of Payments-In-Kind for Construction or Operations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Before concluding an agreement for acceptance of military construction or facility improvements as a payment-in-kind, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a notification on the proposed agreement. Any such notification shall contain the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of the military construction project or facility improvement project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An explanation of the military requirement to be satisfied with the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A certification that the project is included in the current future-years defense program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Before concluding an agreement for acceptance of host country support or host country payment of operating costs of United States forces as a payment-in-kind, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a notification on the proposed agreement. Any such notification shall contain the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of each activity to be covered by the payment-in-kind.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A certification that the costs to be covered by the payment-in-kind are included in the budget of one or more of the military departments or that it will otherwise be necessary to provide for payment of such costs in a budget of one or more of the military departments in the current or the next fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> When the Secretary of Defense submits a notification of a proposed agreement under paragraph (1) or (2), the Secretary may then enter into the agreement described in the notification only after the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the notification is submitted or, if earlier, the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which a copy of the notification is provided in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Military Construction Projects As Payments-In-Kind and In-Kind Contributions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a military construction project costing more than $6,000,000 may be accepted as payment-in-kind or as an in-kind contribution required by a bilateral agreement with a host country only if that military construction project is authorized by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Subparagraph (A) does not apply to a military construction project that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> was specified in a bilateral agreement with a host country that was entered into before <date date="2013-12-26">December 26, 2013</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> was the subject of negotiation between the United States and a host country as of the date of the enactment of the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> was accepted as payment-in-kind for the residual value of improvements made by the United States at military installations released to the host country under section 2921 of the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991 (division B of <ref>Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note) before <date date="2013-12-26">December 26, 2013</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If the Secretary of Defense accepts a military construction project to be built for Department of Defense personnel outside the United States as a payment-in-kind or an in-kind contribution required by a bilateral agreement with a host country, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a written notification at least 30 days before the initiation date for any such military construction project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A notification under subparagraph (A) with respect to a proposed military construction project shall include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The requirements for, and purpose and description of, the proposed project.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The cost of the proposed project.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The scope of the proposed project.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The schedule for the proposed project.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Such other details as the Secretary considers relevant.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a military construction project authorized in a Military Construction Authorization Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To the extent that a payment-in-kind or an in-kind contribution is provided under a bilateral agreement with a host country with respect to a military construction project for which funds have already been obligated or expended by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary shall return to the Treasury funds in an amount equal to the value of the funds already obligated or expended for the project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “military construction project” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 2801 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “fair market value of the improvements” means the value of improvements determined by the Secretary of Defense on the basis of their highest use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “improvements” includes new construction of facilities and all additions, improvements, modifications, or renovations made to existing facilities or to real property, without regard to whether they were carried out with appropriated or nonappropriated funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “nonappropriated funds” means funds received from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the adjustment of, or surcharge on, selling prices at commissary stores fixed under <ref>section 2685 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a nonappropriated fund instrumentality.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “nonappropriated fund instrumentality” means an instrumentality of the United States under the jurisdiction of the armed forces (including the Army and Air Force Exchange Service, the Navy Resale and Services Support Office, and the Marine Corps exchanges) which is conducted for the comfort, pleasure, contentment, or physical or mental improvement of members of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2822(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2665</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(44)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4371</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(34)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2807(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 1008</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2803(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3696</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(11)</ref>, (b)(7), <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1001</ref>, 1002; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2715</ref>, 2716; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(d)(15)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1600</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2822(a)</ref>–(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4330–4332</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2688.</num>
<heading> Utility systems: conveyance authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conveyance Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may convey a utility system, or part of a utility system, under the jurisdiction of the Secretary to a municipal, private, regional, district, or cooperative utility company or other entity. The conveyance may consist of all right, title, and interest of the United States in the utility system or such lesser estate as the Secretary considers appropriate to serve the interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection of Conveyee</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If more than one utility or entity referred to in subsection (a) notifies the Secretary concerned of an interest in a conveyance under such subsection, the Secretary shall carry out the conveyance through the use of competitive procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned may use procedures other than competitive procedures, but only in accordance with subsections (a), (b), (d), and (e) of <ref>section 3204 of this title</ref>, to select the conveyee of a utility system (or part of a utility system) under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> With respect to the solicitation process used in connection with the conveyance of a utility system (or part of a utility system) under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned shall ensure that the process is conducted in a manner consistent with the laws and regulations of the State in which the utility system is located to the extent necessary to ensure that all interested regulated and unregulated utility companies and other interested entities receive an opportunity to acquire and operate the utility system to be conveyed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned may require as consideration for a conveyance under subsection (a) an amount equal to the fair market value (as determined by the Secretary) of the right, title, or interest of the United States conveyed. The consideration may take the form of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a lump sum payment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a reduction in charges for utility services provided by the utility or entity concerned to the military installation at which the utility system is located.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the utility services proposed to be provided as consideration under paragraph (1) are subject to regulation by a Federal or State agency, any reduction in the rate charged for the utility services shall be subject to establishment or approval by that agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contracts for Utility Services</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), a contract for the receipt of utility services as consideration under subsection (c), or any other contract for utility services entered into by the Secretary concerned in connection with the conveyance of a utility system under this section, may be for a period not to exceed 10 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may authorize a contract for utility services described in paragraph (1) or the renewal of such a contract to have a term in excess of 10 years, but not to exceed 50 years, if the Secretary concerned determines that a contract for a longer term will be cost effective. The determination of cost effectiveness shall be made using a business case analysis that includes an independent estimate of the level of investment that should be required to maintain adequate operation of the utility system over the proposed term of the contract or contract renewal. The business case analysis must also demonstrate how a privatized system will operate in a manner consistent with subsection (g)(3). A renewal of a contract pursuant to this paragraph may be entered into only within the last five years of the existing contract term.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A lump sum payment received under subsection (c) shall be credited, at the election of the Secretary concerned—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to an appropriation of the military department concerned available for the procurement of the same utility services as are provided by the utility system conveyed under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to an appropriation of the military department available for carrying out energy savings projects or water conservation projects; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to an appropriation of the military department available for improvements to other utility systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts so credited shall be merged with funds in the appropriation to which credited and shall be available for the same purposes, and subject to the same conditions and limitations, as the appropriation with which merged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(f)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1061(21)(C)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1584</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Terms and Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may require such additional terms and conditions in connection with a conveyance under subsection (a) as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall require in any contract for the conveyance of a utility system (or part of a utility system) under subsection (a) that the conveyee manage and operate the utility system in a manner consistent with applicable Federal and State regulations pertaining to health, safety, fire, and environmental requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall require in any contract for the conveyance of a utility system (or part of a utility system) under subsection (a) that the conveyee manage and operate the utility system in a manner consistent with energy resilience and cybersecurity requirements and associated metrics provided to the conveyee to ensure that the reliability of the utility system meets mission requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall include in the report submitted under section 2925(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002093">1</ref> of this title a description of progress in meeting energy resilience metrics for all conveyance contracts entered into pursuant to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance for Construction, Repair, or Replacement of Utility Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In lieu of carrying out a military construction project to construct, repair, or replace a utility system, the Secretary concerned may use funds authorized and appropriated for the project to facilitate the conveyance of the utility system under this section by making a contribution toward the cost of construction, repair, or replacement of the utility system by the entity to which the utility system is being conveyed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Utility System Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In this section, the term “utility system” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A system for the generation and supply of electric power.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A system for the treatment or supply of water.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A system for the collection or treatment of wastewater.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A system for the generation or supply of steam, hot water, and chilled water.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A system for the supply of natural gas.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A system for the transmission of telecommunications.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “utility system” includes the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Equipment, fixtures, structures, and other improvements utilized in connection with a system referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Real property, easements, and rights-of-way associated with a system referred to in that paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conveyance of Additional Utility Infrastructure After Conveyance of a Utility System</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Upon conveyance of a utility system, the Secretary of a military department may convey additional utility infrastructure under the jurisdiction of the Secretary on a military installation to a utility or entity to which a utility system for the installation has been conveyed under subsection (a) if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the additional utility infrastructure cannot operate without being a part of the conveyed utility system or operation of the additional utility infrastructure by the utility or entity would be in the best interest of the Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the military department receives as consideration an amount for the utility infrastructure determined in the same manner as the consideration the Secretary could require under subsection (c) for a conveyance under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The conveyance under this paragraph may consist of all right, title, and interest of the United States or such lesser estate as the Secretary considers appropriate to serve the interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Improvement of Conveyed Utility System</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of a utility system that has been conveyed under this section and that only provides utility services to a military installation, the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may authorize a contract on a sole source basis with the conveyee of the utility system to carry out a military construction project as authorized and appropriated for by law for an infrastructure improvement that enhances the reliability, resilience, efficiency, physical security, or cybersecurity of the utility system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may convey under subsection (j) any infrastructure constructed under paragraph (1) that is in addition to the utility system conveyed under such paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall not apply to projects constructed or operated by the Army Corps of Engineers under its civil works authorities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1992</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>, 851; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1087(a)(15), div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–291, 1654A–418; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(32)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1600</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2823(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3514–3516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1061(21)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1584</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 1014</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2834</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1858</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title III, § 312(e)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1710</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title III, § 315</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1304</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, §§ 2823(a), 2824, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4294</ref>, 4333; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 748</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(29)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2689.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2917]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2690.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 2918]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2691.</num>
<heading> Restoration of land used by permit or damaged by mishap; reimbursement of State costs of fighting wildland fires</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restoration of Other Agency Land Used by Permit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the military department concerned may remove improvements and take any other action necessary in the judgment of the Secretary to restore land used by that military department by permit from another military department or Federal agency if the restoration is required by the permit making that land available to the military department. The Secretary concerned may carry out this section using funds available for operations and maintenance or for military construction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Screening for Use of Improved Land</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Unless otherwise prohibited by law or the terms of the permit, before restoration of any land under subsection (a) is begun, the Secretary concerned shall determine, under the provisions of subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41, whether another military department or Federal agency has a use for the land in its existing, improved state. During the period required to make such a determination, the Secretary may provide for maintenance and repair of improvements on the land to the standards established for excess property by the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restoration of Department of Defense Land Used by Other Agency</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As a condition of any permit, license, or other grant of access entered into by the Secretary of a military department with another Federal agency authorizing the agency to use lands under the control of the Secretary, the Secretary may require the agency to agree to remove any improvements and to take any other action necessary in the judgment of the Secretary to restore the land used by the agency to its condition before its use by the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In lieu of performing any removal or restoration work under paragraph (1), a Federal agency may elect, with the consent of the Secretary, to reimburse the Secretary for the costs incurred by the military department in performing such removal or restoration work.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Wildland Fires on State Land</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may, in any lease, permit, license, or other grant of access for use of lands owned by a State, agree to reimburse the State for the reasonable costs of the State in suppressing wildland fires caused by the activities of the Department of Defense under such lease, permit, license, or other grant of access.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restoration of Land Damaged by Mishap</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> When land under the administrative jurisdiction of a Federal agency that is not a part of the Department of Defense is damaged as the result of a mishap involving a vessel, aircraft, or vehicle of the Department of Defense, the Secretary of Defense may, with the consent of the Federal agency, restore the land.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> When land under the administrative jurisdiction of the Department of Defense or a military department is damaged as the result of a mishap involving a vessel, aircraft, or vehicle of a Federal agency that is not a part of the Department of Defense, the head of the Federal agency under whose control the vessel, aircraft, or vehicle was operating may, with the consent of the Department of Defense, restore the land.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The authority under paragraphs (1) and (2) includes activities and expenditures necessary to complete restoration to meet the regulations of the Federal department or agency with administrative jurisdiction over the affected land, which may be different than the regulations of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–407, title VIII, § 804(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-08-28">Aug. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1519</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1303(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 739</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2205</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(15)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(46)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3846</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2814(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1849</ref>, 1850; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title III, § 353</ref>, title X, § 1081(a)(27), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1731</ref>, 1985; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2797</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2692.</num>
<heading> Storage, treatment, and disposal of nondefense toxic and hazardous materials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Secretary of Defense may not permit the use of an installation of the Department of Defense for the storage, treatment, or disposal of any material that is a toxic or hazardous material and that is not owned either by the Department of Defense or by a member of the armed forces (or a dependent of the member) assigned to or provided military housing on the installation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall define by regulation what materials are hazardous or toxic materials for the purposes of this section, including specification of the quantity of a material that serves to make it hazardous or toxic for the purposes of this section. The definition shall include materials referred to in section 101(14) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9601(14)</ref>) and materials designated under section 102 of that Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9602</ref>) and shall include materials that are of an explosive, flammable, or pyrotechnic nature.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) does not apply to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The storage, treatment, or disposal of materials that will be or have been used in connection with an activity of the Department of Defense or in connection with a service to be performed on an installation of the Department for the benefit of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The storage of strategic and critical materials in the National Defense Stockpile under an agreement for such storage with the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The temporary storage or disposal of explosives in order to protect the public or to assist agencies responsible for Federal, State, or local law enforcement in storing or disposing of explosives when no alternative solution is available, if such storage or disposal is made in accordance with an agreement between the Secretary of Defense and the head of the Federal, State, or local agency concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The temporary storage or disposal of explosives in order to provide emergency lifesaving assistance to civil authorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The disposal of excess explosives produced under a Department of Defense contract, if the head of the military department concerned determines, in each case, that an alternative feasible means of disposal is not available to the contractor, taking into consideration public safety, available resources of the contractor, and national defense production requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The temporary storage of nuclear materials or nonnuclear classified materials in accordance with an agreement with the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The storage of materials that constitute military resources intended to be used during peacetime civil emergencies in accordance with applicable Department of Defense regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The temporary storage of materials of other Federal agencies in order to provide assistance and refuge for commercial carriers of such material during a transportation emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The storage of any material that is not owned by the Department of Defense if the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the material is required or generated in connection with the authorized and compatible use of a facility of the Department of Defense, including the use of such a facility for testing material or training personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> The treatment and disposal of any material that is not owned by the Department of Defense if the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the material is required or generated in connection with the authorized and compatible use of a facility of that military department and the Secretary enters into a contract or agreement with the prospective user that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is consistent with the best interest of national defense and environmental security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides for the prospective user’s continued financial and environmental responsibility and liability with regard to the material.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The storage of any material that is not owned by the Department of Defense if the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the material is required or generated in connection with the use of a space launch facility located on an installation of the Department of Defense or on other land controlled by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may grant exceptions to subsection (a) when essential to protect the health and safety of the public from imminent danger if the Secretary otherwise determines the exception is essential and if the storage or disposal authorized does not compete with private enterprise.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may assess a charge for any storage or disposal provided under this section. Any such charge shall be on a reimbursable cost basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of storage under this section authorized because of an imminent danger, the storage provided shall be temporary and shall cease once the imminent danger no longer exists. In all other cases of storage or disposal authorized under this section, the storage or disposal authorized shall be terminated as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–407, title VIII, § 805(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-08-28">Aug. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1520</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2852</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 325</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2711</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 343(a)</ref>–(g)(2), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1686</ref>, 1687; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(a)(25)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(21)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2399</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2693.</num>
<heading> Sentinel Landscapes Partnership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies that elect to become full partners in the program, may establish and carry out a program to preserve and restore sentinel landscapes. The program shall be known as the “Sentinel Landscapes Partnership”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Sentinel Landscapes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies that elect to become full partners in the Sentinel Landscapes Partnership may, as such Secretaries and other heads determine appropriate, collectively designate one or more sentinel landscapes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination of Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out this section, the Secretaries and the other heads of Federal departments and agencies may coordinate actions between their departments and agencies and with other Federal, State, interstate, and local agencies, Indian Tribes, and private entities to more efficiently work together for the mutual benefit of conservation, resilience, working lands, and national defense, and to encourage owners and managers of land to engage in voluntary land management, resilience, and conservation activities that contribute to the sustainment of military installations, State-owned National Guard installations, and associated airspace.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Priority Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out this section, the Secretaries and the other heads of Federal departments and agencies may give to any eligible owner or manager of land within a designated sentinel landscape priority consideration for participation in any easement, grant, or assistance program administered by that Secretary or head. Participation by an eligible owner or manager of land in any such program pursuant to this section shall be voluntary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation by Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Other Federal agencies with programs addressing conservation or resilience may, and are encouraged to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> participate in the activities of the Sentinel Landscapes Partnership; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> become full partners in the Sentinel Landscapes Partnership.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section may be construed to require an owner or manager of land, including a private landowner or agricultural producer, to participate in any land management, resilience, or conservation activity under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Military installation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “military installation” has the same meaning as provided in section 100(1) of the Sikes Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 670(1)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State-owned national guard installation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “State-owned National Guard installation” has the same meaning as provided in section 100(3) of the Sikes Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 670(3)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sentinel landscape</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “sentinel landscape” means a landscape-scale area encompassing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> one or more military installations or state-owned National Guard installations and associated airspace; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the publicly and privately owned lands that serve to protect and support the rural economy, the natural environment, outdoor recreation, and the national defense missions of a military installation or State-owned National Guard installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Resilience</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “resilience” means the capability to avoid, prepare for, minimize the effect of, adapt to, and recover from extreme weather events, flooding, wildfire, or other anticipated or unanticipated changes in environmental conditions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 311(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 213</ref>, 214.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2694.</num>
<heading> Conservation and cultural activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish and carry out a program to conduct and manage in a coordinated manner the conservation and cultural activities described in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A conservation or cultural activity eligible for the program that the Secretary establishes under subsection (a) is any activity—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that has regional or Department of Defense-wide significance and that involves more than one military department or involves a sentinel landscape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is necessary to meet legal requirements or to support military operations or that would contribute to maintaining or improving military installation resilience;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> that can be more effectively managed at the Department of Defense level; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for which no executive agency has been designated responsible by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such activities include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The development of ecosystem-wide land management plans or nature-based climate resilience plans.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The conduct of wildlife studies to ensure the safety and sustainability of military operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The identification and return of Native American human remains and cultural items in the possession or control of the Department of Defense, or discovered on land under the jurisdiction of the Department, to the appropriate Native American tribes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The control of invasive species that may hinder military activities or degrade military training ranges.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The establishment of a regional curation system for artifacts found on military installations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> The implementation of ecosystem-wide land management plans—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> for a single ecosystem—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> that encompasses at least two non-contiguous military installations, if those military installations are not all under the administrative jurisdiction of the same Secretary of a military department; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> providing synergistic benefits unavailable if the installations acted separately; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for one or more ecosystems within a sentinel landscape.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may negotiate and enter into cooperative agreements with public and private agencies, organizations, institutions, individuals, or other entities to carry out the program established under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect on Other Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed or interpreted as preempting any otherwise applicable Federal, State, or local law or regulation relating to the management of natural and cultural resources on military installations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sentinel Landscape Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “sentinel landscape” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2693(g) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 332(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2484</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(59)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1903</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2814</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1688</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 317(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1632</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 311(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2694a.</num>
<heading> Conveyance of surplus real property for natural resource conservation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Convey</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of a military department may convey to an eligible entity described in subsection (b) any surplus real property that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is under the administrative control of the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is suitable and desirable for conservation purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has been made available for public benefit transfer for a sufficient period of time to potential claimants; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is not subject to a pending request for transfer to another Federal agency or for conveyance to any other qualified recipient for public benefit transfer under the real property disposal processes and authorities under subtitle I of title 40.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Entities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The conveyance of surplus real property under this section may be made to any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A State or political subdivision of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A nonprofit organization that exists for the primary purpose of conservation of natural resources on real property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reversionary Interest and Other Deed Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The deed of conveyance of any surplus real property conveyed under this section shall require the property to be used and maintained for the conservation of natural resources in perpetuity. If the Secretary concerned determines at any time that the property is not being used or maintained for such purpose, then, at the option of the Secretary, all or any portion of the property shall revert to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The deed of conveyance may permit the recipient of the property—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to convey the property to another eligible entity, subject to the approval of the Secretary concerned and subject to the same covenants and terms and conditions as provided in the deed from the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to conduct incidental revenue-producing activities on the property that are compatible with the use of the property for conservation purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The deed of conveyance may contain such additional terms, reservations, restrictions, and conditions as the Secretary concerned considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Release of Covenants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With the concurrence of the Secretary of Interior, the Secretary concerned may grant a release from a covenant included in the deed of conveyance of real property conveyed under this section, subject to the condition that the recipient of the property pay the fair market value, as determined by the Secretary concerned, of the property at the time of the release of the covenant. The Secretary concerned may reduce the amount required to be paid under this subsection to account for the value of the natural resource conservation benefit that has accrued to the United States during the period the covenant was in effect, if the benefit was not taken into account in determining the original consideration for the conveyance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and Wait Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned may not approve of the reconveyance of real property under subsection (c) or grant the release of a covenant under subsection (d) until after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary submits, in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref>section 480 of this title</ref>, to the appropriate committees of Congress a notice of the proposed reconveyance or release.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The conveyance of real property under this section shall not be used as a condition of allowing any defense activity under any Federal, State, or local permitting or review process. The Secretary concerned may make the conveyance, with the restrictions specified in subsection (c), to establish a mitigation bank, but only if the establishment of the mitigation bank does not occur in order to satisfy any condition for permitting military activity under a Federal, State, or local permitting or review process.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In fixing the consideration for the conveyance of real property under this section, or in determining the amount of any reduction of the amount to be paid for the release of a covenant under subsection (d), the Secretary concerned shall take into consideration any benefit that has accrued or may accrue to the United States from the use of such property for the conservation of natural resources.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relation to Other Conveyance Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may not make a conveyance under this section of any real property to be disposed of under a base closure law in a manner that is inconsistent with the requirements and conditions of the base closure law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of real property on Guam, the Secretary concerned may not make a conveyance under this section unless the Government of Guam has been first afforded the opportunity to acquire the real property as authorized by <ref>section 1 of Public Law 106–504</ref> (<ref>114 Stat. 2309</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “appropriate committees of Congress” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 2801 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Secretary concerned” means the Secretary of a military department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas, Guam, the Virgin Islands, and American Samoa.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2707</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1056(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3438</ref>, 3439; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(22)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2399</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2803(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4458</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(h)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1849</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2694b.</num>
<heading> Participation in wetland mitigation banks</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Participate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department, and the Secretary of Defense with respect to matters concerning a Defense Agency, when engaged in an authorized activity that may or will result in the destruction of, or an adverse impact to, a wetland, may make payments to a wetland mitigation banking program or “in-lieu-fee” mitigation sponsor approved in accordance with the Federal Guidance for the Establishment, Use and Operation of Mitigation Banks (60 Fed. Reg. 58605; <date date="1995-11-28">November 28, 1995</date>) or the Federal Guidance on the Use of In-Lieu-Fee Arrangements for Compensatory Mitigation Under Section 404 of the Clean Water Act and Section 10 of the Rivers and Harbors Act (65 Fed. Reg. 66913; <date date="2000-11-07">November 7, 2000</date>), or any successor administrative guidance or regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternative to Creation of Wetland</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Participation in a wetland mitigation banking program or consolidated user site under subsection (a) shall be in lieu of mitigating wetland impacts through the creation of a wetland on Federal property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Payments made under subsection (a) to a wetland mitigation banking program or consolidated user site may be treated as eligible project costs for military construction.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title III, § 314(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1430</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2694c.</num>
<heading> Participation in conservation banking programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Participate</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to the availability of appropriated funds, the Secretary concerned, when engaged or proposing to engage in an activity described in subsection (b) that may or will result in an adverse impact to one or more species protected (or pending protection) under any applicable provision of law, or habitat for such species, may make payments to a conservation banking program or “in-lieu-fee” mitigation sponsor approved in accordance with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Federal Guidance for the Establishment, Use and Operation of Mitigation Banks (60 Fed. Reg. 58605; <date date="1995-11-28">November 28, 1995</date>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Guidance for the Establishment, Use, and Operation of Conservation Banks (68 Fed. Reg. 24753; <date date="2003-05-02">May 2, 2003</date>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Federal Guidance on the Use of In-Lieu-Fee Arrangements for Compensatory Mitigation Under Section 404 of the Clean Water Act and Section 10 of the Rivers and Harbors Act (65 Fed. Reg. 66915; <date date="2000-11-07">November 7, 2000</date>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any successor or related administrative guidance or regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Payments to a conservation banking program or “in-lieu-fee” mitigation sponsor under subsection (a) may be made only for the purpose of facilitating one or more of the following activities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Military testing, operations, training, or other military activity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Military construction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Amounts for Conservation Banking</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Payments made under subsection (a) to a conservation banking program or “in-lieu-fee” mitigation sponsor for the purpose of facilitating military construction may be treated as eligible costs of the military construction project.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Source of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Amounts available from any of the following shall be available for activities under this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Operation and maintenance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Military construction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Research, development, test, and evaluation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Support for United States Relocation to Guam Account established under section 2824 of the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009 (division B of <ref>Public Law 110–417</ref>; <ref>122 Stat. 4730</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary Concerned Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “Secretary concerned” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of a military department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense with respect to a Defense Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title III, § 311(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4408</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(45)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4371</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2694d.</num>
<heading> Participation in pollutant banks and water quality trading</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Participate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department, and the Secretary of Defense with respect to matters concerning a Defense Agency, when engaged in an authorized activity that may or will result in the discharge of pollutants, may make payments to a pollutant banking program or water quality trading program approved in accordance with the Water Quality Trading Policy dated <date date="2003-01-13">January 13, 2003</date>, set forth by the Office of Water of the Environmental Protection Agency, or any successor administrative guidance or regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Payments made under subsection (a) to a pollutant banking program or water quality trading program may be treated as eligible project costs for military construction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Discharge of Pollutants Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “discharge of pollutants” has the meaning given that term in section 502(12) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1362(12)</ref>) (commonly referred to as the “Clean Water Act”).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 312(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2502</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2695.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of funds to cover administrative expenses relating to certain real property transactions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Accept</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In connection with a real property transaction referred to in subsection (b) with a non-Federal person or entity, the Secretary of a military department may accept amounts provided by the person or entity to cover administrative expenses incurred by the Secretary in entering into the transaction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Transactions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (a) applies to the following transactions involving real property under the control of the Secretary of a military department:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The exchange of real property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The grant of an easement over, in, or upon real property of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The lease or license of real property of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The disposal of real property of the United States for which the Secretary will be the disposal agent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The conveyance of real property under <ref>section 2694a of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Amounts Collected</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Amounts collected by the Secretary of a military department under subsection (a) for administrative expenses shall be credited, at the option of the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the appropriation, fund, or account from which the expenses were paid; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to an appropriate appropriation, fund, or account currently available to the Secretary for the purposes for which the expenses were paid.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts credited under paragraph (1) shall be merged with funds in such appropriation, fund, or account and shall be available for the same purposes and subject to the same limitations as the funds with which merged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1993</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 851</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2696.</num>
<heading> Real property: transfer between armed forces and screening requirements for other Federal use</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfers Between Armed Forces</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If either of the Secretaries concerned requests it and the other approves, real property may be transferred, without compensation, from one armed force to another. <ref>Section 2571(d) of this title</ref> shall apply to the transfer of real property under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Screening Requirements for Additional Federal Use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned may not convey real property that is authorized or required to be conveyed, whether for or without consideration, by any provision of law enacted after <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>, unless the Administrator of General Services has screened the property for further Federal use in accordance with subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time for Screening</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Before the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of a provision of law authorizing or requiring the conveyance of a parcel of real property by the Secretary concerned, the Administrator of General Services shall complete the screening referred to in subsection (b) with regard to the real property and notify the Secretary concerned and Congress of the results of the screening. The notice shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of the Federal agency requesting transfer of the property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the proposed use to be made of the property by the Federal agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the fair market value of the property, including any improvements thereon, as estimated by the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the Administrator fails to complete the screening and notify the Secretary concerned and Congress within such period, the Secretary concerned shall proceed with the conveyance of the real property as provided in the provision of law authorizing or requiring the conveyance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Submission of Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Administrator of General Services submits notice under subsection (c)(1) that further Federal use of a parcel of real property is requested by a Federal agency, the Secretary concerned may not proceed with the conveyance of the real property as provided in the provision of law authorizing or requiring the conveyance until the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date on which the notice is submitted to Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Excepted Conveyance Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The screening requirements of subsection (b) shall not apply to real property authorized or required to be conveyed under any of the following provisions of law:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A base closure law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Chapter 5 of title 40.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any specific provision of law authorizing or requiring the transfer of administrative jurisdiction over a parcel of real property between Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Screening and Conveyance of Property for Correctional Facilities Purposes</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), before any real property or facility of the United States that is under the jurisdiction of any department, agency, or instrumentality of the Department of Defense is determined to be excess to the needs of such department, agency, or instrumentality, the Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide adequate notification of the availability of such real property or facility within the Department of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the real property or facility remains available after such notification, notify the Attorney General of its availability; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if the Attorney General certifies to the Secretary of Defense that a determination has been made by the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance within the Department of Justice to utilize the real property or facility under the correctional options program carried out under section 515 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 3762a</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002094">1</ref> convey the real property or facility, without reimbursement, to a public agency referred to in paragraph (1) or (3) of subsection (a) of such section for such utilization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) shall not apply—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to real property and facilities to which title II of the Defense Authorization Amendments and Base Closure and Realignment Act (<ref>Public Law 100–526</ref>) is applicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> during any portion of a fiscal year after four conveyances have been made under paragraph (1) in such fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2814(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1994</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(a)(26)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(16)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1031(a)(33), 1043(c)(4), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1600</ref>, 1612; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2825(a)</ref>, (b)(5), (c)(3), (d)(2)(A), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2476</ref>, 2477; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(47)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3846</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2697.</num>
<heading> Acceptance and use of landing fees charged for use of military airfields by civil aircraft</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may impose landing fees for the use by civil aircraft of military airfields under the jurisdiction of that Secretary and may use any fees received under this section as a source of funding for the operation and maintenance of airfields of that department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Uniform Landing Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe the amount of the landing fees that may be imposed under this section. Such fees shall be uniform among the military departments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Proceeds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts received for a fiscal year in payment of landing fees imposed under this section for the use of a military airfield shall be credited to the appropriation that is available for that fiscal year for the operation and maintenance of that military airfield, shall be merged with amounts in the appropriation to which credited, and shall be available for that military airfield for the same period and purposes as the appropriation is available.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department shall determine whether consideration for a landing fee has been received in a lease, license, or other real estate agreement for an airfield and shall use such a determination to offset appropriate amounts imposed under subsection (a) for that airfield.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4189</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2846</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2264</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>