<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 43—</num>
<heading>RANK AND COMMAND</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 741.</num>
<heading> Rank: commissioned officers of the armed forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Among the grades listed below, the grades of general and admiral are equivalent and are senior to other grades and the grades of second lieutenant and ensign are equivalent and are junior to other grades. Intermediate grades rank in the order listed as follows:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p><i>Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force</i></p></th><th><p><i>Navy and Coast Guard</i></p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>General</span></p></td><td><p>Admiral.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Lieutenant general</span></p></td><td><p>Vice admiral.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Major general</span></p></td><td><p>Rear admiral.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Brigadier general</span></p></td><td><p>Rear admiral (lower half).</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Colonel</span></p></td><td><p>Captain.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Lieutenant colonel</span></p></td><td><p>Commander.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Major</span></p></td><td><p>Lieutenant commander.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Captain</span></p></td><td><p>Lieutenant.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>First lieutenant</span></p></td><td><p>Lieutenant (junior grade).</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Second lieutenant</span></p></td><td><p>Ensign.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Rank among officers of the same grade or of equivalent grades is determined by comparing dates of rank. An officer whose date of rank is earlier than the date of rank of another officer of the same or equivalent grade is senior to that officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Rank among officers of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force of the same grade or of equivalent grades who have the same date of rank is determined by regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense which shall apply uniformly among the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The date of rank of an officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force who holds a grade as the result of an original appointment shall be determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned at the time of such appointment. The date of rank of an officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force who holds a grade as the result of an original appointment and who at the time of such appointment was awarded service credit for prior commissioned service or constructive credit for advanced education or training, or special experience shall be determined so as to reflect such prior commissioned service or constructive service. Determinations by the Secretary concerned under this paragraph shall be made under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense which shall apply uniformly among the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided by law, the date of rank of an officer who holds a grade as the result of a promotion is the date of his appointment to that grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, which shall apply uniformly among the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force, the date of rank of a reserve commissioned officer (other than a warrant officer) of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force who is to be placed on the active-duty list and who has not been on continuous active duty since his original appointment as a reserve commissioned officer in a grade above chief warrant officer, W–5, or who is transferred from an inactive status to an active status and placed on the active-duty list or the reserve active-status list may, effective on the date on which he is placed on the active-duty list or reserve active-status list, be changed by the Secretary concerned to a later date to reflect such officer’s qualifications and experience. The authority to change the date of rank of a reserve officer who is placed on the active-duty list to a later date does not apply in the case of an officer who (A) has served continuously in the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve since the officer’s last promotion, or (B) is placed on the active-duty list while on a promotion list as described in <ref>section 14317(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned may adjust the date of rank of an officer appointed under <ref>section 624(a) of this title</ref> to a higher grade that is not a general officer or flag officer grade if the appointment of that officer to that grade is delayed from the date on which (as determined by the Secretary) it would otherwise have been made by reason of unusual circumstances (as determined by the Secretary) that cause an unintended delay in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the processing or approval of the report of the selection board recommending the appointment of that officer to that grade; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the processing or approval of the promotion list established on the basis of that report.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The adjusted date of rank applicable to the grade of an officer under subparagraph (A) shall be consistent—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> with the officer’s position on the promotion list for that grade and competitive category when additional officers in that grade and competitive category were needed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with compliance with the applicable authorized strengths for officers in that grade and competitive category.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The adjusted date of rank applicable to the grade of an officer under subparagraph (A) shall be the effective date for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the officer’s pay and allowances for that grade; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the officer’s position on the active-duty list.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> When under subparagraph (A) the Secretary concerned adjusts the date of rank of an officer in a grade to which the officer was appointed by and with the advice and consent of the Senate and the adjustment is to a date before the date of the advice and consent of the Senate to that appointment, the Secretary shall promptly transmit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate a notification of that adjustment. Any such notification shall include the name of the officer and a discussion of the reasons for the adjustment of date of rank.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any adjustment in date of rank under this paragraph shall be made under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, which shall apply uniformly among the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 33</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2869</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(h)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 127</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1106</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(11)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 25(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2873</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1131(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1505</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1626</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2962</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 495</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1089</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(1)(G)</ref>, (3)(M), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3820</ref>, 3821; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1741(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 742.</num>
<heading> Rank: warrant officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Among warrant officer grades, warrant officer grades of a higher numerical designation are senior to warrant officer grades of a lower numerical designation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Rank among warrant officers of the same grade, and date of rank of warrant officers, is determined in the same manner as prescribed in <ref>section 741 of this title</ref> for officers in grades above warrant officer grades.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1114(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1502</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 743.</num>
<heading> Rank: Chief of Staff of the Army; Chief of Naval Operations; Chief of Staff of the Air Force; Commandant of the Marine Corps; Chief of Space Operations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief of Staff of the Army, the Chief of Naval Operations, the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, the Commandant of the Marine Corps, and the Chief of Space Operations rank among themselves according to dates of appointment to those offices, and rank above all other officers on the active-duty list of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force, except the Chairman and the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 501(11)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1010</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XIII, § 1314(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(5)(A), <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(1)(H)</ref>, (20)(A), (B), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3820</ref>, 3823.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 744.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2103</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 745.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1114(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1502</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 747.</num>
<heading> Command: when different commands of Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, and Coast Guard join</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When different commands of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, and Coast Guard join or serve together, the officer highest in rank in the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, or Coast Guard on duty there, who is otherwise eligible to command, commands all those forces unless otherwise directed by the President.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 5(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 760</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(2)(A)(iv)</ref>, (B), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 749.</num>
<heading> Command: commissioned officers in same grade or corresponding grades on duty at same place</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, or Coast Guard, as the case may be, has on duty in the same area, field command, or organization two or more commissioned officers of the same grade who are otherwise eligible to command, the President may assign the command without regard to rank in that grade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When officers of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, or Coast Guard are on duty in the same area, field, command, or organization and two or more commissioned officers of different services, who are otherwise eligible to command, have the same grade or corresponding grades, the President may assign the command without regard to rank in that grade.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 5(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 760</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(2)(A)(v)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 750.</num>
<heading> Command: retired officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A retired officer has no right to command except when on active duty.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2870</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>