<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 50—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS COMMAND RESPONSIBILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 991.</num>
<heading> Management of deployments of members and measurement and data collection of unit operating and personnel tempo</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Management Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The deployment (or potential deployment) of a member of the armed forces shall be managed to ensure that the member is not deployed, or continued in a deployment, on any day on which the total number of days on which the member has been deployed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> out of the preceding 365 days would exceed the one-year high-deployment threshold; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> out of the preceding 730 days would exceed the two-year high-deployment threshold.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “one-year high-deployment threshold” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 220 days; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a lower number of days prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The term “two-year high-deployment threshold” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 400 days; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a lower number of days prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A member may be deployed, or continued in a deployment, without regard to paragraph (1) if the deployment, or continued deployment, is approved by the Secretary of Defense. The authority of the Secretary under the preceding sentence may only be delegated to a civilian officer of the Department of Defense appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe a policy that addresses each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The amount of dwell time a regular member of the armed forces or unit remains at the member’s or unit’s permanent duty station or home port, as the case may be, between deployments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The amount of dwell time a reserve member of the armed forces remains at the member’s permanent duty station after completing a deployment of 30 days or more in length.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deployment Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, a member of the armed forces shall be considered to be deployed or in a deployment on any day on which, pursuant to orders, the member is performing service in a training exercise or operation at a location or under circumstances that make it impossible or infeasible for the member to spend off-duty time in the housing in which the member resides when on garrison duty at the member’s permanent duty station or homeport, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of a member of a reserve component who is performing active service pursuant to orders that do not establish a permanent change of station, the housing referred to in paragraph (1) is any housing (which may include the member’s residence) that the member usually occupies for use during off-duty time when on garrison duty at the member’s permanent duty station or homeport, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this section, a member is not deployed or in a deployment when the member is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> performing service as a student or trainee at a school (including any Government school);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> performing administrative, guard, or detail duties in garrison at the member’s permanent duty station; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> unavailable solely because of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a hospitalization of the member at the member’s permanent duty station or homeport or in the immediate vicinity of the member’s permanent residence; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a disciplinary action taken against the member.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may prescribe a definition of deployment for the purposes of this section other than the definition specified in paragraphs (1) and (2). Any such definition may not take effect until 90 days after the date on which the Secretary notifies the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives of the revised standard definition of deployment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recordkeeping</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish a system for tracking and recording the number of days that each member of the armed forces is deployed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prescribe policies and procedures for measuring operating tempo and personnel tempo; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> maintain a central data collection repository to provide information for research, actuarial analysis, interagency reporting, and evaluation of Department of Defense programs and policies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The data collection repository shall be able to identify—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the active and reserve component units of the armed forces that are participating at the battalion, squadron, or an equivalent level (or a higher level) in contingency operations, major training events, and other exercises and contingencies of such a scale that the exercises and contingencies receive an official designation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the duration of their participation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For each of the armed forces, the data collection repository shall be able to indicate, for a fiscal year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of members who received the high-deployment allowance under <ref>section 436 of title 37</ref> (or who would have been eligible to receive the allowance if the duty assignment was not excluded by the Secretary of Defense);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of members who received each rate of allowance paid (estimated in the case of members described in the parenthetical phrase in subparagraph (A));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number of months each member received the allowance (or would have received it in the case of members described in the parenthetical phrase in subparagraph (A)); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the total amount expended on the allowance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For each of the armed forces, the data collection repository shall be able to indicate, for a fiscal year, the number of days that high demand, low density units (as defined by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff) were deployed, and whether these units met the force goals for limiting deployments, as described in the personnel tempo policies applicable to that armed force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National Security Waiver Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the military department concerned may suspend the applicability of this section to a member or any group of members under the Secretary’s jurisdiction when the Secretary determines that such a waiver is necessary in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Whenever a waiver is in effect under paragraph (1), the member or group of members covered by the waiver shall be subject to specific and measurable deployment thresholds established and maintained for purposes of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Thresholds under this paragraph may be applicable—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> uniformly, Department of Defense-wide; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> separately, with respect to each armed force or the United States Special Operations Command.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> If thresholds under this paragraph are applicable Department-wide, such thresholds shall be established and maintained by the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness. If such thresholds are applicable only to one armed force or the Under States Special Operations Command, such thresholds shall be established and maintained respectively by the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Navy (other than with respect to the Marine Corps), the Secretary of the Air Force, the Commandant of the Marine Corps (with respect to the Marine Corps), and the Commander of the United States Special Operations Command, as applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> In undertaking recordkeeping for purposes of subsection (c), the Under Secretary shall, in conjunction with the officials and officers referred to in subparagraph (C), collect complete and reliable personnel tempo data of members described in subparagraph (A) in order to ensure that the Department, the armed forces, and the United States Special Operations Command fully and completely monitor personnel tempo under any waiver authorized under paragraph (1) and the effect of such waiver on the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to Coast Guard</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not apply to a member of the Coast Guard when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), the term “dwell time” means the time a member of the armed forces or a unit spends at the permanent duty station or home port after returning from a deployment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may modify the definition of dwell time specified in subparagraph (A). If the Secretary establishes a different definition of such term, the Secretary shall transmit the new definition to Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “operating tempo” means the rate at which units of the armed forces are involved in all military activities, including contingency operations, exercises, and training deployments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “personnel tempo” means the amount of time members of the armed forces are engaged in their official duties at a location or under circumstances that make it infeasible for a member to spend off-duty time in the housing in which the member resides.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 586(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 637</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 574(a), (b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–136, 1654A–137; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 515(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1093</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 541(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 522(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1399–1401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 506, 507(a), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1345</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(21)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3871</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 992.</num>
<heading> Financial literacy training: financial services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Financial Literacy Training Program for Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall carry out a program to provide comprehensive financial literacy training to members of the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> financial services that are available under law to members;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> financial services that are routinely offered by private sector sources to members;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> practices relating to the marketing of private sector financial services to members;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such other matters relating to financial services available to members, and the marketing of financial services to members, as the Secretary considers appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> such other financial practices as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Training under this subsection shall be provided to a member of the armed forces—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as a component of the initial entry training of the member;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon arrival at the first duty station of the member;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> upon arrival at each subsequent duty station, in the case of a member in pay grade E–6 or below or in pay grade O–3 or below;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> when the member vests in the Thrift Savings Plan (TSP) under <ref>section 8432(g)(2)(C) of title 5</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> when the member becomes entitled to receive continuation pay under <ref>section 356 of title 37</ref>, at which time the training shall include, at a minimum, information on options available to the member regarding the use of continuation pay;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> at each major life event during the service of the member, such as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> marriage;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> divorce;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> birth of first child; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> disabling sickness or condition;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> during leadership training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> during pre-deployment training and during post-deployment training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> at transition points in the service of the member, such as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> transition from a regular component to a reserve component;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> separation from service; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> retirement; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> as a component of periodically recurring required training that is provided to the member at a military installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The training provided at a military installation under paragraph (2)(J) shall include information on any financial services marketing practices that are particularly prevalent at that military installation and in the vicinity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations setting forth any other events and circumstances (in addition to the events and circumstances described in paragraph (2)) upon which the training required by this subsection shall be provided.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Counseling for Members and Spouses</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall, upon request, provide counseling on financial services to each member of the armed forces, and such member’s spouse, under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of a military installation at which at least 2,000 members of the armed forces on active duty are assigned, the Secretary concerned—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall provide counseling on financial services under this subsection through a full-time financial services counselor at such installation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> shall provide such counseling at such installation—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> through members of the armed forces in pay grade E–7 or above, or civilians, who provide such counseling as part of their other duties for the armed forces or the Department of Defense;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> by contract, including contract for services by telephone and by the Internet; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> through qualified representatives of nonprofit organizations and agencies under formal agreements with the Department of Defense to provide such counseling; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> may not provide financial services through any individual unless such individual agrees to submit financial disclosures annually to the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of any military installation not described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned shall provide counseling on financial services under this subsection at such installation in accordance with the requirements established under subparagraph (A)(ii) and (iii).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each financial services counselor under paragraph (2)(A)(i), and any other individual providing counseling on financial services under paragraph (2), shall be an individual who, by reason of education, training, or experience, is qualified to provide helpful counseling to members of the armed forces and their spouses on financial services and marketing practices described in subsection (a)(1). Such individual may be a member of the armed forces or an employee of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall take such action as is necessary to ensure that each financial services counselor under paragraph (2)(A)(i), and any other individual providing counseling on financial services under paragraphs (2), is free from conflicts of interest relevant to the performance of duty under this section and, in the performance of that duty, is dedicated to furnishing members of the armed forces and their spouses with helpful information and counseling on financial services and related marketing practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In carrying out the requirements of subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned shall establish a requirement that each financial services counselor under paragraph (2)(A)(i), and any other individual providing counseling on financial services under paragraph (2), submit financial disclosures annually to the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned shall review all financial disclosures submitted pursuant to subparagraph (B) to ensure the counselor, or the individual providing counseling, is free from conflict as required under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> If the Secretary concerned determines that a financial services counselor under paragraph (2)(A)(i), or any other individual providing counseling on financial services under paragraph (2), is not free from conflict as required under this paragraph, the Secretary shall ensure that the counselor, or the individual providing counseling, does not provide such services until such time as the Secretary determines that such conflict is resolved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Life Insurance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In counseling a member of the armed forces, or spouse of a member of the armed forces, under this section regarding life insurance offered by a private sector source, a financial services counselor under subsection (b)(2)(A)(i), or another individual providing counseling on financial services under subsection (b)(2), shall furnish the member or spouse, as the case may be, with information on the availability of Servicemembers’ Group Life Insurance under subchapter III of chapter 19 of title 38, including information on the amounts of coverage available and the procedures for electing coverage and the amount of coverage.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provision of Retirement Information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In each training under subsection (a) and in each meeting to provide counseling under subsection (b), a member of the armed forces shall be provided with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all forms relating to retirement that are relevant to the member, including with respect to the Thrift Savings Plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> information with respect to how to find additional information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Financial Literacy and Preparedness Survey</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director of the Defense Manpower Data Center shall annually include in the status of forces survey a survey of the status of the financial literacy and preparedness of members of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The results of the annual financial literacy and preparedness survey—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be used by each of the Secretaries concerned as a benchmark to evaluate and update training provided under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be submitted to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Financial Services Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “financial services” includes the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Life insurance, casualty insurance, and other insurance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Investments in securities or financial instruments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Banking, credit, loans, deferred payment plans, and mortgages.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Health insurance, budget management, Thrift Savings Plan (TSP), retirement lump sum payments (including rollover options and tax consequences), and Survivor Benefit Plan (SBP).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 578(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3274</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VI, § 661(b)</ref>–(e)(1), <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 857</ref>, 858; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 524(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 253</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 541</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1891</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 993.</num>
<heading> Notification of permanent reduction of sizable numbers of members of the armed forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned shall notify Congress under subsection (b) of a plan to reduce more than 1,000 members of the armed forces assigned at a military installation. In calculating the number of members to be reduced, the Secretary shall take into consideration both direct reductions and indirect reductions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No irrevocable action may be taken to effect or implement a reduction described under subsection (a) until—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> submits to Congress a notice of the proposed reduction and the number of military and civilian personnel assignments affected, including reductions in base operations support services and personnel to occur because of the proposed reduction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes in the notice a justification for the reduction and an evaluation of the costs and benefits of the reduction and of the local economic, strategic, and operational consequences of the reduction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a period of 90 days expires following the day on which the notice is submitted to Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Base closure process</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsections (a) and (b) do not apply in the case of the realignment of a military installation pursuant to a base closure law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National security or emergency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsections (a) and (b) do not apply if the President certifies to Congress that the reduction in military personnel at a military installation must be implemented for reasons of national security or a military emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “indirect reduction” means subsequent planned reductions or relocations in base operations support services and personnel able to occur due to the direct reductions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “military installation” means a base, camp, post, station, yard, center, homeport facility for any ship, or other activity under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, including any leased facility, which is located within any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or Guam. Such term does not include any facility used primarily for civil works, rivers and harbors projects, or flood control projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2864(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1702</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2851</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 994.</num>
<heading> Military working dogs: veterinary care for retired military working dogs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish and maintain a system to provide for the veterinary care of retired military working dogs. No funds may be provided by the Federal Government for this purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Dogs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A retired military working dog eligible for veterinary care under this section is any military working dog adopted under <ref>section 2583 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards of Care</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The veterinary care provided under the system authorized by this section shall meet such standards as the Secretary shall establish and from time to time update.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title III, § 371(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 995.</num>
<heading> Accountability for contractors using military working dogs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Reporting Requirement for Contractors</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each covered contract shall specify that the contractor is required to submit to the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller), on an annual basis for the duration of the covered contract, a report containing an identification of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of military working dogs that are in the possession of the covered contractor and located outside of the continental United States in support of a military operation, if any; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the primary location of any such military working dogs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Contract Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section the term “covered contract” means a contract that the Secretary of Defense determines involves military working dogs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 382(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2543</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>