<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 143—</num>
<heading>PRODUCTION BY MILITARY AGENCIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2421.</num>
<heading> Plantations and farms: operation, maintenance, and improvement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Appropriations for the subsistence of members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force are available for expenditures necessary in the operation, maintenance, and improvement of any plantation or farm, outside the United States and under the jurisdiction of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force, as the case may be, for furnishing fresh fruits and vegetables to the armed forces. However, no land may be acquired under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Fruits and vegetables produced under subsection (a) that are over the amount furnished or sold to the armed forces or to civilians serving with the armed forces may be sold only outside the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Of the persons employed by the United States under subsection (a), only nationals of the United States are entitled to the benefits provided by laws relating to the employment, work, compensation, or other benefits of civilian employees of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A plantation or farm covered by subsection (a) shall be operated, maintained, and improved by a private contractor or lessee, so far as practicable. Before using members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force, as the case may be, the Secretary concerned must make a reasonable effort to make a contract or lease with a person in civil life for his services for that operation, maintenance, or improvement, on terms advantageous to the United States. A determination by the Secretary as to the reasonableness of effort to make a contract or lease, and as to the advantageous nature of its terms, is final.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority under this section shall terminate on <date date="2018-09-30">September 30, 2018</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 833(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(FF)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3822</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2422.</num>
<heading> Bakery and dairy products: procurement outside the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may authorize any element of the Department of Defense that procures bakery and dairy products for use by the armed forces outside the United States to procure any products described in subsection (b) through the use of procedures other than competitive procedures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The products referred to in subsection (a) are bakery or dairy products produced by the Army and Air Force Exchange Service in a facility outside the United States that began operating before <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title III, § 312(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2423.</num>
<heading> Laundry and dry cleaning services: procurement from facilities operated by the Navy Resale and Services Support Office</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may authorize an element of the Department of Defense to enter into a contract (through the use of procedures other than competitive procedures) with a laundry and dry cleaning facility operated by the Navy Resale and Services Support Office to procure laundry and dry cleaning services for the armed forces outside the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) shall apply only with respect to a laundry and dry cleaning facility of the Navy Resale and Services Support Office that began operating before <date date="1989-10-01">October 1, 1989</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 323(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1414</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2424.</num>
<heading> Procurement of supplies and services from exchange stores outside the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may authorize an element of the Department of Defense to enter into a contract (through the use of procedures other than competitive procedures) with an exchange store operated under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of a military department outside the United States to procure supplies or services for use by the armed forces outside the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A contract may not be entered into under subsection (a) in an amount in excess of $100,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Supplies provided under a contract entered into under subsection (a) shall be provided from the stocks of the exchange store on hand as of the date the contract is entered into with that exchange store.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A contract entered into with an exchange store under subsection (a) may not provide for the procurement of services not regularly provided by that exchange store.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) do not apply to contracts for the procurement of soft drinks that are manufactured in the United States. The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe in regulations the standards and procedures for determining whether a particular beverage is a soft drink and whether the beverage was manufactured in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 324(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1414</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title III, § 3066</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3337</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(b)(17)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 673</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI, § 671</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3319</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>