<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 39—</num>
<heading>ACTIVE DUTY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 671.</num>
<heading> Members not to be assigned outside United States before completing training</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A member of the armed forces may not be assigned to active duty on land outside the United States and its territories and possessions until the member has completed the basic training requirements of the armed force of which he is a member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In time of war or a national emergency declared by Congress or the President, the period of required basic training (or its equivalent) may not (except as provided in subsection (c)) be less than 12 weeks.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A period of basic training (or equivalent training) shorter than 12 weeks may be established by the Secretary concerned for members of the armed forces who have been credentialed in a medical profession or occupation and are serving in a health-care occupational specialty, as determined under regulations prescribed under paragraph (2). Any such period shall be established under regulations prescribed under paragraph (2) and may be established notwithstanding section 4(a) of the Military Selective Service Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3803(a)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, shall prescribe regulations for the purposes of paragraph (1). The regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense shall apply uniformly to the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–106, title VIII, § 802(b)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-07">Oct. 7, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3863</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 511</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1648</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1081(b)(1)(A)(v)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 671a.</num>
<heading> Members: service extension during war</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless terminated at an earlier date by the Secretary concerned, the period of active service of any member of an armed force is extended for the duration of any war in which the United States may be engaged and for six months thereafter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 1(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 671b.</num>
<heading> Members: service extension when Congress is not in session</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, when the President determines that the national interest so requires, he may, if Congress is not in session, having adjourned sine die, authorize the Secretary of Defense to extend for not more than six months enlistments, appointments, periods of active duty, periods of active duty for training, periods of obligated service, or other military status, in any component of the armed forces, that expire before the thirtieth day after Congress next convenes or reconvenes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An extension under this section continues until the sixtieth day after Congress next convenes or reconvenes or until the expiration of the period of extension specified by the Secretary of Defense, whichever occurs earlier, unless sooner terminated by law or Executive order.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 1(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 753</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VI, § 653(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 672.</num>
<heading> Reference to chapter 1209</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Provisions of law relating to service of members of reserve components on active duty are set forth in chapter 1209 of this title (beginning with section 12301).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 673.</num>
<heading> Consideration of application for permanent change of station or unit transfer for members on active duty who are the victim of a sexual assault or related offense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timely Consideration and Action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned shall provide for timely determination and action on an application for consideration of a change of station or unit transfer submitted by a member of the armed forces serving on active duty who was a victim of a sexual assault or other offense covered by section 920, 920c, or 930 of this title (article 120, 120c, or 130 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice) so as to reduce the possibility of retaliation against the member for reporting the sexual assault or other offense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned shall issue regulations to carry out this section, within guidelines provided by the Secretary of Defense. These guidelines shall provide that the application submitted by a member described in subsection (a) for a change of station or unit transfer must be approved or disapproved by the member’s commanding officer within five calendar days of the submission of the application. Additionally, if the application is disapproved by the commanding officer, the member shall be given the opportunity to request review by the first general officer or flag officer in the chain of command of the member, and that decision must be made within five calendar days of submission of the request for review.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 582(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1432</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1091(a)(8)</ref>, title XVII, § 1712, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 876</ref>, 963; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(c)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 531(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3601</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 673a.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12303]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 673b.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12304]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 673c.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12305]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 674.</num>
<heading> Temporary administrative reassignment or removal of a member on active duty accused of committing a sexual assault or related offense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidance for Timely Consideration and Action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned may provide guidance, within guidelines provided by the Secretary of Defense, for commanders regarding their authority to make a timely determination, and to take action, regarding whether a member of the armed forces serving on active duty who is alleged to have committed an offense under section 920, 920b, 920c, or 930 of this title (article 120, 120b, 120c, or 130 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice) or an attempt to commit such an offense as punishable under <ref>section 880 of this title</ref> (article 80 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice) should be temporarily reassigned or removed from a position of authority or from an assignment, not as a punitive measure, but solely for the purpose of maintaining good order and discipline within the member’s unit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time for Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A determination described in subsection (a) may be made at any time after receipt of notification of an unrestricted report of a sexual assault or other sex-related offense that identifies the member as an alleged perpetrator.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XVII, § 1713(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 963</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(f)(8)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3510</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1599</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 675.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12307]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 676.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12308]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 677.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12309]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 678.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12310]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 679.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12311]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 680.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12312]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 681.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12313]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 682.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12314]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 683.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12315]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 684.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12316]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 685.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12317]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 686.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12318]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 687.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 12319]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 688.</num>
<heading> Retired members: authority to order to active duty; duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, a member described in subsection (b) may be ordered to active duty by the Secretary of the military department concerned at any time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Members</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (d), subsection (a) applies to the following members of the armed forces:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A retired member of the Regular Army, Regular Navy, Regular Air Force, or Regular Marine Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A member of the Retired Reserve who was retired under section 1293, 7311, 7314, 8323, 9311, or 9314 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A member of the Fleet Reserve or Fleet Marine Corps Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A retired member of the Space Force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties of Member Ordered to Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary concerned may, to the extent consistent with other provisions of law, assign a member ordered to active duty under this section to such duties as the Secretary considers necessary in the interests of national defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of Officers Retired on Selective Early Retirement Basis</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The following officers may not be ordered to active duty under this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An officer who retired under <ref>section 638 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An officer who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> after having been notified that the officer was to be considered for early retirement under <ref>section 638 of this title</ref> by a board convened under <ref>section 611(b) of this title</ref> and before being considered by that board, requested retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> was retired pursuant to that request.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation of Period of Recall Service</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A member ordered to active duty under subsection (a) may not serve on active duty pursuant to orders under that subsection for more than 12 months within the 24 months following the first day of the active duty to which ordered under that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) does not apply to the following officers:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A chaplain who is assigned to duty as a chaplain for the period of active duty to which ordered.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A health care professional (as characterized by the Secretary concerned) who is assigned to duty as a health care professional for the period of active duty to which ordered.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An officer assigned to duty with the American Battle Monuments Commission for the period of active duty to which ordered.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> An officer who is assigned to duty as a defense attaché or service attaché for the period of active duty to which ordered.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver for Periods of War or National Emergency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsections (d) and (e) do not apply in time of war or of national emergency declared by Congress or the President.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2515</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 509(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1091</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(4)(I)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1719A(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 664</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 688a.</num>
<heading> Authority to order to active duty in high-demand, low-density assignments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may order to active duty a retired member who agrees to serve on active duty in an assignment intended to alleviate a high-demand, low-density military capability or in any other specialty designated by the Secretary as critical to meet wartime or peacetime requirements. Any such order may be made only with the consent of the member ordered to active duty and in accordance with an agreement between the Secretary and the member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The period of active duty of a member under an order to active duty under subsection (a) shall be specified in the agreement entered into under that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No more than a total of 1,000 members may be on active duty at any time under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority to order a retired member to active duty under this section is in addition to the authority under <ref>section 688 of this title</ref> or any other provision of law authorizing the Secretary concerned to order a retired member to active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of Certain Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Retired members ordered to active duty under subsection (a) shall not be counted for purposes of section 688 or 690 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions During Periods of War or National Emergency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The limitation in subsection (c) shall not apply during a time of war or of national emergency declared by Congress or the President.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">High-Demand, Low-Density Military Capability Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “high-demand, low-density military capability” means a combat, combat support or service support capability, unit, system, or occupational specialty that the Secretary of Defense determines has funding, equipment, or personnel levels that are substantially below the levels required to fully meet or sustain actual or expected operational requirements set by regional commanders.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 503(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2530</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VI, § 621(b)</ref>, (d)(2)(A), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2254</ref>, 2255; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 531(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4215</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 527</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1383</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 511</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3587</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 249</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 689.</num>
<heading> Retired members: grade in which ordered to active duty and upon release from active duty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Rule for Grade in Which Ordered to Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), a retired member ordered to active duty under section 688 or 688a of this title shall be ordered to active duty in the member’s retired grade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members Retired in O–</inline>9 <inline class="small-caps">and O–</inline>10 <inline class="small-caps">Grades</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A retired member ordered to active duty under section 688 or 688a of this title whose retired grade is above the grade of major general or rear admiral shall be ordered to active duty in the highest permanent grade held by such member while serving on active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members Who Previously Served in Grade Higher Than Retired Grade</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A retired member ordered to active duty under section 688 or 688a of this title who has previously served on active duty satisfactorily, as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned, in a grade higher than that member’s retired grade may be ordered to active duty in the highest grade in which the member had so served satisfactorily, except that such a member may not be so ordered to active duty in a grade above major general or rear admiral.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A retired member ordered to active duty in a grade that is higher than the member’s retired grade pursuant to subsection (a) shall be treated for purposes of <ref>section 690 of this title</ref> as if the member was promoted to that higher grade while on that tour of active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If, upon being released from that tour of active duty, such a retired member has served on active duty satisfactorily, as determined by the Secretary concerned, for not less than a total of 36 months in a grade that is a higher grade than the member’s retired grade, the member is entitled to placement on the retired list in that grade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Grade Upon Release From Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member ordered to active duty under section 688 or 688a of this title who, while on active duty, is promoted to a grade that is higher than that member’s retired grade is entitled, upon that member’s release from that tour of active duty, to placement on the retired list in the highest grade in which the member served on active duty satisfactorily, as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned, for not less than six months.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2516</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 503(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2531</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 690.</num>
<heading> Retired members ordered to active duty: limitation on number</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General and Flag Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not more than 15 retired general officers of the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force, and not more than 15 retired flag officers of the Navy, may be on active duty at any one time. For the purposes of this subsection a retired officer ordered to active duty for a period of 60 days or less is not counted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation by Service</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not more than 25 officers of any one armed force may be serving on active duty concurrently pursuant to orders to active duty issued under <ref>section 688 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the administration of paragraph (1), the following officers shall not be counted:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A chaplain who is assigned to duty as a chaplain for the period of active duty to which ordered.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A health care professional (as characterized by the Secretary concerned) who is assigned to duty as a health care professional for the period of the active duty to which ordered.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any officer assigned to duty with the American Battle Monuments Commission for the period of active duty to which ordered.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any member of the Retiree Council of the Army, Navy, or Air Force for the period on active duty to attend the annual meeting of the Retiree Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> An officer who is assigned to duty as a defense attaché or service attaché for the period of active duty to which ordered.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver for Periods of War or National Emergency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) does not apply in time of war or of national emergency declared by Congress or the President after <date date="1980-11-30">November 30, 1980</date>. Subsection (b) does not apply in time of war or of national emergency declared by Congress or the President.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2516</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 591</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1091</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1741(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 691.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title IV, § 402(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2551</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>