<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 16—</num>
<heading>SECURITY COOPERATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The terms “appropriate congressional committees” and “appropriate committees of Congress” mean—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “defense article” has the meaning given that term in section 644 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2403</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “defense service” has the meaning given that term in section 644 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2403</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “developing country” has the meaning prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for purposes of this chapter in accordance with section 1241(n) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “incremental expenses”, with respect to a foreign country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means the reasonable and proper costs of rations, fuel, training ammunition, transportation, and other goods and services consumed by the country as a direct result of the country’s participation in activities authorized by this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any form of lethal assistance (excluding training ammunition); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> pay, allowances, and other normal costs of the personnel of the country.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The term “national security forces”, in the case of a foreign country, means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> National military and national-level security forces of the foreign country that have the functional responsibilities for which training is authorized in <ref>section 333(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> With respect to operations referred to in <ref>section 333(a)(2) of this title</ref>, military and civilian first responders of the foreign country at the national or local level that have such operations among their functional responsibilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> The term “security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense” means any program, activity (including an exercise), or interaction of the Department of Defense with the security establishment of a foreign country to achieve a purpose as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To build and develop allied and friendly security capabilities for self-defense and multinational operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To provide the armed forces with access to the foreign country during peacetime or a contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To build relationships that promote specific United States security interests.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “small-scale construction” means construction at a cost not to exceed $2,000,000 for any project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “training” has the meaning given the term “military education and training” in section 644 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2403</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2498</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1203(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XII, § 1203(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 441</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>MILITARY-TO-MILITARY ENGAGEMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 311.</num>
<heading> Exchange of defense personnel between United States and friendly foreign countries: authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Enter Into International Exchange Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may enter into international defense personnel exchange agreements. Any exchange of personnel under such an agreement is subject to paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section, an international defense personnel exchange agreement is an agreement with the government of a friendly foreign country or international or regional security organization for the reciprocal or non-reciprocal exchange of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> members of the armed forces and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> military and civilian personnel of the defense or security ministry of that foreign government or international or regional security organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> An exchange of personnel under an international defense personnel exchange agreement under this section may only be made with the concurrence of the Secretary of State to the extent the exchange is with either of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A non-defense security ministry of a foreign government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An international or regional security organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assignment of Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Pursuant to an international defense personnel exchange agreement, personnel of the defense ministry of a foreign government may be assigned to positions in the Department of Defense and personnel of the Department of Defense may be assigned to positions in the defense ministry of such foreign government. Positions to which exchanged personnel are assigned may include positions of instructors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An agreement for the exchange of personnel engaged in research and development activities may provide for assignment of Department of Defense personnel to positions in private industry that support the defense ministry of the host foreign government, subject to the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An individual may not be assigned to a position pursuant to an international defense personnel exchange agreement unless the assignment is acceptable to both governments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reciprocity of Personnel Qualifications Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of an international defense personnel exchange agreement that provides for reciprocal exchanges, each government shall be required to provide personnel with qualifications, training, and skills that are essentially equal to those of the personnel provided by the other government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of Personnel Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each government shall pay the salary, per diem, cost of living, travel costs, cost of language or other training, and other costs for its own personnel in accordance with the applicable laws and regulations of such government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) does not apply to the following costs:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The cost of temporary duty directed by the host government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The cost of training programs conducted to familiarize, orient, or certify exchanged personnel regarding unique aspects of the assignments of the exchanged personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Costs incident to the use of the facilities of the host government in the performance of assigned duties.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibited Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No personnel exchanged pursuant to an agreement under this section may take or be required to take an oath of allegiance to the host country or to hold an official capacity in the government of such country.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirements in subsections (c) and (d) shall apply in the exercise of any authority of the Secretaries of the military departments to enter into an agreement with the government of a foreign country to provide for the exchange of members of the armed forces and military personnel of the defense or security ministry of that foreign country. The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations for the application of such subsections in the exercise of such authority.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1242(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2512</ref>, 2513; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1204(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2017</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 312.</num>
<heading> Payment of personnel expenses necessary for theater security cooperation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may pay expenses specified in subsection (b) that the Secretary considers necessary for theater security cooperation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Types of Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The expenses that may be paid under the authority provided in subsection (a) are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may pay travel, subsistence, and similar personnel expenses of, and special compensation for, the following that the Secretary considers necessary for theater security cooperation:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Defense personnel of friendly foreign governments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> With the concurrence of the Secretary of State, other personnel of friendly foreign governments and non-governmental personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative services and support for liaison officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may provide administrative services and support for the performance of duties by a liaison officer of a foreign country while the liaison officer is assigned temporarily to any headquarters in the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel, subsistence, and medical care for liaison officers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may pay the expenses of a liaison officer in connection with the assignment of that officer as described in paragraph (2) if the assignment is requested by the commander of a combatant command, the Chief of Staff of the Army, the Chief of Naval Operations, the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, the Commandant of the Marine Corps, the Chief of Space Operations, or the head of a Defense Agency as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Travel and subsistence expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Personal expenses directly necessary to carry out the duties of that officer in connection with that assignment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Expenses for medical care at a civilian medical facility if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> adequate medical care is not available to the liaison officer at a local military medical treatment facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that payment of such medical expenses is necessary and in the best interests of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> medical care is not otherwise available to the liaison officer pursuant to any treaty or other international agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Mission-related travel expenses if such travel meets each of the following conditions:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The travel is in support of the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The officer or official making the request directs round-trip travel from the assigned location to one or more travel locations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conferences, seminars, and similar meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided by paragraph (1) includes authority to pay travel and subsistence expenses for personnel described in that paragraph in connection with the attendance of such personnel at any conference, seminar, or similar meeting that is in direct support of enhancing interoperability between the United States armed forces and the national security forces of a friendly foreign country for the purposes of conducting operations, the provision of equipment or training, or the planning for, or the execution of, bilateral or multilateral training, exercises, or military operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to the personnel expenses payable under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense may pay such other limited expenses in connection with conferences, seminars, and similar meetings covered by paragraph (4) as the Secretary considers appropriate in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Expenses Payable.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel from developing countries</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority provided in subsection (a) may be used only for the payment of expenses of, and special compensation for, personnel from developing countries, except that the Secretary of Defense may authorize the payment of such expenses and special compensation for personnel from a country other than a developing country if the Secretary determines that such payment is necessary to respond to extraordinary circumstances and is in the national security interest of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-defense liaison officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a non-defense liaison officer of a foreign country, the authority of the Secretary of Defense under subsection (a) to pay expenses specified in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (b) may be exercised only if the assignment of that liaison officer as a liaison officer with the Department of Defense was accepted by the Secretary of Defense with the coordination of the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may provide the services and support specified in subsection (b)(2) with or without reimbursement from (or on behalf of) the recipients. The terms of reimbursement (if any) shall be specified in the appropriate agreements used to assign the liaison officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Monetary Limitations on Expenses Payable.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel and subsistence expenses generally</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Travel and subsistence expenses authorized to be paid under subsection (a) may not, in the case of any individual, exceed the amount that would be paid under chapter 7 or 8 of title 37 to a member of the armed forces (of a comparable grade) for authorized travel of a similar nature.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Travel and related expenses of liaison officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount paid for expenses specified in subsection (b)(3) for any liaison officer in any fiscal year may not exceed $150,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section. Such regulations shall be submitted to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative Services and Support Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “administrative services and support” includes base or installation support services, office space, utilities, copying services, fire and police protection, training programs conducted to familiarize, orient, or certify liaison personnel regarding unique aspects of the assignments of the liaison personnel, and computer support.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1243(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2514</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3823</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 313.</num>
<heading> Bilateral or regional cooperation programs: awards and mementos to recognize superior noncombat achievements or performance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may present awards and mementos purchased with funds appropriated for operation and maintenance of the armed forces to recognize superior noncombat achievements or performance by members of friendly foreign forces and other foreign nationals that significantly enhance or support the National Security Strategy of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Activities That May Be Recognized</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Activities that may be recognized under subsection (a) include superior achievement or performance that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> plays a crucial role in shaping the international security environment in ways that protect and promote United States interests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> supports or enhances United States overseas presence and peacetime engagement activities, including defense cooperation initiatives, security assistance training and programs, and training and exercises with the armed forces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> helps to deter aggression and coercion, build coalitions, and promote regional stability; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> serves as a role model for appropriate conduct by military forces in emerging democracies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Expenditures for the purchase or production of mementos for award under this section may not exceed the minimal value in effect under <ref>section 7342(a)(5) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XII, § 1222(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1652</ref>, § 1051b; renumbered § 313, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2500</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>TRAINING WITH FOREIGN FORCES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 321.</num>
<heading> Training with friendly foreign countries: payment of training and exercise expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Training Authorized.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training with foreign forces generally</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense may train with the military forces or other security forces of a friendly foreign country if the Secretary determines that it is in the national security interest of the United States to do so.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on training of general purpose forces</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The general purpose forces of the United States armed forces may train only with the military forces of a friendly foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training to support mission essential tasks</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any training conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, support the mission essential tasks for which the unit of the United States armed forces participating in such training is responsible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of training</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any training conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, include elements that promote—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> observance of and respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> respect for legitimate civilian authority within the foreign country concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Pay Training and Exercise Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (e), the Secretary of a military department or the commander of a combatant command may pay, or authorize payment for, any of the following expenses:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Expenses of training forces assigned or allocated to that command in conjunction with training, and training with, the military forces or other security forces of a friendly foreign country under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Expenses of deploying such forces for that training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The incremental expenses of a friendly foreign country as the direct result of participating in such training, as specified in the regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The incremental expenses of a friendly foreign country as the direct result of participating in an exercise with the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Small-scale construction that is directly related to the effective accomplishment of the training described in paragraph (1) or an exercise described in paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Purpose of Training and Exercises.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The primary purpose of the training and exercises for which payment may be made under subsection (b) shall be to train United States forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection of foreign partners</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Training and exercises with friendly foreign countries under subsection (a) should be planned and prioritized consistent with applicable guidance relating to the security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds for Activities That Cross Fiscal Years</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts available for the authority to pay expenses in subsection (b) for a fiscal year may be used to pay expenses under that subsection for training and exercises that begin in such fiscal year but end in the next fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quarterly Notice on Planned Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than the end of the first calendar quarter beginning after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017, and every calendar quarter thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a notice setting forth the schedule of planned training engagement pursuant to subsection (a) during the calendar quarter first following the calendar quarter in which such notice is submitted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Regulations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section. The Secretary shall submit the regulations to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The regulations required under this section shall provide the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A requirement that training and exercise activities may be carried out under this section only with the prior approval of the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Accounting procedures to ensure that the expenditures pursuant to this section are appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Procedures to limit the payment of incremental expenses to friendly foreign countries only to developing countries, except in the case of exceptional circumstances as specified in the regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIII, § 1321(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3988</ref>, § 2010; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(35)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title XII, § 1203(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1061(12)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1583</ref>; renumbered § 321 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1244(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1204(c)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2017</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 322.</num>
<heading> Special operations forces: training with friendly foreign forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Pay Training Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Under regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (c), the commander of the special operations command established pursuant to <ref>section 167 of this title</ref> and the commander of any other unified or specified combatant command may pay, or authorize payment for, any of the following expenses:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Expenses of training special operations forces assigned to that command in conjunction with training, and training with, armed forces and other security forces of a friendly foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Expenses of deploying such special operations forces for that training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of training in conjunction with a friendly developing country, the incremental expenses incurred by that country as the direct result of such training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose of Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The primary purpose of the training for which payment may be made under subsection (a) shall be to train the special operations forces of the combatant command.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section. The regulations shall require that training activities may be carried out under this section only with the prior approval of the Secretary of Defense. The regulations shall establish accounting procedures to ensure that the expenditures pursuant to this section are appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “special operations forces” includes civil affairs forces and military information support operations forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “incremental expenses”, with respect to a developing country, means the reasonable and proper cost of rations, fuel, training ammunition, transportation, and other goods and services consumed by such country, except that the term does not include pay, allowances, and other normal costs of such country’s personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than April 1 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report regarding training during the preceding fiscal year for which expenses were paid under this section. Each report shall specify the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> All countries in which that training was conducted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The type of training conducted, including whether such training was related to counter-narcotics or counter-terrorism activities, the duration of that training, the number of members of the armed forces involved, and expenses paid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The extent of participation by foreign military forces, including the number and service affiliation of foreign military personnel involved and physical and financial contribution of each host nation to the training effort.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The relationship of that training to other overseas training programs conducted by the armed forces, such as military exercise programs sponsored by the Joint Chiefs of Staff, military exercise programs sponsored by a combatant command, and military training activities sponsored by a military department (including deployments for training, short duration exercises, and other similar unit training events).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A summary of the expenditures under this section resulting from the training for which expenses were paid under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A discussion of the unique military training benefit to United States special operations forces derived from the training activities for which expenses were paid under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1052(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1470</ref>, § 2011; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1503(a)(18)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1062</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2129</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1086(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1603</ref>; renumbered § 322, <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1244(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2518</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>SUPPORT FOR OPERATIONS AND CAPACITY BUILDING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 331.</num>
<heading> Friendly foreign countries: authority to provide support for conduct of operations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may provide support to friendly foreign countries in connection with the conduct of operations designated pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Designated Operations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall designate the operations for which support may be provided under the authority in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall notify the appropriate committees of Congress of the designation of any operation pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual review for continuing designation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall undertake on an annual basis a review of the operations currently designated pursuant to this subsection in order to determine whether each such operation merits continuing designation for purposes of this section for another year. If the Secretary determines that any operation so reviewed merits continuing designation for purposes of this section for another year, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may continue the designation of such operation under this subsection for such purposes for another year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the Secretary so continues the designation of such operation, shall notify the appropriate committees of Congress of the continuation of designation of such operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Types of Support Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The types of support that may be provided under the authority in subsection (a) are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Logistic support, supplies, and services to security forces of a friendly foreign country participating in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an operation with the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a military or stability operation that benefits the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Logistic support, supplies, and services—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to military forces of a friendly foreign country solely for the purpose of enhancing the interoperability of the logistical support systems of military forces participating in a combined operation with the United States in order to facilitate such operation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to a nonmilitary logistics, security, or similar agency of a friendly foreign government if such provision would directly benefit the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Procurement of equipment for the purpose of the loan of such equipment to the military forces of a friendly foreign country participating in a United States-supported coalition or combined operation and the loan of such equipment to those forces to enhance capabilities or to increase interoperability with the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense and other coalition partners.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Provision of specialized training to personnel of friendly foreign countries in connection with such an operation, including training of such personnel before deployment in connection with such operation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Small-scale construction to support military forces of a friendly foreign country participating in a United States-supported coalition or combined operation when the construction is directly linked to the ability of such forces to participate in such operation effectively and is limited to the geographic area where such operation is taking place. In the case of support provided under this paragraph that results in the provision of small-scale construction above $750,000, the notification pursuant to subsection (b)(2) shall include the location, project title, and cost of each such small-scale construction project that will be carried out, a Department of Defense Form 1391 for each such project, and a masterplan of planned infrastructure investments at the location.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Certification Required.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operations in which the united states is not participating</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may provide support under subsection (a) to a friendly foreign country with respect to an operation in which the United States is not participating only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State jointly certify to the appropriate committees of Congress that the operation is in the national security interests of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after the expiration of the 15-day period beginning on the date of such certification.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accompanying report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any certification under paragraph (1) shall be accompanied by a report that includes the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of the operation, including the geographic area of the operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A list of participating countries.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A description of the type of support and the duration of support to be provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A description of the national security interests of the United States supported by the operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A description of each entity with which the applicable friendly foreign country is engaged in hostilities and whether each such entity is covered by an authorization for the use of military force.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Such other matters as the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State consider significant to a consideration of such certification.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Secretary of State Concurrence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provision of support under subsection (a) may be made only with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support Otherwise Prohibited by Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may not use the authority in subsection (a) to provide any type of support described in subsection (c) that is otherwise prohibited by any provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Value.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The aggregate value of all logistic support, supplies, and services provided under paragraphs (1), (4), and (5) of subsection (c) in any fiscal year may not exceed $450,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The aggregate value of all logistic support, supplies, and services provided under subsection (c)(2) in any fiscal year may not exceed $5,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Logistic Support, Supplies, and Services Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “logistic support, supplies, and services” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2350(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title XII, § 1201(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2410</ref>, § 127c; renumbered § 127d, <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1063(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 321</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(3)</ref>, title XII, § 1202, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4369</ref>, 4385; renumbered § 331 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1245(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2518</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1203(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2823</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 332.</num>
<heading> Friendly foreign countries; international and regional organizations: defense institution capacity building</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ministry of Defense Advisor Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, carry out a program to assign civilian employees of the Department of Defense and members of the armed forces as advisors to the ministries of defense (or security agencies serving a similar defense function) of foreign countries or regional organizations with security missions in order to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide institutional, ministerial-level advice, and other training to personnel of the ministry or regional organization to which assigned in support of stabilization or post-conflict activities; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assist such ministry or regional organization in building core institutional capacity, competencies, and capabilities to manage defense-related processes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Training of Personnel of Foreign Ministries With Security Missions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, carry out a program to provide advisors or trainers to provide training and associated training support services to personnel of foreign ministries of defense (or ministries with security force oversight) or regional organizations with security missions—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> enhancing civilian oversight of foreign security forces;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> establishing responsible defense governance and internal controls in order to help build effective, transparent, and accountable defense institutions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> assessing organizational weaknesses and establishing a roadmap for addressing shortfalls; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> enhancing ministerial, general or joint staff, or service level core management competencies; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for such other purposes as the Secretary considers appropriate, consistent with the authority in subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than February 1 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on activities under the program under paragraph (1) during the preceding fiscal year. Each report shall include, for the fiscal year covered by such report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A list of activities under the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A list of any organization described in paragraph (1) to which the Secretary provided advisors or trainers under the program, including the number of such advisors or trainers so provided, the duration of each provision of such an advisor or trainer, a brief description of the activities of each advisor or trainer so provided, and a statement of the cost of each provision of such an advisor or trainer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A comprehensive justification of any activities conducted pursuant to paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 15 days before assigning a civilian employee of the Department of Defense or a member of the armed forces as an advisor to a regional organization with a security mission under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a notification of such assignment. Such a notification shall include each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A statement of the intent of the Secretary to assign the advisor or trainer to the regional organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The name of the regional organization and the location and duration of the assignment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A description of the assignment, including a description of the training or assistance proposed to be provided to the regional organization, the justification for the assignment, a description of the unique capabilities the advisor or trainer can provide to the regional organization, and a description of how the assignment serves the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any other information relating to the assignment that the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(c)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2500</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XII, § 1204(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1642</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1202</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1202(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2823</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 333.</num>
<heading> Foreign security forces: authority to build capacity</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense is authorized to conduct or support a program or programs to provide training and equipment to the national security forces of one or more foreign countries for the purpose of building the capacity of such forces to conduct one or more of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Counterterrorism operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Counter-weapons of mass destruction operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Counter-illicit drug trafficking operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Counter-transnational organized crime operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Maritime and border security operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Military intelligence operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Air domain awareness operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Operations or activities that contribute to an existing international coalition operation that is determined by the Secretary to be in the national interest of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Cyberspace security and defensive cyberspace operations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Concurrence and Coordination With Secretary of State.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Concurrence in conduct of programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The concurrence of the Secretary of State is required to conduct or support any program authorized by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joint development and planning of programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State shall jointly develop and plan any program carried out pursuant to subsection (a). In developing and planning a program to build the capacity of the national security forces of a foreign country under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense and Secretary of State should jointly consider political, social, economic, diplomatic, and historical factors, if any, of the foreign country that may impact the effectiveness of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation of programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State shall coordinate the implementation of any program under subsection (a). The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State shall each designate an individual responsible for program coordination under this paragraph at the lowest appropriate level in the Department concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination in preparation of certain notices</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any notice required by this section to be submitted to the appropriate committees of Congress shall be prepared in coordination with the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Types of Capacity Building.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized elements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A program under subsection (a) may include the provision and sustainment of defense articles, training, defense services, supplies (including consumables), and small-scale construction supporting security cooperation programs under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A program under subsection (a) shall include elements that promote the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Observance of and respect for the law of armed conflict, human rights and fundamental freedoms, the rule of law, and civilian control of the military.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Institutional capacity building.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Observance of and respect for the law of armed conflict, human rights and fundamental freedoms, the rule of law, and civilian control of the military</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In order to meet the requirement in paragraph (2)(A) with respect to particular national security forces under a program under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall certify, prior to the initiation of the program, that the Department of Defense or the Department of State is already undertaking, or will undertake as part of the security sector assistance provided to the foreign country concerned, training that includes a comprehensive curriculum on the law of armed conflict, human rights and fundamental freedoms, and the rule of law, and that enhances the capacity to exercise responsible civilian control of the military, as applicable, to such national security forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Institutional capacity building</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In order to meet the requirement in paragraph (2)(B) with respect to a particular foreign country under a program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall certify, prior to the initiation of the program, that the Department of Defense or another department or agency is already undertaking, or will undertake as part of the security sector assistance provided to the foreign country concerned, a program of institutional capacity building with appropriate institutions of such foreign country to enhance the capacity of such foreign country to organize, administer, employ, manage, maintain, sustain, or oversee the national security forces of such foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance otherwise prohibited by law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may not use the authority in subsection (a) to provide any type of assistance described in subsection (c) that is otherwise prohibited by any provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on assistance to units that have committed gross violations of human rights</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provision of assistance pursuant to a program under subsection (a) shall be subject to the provisions of <ref>section 362 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration of sustainment support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Sustainment support may not be provided pursuant to a program under subsection (a), or for equipment previously provided by the Department of Defense under any authority available to the Secretary during fiscal year 2015 or 2016, for a period in excess of five years unless the notice on the program pursuant to subsection (e) includes the information specified in paragraph (7) of subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and Wait on Activities Under Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 15 days before initiating activities under a program under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a written and electronic notice of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The foreign country, and specific unit, whose capacity to engage in activities specified in subsection (a) will be built under the program, and the amount, type, and purpose of the support to be provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A detailed evaluation of the capacity of the foreign country and unit to absorb the training or equipment to be provided under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The cost, implementation timeline, and delivery schedule for assistance under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A description of the arrangements, if any, for the sustainment of the program and the estimated cost and source of funds to support sustainment of the capabilities and performance outcomes achieved under the program beyond its completion date, if applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Information, including the amount, type, and purpose, on the security assistance provided the foreign country during the three preceding fiscal years pursuant to authorities under this title, the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, and any other train and equip authorities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A description of the elements of the theater security cooperation plan of the geographic combatant command concerned, and of the interagency integrated country strategy, that will be advanced by the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of a program described in subsection (d)(3), each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A written justification that the provision of sustainment support described in that subsection for a period in excess of five years will enhance the security interest of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To the extent practicable, a plan to transition such sustainment support from funding through the Department to funding through another security sector assistance program of the United States Government or funding through partner nations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> In the case of activities under a program that results in the provision of small-scale construction above $750,000, the location, project title, and cost of each small-scale construction project that will be carried out, a Department of Defense Form 1391 for each such project, and a masterplan of planned infrastructure investments at the location over the next 5 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of a program described in subsection (a), each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of whether assistance under the program could be provided pursuant to other authorities under this title, the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, or any other train and equip authorities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An identification of each such authority described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Semi-Annual Monitoring Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency shall, on a semi-annual basis, submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report setting forth, for the preceding 180 days, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Information, by recipient country, of the delivery and execution status of all defense articles, training, defense services, supplies (including consumables), and small-scale construction under programs under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Information on the timeliness of delivery of defense articles, defense services, supplies (including consumables), and small-scale construction when compared with delivery schedules for such articles, services, supplies, and construction previously provided to Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Information, by recipient country, on the status of funds allocated for programs under subsection (a), including amounts of unobligated funds, unliquidated obligations, and disbursements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Funding.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sole source of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts for programs carried out pursuant to subsection (a) in a fiscal year, and for other purposes in connection with such programs as authorized by this section, may be derived only from amounts authorized to be appropriated for such fiscal year for the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance, Defense-wide, and available for the Defense Security Cooperation Agency for such programs and purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of funds for programs across fiscal years</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts made available in fiscal year 2025 or any subsequent fiscal year to carry out the authority in subsection (a) may be used for programs under that authority that begin in such fiscal year and end not later than the end of the third fiscal year thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Equipment Disposition; Notice and Wait.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may treat as stocks of the Department of Defense—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> equipment procured to carry out a program pursuant to subsection (a) that has not yet been transferred to a foreign country and is no longer needed to support such program or any other program carried out pursuant to such subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> equipment that has been transferred to a foreign country to carry out a program pursuant to subsection (a) and is returned by the foreign country to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and wait</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 15 days before initiating activities under a program under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a written and electronic notice of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The foreign country, and specific unit, whose capacity was intended to be built under the program, and the amount, type, and purpose of the equipment that was to be provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An explanation why the equipment is no longer needed to support such program or another program carried out pursuant to such subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">International Agreements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> allow a foreign country to provide sole-source direction for assistance in support of a program carried out pursuant to subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enter into an agreement with a foreign country to provide such sole-source direction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 72 hours after the Secretary of Defense enters into an agreement under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a written notification that includes the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of the parameters of the agreement, including types of support, objectives, and duration of support and cooperation under the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description and justification of any anticipated use of sole-source direction pursuant to such agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> An assessment of the extent to which the equipment to be provided under the agreement—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> responds to the needs of the foreign country; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> can be sustained by the foreign country.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A determination as to whether the anticipated costs to be incurred under the agreement are fair and reasonable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A certification that the agreement is in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Any other matter relating to the agreement, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2500</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XII, § 1204(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1643</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII</ref>, §§ 1201, 1203(c), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2016</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XII, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1620</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1202(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2823</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XII, § 1203(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 441</ref>, 442; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XII, § 1201(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2093</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 334.</num>
<heading> Administrative support and payment of certain expenses for covered foreign defense personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide administrative services and support to the United Nations Command for the performance of duties by covered foreign defense personnel during the period in which the covered foreign defense personnel are assigned to the United Nations Command or the Neutral Nations Supervisory Commission in accordance with the Korean War Armistice Agreement of 1953; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> pay the expenses specified in subsection (b) for covered foreign defense personnel who are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> from a developing country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assigned to the headquarters of the United Nations Command.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Types of Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The types of expenses that may be paid under the authority of subsection (a)(2) are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Travel and subsistence expenses directly related to the duties of covered foreign defense personnel described in subsection (a)(2) in connection with the assignment of such covered foreign defense personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Personal expenses directly related to carrying out such duties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Expenses for medical care at a military medical facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Expenses for medical care at a civilian medical facility, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> adequate medical care is not available to such covered foreign defense personnel at a local military medical treatment facility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that payment of such medical expenses is necessary and in the best interests of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> medical care is not otherwise available to such covered foreign defense personnel pursuant to a treaty or any other international agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Mission-related travel expenses, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such travel is in direct support of the national interests of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Commander of the United Nations Command directs round-trip travel from the headquarters of the United Nations Command to one or more locations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may provide the administrative services and support and pay the expenses authorized by subsection (a) with or without reimbursement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “administrative services and support” means base or installation support services, facilities use, base operations support, office space, office supplies, utilities, copying services, computer support, communication services, fire and police protection, postal services, bank services, transportation services, housing and temporary billeting (including ancillary services), specialized clothing required to perform assigned duties, temporary loan of special equipment, storage services, training services, and repair and maintenance services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered foreign defense personnel” means members of the military of a foreign country who are assigned to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the United Nations Command; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Neutral Nations Supervisory Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “developing country” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 301(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “Neutral Nations Supervisory Commission” means the delegations from Sweden and Switzerland (or successor delegations) appointed in accordance with the Korean War Armistice Agreement of 1953 or its subsequent agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “United Nations Command” means the headquarters of the United Nations Command, the United Nations Command Military Armistice Commission, the United Nations Command-Rear, and the United Nations Command Honor Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XII, § 1201(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1957</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 335.</num>
<heading> Payment of personnel expenses necessary for participation in training program conducted by Colombia under the United States-Colombia Action Plan for Regional Security</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may pay the expendable training supplies, travel, subsistence, and similar personnel expenses of, and special compensation for, the following that the Secretary considers necessary for participation in the training program conducted by Colombia under the United States-Colombia Action Plan for Regional Security:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Defense personnel of friendly foreign governments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> With the concurrence of the Secretary of State, other personnel of friendly foreign governments and nongovernmental personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the authority provided in subsection (a) may only be used for the payment of such expenses of, and special compensation for, such personnel from developing countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau> The Secretary may authorize the payment of such expenses of, and special compensation for, such personnel from a country other than a developing country if the Secretary determines that such payment is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> necessary to respond to extraordinary circumstances; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the national security interest of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1201(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2822</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 336.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(11)(B)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2921</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>EDUCATIONAL AND TRAINING ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 341.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense State Partnership Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, is authorized to establish a program of activities described in paragraph (2), to support the security cooperation objectives of the United States, between members of the National Guard of a State or territory and any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The military forces of a foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The security forces of a foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Governmental organizations of a foreign country whose primary functions include disaster response or emergency response.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State partnership</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each program established under this subsection shall be known as a “State Partnership”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An activity with forces referred to in subsection (a)(1)(B) or organizations described in subsection (a)(1)(C) under a program established under subsection (a) may be carried out only if the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, determines and notifies the appropriate congressional committees not less than 15 days before initiating such activity that the activity is in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on activities with units that have committed gross violations of human rights</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The conduct of any assistance activities under a program established under subsection (a) shall be subject to the provisions of <ref>section 362 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination of Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall designate a director for each State and territory to be responsible for the coordination of activities under a program established under subsection (a) for such State or territory and reporting on activities under the program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall be carried out in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe for purposes of this section. Such regulations shall include accounting procedures to ensure that expenditures of funds to carry out this section are accounted for and appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Availability of Authorized Funds for Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense, including funds authorized to be appropriated for the Army National Guard and Air National Guard, are authorized to be available—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for payment of costs incurred by the National Guard of a State or territory to conduct activities under a program established under subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for payment of incremental expenses of a foreign country to conduct activities under a program established under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Active duty requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds shall not be available under paragraph (1) for the participation of a member of the National Guard of a State or territory in activities in a foreign country unless the member is on active duty in the Armed Forces at the time of such participation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incremental expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total amount of payments for incremental expenses of foreign countries as authorized under paragraph (1)(B) for activities under programs established under subsection (a) in any fiscal year may not exceed $10,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to supersede any authority under title 10 as in effect on <date date="2013-12-26">December 26, 2013</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1246(a)</ref>–(c), (d)(1), (2)(B), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2520</ref>, 2521; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1210</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2023</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVII, § 1731(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1813</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 342.</num>
<heading> Regional Centers for Security Studies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall administer the Department of Defense Regional Centers for Security Studies in accordance with this section as international venues for bilateral and multilateral research, communication, exchange of ideas, and training involving military and civilian participants.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regional Centers Specified</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A Department of Defense Regional Center for Security Studies is a Department of Defense institution that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is operated, and designated as such, by the Secretary of Defense for the study of security issues relating to a specified geographic region of the world; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> serves as a forum for bilateral and multilateral research, communication, exchange of ideas, and training involving military and civilian participants.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Department of Defense Regional Centers for Security Studies are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The George C. Marshall European Center for Security Studies, established in 1993 and located in Garmisch-Partenkirchen, Germany.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Daniel K. Inouye Asia-Pacific Center for Security Studies, established in 1995 and located in Honolulu, Hawaii.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The William J. Perry Center for Hemispheric Defense Studies, established in 1997 and located in Washington, D.C.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Africa Center for Strategic Studies, established in 1999 and located in Washington, D.C.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Near East South Asia Center for Strategic Studies, established in 2000 and located in Washington, D.C.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Ted Stevens Center for Arctic Security Studies, established in 2021 and located in Anchorage, Alaska.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No institution or element of the Department of Defense may be designated as a Department of Defense Regional Center for Security Studies for purposes of this section, other than the institutions specified in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The administration of the Regional Centers under this section shall be carried out under regulations prescribed by the Secretary. The regulations shall prioritize within the respective areas of focus of each Regional Center the functional areas for engagement of territorial and maritime security, transnational and asymmetric threats, and defense sector governance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Participants in activities of the Regional Centers may include United States and foreign military, civilian, and nongovernmental personnel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment and Compensation of Faculty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At each Regional Center, the Secretary may, subject to the availability of appropriations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> employ a Director, a Deputy Director, and as many civilians as professors, instructors, and lecturers as the Secretary considers necessary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prescribe the compensation of such persons, in accordance with Federal guidelines.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Payment of Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Participation in activities of a Regional Center shall be on a reimbursable basis (or by payment in advance), except in a case in which reimbursement is waived in accordance with paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For a foreign national participant, payment of costs may be made by the participant, the participant’s own government, by a Department or agency of the United States other than the Department of Defense, or by a gift or donation on behalf of one or more Regional Centers accepted under <ref>section 2611 of this title</ref> on behalf of the participant’s government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive reimbursement of the costs of activities of the Regional Centers for foreign military officers and foreign defense and security personnel from a developing country if the Secretary determines that attendance of such personnel without reimbursement is in the national security interest of the United States. Costs for which reimbursement is waived pursuant to this paragraph shall be paid from appropriations available to the Regional Centers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, waive reimbursement otherwise required under this subsection of the costs of activities of the Regional Centers for personnel of nongovernmental and international organizations who participate in activities of the Regional Centers that enhance cooperation of nongovernmental organizations and international organizations with United States forces if the Secretary of Defense determines that attendance of such personnel without reimbursement is in the national security interest of the United States.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The amount of reimbursement that may be waived under clause (i) in any fiscal year may not exceed $1,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Funds accepted for the payment of costs shall be credited to the appropriation then currently available to the Department of Defense for the Regional Center that incurred the costs. Funds so credited shall be merged with the appropriation to which credited and shall be available to that Regional Center for the same purposes and same period as the appropriation with which merged.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Funds available for the payment of personnel expenses under <ref>section 312 of this title</ref> are also available for the costs of the operation of the Regional Centers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Funds available to carry out this section, including funds accepted under paragraph (4) and funds available under paragraph (5), shall be available, to the extent provided in appropriations Acts, for programs and activities under this section that begin in a fiscal year and end in the following fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support to Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of a Regional Center may enter into agreements with the Secretaries of the military departments, the heads of the Defense Agencies, and, with the concurrence of the Secretary of Defense, the heads of other Federal departments and agencies for the provision of services by that Regional Center under this section. Any such participating department and agency shall transfer to the Regional Center funds to pay the full costs of the services received.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorities Specific to Marshall Center</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may authorize participation by a European or Eurasian country in programs of the George C. Marshall Center for Security Studies (in this subsection referred to as the “Marshall Center”) if the Secretary determines, after consultation with the Secretary of State, that such participation is in the national interest of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of any person invited to serve without compensation on the Marshall Center Board of Visitors, the Secretary of Defense may waive any requirement for financial disclosure that would otherwise apply to that person solely by reason of service on such Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A member of the Marshall Center Board of Visitors may not be required to register as an agent of a foreign government solely by reason of service as a member of the Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 219 of title 18</ref>, a non-United States citizen may serve on the Marshall Center Board of Visitors even though registered as a foreign agent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive reimbursement of the costs of conferences, seminars, courses of instruction, or similar educational activities of the Marshall Center for military officers and civilian officials from states located in Europe or the territory of the former Soviet Union if the Secretary determines that attendance by such personnel without reimbursement is in the national security interest of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Costs for which reimbursement is waived pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be paid from appropriations available for the Center.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorities Specific to Inouye Center</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may waive reimbursement of the cost of conferences, seminars, courses of instruction, or similar educational activities of the Daniel K. Inouye Center for Security Studies for military officers and civilian officials of foreign countries if the Secretary determines that attendance by such personnel, without reimbursement, is in the national security interest of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Costs for which reimbursement is waived pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be paid from appropriations available for the Center.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Review of Program Structure and Programs of Centers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall on an annual basis review the program and structure of each Regional Center in order to determine whether such Regional Center is appropriately aligned with the strategic priorities of the Department of Defense and the applicable geographic combatant commands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may revise the program, structure, or both of a Regional Center following an annual review under paragraph (1) in order to more appropriately align the Regional Center with strategic priorities and the geographic combatant commands as described in that paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title IX, § 912(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–228, § 184; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1226</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 931(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1581</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title IX, § 903(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3399</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title IX, § 904(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 941(a)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4576</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1061(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1583</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2854(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2161</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2861(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3715</ref>; renumbered § 342 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(e)(1)</ref>–(4), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2505</ref>, 2506; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1595</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1082(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1922</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 343.</num>
<heading> Western Hemisphere Institute for Security Cooperation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Administration</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may operate an education and training facility for the purpose set forth in subsection (b). The facility shall be known as the “Western Hemisphere Institute for Security Cooperation”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may designate the Secretary of a military department as the Department of Defense executive agent for carrying out the responsibilities of the Secretary of Defense under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The purpose of the Institute is to provide professional education and training to eligible personnel of countries of the Western Hemisphere within the context of the democratic principles set forth in the Charter of the Organization of American States (such charter being a treaty to which the United States is a party), while fostering mutual knowledge, transparency, confidence, and cooperation among the participating countries and promoting democratic values, respect for human rights, and knowledge and understanding of United States customs and traditions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2), personnel of countries of the Western Hemisphere are eligible for education and training at the Institute as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Military personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Law enforcement personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Civilian personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of State shall be consulted in the selection of foreign personnel for education or training at the Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Curriculum</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The curriculum of the Institute shall include mandatory instruction for each student, for at least 8 hours, on human rights, the rule of law, due process, civilian control of the military, and the role of the military in a democratic society.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The curriculum may include instruction and other educational and training activities on the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Leadership development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Counterdrug operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Peace support operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Disaster relief.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any other matter that the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board of Visitors</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> There shall be a Board of Visitors for the Institute. The Board shall be composed of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, or a designee of either of them.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, or a designee of either of them.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Six persons designated by the Secretary of Defense including, to the extent practicable, persons from academia and the religious and human rights communities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> One person designated by the Secretary of State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The senior military officer responsible for training and doctrine for the Army or, if the Secretary of the Navy or the Secretary of the Air Force is designated as the executive agent of the Secretary of Defense under subsection (a)(2), the senior military officer responsible for training and doctrine for the Navy or Marine Corps or for the Air Force or Space Force, respectively, or a designee of the senior military officer concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The commanders of the combatant commands having geographic responsibility for the Western Hemisphere, or the designees of those officers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A vacancy in a position on the Board shall be filled in the same manner as the position was originally filled.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Board shall meet at least once each year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Board shall inquire into the curriculum, instruction, physical equipment, fiscal affairs, and academic methods of the Institute, other matters relating to the Institute that the Board decides to consider, and any other matter that the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Board shall review the curriculum of the Institute to determine whether—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the curriculum complies with applicable United States laws and regulations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the curriculum is consistent with United States policy goals toward Latin America and the Caribbean;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the curriculum adheres to current United States doctrine; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the instruction under the curriculum appropriately emphasizes the matters specified in subsection (d)(1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Not later than 60 days after its annual meeting, the Board shall submit to the Secretary of Defense a written report of its activities and of its views and recommendations pertaining to the Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Members of the Board shall not be compensated by reason of service on the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> With the approval of the Secretary of Defense, the Board may accept and use the services of voluntary and uncompensated advisers appropriate to the duties of the Board without regard to <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> Members of the Board and advisers whose services are accepted under paragraph (7) shall be allowed travel and transportation expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Board. Allowances under this paragraph shall be computed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of members of the Board who are officers or employees of the United States, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of other members of the Board and advisers, as authorized under <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref> for employees serving without pay.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Chapter 10 of title 5, other than <ref>section 1013 of title 5</ref> (relating to termination after two years), shall apply to the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Accept Foreign Gifts and Donations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may, on behalf of the Institute, accept foreign gifts or donations in order to defray the costs of, or enhance the operation of, the Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds received by the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall be credited to appropriations available for the Department of Defense for the Institute. Funds so credited shall be merged with the appropriations to which credited and shall be available for the Institute for the same purposes and same period as the appropriations with which merged.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall notify Congress if the total amount of money accepted under paragraph (1) exceeds $1,000,000 in any fiscal year. Any such notice shall list each of the contributors of such money and the amount of each contribution in such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this subsection, a foreign gift or donation is a gift or donation of funds, materials (including research materials), property, or services (including lecture services and faculty services) from a foreign government, a foundation or other charitable organization in a foreign country, or an individual in a foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fixed Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The fixed costs of operating and maintaining the Institute for a fiscal year may be paid from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any funds available for that fiscal year for operation and maintenance for the executive agent designated under subsection (a)(2); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if no executive agent is designated under subsection (a)(2), any funds available for that fiscal year for the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance for Defense-wide activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tuition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Tuition fees charged for persons who attend the Institute may not include the fixed costs of operating and maintaining the Institute.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than March 15 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a detailed report on the activities of the Institute during the preceding year. The report shall include a copy of the latest report of the Board of Visitors received by the Secretary under subsection (e)(5), together with any comments of the Secretary on the Board’s report. The report shall be prepared in consultation with the Secretary of State.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title IX, § 911(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–226, § 2166; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title IX, § 932</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2625</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 956</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 296</ref>; renumbered § 343 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(f)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(12)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3823</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(45)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4310</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 344.</num>
<heading> Participation in multinational centers of excellence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, authorize the participation of members of the armed forces and Department of Defense civilian personnel in any multinational center of excellence for purposes of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enhancing the ability of military forces and civilian personnel of the nations participating in such center to engage in joint exercises or coalition or international military operations; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> improving interoperability between the armed forces and the military forces of friendly foreign nations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Memorandum of Understanding</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The participation of members of the armed forces or Department of Defense civilian personnel in a multinational center of excellence under subsection (a) shall be in accordance with the terms of one or more memoranda of understanding entered into by the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, or entered into by the Secretary of State, and the foreign nation or nations concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If Department of Defense facilities, equipment, or funds are used to support a multinational center of excellence under subsection (a), the memoranda of understanding under paragraph (1) with respect to that center shall provide details of any cost-sharing arrangement or other funding arrangement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of Appropriated Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance are available as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To pay the United States share of the operating expenses of any multinational center of excellence in which the United States participates under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To pay the costs of the participation of members of the armed forces and Department of Defense civilian personnel in multinational centers of excellence under this section, including the costs of expenses of such participants.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No funds may be used under this section to fund the pay or salaries of members of the armed forces and Department of Defense civilian personnel who participate in multinational centers of excellence under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Department of Defense Facilities and Equipment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Facilities and equipment of the Department of Defense may be used for purposes of the support of multinational centers of excellence under this section that are hosted by the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days before the date on which the Secretary of Defense authorizes participation under subsection (a) in a new multinational center of excellence, the Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees of such participation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Multinational Center Of Excellence Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “multinational center of excellence” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> an entity sponsored by one or more nations that is accredited and approved by the Military Committee of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) as offering recognized expertise and experience to personnel participating in the activities of such entity for the benefit of NATO by providing such personnel opportunities to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> enhance education and training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improve interoperability and capabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assist in the development of doctrine;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> validate concepts through experimentation;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the European Centre of Excellence for Countering Hybrid Threats, established in 2017 and located in Helsinki, Finland; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the International Special Training Centre, established in 1979 and located in Pfullendorf, Germany.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title XII, § 1232(a)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4637</ref>, § 2350m; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(25)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1953</ref>; renumbered § 344 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(g)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1206(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3912</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1203</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2826</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 345.</num>
<heading> Irregular Warfare Center and Regional Defense Fellowship Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authorities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> operate and administer a Center for Strategic Studies in Irregular Warfare, to be known as the “Irregular Warfare Center”, in accordance with the requirements described in subsection (c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> carry out a program, to be known as the “Regional Defense Fellowship Program”, to provide for the education and training of foreign personnel described in paragraph (2) at military or civilian educational institutions, the Irregular Warfare Center, regional centers, conferences, seminars, or other training programs conducted for purposes of regional defense in connection with irregular warfare or combating terrorism.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered costs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may pay the following costs associated with exercising the authorities under this section:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Costs of travel, subsistence, and similar personnel expenses of, and special compensation for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> defense personnel of friendly foreign governments to attend activities of the Irregular Warfare Center or attend the Regional Defense Fellowship Program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, other personnel of friendly foreign governments and non-governmental personnel to attend activities of the Irregular Warfare Center or attend the Regional Defense Fellowship Program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> foreign personnel and United States Government personnel necessary for the administration and execution of the authorities under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Costs associated with the administration and operation of the Irregular Warfare Center, including costs associated with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> research, communication, the exchange of ideas, curriculum development and review, and training of military and civilian participants of the United States and other countries, as the Secretary considers necessary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> maintaining an international network of irregular warfare policymakers and practitioners to achieve the objectives of the Department of Defense and the Department of State.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Costs associated with strategic engagement with alumni of the Regional Defense Fellowship Program to address Department of Defense objectives and planning on irregular warfare and combating terrorism topics.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Regulations for Regional Defense Fellowship Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authorities granted to the Secretary of Defense under subsection (a)(1)(B) shall be carried out under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The regulations shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> jointly develop and plan activities under the program that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> advance United States security cooperation objectives; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> support theater security cooperation planning of the combatant commands; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> coordinate on the implementation of activities under the program;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> each of the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State designates an individual at the lowest appropriate level of the Department of Defense or the Department of State, as applicable, who shall be responsible for program coordination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, activities under the program are appropriately coordinated with, and do not duplicate or conflict with, activities under International Military Education and Training (IMET) authorities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submittal to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon any update of the regulations, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a copy of the regulations as so updated, together with a description of the update.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Irregular Warfare Center.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mission</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The mission of the Irregular Warfare Center shall be to serve as a central mechanism for developing the irregular warfare knowledge of the Department of Defense and advancing the understanding of irregular warfare concepts and doctrine, in collaboration with key partners and allies, by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordinating and aligning Department education curricula, standards, and objectives related to irregular warfare;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> facilitating research on irregular warfare, strategic competition, and the role of the Department in supporting interagency activities relating to irregular warfare;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> engaging and coordinating with Federal departments and agencies and with academia, nongovernmental organizations, civil society, and international partners to discuss and coordinate efforts on security challenges in irregular warfare;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> developing curriculum and conducting training and education of military and civilian participants of the United States and other countries, as determined by the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> serving as a coordinating body and central repository for irregular warfare resources, including educational activities and programs, and lessons learned across components of the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employment and compensation of faculty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With respect to the Irregular Warfare Center—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Defense may, subject to the availability of appropriations, employ a Director, a Deputy Director, and such civilians as professors, instructors, and lecturers, as the Secretary considers necessary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compensation of individuals employed under this section shall be as prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Partnership with institution of higher education.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In operating the Irregular Warfare Center, to promote integration throughout the United States Government and civil society across the full spectrum of irregular warfare competition and conflict challenges, the Secretary of Defense may partner with an institution of higher education (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>)).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Types of partnerships</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may establish a partnership under subparagraph (A) by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> entering into an intergovernmental support agreement pursuant to <ref>section 2679 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> entering into a contract or cooperative agreement or awarding a grant through the Defense Security Cooperation University.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall make a determination with respect to the desirability of partnering with an institution of higher education in a Government-owned, contractor-operated partnership, such as the partnership structure used by the Department of Defense for University Affiliated Research Centers, for meeting the mission requirements of the Irregular Warfare Center.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Roles and responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe guidance for the roles and responsibilities of the relevant components of the Department of Defense in the administration, operation, and oversight of the Irregular Warfare Center, which shall include the roles and responsibilities of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of Defense for Policy and the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Special Operations and Low Intensity Conflict in policy oversight and governance structure of the Center.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency, as the Executive Agent in support of the operation of the Center.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any other official of the Department of Defense, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total amount of funds used under the authority in subsection (a)(1)(B) in any fiscal year may not exceed $35,000,000. Amounts available under the authority in subsection (a)(1)(B) for a fiscal year may be used for programs that begin in such fiscal year but end in the next fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than December 1 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the administration of this section during the fiscal year ended in such year. The report shall include the following matters:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A complete accounting of the expenditure of appropriated funds for purposes authorized under subsection (a), including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the countries of the foreign officers and officials for whom costs were paid; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for each such country, the total amount of the costs paid.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The training courses attended by the foreign officers and officials, including a specification of which, if any, courses were conducted in foreign countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An assessment of the effectiveness of the program referred to in subsection (a)(1)(B), including engagement activities for program alumni, in increasing the cooperation of the governments of foreign countries with the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A discussion of any actions being taken to improve the program, including a list of any unfunded or unmet training requirements and requests.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A discussion and justification of how the program fits within the theater security priorities of each of the commanders of the geographic combatant commands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A discussion of how the training from the previous year incorporated lessons learned from ongoing conflicts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Review of Irregular Warfare Center</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than <date date="2024-12-01">December 1, 2024</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall conduct a review of the structure and activities of the Irregular Warfare Center to determine whether such structure and activities are appropriately aligned with the strategic priorities of the Department of Defense and the applicable combatant commands; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may, after an annual review under paragraph (1), revise the relevant structure and activities so as to more appropriately align such structure and activities with the strategic priorities and combatant commands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XII, § 1221(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1651</ref>, § 2249c; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title XII, § 1204(a)</ref>–(d)(2), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2415</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title XII, § 1209(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4627</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1032(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 850</ref>; renumbered § 345 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1247(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1209(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2022</ref>, 2023; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1204(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2827</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 346.</num>
<heading> Distribution to certain foreign personnel of education and training materials and information technology to enhance military interoperability with the armed forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Distribution Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To enhance interoperability between the armed forces and military forces of friendly foreign countries, the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide to personnel referred to in subsection (b) electronically-distributed learning content for the education and training of such personnel for the development or enhancement of allied and friendly military and civilian capabilities for multinational operations, including joint exercises and coalition operations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide information technology, including computer software developed for such purpose, but only to the extent necessary to support the use of such learning content for the education and training of such personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Recipients</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The personnel to whom learning content and information technology may be provided under subsection (a) are military and civilian personnel of a friendly foreign government, with the permission of that government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Education and Training</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any education and training provided under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Internet-based education and training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Advanced distributed learning and similar Internet learning tools, as well as distributed training and computer-assisted exercises.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Export Control Regimes</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provision of learning content and information technology under this section shall be subject to the provisions of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.) and any other export control regime under law relating to the transfer of military technology to foreign countries.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Guidance on Utilization of Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidance required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop and issue guidance on the procedures for the use of the authority in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Modification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary modifies the guidance issued under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report setting forth the modified guidance not later than 30 days after the date of such modification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title XII, § 1205(a)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4623</ref>, § 2249d; renumbered § 346 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(h)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 347.</num>
<heading> International engagement authorities for service academies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Selection of Persons From Foreign Countries To Receive Instruction at Service Academies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Attendance authorized.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of each military department may permit persons from foreign countries to receive instruction at the Service Academy under the jurisdiction of the Secretary. Such persons shall be in addition to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of the United States Military Academy, the authorized strength of the Corps of the Cadets of the Academy under <ref>section 7442 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of the United States Naval Academy, the authorized strength of the Brigade of Midshipmen of the Academy under <ref>section 8454 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of the United States Air Force Academy, the authorized strength of the Cadet Wing of the Academy under <ref>section 9442 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on number</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The number of persons permitted to receive instruction at each Service Academy under this subsection may not be more than 80 at any one time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of foreign countries from which persons may be selected</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of a military department, upon approval by the Secretary of Defense, shall determine—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the countries from which persons may be selected for appointment under this subsection to the Service Academy under the jurisdiction of that Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of persons that may be selected from each country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifications and selection</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of each military department—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may establish entrance qualifications and methods of competition for selection among individual applicants under this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall select those persons who will be permitted to receive instruction at the Service Academy under the jurisdiction of the Secretary under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection priority to persons with national service obligation upon graduation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In selecting persons to receive instruction under this subsection from among applicants from the countries approved under paragraph (2), the Secretary of the military department concerned shall give a priority to persons who have a national service obligation to their countries upon graduation from the Service Academy concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pay, allowances, and emoluments of persons admitted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person receiving instruction under this subsection is entitled to the pay, allowances, and emoluments of a cadet or midshipman appointed from the United States, and from the same appropriations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement of costs by foreign countries from which persons are admitted.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each foreign country from which a cadet or midshipman is permitted to receive instruction at one of the Service Academies under this subsection shall reimburse the United States for the cost of providing such instruction, including the cost of pay, allowances, and emoluments provided under paragraph (5). The Secretaries of the military departments shall prescribe the rates for reimbursement under this paragraph, except that the reimbursement rates may not be less than the cost to the United States of providing such instruction, including pay, allowances, and emoluments, to a cadet or midshipman appointed from the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may waive, in whole or in part, the requirement for reimbursement of the cost of instruction for a cadet or midshipman under subparagraph (A). In the case of a partial waiver, the Secretary of Defense shall establish the amount waived.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applicability of academy regulations, etc.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as the Secretary of the military department concerned determines, a person receiving instruction under this subsection at the Service Academy under the jurisdiction of that Secretary is subject to the same regulations governing admission, attendance, discipline, resignation, discharge, dismissal, and graduation as a cadet or midshipman at that Academy appointed from the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Classified information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the military department concerned may prescribe regulations with respect to access to classified information by a person receiving instruction under this subsection at the Service Academy under the jurisdiction of that Secretary that differ from the regulations that apply to a cadet or midshipman at that Academy appointed from the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ineligibility for appointment in the united states armed forces</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person receiving instruction at a Service Academy under this subsection is not entitled to an appointment in an armed force of the United States by reason of graduation from the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of requirement for taking oath of admission</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person receiving instruction under this subsection is not subject to section 7446(d), 8458(d), or 9446(d) of this title, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exchange Programs With Foreign Military Academies.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exchange programs authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may permit a student enrolled at a military academy of a foreign country to receive instruction at the Service Academy under the jurisdiction of that Secretary in exchange for a cadet or midshipman receiving instruction at that foreign military academy pursuant to an exchange agreement entered into between the Secretary and appropriate officials of the foreign country. A student receiving instruction at a Service Academy under the exchange program under this subsection shall be in addition to persons receiving instruction at the Academy under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations on number and duration of exchanges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An exchange agreement under this subsection between the Secretary and a foreign country shall provide for the exchange of students on a one-for-one basis each fiscal year. Not more than 100 cadets or midshipmen from each Service Academy and a comparable number of students from foreign military academies participating in the exchange program may be exchanged during any fiscal year. The duration of an exchange may not exceed the equivalent of one academic semester at a Service Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Costs and expenses.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No pay and allowances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A student from a military academy of a foreign country is not entitled to the pay, allowances, and emoluments of a cadet or midshipman by reason of attendance at a Service Academy under the exchange program, and the Department of Defense may not incur any cost of international travel required for transportation of such a student to and from the sponsoring foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subsistence, transportation, etc</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the military department concerned may provide a student from a foreign country under the exchange program, during the period of the exchange, with subsistence, transportation within the continental United States, clothing, health care, and other services to the same extent that the foreign country provides comparable support and services to the exchanged cadet or midshipman in that foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Source of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Service Academy shall bear all costs of the exchange program from funds appropriated for that Academy and from such additional funds as may be available to that Academy from a source, other than appropriated funds, to support cultural immersion, regional awareness, or foreign language training activities in connection with the exchange program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on expenditures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Expenditures in support of the exchange program from funds appropriated for each Academy may not exceed $1,000,000 during any fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of other laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraphs (7), (8), and (9) of subsection (a) shall apply with respect to a student enrolled at a military academy of a foreign country while attending a Service Academy under the exchange program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the military department concerned shall prescribe regulations to implement this subsection. Such regulations may include qualification criteria and methods of selection for students of foreign military academies to participate in the exchange program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Foreign and Cultural Exchange Activities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Attendance authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may authorize the Service Academy under the jurisdiction of that Secretary to permit students, officers, and other representatives of a foreign country to attend that Academy for periods of not more than four weeks if the Secretary determines that the attendance of such persons contributes significantly to the development of foreign language, cross-cultural interactions and understanding, and cultural immersion of cadets or midshipmen, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of attendance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Persons attending a Service Academy under paragraph (1) are not considered to be students enrolled at that Academy and are in addition to persons receiving instruction at that Academy under subsection (a) or (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Financial matters.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Costs and expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of a military department may pay the travel, subsistence, and similar personal expenses of persons incurred to attend the Service Academy under the jurisdiction of that Secretary under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Source of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Service Academy shall bear the costs of the attendance of persons at that Academy under paragraph (1) from funds appropriated for that Academy and from such additional funds as may be available to that Academy from a source, other than appropriated funds, to support cultural immersion, regional awareness, or foreign language training activities in connection with their attendance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on expenditures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Expenditures from appropriated funds in support of activities under this subsection for any Service Academy may not exceed $40,000 during any fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Service Academy Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “Service Academy” means the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States Military Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The United States Naval Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The United States Air Force Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1248(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2522</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(18)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1595</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, title XII, § 1204(c)(1)(D), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1840</ref>, 2017; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 551</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1893</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 348.</num>
<heading> Aviation Leadership Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Air Force may carry out an Aviation Leadership Program to provide undergraduate pilot training and necessary related training to personnel of the air forces of friendly, developing foreign countries. Training under this section shall include language training and programs to promote better awareness and understanding of the democratic institutions and social framework of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supplies and Clothing</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Air Force may, under such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, provide to a person receiving training under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> transportation incident to the training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> supplies and equipment to be used during the training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> flight clothing and other special clothing required for the training; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> billeting, food, and health services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may authorize such expenditures from the appropriations of the Air Force as the Secretary considers necessary for the efficient and effective maintenance of the Program in accordance with this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allowances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may pay to a person receiving training under this section a living allowance at a rate to be prescribed by the Secretary, taking into account the amount of living allowances authorized for a member of the armed forces under similar circumstances.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 349.</num>
<heading> Inter-American Air Forces Academy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may operate the Air Force education and training facility known as the Inter-American Air Forces Academy for the purpose of providing military education and training to military personnel of Central and South American countries, Caribbean countries, and other countries eligible for assistance under chapter 5 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2347</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Concurrence of secretary of state</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Military personnel of a foreign country may be provided education and training under this section only with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance otherwise prohibited by law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Education and training may not be provided under this section to the military personnel of any country that is otherwise prohibited from receiving such type of assistance under any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The fixed costs of operating and maintaining the Inter-American Air Forces Academy may be paid from funds available for operation and maintenance of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title III, § 330(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1535</ref>, § 9415; renumbered § 349 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(j)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2508</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 350.</num>
<heading> Inter-European Air Forces Academy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may operate the Air Force education and training facility known as the Inter-European Air Forces Academy (in this section referred to as the “Academy”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purpose of the Academy shall be to provide military education and training to military personnel of countries that are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> signatories to the Partnership for Peace Framework Documents; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> within the United States Africa Command area of responsibility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> eligible for assistance under chapter 5 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2347</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Concurrence of secretary of state</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Military personnel of a country may be provided education and training under this section only with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assistance otherwise prohibited by law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Education and training may not be provided under this section to the military personnel of any country that is otherwise prohibited from receiving such type of assistance under any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Supplies and Clothing</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Air Force may, under such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, provide to a person receiving education and training under this section the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Transportation incident to such education and training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Supplies and equipment to be used during such education and training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Billeting, food, and health services in connection with the receipt of such education and training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Living Allowance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may pay to a person receiving education and training under this section a living allowance at a rate to be prescribed by the Secretary, taking into account the rates of living allowances authorized for a member of the Armed Forces under similar circumstances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts for the operations and maintenance of the Academy, and for the provision of education and training through the Academy, may be paid from funds available for the Air Force for operation and maintenance.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2508</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1205</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3912</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 351.</num>
<heading> Inter-American Defense College</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Support</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may authorize members of the armed forces and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense to participate in the operation of and the provision of support to the Inter-American Defense College and provide logistic support, supplies, and services to the Inter-American Defense College, including the use of Department of Defense facilities and equipment, as the Secretary considers necessary to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assist the Inter-American Defense College in its mission to develop and offer to military officers and civilian officials from member states of the Organization of American States advanced academic courses on matters related to military and defense issues, the inter-American system, and related disciplines; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that the Inter-American Defense College provides an academic program of a level of quality, rigor, and credibility that is commensurate with the standards of Department of Defense senior service colleges and that includes the promotion of security cooperation, human rights, humanitarian assistance and disaster response, peacekeeping, and democracy in the Western Hemisphere.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Memorandum of Understanding</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Inter-American Defense Board for the participation of members of the armed forces and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense in the operation of and provision of host nation support to the Inter-American Defense College under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If Department of Defense facilities, equipment, or funds will be used to support the Inter-American Defense College under subsection (a), a memorandum of understanding entered into under paragraph (1) shall include a description of any cost-sharing arrangement or other funding arrangement relating to the use of such facilities, equipment, or funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A memorandum of understanding entered into under paragraph (1) shall also include a curriculum and a plan for academic program development.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance may be used to pay costs that the Secretary determines are necessary for the participation of members of the armed forces and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense in the operation of and provision of host nation support to the Inter-American Defense College, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the costs of expenses of such participants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost of hiring and retaining qualified professors, instructors, and lecturers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> curriculum support costs, including administrative costs, academic outreach, and curriculum support personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the cost of translation and interpretation services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the cost of information and educational technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the cost of utilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the cost of maintenance and repair of facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No funds may be used under this section to provide for the pay of members of the armed forces or civilian personnel of the Department of Defense who participate in the operation of and the provision of host nation support to the Inter-American Defense College under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Funds available to carry out this section for a fiscal year may be used for activities that begin in such fiscal year and end in the next fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver of Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may waive reimbursement for developing countries (as such term is defined in <ref>section 301 of this title</ref>) of the costs of funding and other host nation support provided to the Inter-American Defense College under this section if the Secretary determines that the provision of such funding or support without reimbursement is in the national security interest of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Logistic Support, Supplies, and Services Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “logistic support, supplies, and services” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2350 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1207(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2019</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 352.</num>
<heading> Naval Small Craft Instruction and Technical Training School</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may operate an education and training facility known as the “Naval Small Craft Instruction and Technical Training School” (in this section referred to as the “School”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Executive Agent</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall designate the Secretary of a military department as the Department of Defense executive agent for carrying out the responsibilities of the Secretary of Defense under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purpose of the School shall be to provide to the military and other security forces of one or more friendly foreign countries education and training under any other provision of law related to naval small craft instruction and training and to increase professionalism, readiness, and respect for human rights through formal courses of instruction or mobile training teams for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the operation, employment, maintenance, and logistics of specialized equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> participation in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> joint exercises; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coalition or international military operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> improved interoperability between—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the armed forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the military and other security forces of the one or more friendly foreign countries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Personnel Eligible To Receive Education and Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may not provide education or training at the School to any personnel of a country that is prohibited from receiving such education or training under any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Costs</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The fixed costs of the School may be paid from amounts made available for the Navy as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The costs of operating and maintaining the School may be paid from amounts made available to the Navy for operation and maintenance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The costs of the equipment requirements of the School may be paid from amounts made available to the Navy for procurement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The costs of the facilities construction requirements of the School may be paid from amounts made available to the Navy for military construction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The food procurement and service costs of the School that may be paid from amounts made available to the Navy for operation and maintenance are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The costs of providing food services to personnel, visitors, and international students at the School.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The costs of operating, maintaining, and sustaining a dining facility or contracted food services at the School.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than March 15 each year, the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a detailed report on the activities and operating costs of the School during the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1208(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2021</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2093</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>LIMITATIONS ON USE OF DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE FUNDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 361.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on providing financial assistance to terrorist countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds available to the Department of Defense may not be obligated or expended to provide financial assistance to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any country with respect to which the Secretary of State has made a determination under section 6(j)(1)(A) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002031">1</ref> of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 4605(j)(1)(A)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any country identified in the latest report submitted to Congress under section 140 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2656f</ref>), as providing significant support for international terrorism; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> any other country that, as determined by the President—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> grants sanctuary from prosecution to any individual or group that has committed an act of international terrorism; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> otherwise supports international terrorism.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The President may waive the application of subsection (a) to a country if the President determines—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that it is in the national security interests of the United States to do so; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that the waiver should be granted for humanitarian reasons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The President shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> notify the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives at least 15 days before the waiver takes effect; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> publish a notice of the waiver in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “international terrorism” has the meaning given that term in section 140(d) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2656f(d)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XIII, § 1341(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 485</ref>, § 2249a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(40)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; renumbered § 361 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1081(b)(3)(B)</ref>, title XII, § 1241(<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2418</ref>, 2509.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 362.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on use of funds for assistance to units of foreign security forces that have committed a gross violation of human rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Of the amounts made available to the Department of Defense, none may be used for any training, equipment, or other assistance for a unit of a foreign security force if the Secretary of Defense has credible information that the unit has committed a gross violation of human rights.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall, in consultation with the Secretary of State, ensure that prior to a decision to provide any training, equipment, or other assistance to a unit of a foreign security force full consideration is given to any credible information available to the Department of State relating to human rights violations by such unit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibition in subsection (a)(1) shall not apply if the Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretary of State, determines that the government of such country has taken all necessary corrective steps, or if the equipment or other assistance is necessary to assist in disaster relief operations or other humanitarian or national security emergencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretary of State, may waive the prohibition in subsection (a)(1) if the Secretary determines that the waiver is required by extraordinary circumstances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish, and periodically update, procedures to ensure that any information in the possession of the Department of Defense about gross violations of human rights by units of foreign security forces is shared on a timely basis with the Department of State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 15 days after the application of any exception under subsection (b) or the exercise of any waiver under subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of an exception under subsection (b), providing notice of the use of the exception and stating the grounds for the exception; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a waiver under subsection (c), describing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the information relating to the gross violation of human rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the extraordinary circumstances that necessitate the waiver;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the purpose and duration of the training, equipment, or other assistance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the United States forces and the foreign security force unit involved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XII, § 1204(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3531</ref>, § 2249e; renumbered § 362 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 371.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 271]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 372.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 272]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 373.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 273]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 374.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 274]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 375.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 275]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 376.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 276]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 377.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 277]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 378.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 278]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 379.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 279]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 380.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 280]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATIVE AND MISCELLANEOUS MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 381.</num>
<heading> Consolidated budget</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consolidated Budget</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The budget of the President for each fiscal year, as submitted to Congress by the President pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, shall set forth by budget function and as a separate item the amounts requested for the Department of Defense for such fiscal year for all security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense, including the military departments, to be conducted in such fiscal year, including the specific country or region and the applicable authority, to the extent practicable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Semiannual Report on Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the obligation and expenditure of funds for security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by not later than August 31 of each year, for the first six-month period of that year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by not later than February 28 of each year, for the second six-month period of the preceding year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1249(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2526</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XII, § 1204</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 382.</num>
<heading> Execution and administration of programs and activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy Oversight and Resource Allocation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall assign responsibility for the oversight of strategic policy and guidance and responsibility for overall resource allocation for security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense to a single official and office in the Office of the Secretary of Defense at the level of Under Secretary of Defense or below.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Execution and Administration of Certain Programs and Activities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency shall be responsible for the execution and administration of all security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense involving the provision of defense articles, military training, and other defense-related services by grant, loan, cash sale, or lease.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of responsibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director may designate an element of an armed force, combatant command, Defense Agency, Department of Defense Field Activity, or other element or organization of the Department of Defense to execute and administer security cooperation programs and activities described in paragraph (1) if the Director determines that the designation will achieve maximum effectiveness, efficiency, and economy in the activities for which designated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds available to the Defense Security Cooperation Agency, and other funds available to the Department of Defense for security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense, may be used to implement security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense authorized by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget justification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds necessary for implementing security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense under this chapter for a fiscal year shall be identified, with appropriate justification, in the consolidated budget for such fiscal year required by <ref>section 381 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(m)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 383.</num>
<heading> Assessment, monitoring, and evaluation of programs and activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall maintain a program of assessment, monitoring, and evaluation in support of the security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Program Elements and Requirements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The program under subsection (a) shall provide for the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Initial assessments of partner capability requirements, potential programmatic risks, baseline information, and indicators of efficacy for purposes of planning, monitoring, and evaluation of security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Monitoring of implementation of such programs and activities in order to measure progress in execution and, to the extent possible, achievement of desired outcomes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Evaluation of the efficiency and effectiveness of such programs and activities in achieving desired outcomes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Identification of lessons learned in carrying out such programs and activities, and development of recommendation for improving future security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Incorporation of lessons learned from prior security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense that were carried out any time on or after <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Best practices</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The program shall be conducted in accordance with international best practices, interagency standards, and, if applicable, the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993 (<ref>Public Law 103–62</ref>), and the amendments made by that Act, and the GPRA Modernization Act of 2010 (<ref>Public Law 111–352</ref>), and the amendments made by that Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds available to the Defense Security Cooperation Agency, and other funds available to the Department of Defense for security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense, may be used to carry out the program required by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget justification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds described in paragraph (1) for a fiscal year shall be identified, with appropriate justification, in the consolidated budget for such fiscal year required by <ref>section 381 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees each year a report on the program under subsection (a) during the previous year. Each report shall include, for the year covered by such report, the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A description of the activities under the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An evaluation of the lessons learned, including a description of challenges in executing the program, and best practices identified through activities under the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information for the public on evaluations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall make available to the public, on an Internet website of the Department of Defense available to the public, a summary of each evaluation conducted pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(C). In making a summary so available, the Secretary may redact or omit any information that the Secretary determines should not be disclosed to the public in order to protect the interest of the United States or the foreign country or countries covered by such evaluation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(m)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2510</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1211(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2024</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XII, § 1203</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2094</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 384.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense security cooperation workforce development</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program to be known as the “Department of Defense Security Cooperation Workforce Development Program” (in this section referred to as the “Program”) to oversee the development and management of a professional workforce supporting security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assessment, planning, monitoring, execution, evaluation, and administration of such programs and activities under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> execution of security assistance programs and activities under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 and the Arms Export Control Act by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purpose of the Program is to improve the quality and professionalism of the security cooperation workforce in order to ensure that the workforce—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has the capacity, in both personnel and skills, needed to properly perform its mission, provide appropriate support to the assessment, planning, monitoring, execution, evaluation, and administration of security cooperation programs and activities described in subsection (a), and ensure that the Department receives the best value for the expenditure of public resources on such programs and activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is assigned in a manner that ensures personnel with the appropriate level of expertise and experience are assigned in sufficient numbers to fulfill requirements for the security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense and the execution of security assistance programs and activities described in subsection (a)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Program shall consist of elements relating to the development and management of the security cooperation workforce for the purposes specified in subsection (b), including the following elements on training, certification, assignment, career development, and tracking of personnel of the security cooperation workforce:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Establishment of a comprehensive system to track and account for all Department of Defense personnel in the security cooperation workforce, using systems of record in the military departments, the Office of the Secretary of Defense, the combatant commands, Defense Agencies, Department of Defense Field Activities, and the National Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Establishment of a management information system, pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy and the Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency, to ensure that all organizations and elements of the Department provide standardized information and data to the Secretary on persons serving in security cooperation positions. Such management information system shall, at a minimum, provide for the collection and retention of information concerning the qualification, assignments, and tenure of persons in the security cooperation workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Implementation and management of the security cooperation human capital initiative under subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Establishment of a defense security cooperation service, pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy and the Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency, to ensure that security cooperation organizations of the United States located at overseas missions possess the requisite personnel, and that such personnel possess the skills needed, to properly perform their missions, which shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> members of the armed forces and civilians assigned to security cooperation organizations of United States missions overseas who are performing security cooperation functions, regardless of funding source; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> personnel of the Department of Defense performing functions in furtherance of section 515 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2321i</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other elements as the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Management.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Program shall be managed by the Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Managing entity.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy and the Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency, shall designate the Defense Security Cooperation University to serve as the lead entity for managing the implementation of the Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Defense Security Cooperation University shall carry out the management and implementation of the Program, consistent with objectives formulated by the Secretary of Defense, which shall include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Providing for comprehensive tracking of and accounting for all Department of Defense employees engaged in the security cooperation enterprise.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Providing training requirements specified at the requisite proficiency levels for each position.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, not less frequently than semi-annually, each military department, the Office of the Secretary of Defense, and each combatant command, Defense Agency, Department of Defense Field Activity, and unit of the National Guard submits to the Defense Security Cooperation University a formal manpower document as determined by the Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> lists each position in the security cooperation workforce of the organization concerned as determined by the Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> uniquely codes every position within component manpower systems for the security cooperation workforce for the management and career development of the security cooperation workforce, as determined by the Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Security cooperation workforce management information system</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency, shall prescribe regulations to ensure that each military department, the Office of the Secretary of Defense, and each combatant command, Defense Agency, Department of Defense Field Activity, and unit of the National Guard provides standardized information and data to the Secretary on persons serving in positions within the security cooperation workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Security Cooperation Human Capital Initiative.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall implement a security cooperation human capital initiative within the Defense Security Cooperation University to identify, account for, and manage the career progression of personnel in the security cooperation workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The security cooperation human capital initiative shall do the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Provide direction to the Department of Defense on the establishment of professional career paths for the personnel of the security cooperation workforce, addressing training and education standards, promotion opportunities and requirements, retention policies, and scope of workforce demands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Provide for a mechanism to identify and define training and certification requirements for security cooperation positions in the Department and a means to track workforce skills and certifications.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Provide for a mechanism to establish a program of professional certification in Department of Defense security cooperation for personnel of the security cooperation workforce in different career tracks and levels of competency based on requisite training and experience.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Establish requirements for training and professional development associated with each level of certification provided for under subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Provide for a mechanism for assigning appropriately certified personnel of the security cooperation workforce to assignments associated with key positions in connection with security cooperation programs and activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Identify the appropriate composition of career and temporary personnel necessary to constitute the security cooperation workforce.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Identify specific positions throughout the security cooperation workforce to be managed and assigned through the Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Identify career paths that provide a competency-based road map for security cooperation employees to aid in their career planning and professional development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Develop a competency-based approach to the security cooperation workforce that enables components of the Department of Defense to incorporate competencies in recruitment and retention tools such as job analysis, position descriptions, vacancy announcements, selection assessment questionnaires, and employee training and development plans.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Align with the Department of Defense and Defense Security Cooperation Agency strategic planning, budget process, performance management goals, and metrics to ensure the appropriate workforce mix and skill sets to accomplish the security cooperation mission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> Include assessment measures intended to assess progress in implementing the security cooperation workforce using results-oriented performance measures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Foreign Military Sales Center of Excellence.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall direct an educational institution of the Department of Defense with the requisite expertise in foreign military sales and in education, training, research, and analysis of the security cooperation workforce within the Department of Defense to serve as a Foreign Military Sales Center of Excellence to improve the training and education of personnel engaged in foreign military sales planning and execution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Objectives</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The objectives of the Foreign Military Sales Center of Excellence shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conducting research on and promoting best practices for ensuring that foreign military sales are timely and effective; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enhancing existing curricula for the purpose of ensuring that the foreign military sales workforce is fully trained and prepared to execute the foreign military sales program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Defense Security Cooperation University.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Charter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop and promulgate a charter for the operation of the Defense Security Cooperation University.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mission</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The charter required by paragraph (1) shall set forth the mission, and associated structures and organizations, of the Defense Security Cooperation University, which shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> management and implementation of international military training and education security cooperation programs and authorities executed by the Department of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> management and provision of institutional capacity-building services executed by the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> advancement of the profession of security cooperation through research, data collection, analysis, publication, and learning.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cooperative research and development arrangements.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In engaging in research and development projects pursuant to subsection (a) of <ref>section 4001 of this title</ref> by a contract, cooperative agreement, or grant pursuant to subsection (b)(1) of such section, the Secretary of Defense may enter into such contract or cooperative agreement, or award such grant, through the Defense Security Cooperation University.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as government-operated federal laboratory</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Defense Security Cooperation University shall be considered a Government-operated Federal laboratory for purposes of section 12 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 3710a</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of research grants</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, through the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy, may authorize the President of the Defense Security Cooperation University to accept qualifying research grants. Any such grant may only be accepted if the work under the grant is to be carried out by a professor or instructor of the Defense Security Cooperation University for a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifying grants</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A qualifying research grant under this paragraph is a grant that is awarded on a competitive basis by an entity described in subparagraph (C) for a research project with a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Entities from which grants may be accepted</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A grant may be accepted under this paragraph only from a corporation, fund, foundation, educational institution, or similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific, literary, or educational purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration of grant funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency shall establish an account for administering funds received as research grants under this section. The President of the Defense Security Cooperation University shall use the funds in the account in accordance with applicable provisions of the regulations and the terms and condition of the grants received.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Related expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the Defense Security Cooperation University may be used to pay expenses incurred by the Defense Security Cooperation University in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, the award of qualifying research grants.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, through the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy, shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Source of Funds.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds available to the Defense Security Cooperation Agency, and other funds available to the Department of Defense for security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense, may be used to carry out the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Budget justification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds necessary to carry out the Program as described in paragraph (1) for a fiscal year shall be identified, with appropriate justification, in the consolidated budget for such fiscal year required by <ref>section 381 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts available for use for the Program may be transferred to any account of the military departments or the Defense Agencies for purposes of the Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Security Cooperation Workforce Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “security cooperation workforce” means the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Members of the armed forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense working in the security cooperation organizations of United States missions overseas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Members of the armed forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense in the geographic combatant commands and functional combatant commands responsible for planning, monitoring, or conducting security cooperation activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Members of the armed forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense in the military departments performing security cooperation activities, including activities in connection with the acquisition and development of technology release policies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Other military and civilian personnel of Defense Agencies and Field Activities who perform security cooperation activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Personnel of the Department of Defense who perform assessments, monitoring, or evaluations of security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense, including assessments under <ref>section 383 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Other members of the armed forces or civilian employees of the Department of Defense who contribute significantly to the security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense by virtue of their assigned duties, as determined pursuant to the security cooperation human capital initiative under subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Report on Security Cooperation Workforce.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the Department of Defense security cooperation workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify current and projected security cooperation workforce manpower requirements, including expeditionary requirements within the context of total force planning, needed to meet the security cooperation mission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify critical skill gaps (such as recruitment in the existing or projected workforce) and development of strategies to manage the security cooperation workforce to address those gaps;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> address development, validation, implementation, and assessment of security cooperation workforce and Department-wide competencies for security cooperation and associated occupational series using the Department taxonomy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> produce a comparison between competency proficiency levels against target proficiency levels at enterprise and individual levels to identify competency gaps and gap closure strategies, for competencies needed at the time of the report and in the future;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> identify any exceptions and waivers granted with respect to the application of qualification, assignment, and tenure policies, procedures, and practices to persons, billets or positions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> indicate relative promotion rates for security cooperation workforce personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> identify the funds requested or allocated for the Department of Defense security cooperation workforce and address whether such funds are sufficient to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> address the critical skill gaps identified pursuant to subparagraph (B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide incentives to recruit and retain high-quality personnel in the security cooperation workforce; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> include any other matters the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Comptroller General Evaluation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an independent evaluation of the actions taken by the Secretary of Defense to carry out the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1). Such report shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an analysis of the effectiveness of the actions taken by the Secretary to carry out the requirements of this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such legislative and administrative recommendations as the Comptroller General considers appropriate to meet the objectives of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1250(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2526</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XII, § 1204(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 385.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense support for other departments and agencies of the United States Government that advance Department of Defense security cooperation objectives</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense is authorized to support other departments and agencies of the United States Government for the purpose of implementing or supporting foreign assistance programs and activities described in subsection (b) that advance security cooperation objectives of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Foreign Assistance Programs and Activities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The foreign assistance programs and activities described in this subsection are foreign assistance programs and activities that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are necessary for the effectiveness of one or more programs of the Department of Defense relating to security cooperation conducted pursuant to an authority in this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> cannot be carried out by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Limitation on Amount of Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of support provided pursuant to subsection (a) in any fiscal year may not exceed $75,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice and Wait</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a determination is made to transfer funds in connection with the provision of support pursuant to subsection (a) for a program or activity, the transfer may not occur until—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary and the head of the department or agency to receive the funds jointly submit to the congressional defense committees a notice on the transfer, which notice shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a detailed description of the purpose and estimated cost of such program or activity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a detailed description of the security cooperation objectives of the Department, including the theater campaign plan of the combatant command concerned, that will be advanced;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a justification why such program or activity will advance such objectives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a justification why such program or activity cannot be carried out by the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an identification of any funds programmed or obligated by the department or agency other than the Department on such program or activity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a timeline for the provision of such support; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a period of 30 days elapses after the date of the submittal of the notice pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(m)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2511</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1204(c)(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2017</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 386.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Report Required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than March 31 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that sets forth, on a country-by-country basis, an overview of security cooperation activities carried out by the Department of Defense during the fiscal year in which such report is submitted, using the authorities specified in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each report required under subsection (a) shall include, with respect to each country and for the entirety of the period covered by such report, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A narrative summary that provides—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a brief overview of the primary security cooperation objectives for the activities encompassed by the report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of how such activities advance the theater security cooperation strategy of the relevant geographic combatant command.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A table that includes an aggregated amount with respect to each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> With respect to <ref>section 331 of this title</ref>, the value of all logistic support, supplies, and services for which notice is required by such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> With respect to amounts made available for <ref>section 332(a) of this title</ref>, the Department of Defense cost to provide any Department personnel as advisors to a ministry of defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> With respect to amounts made available for <ref>section 332(b) of this title</ref>, the Department of Defense incremental execution costs to conduct activities under such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> With respect to <ref>section 333 of this title</ref>, the value of all programs for which notice is required by such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> With respect to <ref>section 335 of this title</ref>, the total Department of Defense costs to fund expenses to attend training provided by the Government of Colombia that began during the period of the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> With respect to amounts made available for <ref>section 341 of this title</ref>, the Department of Defense manpower and travel costs to conduct bilateral state partnership program engagements with the partner country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> With respect to amounts made available for <ref>section 342 of this title</ref>, the Department of Defense-funded, foreign-partner travel costs to attend a regional center activity that began during the period of the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> With respect to amounts made available for <ref>section 345 of this title</ref>, the estimated Department of Defense execution cost to complete all training that began during the period of the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> With respect to amounts made available for <ref>section 2561 of this title</ref>, the planned execution cost of completing humanitarian assistance activities for the partner country that were approved for the period of the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A table that includes aggregated totals for each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Pursuant to <ref>section 311 of this title</ref>, the number of personnel from a partner country assigned to a Department of Defense organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The number of new programs carried out during the period of the report that required notice under <ref>section 331 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Pursuant to <ref>section 332(a) of this title</ref>, the number of Department of Defense personnel assigned as advisors to a ministry of defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Pursuant to <ref>section 332(b) of this title</ref>, the number of activities conducted by the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The number of new programs carried out during the period of the report that required notice under <ref>section 333 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> With respect to <ref>section 335 of this title</ref>, the number of partner country officials who participated in training provided by the Government of Colombia that began during the period of the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> With respect to <ref>section 341 of this title</ref>, the number of Department of Defense bilateral state partnership program engagements with the partner country that began during the period of the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> With respect to <ref>section 342 of this title</ref>, the number of partner country officials who participated in regional center activity that began during the period of the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Pursuant to the authorities under sections 343, 345, 348, 349, 350 and 352 of this title, the total number of partner country personnel who began training during the period of the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Pursuant to <ref>section 347 of this title</ref>, the number of cadets from the partner country that were enrolled in the Service Academies during the period of the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> Pursuant to amounts made available to carry out <ref>section 2561 of this title</ref>, the number of new humanitarian assistance projects funded through the Overseas Humanitarian Disaster and Civic Aid account that were approved during the period of the required report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> A table that includes the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> For each person from the partner country assigned to a Department of Defense organization pursuant to <ref>section 311 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> whether the person is a member of the armed forces or a civilian;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the rank of the person (if applicable); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the component of the Department of Defense and location to which such person is assigned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> With respect to each civilian employee of the Department of Defense or member of the armed forces that was assigned, pursuant to <ref>section 332(a) of this title</ref>, as an advisor to a ministry of defense during the period of the report, a description of the object of the Department of Defense for such support and the name of the ministry or regional organization to which the employee or member was assigned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to each activity commenced under <ref>section 332(b) of this title</ref> during the period of the report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the name of the supported ministry or regional organization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the component of the Department of Defense that conducted the activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the duration of the activity; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a description of the objective of the activity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> For each program that required notice to Congress under <ref>section 333 of this title</ref> during the period of the report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the units of the national security forces of the foreign country to which assistance was provided;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the type of operation capability assisted;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a description of the nature of the assistance being provided; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the estimated cost included in the notice provided for such assistance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to each Government of Colombia training activity which included Department of Defense funded participants under <ref>section 335 of this title</ref> that commenced during the period of the report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the units of the defense personnel of the friendly foreign country to which the Department of Defense funded assistance was provided;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the units of the Government of Colombia that conducted the training activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the duration of the training activity provided by the Government of Colombia; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a description of the objective of the training activity provided by the Government of Colombia.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to each activity commenced under <ref>section 341 of this title</ref> during the period of the report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of the activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the duration of the activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the number of participating members of the National Guard; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the number of participating personnel of foreign country.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to each activity of a Regional Center for Security Studies commenced under <ref>section 342 of this title</ref> during the period of the report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of the activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the name of the Regional Center that sponsored the activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the location and duration of the training; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the number of officials from the foreign country who participated the activity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to each training event that commenced under section 343, 345, 348, 349, 350, or 352 of this title during the period of the report—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of the training;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the location and duration of the training; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the number of personnel of the foreign country trained.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to each new project approved under <ref>section 2561 of this title</ref> during the period of the report and funded through the Overseas Humanitarian Disaster and Civic Aid account—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the title of the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a description of the assistance to be provided; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the anticipated costs to provide such assistance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII</ref>, §§ 1246(d)(2)(A), 1251(a)–(f), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2521</ref>, 2529–2531; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1204(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1202(d)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2823</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 683</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XII, § 1205(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2094</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>