<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 951—</num>
<heading>TRAINING GENERALLY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9401.</num>
<heading> Members of Air Force and Space Force: detail as students, observers, and investigators at educational institutions, industrial plants, and hospitals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force may detail members of the Air Force and members of the Space Force as students at such technical, professional, and other civilian educational institutions, or as students, observers, or investigators at such industrial plants, hospitals, and other places, as are best suited to enable them to acquire knowledge or experience in the specialties in which it is considered necessary that they perfect themselves.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An officer, other than one of the Regular Air Force on the active-duty list, or one of the Space Force in a space force active status not on sustained duty, who is detailed under subsection (a) shall be ordered to additional active duty immediately upon termination of the detail, for a period at least as long as the detail. However, if the detail is for 90 days or less, the officer may be ordered to that additional duty only with his consent and in the discretion of the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> No Reserve of the Air Force or member of the Space Force in a space force active status not on sustained duty may be detailed as a student, observer, or investigator, or ordered to active duty under this section, without the member’s consent and, if a member of the Air National Guard of the United States, without the approval of the governor or other appropriate authority of the State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, Guam, or the Virgin Islands of whose Air National Guard the Reserve is a member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary may require, as a condition of a detail under subsection (a), that an enlisted member accept a discharge and be reenlisted in his component for at least three years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The total length of details of an enlisted member of the Air Force or the Space Force under subsection (a) during one enlistment period may not exceed 50 percent of that enlistment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> At no time may more than 8 percent of the authorized strength in commissioned officers, 8 percent of the authorized strength in warrant officers, or 2 percent of the authorized strength in enlisted members, of the Regular Air Force or of Space Force members on sustained duty, or more than 8 percent of the actual strength in commissioned officers, 8 percent of the actual strength in warrant officers, or 2 percent of the actual strength in enlisted members, of the total of reserve components of the Air Force or of Space Force members in an active status not on sustained duty, be detailed as students under subsection (a). For the purposes of this subsection, the actual strength of each category of Reserves includes both members on active duty and those not on active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Expenses incident to the detail of members under this section shall be paid from any funds appropriated for the Department of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 559</ref>, § 9301; <ref>Pub. L. 93–169</ref>, <date date="1973-11-29">Nov. 29, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 689</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 504(23)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2917</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3441</ref>; renumbered § 9401, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(1)(A)</ref>–(C), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3813</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(35)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1921</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1721(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 666</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9402.</num>
<heading> Enlisted members of Air Force or Space Force: schools</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> So far as consistent with the requirements of military training and service, and under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force with the approval of the President, enlisted members of the Air Force and enlisted members of the Space Force shall be permitted to study and receive instruction to increase their military efficiency and to enable them to return to civilian life better equipped for industrial, commercial, and business occupations. Part of this instruction may be vocational education in agriculture or the mechanic arts. Civilian teachers may be employed to aid Air Force officers and Space Force officers in this instruction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Schools for the instruction of enlisted members of the Air Force or the Space Force in the common branches of education, including United States history, shall be maintained at all air bases at which members of the Air Force or the Space Force are stationed. The Secretary may detail members of the Air Force or the Space Force to carry out this subsection. The commander of each air base where schools are maintained under this subsection shall provide a suitable room or building for school and religious purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 560</ref>, § 9302; renumbered § 9402, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(2)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3813</ref>, 3814; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(36)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1921</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9403.</num>
<heading> Aviation cadets and aviation students: schools</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Air Force shall establish and maintain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> one or more schools for the training and instruction of aviation cadets; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> courses of instruction for aviation students at one or more established flying schools.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 560</ref>, § 9303; renumbered § 9403, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9404.</num>
<heading> Aviation students: detail of enlisted members of Air Force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Air Force may detail enlisted Regulars of the Air Force, and enlisted Reserves of the Air Force who are on active duty, for training and instruction as aviation students in their respective grades at schools selected by him.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 560</ref>, § 9304; renumbered § 9404, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9405.</num>
<heading> Civilian flying school instructors: instruction at Air Force training commands</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force may provide for the instruction and training, at Air Force training commands, of civilians selected from the instructional staffs of civilian flying schools that are accredited by the Department of the Air Force for the education and training of members of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The training of civilians under subsection (a) shall be without cost to the United States, except for supplies necessary for training purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A civilian undergoing training under subsection (a) may be treated in a Government hospital if he becomes sick or is injured. However, that treatment shall be without cost to the United States except for services of Government medical personnel and the use of hospital equipment other than medicine or supplies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> No civilian who sustains a personal injury, and no dependent of a civilian who dies of disease or injury, while undergoing training under subsection (a), is entitled to any compensation, pension, or gratuity for that injury or death.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 560</ref>, § 9305; renumbered § 9405, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9406.</num>
<heading> Service schools: leaves of absence for instructors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The officer in charge of an Air Force or Space Force service school may grant a leave of absence for the period of the suspension of the ordinary academic studies, without deduction of pay or allowances, to any officer on duty exclusively as an instructor at the school.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 561</ref>, § 9306; renumbered § 9406, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9413.</num>
<heading> United States Air Force Institute of Technology: establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is in the Department of the Air Force a United States Air Force Institute of Technology, the purposes of which are to perform research and to provide, to members of the Air Force and Space Force (including the reserve components) and civilian employees of such Department, advanced instruction and technical education regarding their duties.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 558(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1741</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9414.</num>
<heading> Degree granting authority for United States Air Force Institute of Technology</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force, the commander of the Air University may, upon the recommendation of the faculty of the United States Air Force Institute of Technology, confer appropriate degrees upon graduates of the United States Air Force Institute of Technology who meet the degree requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A degree may not be conferred under this section unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Education has recommended approval of the degree in accordance with the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States Air Force Institute of Technology is accredited by the appropriate civilian academic accrediting agency or organization to award the degree, as determined by the Secretary of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> When seeking to establish degree granting authority under this section, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a copy of the self assessment questionnaire required by the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies, at the time the assessment is submitted to the Department of Education’s National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the subsequent recommendations and rationale of the Secretary of Education regarding the establishment of the degree granting authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon any modification or redesignation of existing degree granting authority, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing the rationale for the proposed modification or redesignation and any subsequent recommendation of the Secretary of Education on the proposed modification or redesignation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing an explanation of any action by the appropriate academic accrediting agency or organization not to accredit the United States Air Force Institute of Technology to award any new or existing degree.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civilian Faculty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force may employ as many civilian faculty members at the United States Air Force Institute of Technology as is consistent with the needs of the Air Force or the Space Force and with Department of Defense personnel limits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations determining—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> titles and duties of civilian members of the faculty; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> pay of civilian members of the faculty, notwithstanding chapter 53 of title 5, but subject to the limitation set out in <ref>section 5373 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement and Tuition</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, and the Department of Homeland Security shall bear the cost of the instruction at the Air Force Institute of Technology that is received by members of the armed forces detailed for that instruction by the Secretaries of the Army, Navy, and Homeland Security, respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Members of the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard may only be detailed for instruction at the Institute on a space-available basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of an enlisted member of the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard permitted to receive instruction at the Institute, the Secretary of the Air Force shall charge that member only for such costs and fees as the Secretary considers appropriate (taking into consideration the admission of enlisted members on a space-available basis).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Institute shall charge tuition for the cost of providing instruction at the Institute for any civilian employee of a military department (other than a civilian employee of the Department of the Air Force), of another component of the Department of Defense, or of another Federal agency who receives instruction at the Institute.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The cost of any tuition charged an individual under this paragraph shall be borne by the department, agency, or component sending the individual for instruction at the Institute.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Amounts received by the Institute for the instruction of students under this subsection shall be retained by the Institute. Such amounts shall be available to the Institute to cover the costs of such instruction. The source and disposition of such amounts shall be specifically identified in the records of the Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Research Grants</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force may authorize the Director and Chancellor of the United States Air Force Institute of Technology to accept qualifying research grants. Any such grant may only be accepted if the work under the grant is to be carried out by a professor or instructor of the Institute for a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A qualifying research grant under this subsection is a grant that is awarded on a competitive basis by an entity referred to in paragraph (3) for a research project with a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A grant may be accepted under this subsection only from a corporation, fund, foundation, educational institution, or similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific, literary, or educational purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish an account for administering funds received as research grants under this section. The Director and Chancellor of the Institute shall use the funds in the account in accordance with applicable provisions of the regulations and the terms and condition of the grants received.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the Institute may be used to pay expenses incurred by the Institute in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, the award of qualifying research grants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 561</ref>, § 9314; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 504(a)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 622</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V, § 510</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3868</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 106(b)(6)(C)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1440; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title XI, § 1102</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2141</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 533</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1473</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 522(e)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, §§ 543(h)(1), 544, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4463</ref>, 4465; renumbered § 9414, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 556(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9414a.</num>
<heading> United States Air Force Institute of Technology: admission of certain private sector civilians</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Admission Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force may permit a covered private sector employee to receive instruction at the United States Air Force Institute of Technology in accordance with this section. A covered private sector employee may be enrolled in, and may be provided instruction in, a program leading to a graduate degree or professional continuing education certificate in a defense-focused or homeland security-focused curriculum related to aeronautics and astronautics, electrical and computer engineering, engineering physics, mathematics and statistics, operational sciences, or systems and engineering management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No more than 125 covered private sector employees may be enrolled at the United States Air Force Institute of Technology at any one time under the authority of paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Upon successful completion of the course of instruction at the United States Air Force Institute of Technology in which a covered private sector employee is enrolled, the covered private sector employee may be awarded an appropriate degree under <ref>section 9414 of this title</ref> or an appropriate professional continuing education certificate, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Private Sector Employee Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In this section, the term “covered private sector employee” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an individual employed by a private firm that is engaged in providing to the Department of Defense significant and substantial defense-related systems, products, or services; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an individual employed by a private firm in one of the critical infrastructure sectors identified in Presidential Policy Directive 21 (Critical Infrastructure Security and Resilience).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A covered private sector employee admitted for instruction at the United States Air Force Institute of Technology remains eligible for such instruction only so long as the person remains employed by the same firm.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Determination by the Secretary of the Air Force</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A covered private sector employee may receive instruction at the United States Air Force Institute of Technology during any academic year only if, before the start of that academic year, the Secretary of the Air Force, or the designee of the Secretary, determines that providing instruction to covered private sector employees under this section during that year—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> will further the military mission of the United States Air Force Institute of Technology; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> will not require an increase in the permanently authorized size of the faculty of the school, an increase in the course offerings of the school, or an increase in the laboratory facilities or other infrastructure of the school.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Air Force shall ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the curriculum in which a covered private sector employee may be enrolled under this section is not readily available through other schools and concentrates on the areas of focus specified in subsection (a)(1) that are conducted by military organizations and defense or homeland security contractors working in close cooperation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the course offerings at the United States Air Force Institute of Technology continue to be determined solely by the needs of the Department of Defense or the Department of Homeland Security, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tuition</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States Air Force Institute of Technology shall charge tuition for students enrolled under this section at a rate not less than the rate charged for employees of the United States outside the Department of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts received by the United States Air Force Institute of Technology for instruction of students enrolled under this section shall be retained by the school to defray the costs of such instruction. The source, and the disposition, of such funds shall be specifically identified in records of the school.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards of Conduct</inline>.—</heading>
<content>While receiving instruction at the United States Air Force Institute of Technology, covered private sector employees enrolled under this section, to the extent practicable, are subject to the same regulations governing academic performance, attendance, norms of behavior, and enrollment as apply to Government civilian employees receiving instruction at the school.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 593(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 4232</ref>, § 9314a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 589(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 558</ref>, title X, § 1081(a)(13), <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 827</ref>, 1001; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 581(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1414</ref>, 1415; renumbered § 9414a and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(a)(3), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9414b.</num>
<heading> United States Air Force Institute of Technology: administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Director and Chancellor.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selection</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director and Chancellor of the United States Air Force Institute of Technology shall be selected by the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director and Chancellor shall be one of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An officer of the Air Force or the Space Force on active duty in a grade not below the grade of colonel who possesses such qualifications as the Secretary considers appropriate and is assigned or detailed to such position.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A member of the Senior Executive Service or a civilian individual, including an individual who was retired from the Air Force or the Space Force in a grade not below brigadier general, who has the qualifications appropriate for the position of Director and Chancellor and is selected by the Secretary as the best qualified from among candidates for the position in accordance with a process and criteria determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term for civilian director and chancellor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual selected for the position of Director and Chancellor under paragraph (2)(B) shall serve in that position for a term of not more than five years and may be continued in that position for an additional term of up to five years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Provost and Chief Academic Officer.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established at the United States Air Force Institute of Technology the civilian position of Provost and Chief Academic Officer who shall be selected by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual selected for the position of Provost and Chief Academic Officer shall serve in that position for a term of not more than five years and may be continued in that position for an additional term of up to five years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The individual serving as Provost and Chief Academic Officer is entitled to such compensation for such service as the Secretary shall prescribe for purposes of this section, but not more than the rate of compensation authorized for level IV of the Executive Schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 554(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1414</ref>, § 9314b; renumbered § 9414b, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 556(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(5)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 554(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2594</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 521</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1882</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9415.</num>
<heading> Community College of the Air Force: associate degrees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Mission</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There is in the Department of the Air Force a Community College of the Air Force. Such college, in cooperation with civilian colleges and universities, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prescribe programs of higher education for enlisted members described in subsection (b) designed to improve the technical, managerial, and related skills of such members and to prepare such members for military jobs which require the utilization of such skills; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> monitor on a continuing basis the progress of members pursuing such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members Eligible for Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to such other eligibility requirements as the Secretary concerned may prescribe, the following members of the armed forces are eligible to participate in programs of higher education under subsection (a)(1):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Enlisted members of the Air Force or the Space Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Enlisted members of the armed forces other than the Air Force or the Space Force who are serving as instructors at Department of the Air Force training schools.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Enlisted members of the armed forces other than the Air Force or the Space Force who are participating in Community College of the Air Force affiliated joint-service training and education courses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Seriously Wounded, Ill, or Injured Former and Retired Enlisted Members</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Air Force may authorize participation in a program of higher education under subsection (a)(1) by a person who is a former or retired enlisted member of the armed forces who at the time of the person’s separation from active duty—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> had commenced but had not completed a program of higher education under subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is categorized by the Secretary concerned as seriously wounded, ill, or injured.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, a person who may be categorized as seriously wounded, ill, or injured is a person with a serious injury or illness (as that term is defined in section 1602(8) of the Wounded Warrior Act (title XVI of <ref>Public Law 110–181</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 1071</ref> note)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A person may not be authorized under paragraph (1) to participate in a program of higher education after the end of the 10-year period beginning on the date of the person’s separation from active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not pay the tuition for participation in a program of higher education under subsection (a)(1) of a person participating in such program pursuant to an authorization under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Associate Degrees</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), an academic degree at the level of associate may be conferred under <ref>section 9417 of this title</ref> upon any person who has completed a program prescribed by the Community College of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No degree may be conferred upon any person under this section unless the Secretary of Education determines that the standards for the award of academic degrees in agencies of the United States have been met.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–361, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1976-07-14">July 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 928</ref>, § 9315; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 514(9)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2935</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1182(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1078(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 451</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 552(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1748</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 556(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1915</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 555(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1415</ref>; renumbered § 9415 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(a)(3), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>, 1840; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 557</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9417.</num>
<heading> Degree granting authority for Air University</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in sections 9414 and 9415 of this title, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force, the commander of the Air University may, upon the recommendation of the faculty of the Air University components, confer appropriate degrees upon graduates who meet the degree requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A degree may not be conferred under this section unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Education has recommended approval of the degree in accordance with the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Air University is accredited by the appropriate civilian academic accrediting agency or organization to award the degree, as determined by the Secretary of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> When seeking to establish degree granting authority under this section, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a copy of the self assessment questionnaire required by the Federal Policy Governing Granting of Academic Degrees by Federal Agencies, at the time the assessment is submitted to the Department of Education’s National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the subsequent recommendations and rationale of the Secretary of Education regarding the establishment of the degree granting authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon any modification or redesignation of existing degree granting authority, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing the rationale for the proposed modification or redesignation and any subsequent recommendation of the Secretary of Education on the proposed modification or redesignation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing an explanation of any action by the appropriate academic accrediting agency or organization not to accredit the Air University to award any new or existing degree.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 913(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2828</ref>, § 9317; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 543(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 607</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 556(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1914</ref>, 1915; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 527</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 543(i)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4464</ref>; renumbered § 9417 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(a)(3), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9419.</num>
<heading> Recruit basic training: separate housing for male and female recruits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Physically Separate Housing</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Air Force shall provide for housing male recruits and female recruits separately and securely from each other during basic training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To meet the requirements of paragraph (1), the sleeping areas and latrine areas provided for male recruits shall be physically separated from the sleeping areas and latrine areas provided for female recruits by permanent walls, and the areas for male recruits and the areas for female recruits shall have separate entrances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall ensure that, when a recruit is in an area referred to in paragraph (2), the area is supervised by one or more persons who are authorized and trained to supervise the area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Alternative Separate Housing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If male recruits and female recruits cannot be housed as provided under subsection (a) by <date date="2001-10-01">October 1, 2001</date>, at a particular installation, the Secretary of the Air Force shall require (on and after that date) that male recruits in basic training at such installation be housed in barracks or other troop housing facilities that are only for males and that female recruits in basic training at such installation be housed in barracks or other troop housing facilities that are only for females.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction Planning</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In planning for the construction of housing to be used for housing recruits during basic training, the Secretary of the Air Force shall ensure that the housing is to be constructed in a manner that facilitates the housing of male recruits and female recruits separately and securely from each other.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basic Training Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “basic training” means the initial entry training program of the Air Force or the Space Force that constitutes the basic training of new recruits.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 521(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2011</ref>, § 9319; renumbered § 9419, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1741(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 681</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9420.</num>
<heading> Recruit basic training: privacy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Air Force shall require that access by military training instructors and other training personnel to a living area in which recruits are housed during basic training shall be limited after the end of the training day, other than in the case of an emergency or other exigent circumstance, to military training instructors and other training personnel who are of the same sex as the recruits housed in that living area or to superiors in the chain of command of those recruits who, if not of the same sex as the recruits housed in that living area, are accompanied by a member (other than a recruit) who is of the same sex as the recruits housed in that living area.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 522(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2013</ref>, § 9320; renumbered § 9420, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>