<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 247—</num>
<heading>PROCUREMENT OF COMMERCIAL PRODUCTS AND COMMERCIAL SERVICES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3451.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The terms “commercial product”, “commercial service”, “nondevelopmental item”, “component”, and “commercial component” have the meanings provided in sections 103, 103a, 110, 105, and 102, respectively, of title 41.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “head of an agency” means the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “agency” means the Department of Defense, the Coast Guard, and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title VIII, § 8103</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3390</ref>, § 2376; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(a)(19)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(22)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3844</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1866</ref>; renumbered § 3451 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1821(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(1)(A), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4195</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3452.</num>
<heading> Relationship of other provisions of law to procurement of commercial products and commercial services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Government-wide Statutes</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No contract for the procurement of a commercial product or commercial service entered into by the head of an agency shall be subject to any law properly listed in the Federal Acquisition Regulation pursuant to <ref>section 1906(b) of title 41</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No subcontract under a contract for the procurement of a commercial product or commercial service entered into by the head of an agency shall be subject to any law properly listed in the Federal Acquisition Regulation pursuant to <ref>section 1906(c) of title 41</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No contract for the procurement of a commercially available off-the-shelf item entered into by the head of an agency shall be subject to any law properly listed in the Federal Acquisition Regulation pursuant to <ref>section 1907 of title 41</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Defense-unique Statutes to Contracts for Commercial Products and Commercial Services</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement shall include a list of defense-unique provisions of law and of contract clause requirements based on government-wide acquisition regulations, policies, or executive orders not expressly authorized in law that are inapplicable to contracts for the procurement of commercial products and commercial services. A provision of law or contract clause requirement properly included on the list pursuant to paragraph (2) does not apply to purchases of commercial products and commercial services by the Department of Defense. This section does not render a provision of law or contract clause requirement not included on the list inapplicable to contracts for the procurement of commercial products and commercial services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A provision of law or contract clause requirement described in subsection (e) that is enacted after <date date="1994-10-13">October 13, 1994</date>, shall be included on the list of inapplicable provisions of law and contract clause requirements required by paragraph (1) unless the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment makes a written determination that it would not be in the best interest of the Department of Defense to exempt contracts for the procurement of commercial products and commercial services from the applicability of the provision or contract clause requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Defense-unique Statutes to Subcontracts for Commercial Products and Commercial Services</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement shall include a list of provisions of law and of contract clause requirements based on government-wide acquisition regulations, policies, or executive orders not expressly authorized in law that are inapplicable to subcontracts under a Department of Defense contract or subcontract for the procurement of commercial products and commercial services. A provision of law or contract clause requirement properly included on the list pursuant to paragraph (2) does not apply to those subcontracts. This section does not render a provision of law or contract clause requirement not included on the list inapplicable to subcontracts under a contract for the procurement of commercial products and commercial services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A provision of law or contract clause requirement described in subsection (e) shall be included on the list of inapplicable provisions of law and contract clause requirements required by paragraph (1) unless the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment makes a written determination that it would not be in the best interest of the Department of Defense to exempt subcontracts under a contract for the procurement of commercial products and commercial services from the applicability of the provision or contract clause requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “subcontract” includes a transfer of commercial products and commercial services between divisions, subsidiaries, or affiliates of a contractor or subcontractor. The term does not include agreements entered into by a contractor for the supply of commodities that are intended for use in the performance of multiple contracts with the Department of Defense and other parties and are not identifiable to any particular contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> This subsection does not authorize the waiver of the applicability of any provision of law or contract clause requirement with respect to any first-tier subcontract under a contract with a prime contractor reselling or distributing commercial products and commercial services of another contractor without adding value.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Defense-unique Statutes to Contracts for Commercially Available, Off-the-shelf Items</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement shall include a list of provisions of law and of contract clause requirements based on government-wide acquisition regulations, policies, or executive orders not expressly authorized in law that are inapplicable to contracts for the procurement of commercially available off-the-shelf items. A provision of law or contract clause requirement properly included on the list pursuant to paragraph (2) does not apply to Department of Defense contracts for the procurement of commercially available off-the-shelf items. This section does not render a provision of law or contract clause requirement not included on the list inapplicable to contracts for the procurement of commercially available off-the-shelf items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A provision of law or contract clause requirement described in subsection (e) shall be included on the list of inapplicable provisions of law and contract clause requirements required by paragraph (1) unless the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment makes a written determination that it would not be in the best interest of the Department of Defense to exempt contracts for the procurement of commercially available off-the-shelf items from the applicability of the provision or contract clause requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Provision of Law or Contract Clause Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A provision of law or contract clause requirement referred to in subsections (b)(2), (c)(2), and (d)(2) is a provision of law or contract clause requirement that the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment determines sets forth policies, procedures, requirements, or restrictions for the procurement of property or services by the Federal Government, except for a provision of law or contract clause requirement that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provides for criminal or civil penalties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> requires that certain articles be bought from American sources pursuant to <ref>section 4862 of this title</ref>, or requires that strategic materials critical to national security be bought from American sources pursuant to <ref>section 4863 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> specifically refers to this section and provides that, notwithstanding this section, it shall be applicable to contracts for the procurement of commercial products and commercial services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title VIII, § 8102</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3390</ref>, § 2375; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(51)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1903</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(a)(18)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(21)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3844</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 874(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2308</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 836(d)(1), (8)(B), 837(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1866</ref>, 1868, 1875; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(57)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1549</ref>; renumbered § 3452 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1821(a)(2), (b)(2), 1870(c)(6)(A), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4195</ref>, 4285.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3453.</num>
<heading> Preference for commercial products and commercial services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preference</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of an agency shall ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> requirements of the agency with respect to a procurement of supplies or services are stated in terms of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> functions to be performed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> performance required; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> essential physical characteristics;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such requirements are defined so that commercial services or commercial products or, to the extent that commercial products suitable to meet the agency’s needs are not available, nondevelopmental items other than commercial products, may be procured to fulfill such requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> offerors of commercial services, commercial products, and nondevelopmental items other than commercial products are provided an opportunity to compete in any procurement to fill such requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The head of an agency shall ensure that procurement officials in that agency, to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquire commercial services, commercial products, or nondevelopmental items other than commercial products to meet the needs of the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> require prime contractors and subcontractors at all levels under the agency contracts to incorporate commercial services, commercial products, or nondevelopmental items other than commercial products as components of items supplied to the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> modify requirements in appropriate cases to ensure that the requirements can be met by commercial services or commercial products or, to the extent that commercial products suitable to meet the agency’s needs are not available, nondevelopmental items other than commercial products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> state specifications in terms that enable and encourage bidders and offerors to supply commercial services or commercial products or, to the extent that commercial products suitable to meet the agency’s needs are not available, nondevelopmental items other than commercial products in response to the agency solicitations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> revise the agency’s procurement policies, practices, and procedures not required by law to reduce any impediments in those policies, practices, and procedures to the acquisition of commercial products and commercial services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> require training of appropriate personnel in the acquisition of commercial products and commercial services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> establish criteria in performance evaluations for appropriate personnel to reward risk-informed decisions that maximize the acquisition of commercial products, commercial services, or nondevelopmental items other than commercial products.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preliminary Market Research</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The head of an agency shall conduct market research appropriate to the circumstances—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> before developing new specifications for a procurement by that agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> before soliciting bids or proposals for a contract in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> before awarding a task order or delivery order in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The head of an agency shall use the results of market research to determine whether there are commercial services or commercial products or, to the extent that commercial products suitable to meet the agency’s needs are not available, nondevelopmental items other than commercial products available that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> meet the agency’s requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> could be modified to meet the agency’s requirements; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> could meet the agency’s requirements if those requirements were modified to a reasonable extent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In conducting market research, the head of an agency should not require potential sources to submit more than the minimum information that is necessary to make the determinations required in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The head of an agency shall document the results of market research in a manner appropriate to the size and complexity of the acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The head of an agency shall take appropriate steps to ensure that any prime contractor of a contract (or task order or delivery order) in an amount in excess of $5,000,000 for the procurement of products other than commercial products or services other than commercial services engages in such market research as may be necessary to carry out the requirements of subsection (b)(2) before making purchases for or on behalf of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Market Research for Price Analysis</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that procurement officials in the Department of Defense conduct or obtain market research to support the determination of the reasonableness of price for commercial products or commercial services contained in any bid or offer submitted in response to an agency solicitation. To the extent necessary to support such market research, the procurement official for the solicitation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of products or services acquired under <ref>section 3455 of this title</ref>, shall use information submitted under subsection (d) of that section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of other products or services, may require the offeror to submit relevant information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Market Research Training Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall provide mandatory training for members of the armed forces and employees of the Department of Defense responsible for the conduct of market research required under subsections (c) and (d). Such mandatory training shall, at a minimum—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide comprehensive information on the subject of market research and the function of market research in the acquisition of commercial products and commercial services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> teach best practices for conducting and documenting market research; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide methodologies for establishing standard processes and reports for collecting and sharing market research across the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–355, title VIII, § 8104(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3390</ref>, § 2377; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VIII, § 826(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 227</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 844(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 915</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 871</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(d)(3)</ref>, (8)(C), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1866</ref>, 1868; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 818(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1488</ref>; renumbered § 3453 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1821(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4195</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 834</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3455.</num>
<heading> Procurement of a major weapon system as a commercial product: requirement for prior determination by Secretary of Defense and notification to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Determination and Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A major weapon system of the Department of Defense may be treated as a commercial product, or purchased under procedures established for the procurement of commercial products, only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of Defense determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the major weapon system is a commercial product; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such treatment is necessary to meet national security objectives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the congressional defense committees are notified at least 30 days before such treatment or purchase occurs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Subsystems as Commercial Products</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A subsystem of a major weapon system (other than a commercially available off-the-shelf item as defined in <ref>section 104 of title 41</ref>) shall be treated as a commercial product and purchased under procedures established for the procurement of commercial products if either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the subsystem is intended for a major weapon system that is being purchased, or has been purchased, under procedures established for the procurement of commercial products in accordance with the requirements of subsection (a); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the contracting officer determines in writing that the subsystem is a commercial product.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> For a subsystem proposed as commercial (as defined in <ref>section 103(1) of title 41</ref>) and that has not been previously determined commercial in accordance with <ref>section 3703(d) of this title</ref>, the offeror shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identify the comparable commercial product the offeror sells to the general public or nongovernmental entities that serves as the basis for the “of a type” assertion;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> submit to the contracting officer a comparison necessary to serve as the basis of the “of a type” assertion of the physical characteristics and functionality between the subsystem and the comparable commercial product identified under clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provide to the contracting officer the National Stock Number for both the comparable commercial product identified under clause (i), if one is assigned, and the subsystem, if one is assigned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If the offeror does not sell a comparable commercial product to the general public or nongovernmental entities for purposes other than governmental purposes that can serve as the basis for an “of a type” assertion with respect to the subsystem—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the offeror shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> notify the contracting officer in writing that it does not so sell such a comparable commercial product; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> provide to the contracting officer a comparison necessary to serve as the basis of the “of a type” assertion of the physical characteristics and functionality between the subsystem and the most comparable commercial product in the commercial marketplace, to the extent reasonably known by the offeror; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to the offeror for such subsystem.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Components and Spare Parts as Commercial Products</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A component or spare part for a major weapon system (other than a commercially available off-the-shelf item as defined in <ref>section 104 of title 41</ref>) may be treated as a commercial product for the purposes of chapter 271 of this title if either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the component or spare part is intended for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a major weapon system that is being purchased, or has been purchased, under procedures established for the procurement of commercial products in accordance with the requirements of subsection (a); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a subsystem of a major weapon system that is being purchased, or has been purchased, under procedures established for the procurement of commercial products in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b); or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the contracting officer determines in writing that the component or spare part is a commercial product.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> For a component or spare part proposed as commercial (as defined in <ref>section 103(1) of title 41</ref>) and that has not previously been determined commercial in accordance with <ref>section 3703(d) of this title</ref>, the offeror shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identify the comparable commercial product the offeror sells to the general public or nongovernmental entities that serves as the basis for the “of a type” assertion;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> submit to the contracting officer a comparison necessary to serve as the basis of the “of a type” assertion of the physical characteristics and functionality between the component or spare part and the comparable commercial product identified under clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provide to the contracting officer the National Stock Number for both the comparable commercial product identified under clause (i), if one is assigned, and the component or spare part, if one is assigned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If the offeror does not sell a comparable commercial product to the general public or nongovernmental entities for purposes other than governmental purposes that can serve as the basis for an “of a type” assertion with respect to the component or spare part—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the offeror shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> notify the contracting officer in writing that it does not so sell such a comparable commercial product; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> provide to the contracting officer a comparison necessary to serve as the basis of the “of a type” assertion of the physical characteristics and functionality between the component or spare part and the most comparable commercial product in the commercial marketplace, to the extent reasonably known by the offeror; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to the offeror for such component or spare part.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information Submitted for Procurements That Are Not Covered by the Exceptions in Section </inline>3703<inline class="small-caps">(a)(</inline>1<inline class="small-caps">) of This Title</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent necessary to determine the reasonableness of the price for items acquired under this section, the offeror shall, in accordance with paragraph (4), submit to the contracting officer or provide the contracting officer access to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a representative sample, as determined by the contracting officer, of the prices paid for the same or similar commercial products under comparable terms and conditions by both Government and commercial customers, and the terms and conditions of such sales;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the contracting officer determines that the offeror does not have access to and cannot provide sufficient information described in subparagraph (A) to determine the reasonableness of price, a representative sample, as determined by the contracting officer, of the prices paid for the same or similar commercial products sold under different terms and conditions, and the terms and conditions of such sales; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> only if the contracting officer determines that the information submitted pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) is not sufficient to determine the reasonableness of price because either the comparable commercial products provided by the offeror are not a valid basis for a price analysis or the contracting officer determines the proposed price is not reasonable after evaluating sales data, and the contracting officer receives the approval described in paragraph (5), other relevant information regarding the basis for price or cost, including information on labor costs, material costs, and overhead rates.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An offeror may submit information or analysis relating to the value of a commercial product to aid in the determination of the reasonableness of the price of such item. A contracting officer may consider such information or analysis in addition to the information submitted pursuant to paragraphs (1)(A) and (1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An offeror may not be required to submit information described in paragraph (1)(C) with regard to a commercially available off-the-shelf item and may be required to submit such information with regard to any other item that was developed exclusively at private expense only after the head of the contracting activity determines in writing that the information submitted pursuant to paragraphs (1)(A) and (1)(B) is not sufficient to determine the reasonableness of price.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An offeror may redact data information submitted or made available under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) with respect to sales of an item acquired under this section only to the extent necessary to remove information individually identifying government customers, commercial customers purchasing such item for governmental purposes, and commercial customers purchasing such item for commercial, mixed, or unknown purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Before an offeror may exercise the authority under subparagraph (A) with respect to a customer, the offeror shall certify in writing to the contracting officer whether the customer is a government customer, a commercial customer purchasing the item for governmental purpose, or a commercial customer purchasing the item for a commercial, mixed, or unknown purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A contracting officer may not require an offeror to submit or make available information under paragraph (1)(C) without approval from a level above the contracting officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall relieve an offeror of other obligations under any other law or regulation to disclose and support the actual rationale of the offeror for the price proposed by the offeror to the Government for any good or service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary of Defense to make a determination under subsection (a) may be delegated only to the Deputy Secretary of Defense, without further redelegation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major Weapon System Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “major weapon system” means a weapon system acquired pursuant to a major defense acquisition program (as that term is defined in section 2430 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002119">1</ref> of this title).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applicability.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsections (b) and (c) shall apply only with respect to subsystems described in subsection (b) and components or spare parts described in subsection (c), respectively, that the Department of Defense acquires through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a prime contract;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a modification to a prime contract; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a subcontract described in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subcontract described</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A subcontract described in this paragraph is a subcontract through which the Department of Defense acquires a subsystem or component or spare part proposed as commercial (as defined in <ref>section 103(1) of title 41</ref>) under this section and that has not previously been determined commercial in accordance with section 3703(d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VIII, § 803(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3370</ref>, § 2379; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VIII, § 815(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 222</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 852(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 917</ref>, 918; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 872</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(d)(4)</ref>, (8)(D), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1868</ref>, 1869; renumbered § 3455 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1821(a)(2), (b)(4), 1831(j)(4), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4195</ref>, 4217, 4294; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(10)(i)(ii)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2134</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3456.</num>
<heading> Commercial product and commercial service determinations by Department of Defense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish and maintain a centralized capability with necessary expertise and resources to provide assistance to the military departments and Defense Agencies in making commercial product and commercial service determinations, conducting market research, and performing analysis of price reasonableness for the purposes of procurements by the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide to officials of the Department of Defense access to previous Department of Defense commercial product and commercial service determinations, market research, and analysis used to determine the reasonableness of price for the purposes of procurements by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Determinations Regarding the Commercial Nature of Products or Services.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In making a determination whether a particular product or service offered by a contractor meets the definition of a commercial product or commercial service, a contracting officer of the Department of Defense may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> request support from the Director of the Defense Contract Management Agency, the Director of the Defense Contract Audit Agency, or other appropriate experts in the Department to make a determination whether a product or service is a commercial product or commercial service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consider the views of appropriate public and private sector entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Memorandum</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Within 30 days after a contract award, the contracting officer shall, consistent with the policies and regulations of the Department, submit a written memorandum summarizing the determination referred to in paragraph (1), including a detailed justification why the product or service was determined to be commercial or noncommercial. Upon the request of the contractor or subcontractor offering the product or service for which such determination is summarized in such memorandum, the contracting officer shall provide to such contractor or subcontractor a copy of such memorandum.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Items Previously Acquired Using Commercial Acquisition Procedures.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determinations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A contract or subcontract for a product (including a product without a part number or a product with a prior part number that has the same functionality as the product had with the prior part number) or service acquired using commercial acquisition procedures under part 12 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall serve as a prior commercial product or commercial service determination with respect to such product or service for purposes of this chapter, including when subject to minor modifications, unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the prior determination was not issued or approved by a contracting officer of the Department of Defense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the senior procurement executive of the military department or the Department of Defense as designated for purposes of <ref>section 1702(c) of title 41</ref> determines in writing that it is no longer appropriate to acquire the product or service using commercial acquisition procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided under subparagraph (B), funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Defense may not be used for the procurement under part 15 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation of a product or service that was previously acquired under a contract using commercial acquisition procedures under part 12 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The limitation under subparagraph (A) does not apply to the procurement of a product or service that was previously acquired using commercial acquisition procedures under part 12 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation following—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a written determination by the head of contracting activity pursuant to <ref>section 3703(d)(2) of this title</ref> that the use of such procedures was improper; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a written determination by the senior procurement executive of the military department or the Department of Defense as designated for purposes of <ref>section 1702(c) of title 41</ref> that it is no longer appropriate to acquire the product or service using such procedures.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 851(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 916</ref>, § 2380; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 873</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 848</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1487</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(d)(5)</ref>, (8)(E), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1868</ref>, 1869; renumbered § 3456 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 816</ref>, title XVIII, §§ 1821(a)(2), (b)(5), 1831(j)(5), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3750</ref>, 4195, 4217; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(9)</ref>, (10)(I)(ii), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2133</ref>, 2134; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 312</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 814</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1980</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3457.</num>
<heading> Treatment of certain products and services as commercial products and commercial services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Goods and Services Provided by Nontraditional Defense Contractors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 3451(1) of this title</ref>, products and services provided by nontraditional defense contractors (as that term is defined in <ref>section 3014 of this title</ref>) may be treated by the head of an agency as commercial products and commercial services, respectively, for purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Services Provided by Certain Nontraditional Contractors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 3451(1) of this title</ref>, services provided by a business unit that is a nontraditional defense contractor (as that term is defined in <ref>section 3014 of this title</ref>) shall be treated as commercial services for purposes of this chapter, to the extent that such services use the same pool of employees as used for commercial customers and are priced using methodology similar to methodology used for commercial pricing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Commingled Items Purchased by Contractors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 3451(1) of this title</ref>, items valued at less than $10,000 that are purchased by a contractor for use in the performance of multiple contracts with the Department of Defense and other parties and are not identifiable to any particular contract shall be treated as a commercial product for purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VIII, § 857(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 921</ref>, § 2380A; renumbered § 2380a and amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 878(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2312</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(d)(6)</ref>, (8)(F), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1868</ref>, 1869; renumbered § 3457 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1821(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(6), (7)(A), (B), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4195</ref>, 4196.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3458.</num>
<heading> Authority to acquire innovative commercial products and commercial services using general solicitation competitive procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments may acquire innovative commercial products and commercial services through a competitive selection of proposals resulting from a general solicitation and the peer review of such proposals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment as Competitive Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Use of general solicitation competitive procedures under subsection (a) shall be considered to be use of competitive procedures for purposes of chapter 221 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not enter into a contract or agreement in excess of $100,000,000 using the authority under subsection (a) without a written determination from the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment or the relevant service acquisition executive of the efficacy of the effort to meet mission needs of the Department of Defense or the relevant military department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Contracts or agreements entered into using the authority under subsection (a) shall be fixed-price, including fixed-price incentive contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 3451(1) of this title</ref>, products and services acquired using the authority under subsection (a) shall be treated as commercial products and commercial services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification Required</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than 45 days after the award of a contract for an amount exceeding $100,000,000 using the authority in subsection (a), the Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees of such award.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Notice of an award under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Description of the innovative commercial product or commercial service acquired.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Description of the requirement, capability gap, or potential technological advancement with respect to which the innovative commercial product or commercial service acquired provides a solution or a potential new capability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Amount of the contract awarded.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Identification of the contractor awarded the contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Innovative Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “innovative” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any technology, process, or method, including research and development, that is new as of the date of submission of a proposal; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any application that is new as of the date of submission of a proposal of a technology, process, or method existing as of such date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added § 2380c, renumbered § 3458, and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 803(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), (3), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1814–1816</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 814(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2707</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>