<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 703—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF THE ARMY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7011.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of the Army is separately organized under the Secretary of the Army. It operates under the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 87–651, title II, § 210(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 524</ref>, § 3010; renumbered § 3011, <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 501(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1034</ref>; renumbered § 7011, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7012.</num>
<heading> Department of the Army: seal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army shall have a seal for the Department of the Army. The design of the seal must be approved by the President. Judicial notice shall be taken of the seal.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 157</ref>, § 3011; renumbered § 3012, <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 501(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1034</ref>; renumbered § 7012, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7013.</num>
<heading> Secretary of the Army</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is a Secretary of the Army, appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Secretary shall, to the greatest extent practicable, be appointed from among persons most highly qualified for the position by reason of background and experience, including persons with appropriate management or leadership experience. The Secretary is the head of the Department of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person may not be appointed as Secretary of the Army within seven years after relief from active duty as a commissioned officer of a regular component of an armed force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense and subject to the provisions of chapter 6 of this title, the Secretary of the Army is responsible for, and has the authority necessary to conduct, all affairs of the Department of the Army, including the following functions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Recruiting.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Organizing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Supplying.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Equipping (including research and development).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Servicing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Mobilizing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Demobilizing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Administering (including the morale and welfare of personnel).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Maintaining.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The construction, outfitting, and repair of military equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The construction, maintenance, and repair of buildings, structures, and utilities and the acquisition of real property and interests in real property necessary to carry out the responsibilities specified in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Army is also responsible to the Secretary of Defense for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the functioning and efficiency of the Department of the Army;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the formulation of policies and programs by the Department of the Army that are fully consistent with national security objectives and policies established by the President or the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the effective and timely implementation of policy, program, and budget decisions and instructions of the President or the Secretary of Defense relating to the functions of the Department of the Army;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> carrying out the functions of the Department of the Army so as to fulfill the current and future operational requirements of the unified and specified combatant commands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> effective cooperation and coordination between the Department of the Army and the other military departments and agencies of the Department of Defense to provide for more effective, efficient, and economical administration and to eliminate duplication;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the presentation and justification of the positions of the Department of the Army on the plans, programs, and policies of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the effective supervision and control of the intelligence activities of the Department of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army is also responsible for such other activities as may be prescribed by law or by the President or Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> After first informing the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Army may make such recommendations to Congress relating to the Department of Defense as he considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army may assign such of his functions, powers, and duties as he considers appropriate to the Under Secretary of the Army and to the Assistant Secretaries of the Army. Officers of the Army shall, as directed by the Secretary, report on any matter to the Secretary, the Under Secretary, or any Assistant Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Army may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assign, detail, and prescribe the duties of members of the Army and civilian personnel of the Department of the Army;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> change the title of any officer or activity of the Department of the Army not prescribed by law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> prescribe regulations to carry out his functions, powers, and duties under this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 501(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1035</ref>, § 3013; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V, § 534</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3873</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1558</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 931(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2362</ref>; renumbered § 7013, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title IX, § 901(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1868</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7014.</num>
<heading> Office of the Secretary of the Army</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is in the Department of the Army an Office of the Secretary of the Army. The function of the Office is to assist the Secretary of the Army in carrying out his responsibilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Office of the Secretary of the Army is composed of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretaries of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Administrative Assistant to the Secretary of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The General Counsel of the Department of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Inspector General of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Chief of Legislative Liaison.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Army Reserve Forces Policy Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Such other offices and officials as may be established by law or as the Secretary of the Army may establish or designate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Office of the Secretary of the Army shall have sole responsibility within the Office of the Secretary and the Army Staff for the following functions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Acquisition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Auditing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Comptroller (including financial management).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Information management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Inspector General.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Legislative affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Public affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army shall establish or designate a single office or other entity within the Office of the Secretary of the Army to conduct each function specified in paragraph (1). No office or other entity may be established or designated within the Army Staff to conduct any of the functions specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe the relationship of each office or other entity established or designated under paragraph (2) to the Chief of Staff and to the Army Staff and shall ensure that each such office or entity provides the Chief of Staff such staff support as the Chief of Staff considers necessary to perform his duties and responsibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The vesting in the Office of the Secretary of the Army of the responsibility for the conduct of a function specified in paragraph (1) does not preclude other elements of the executive part of the Department of the Army (including the Army Staff) from providing advice or assistance to the Chief of Staff or otherwise participating in that function within the executive part of the Department under the direction of the office assigned responsibility for that function in the Office of the Secretary of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The head of the office or other entity established or designated by the Secretary to conduct the auditing function shall have at least five years of professional experience in accounting or auditing. The position shall be considered to be a career reserved position as defined in <ref>section 3132(a)(8) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), the Office of the Secretary of the Army shall have sole responsibility within the Office of the Secretary and the Army Staff for the function of research and development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army may assign to the Army Staff responsibility for those aspects of the function of research and development that relate to military requirements and test and evaluation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish or designate a single office or other entity within the Office of the Secretary of the Army to conduct the function specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe the relationship of the office or other entity established or designated under paragraph (3) to the Chief of Staff of the Army and to the Army Staff and shall ensure that each such office or entity provides the Chief of Staff such staff support as the Chief of Staff considers necessary to perform his duties and responsibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army shall ensure that the Office of the Secretary of the Army and the Army Staff do not duplicate specific functions for which the Secretary has assigned responsibility to the other.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The total number of members of the armed forces and civilian employees of the Department of the Army assigned or detailed to permanent duty in the Office of the Secretary of the Army and on the Army Staff may not exceed 3,250.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not more than 1,900 officers of the Army on the active-duty list may be assigned or detailed to permanent duty in the Office of the Secretary of the Army and on the Army Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The total number of general officers assigned or detailed to permanent duty in the Office of the Secretary of the Army and on the Army Staff may not exceed 67.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The limitations in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) do not apply in time of war.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Each limitation in paragraphs (1) and (2) may be exceeded by a number equal to 15 percent of such limitation in time of national emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 501(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1036</ref>, § 3014; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XIII, § 1314(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title III, § 325(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1955</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VI, § 652(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1461</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(a)(27)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 504(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2532</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 903(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2344</ref>; renumbered § 7014, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 901(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1541</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7015.</num>
<heading> Under Secretary of the Army</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is an Under Secretary of the Army, appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary shall perform such duties and exercise such powers as the Secretary of the Army may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 501(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1037</ref>, § 3015; renumbered § 7015, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7016.</num>
<heading> Assistant Secretaries of the Army</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There are five Assistant Secretaries of the Army. They shall be appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretaries shall perform such duties and exercise such powers as the Secretary of the Army may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> One of the Assistant Secretaries shall be the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Manpower and Reserve Affairs. He shall have as his principal duty the overall supervision of manpower and reserve component affairs of the Department of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> One of the Assistant Secretaries shall be the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works. He shall have as his principal duty the overall supervision of the functions of the Department of the Army relating to programs for conservation and development of the national water resources, including flood control, navigation, shore protection, and related purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> One of the Assistant Secretaries shall be the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Financial Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary shall be appointed from among persons who have significant budget, financial management, or audit experience in complex organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The principal responsibility of the Assistant Secretary shall be the exercise of the comptroller functions of the Department of the Army, including financial management functions. The Assistant Secretary shall be responsible for all financial management activities and operations of the Department of the Army and shall advise the Secretary of the Army on financial management.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> One of the Assistant Secretaries shall be the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Acquisition, Logistics, and Technology. The principal duty of the Assistant Secretary shall be the overall supervision of acquisition, technology, and logistics matters of the Department of the Army.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary shall have a Principal Military Deputy, who shall be an officer of the Army on active duty. The Principal Military Deputy shall be appointed from among officers who have significant experience in the areas of acquisition and program management. The position of Principal Military Deputy shall be designated as a critical acquisition position under <ref>section 1731 of this title</ref>. In the event of a vacancy in the position of Assistant Secretary of the Army for Acquisition, Logistics, and Technology, the Principal Military Deputy may serve as Acting Assistant Secretary for a period of not more than one year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> One of the Assistant Secretaries shall be the Assistant Secretary for Energy, Installations, and Environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The principal duty of the Assistant Secretary for Energy, Installations, and Environment shall be the overall supervision of energy, installation, and environment matters for the Department of the Army.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 501(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1038</ref>, § 3016; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title VII, § 702(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1992</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IX, § 908(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 278</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 802(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2249</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 505</ref>, title IX, § 921(a), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1374</ref>, 1524; renumbered § 7016, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 861(j)(14)</ref>, title IX, § 911(a), title XVII, § 1731(a)(64), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1520</ref>, 1559, 1816.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7017.</num>
<heading> Secretary of the Army: successors to duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary of the Army dies, resigns, is removed from office, is absent, or is disabled, the person who is highest on the following list, and who is not absent or disabled, shall perform the duties of the Secretary until the President, under section 3347 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002156">1</ref> of title 5, directs another person to perform those duties or until the absence or disability ceases:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Under Secretary of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretaries of the Army, in the order prescribed by the Secretary of the Army and approved by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The General Counsel of the Department of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Chief of Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 159</ref>, § 3017; <ref>Pub. L. 89–718, § 23</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–235, § 4(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 759</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 501(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1038</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2823</ref>; renumbered § 7017, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7018.</num>
<heading> Administrative Assistant</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is an Administrative Assistant in the Department of the Army. The Administrative Assistant shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Army and shall perform duties that the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> During a vacancy in the office of Secretary, the Administrative Assistant has charge and custody of all records, books, and papers of the Department of the Army.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may authorize the Administrative Assistant to sign, during the temporary absence of the Secretary, any paper requiring his signature. In such a case, the Administrative Assistant’s signature has the same effect as the Secretary’s signature.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 159</ref>, § 3016; renumbered § 3018, <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 501(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1034</ref>; renumbered § 7018, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7019.</num>
<heading> General Counsel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is a General Counsel of the Department of the Army, appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The General Counsel shall perform such functions as the Secretary of the Army may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 501(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1038</ref>, § 3019; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title VII, § 703(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1996</ref>; renumbered § 7019, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7020.</num>
<heading> Inspector General</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is an Inspector General of the Army who shall be detailed to such position by the Secretary of the Army from the general officers of the Army. An officer may not be detailed to such position for a tour of duty of more than four years, except that the Secretary may extend such a tour of duty if he makes a special finding that the extension is necessary in the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> When directed by the Secretary or the Chief of Staff, the Inspector General shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> inquire into and report upon the discipline, efficiency, and economy of the Army; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> perform any other duties prescribed by the Secretary or the Chief of Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Inspector General shall periodically propose programs of inspections to the Secretary of the Army and shall recommend additional inspections and investigations as may appear appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Inspector General shall cooperate fully with the Inspector General of the Department of Defense in connection with the performance of any duty or function by the Inspector General of the Department of Defense under chapter 4 of title 5 regarding the Department of the Army.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Inspector General shall have such deputies and assistants as the Secretary of the Army may prescribe. Each such deputy and assistant shall be an officer detailed by the Secretary to that position from the officers of the Army for a tour of duty of not more than four years, under a procedure prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–433, title V, § 501(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1038</ref>, § 3020; renumbered § 7020, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(30)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4346</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7021.</num>
<heading> Army Reserve Forces Policy Committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is in the Office of the Secretary of the Army an Army Reserve Forces Policy Committee. The functions, membership, and organization of that committee are set forth in <ref>section 10302 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1661(b)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2982</ref>, § 3021; renumbered § 7021, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7022.</num>
<heading> Financial management</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Army shall provide that the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Financial Management shall direct and manage financial management activities and operations of the Department of the Army, including ensuring that financial management systems of the Department of the Army comply with subsection (b). The authority of the Assistant Secretary for such direction and management shall include the authority to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> supervise and direct the preparation of budget estimates of the Department of the Army and otherwise carry out, with respect to the Department of the Army, the functions specified for the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) in <ref>section 135(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> approve and supervise any project to design or enhance a financial management system for the Department of the Army; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> approve the establishment and supervise the operation of any asset management system of the Department of the Army, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> systems for cash management, credit management, and debt collection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> systems for the accounting for the quantity, location, and cost of property and inventory.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Financial management systems of the Department of the Army (including accounting systems, internal control systems, and financial reporting systems) shall be established and maintained in conformance with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the accounting and financial reporting principles, standards, and requirements established by the Comptroller General under <ref>section 3511 of title 31</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the internal control standards established by the Comptroller General under <ref>section 3512 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such systems shall provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> complete, reliable, consistent, and timely information which is prepared on a uniform basis and which is responsive to the financial information needs of department management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the development and reporting of cost information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the integration of accounting and budgeting information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the systematic measurement of performance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary shall maintain a five-year plan describing the activities the Department of the Army proposes to conduct over the next five fiscal years to improve financial management. Such plan shall be revised annually.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary of the Army for Financial Management shall transmit to the Secretary of the Army a report each year on the activities of the Assistant Secretary during the preceding year. Each such report shall include a description and analysis of the status of Department of the Army financial management.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title VII, § 702(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1993</ref>, § 3022; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1070(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2856</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1503(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 512</ref>; renumbered § 7022, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7023.</num>
<heading> Chief of Legislative Liaison</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is a Chief of Legislative Liaison in the Department of the Army.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Chief of Legislative Liaison shall perform legislative affairs functions as specified for the Office of the Secretary of the Army by <ref>section 7014(c)(1)(F) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 504(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2531</ref>, § 3023; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(j)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2103</ref>; renumbered § 7023 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 808(a), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>, 1840.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7024.</num>
<heading> Director of Small Business Programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a Director of Small Business Programs in the Department of the Army. The Director is appointed by the Secretary of the Army.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Office of Small Business Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Office of Small Business Programs of the Department of the Army is the office that is established within the Department of the Army under section 15(k) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 644(k)</ref>). The Director of Small Business Programs is the head of such office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties and Powers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director of Small Business Programs shall, subject to paragraph (2), perform such duties regarding small business programs of the Department of the Army, and shall exercise such powers regarding those programs, as the Secretary of the Army may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Section 15(k) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 644(k)</ref>), except for the designations of the Director and the Office, applies to the Director of Small Business Programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title IX, § 904(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3400</ref>, § 3024; renumbered § 7024, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>