<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 881—</num>
<heading>CLAIMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8821.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this chapter “vessel in the naval service” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any vessel of the Navy, manned by the Navy, or chartered on bareboat charter to the Navy; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when the Coast Guard is operating as a service in the Navy, any vessel of the Coast Guard, manned by the Coast Guard, or chartered on bareboat charter to the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In this chapter “settle” means consider, ascertain, adjust, determine, and dispose of a claim, whether by full or partial allowance or by disallowance.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 472</ref>, § 7621; renumbered § 8821, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8822.</num>
<heading> Admiralty claims against the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Navy may settle, or compromise, and pay in an amount not more than $15,000,000 an admiralty claim against the United States for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> damage caused by a vessel in the naval service or by other property under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Navy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> compensation for towage and salvage service, including contract salvage, rendered to a vessel in the naval service or to other property under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Navy; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> damage caused by a maritime tort committed by any agent or employee of the Department of the Navy or by property under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If a claim under this section is settled or compromised for more than $15,000,000, the Secretary shall certify it to Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In any case where the amount to be paid is not more than $1,000,000, the Secretary may delegate his authority under this section to any person designated by him.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Upon acceptance of payment by the claimant, the settlement or compromise of a claim under this section is final and conclusive notwithstanding any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 472</ref>, § 7622; <ref>Pub. L. 89–67</ref>, <date date="1965-07-07">July 7, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–417, § 1(5)</ref>, <date date="1972-08-29">Aug. 29, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 654</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1633</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1608</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1014(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1212</ref>; renumbered § 8822, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8823.</num>
<heading> Admiralty claims by the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of the Navy may settle, or compromise, and receive payment of a claim by the United States for damage to property under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Navy or property for which the Department has assumed an obligation to respond for damage, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the claim is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> of a kind that is within the admiralty jurisdiction of a district court of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for damage caused by a vessel or floating object; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the net amount to be received by the United States is not more than $15,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In exchange for payment of an amount found to be due the United States under this section, the Secretary may execute a release of the claim on behalf of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), amounts received under this section shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Amounts received under this section for damage or loss to property operated and maintained with funds from a Department of Defense working capital fund or account shall be credited to that fund or account.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In any case where the amount to be received by the United States is not more than $1,000,000, the Secretary may delegate his authority under this section to any person designated by him.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Upon acceptance of payment by the Secretary, the settlement or compromise of a claim under this section is final and conclusive notwithstanding any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to any claim while there is pending as to that claim a suit filed by or against the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 472</ref>, § 7623; <ref>Pub. L. 89–67</ref>, <date date="1965-07-07">July 7, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1633</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1608</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1014(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title X, § 1032, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4591</ref>; renumbered § 8823, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>