<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1209—</num>
<heading>ACTIVE DUTY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 12301.</num>
<heading> Reserve components generally</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In time of war or of national emergency declared by Congress, or when otherwise authorized by law, an authority designated by the Secretary concerned may, without the consent of the persons affected, order any unit, and any member not assigned to a unit organized to serve as a unit, of a reserve component under the jurisdiction of that Secretary to active duty for the duration of the war or emergency and for six months thereafter. However a member on an inactive status list or in a retired status may not be ordered to active duty under this subsection unless the Secretary concerned, with the approval of the Secretary of Defense in the case of the Secretary of a military department, determines that there are not enough qualified Reserves in an active status or in the inactive National Guard in the required category who are readily available.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> At any time, an authority designated by the Secretary concerned may, without the consent of the persons affected, order any unit, and any member not assigned to a unit organized to serve as a unit, in an active status in a reserve component under the jurisdiction of that Secretary to active duty for not more than 15 days a year. However, units and members of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States may not be ordered to active duty under this subsection without the consent of the governor of the State (or, in the case of the District of Columbia National Guard, the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> So far as practicable, during any expansion of the active armed forces that requires that units and members of the reserve components be ordered to active duty as provided in subsection (a), members of units organized and trained to serve as units who are ordered to that duty without their consent shall be so ordered with their units. However, members of those units may be reassigned after being so ordered to active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> At any time, an authority designated by the Secretary concerned may order a member of a reserve component under his jurisdiction to active duty, or retain him on active duty, with the consent of that member. However, a member of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States may not be ordered to active duty under this subsection without the consent of the governor or other appropriate authority of the State concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The period of time allowed between the date when a Reserve ordered to active duty as provided in subsection (a) is alerted for that duty and the date when the Reserve is required to enter upon that duty shall be determined by the Secretary concerned based upon military requirements at that time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The consent of a Governor described in subsections (b) and (d) may not be withheld (in whole or in part) with regard to active duty outside the United States, its territories, and its possessions, because of any objection to the location, purpose, type, or schedule of such active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A member of a reserve component may be ordered to active duty without his consent if the Secretary concerned determines that the member is in a captive status. A member ordered to active duty under this section may not be retained on active duty, without his consent, for more than 30 days after his captive status is terminated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Such regulations shall apply uniformly among the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary. A determination for the purposes of this subsection that a member is in a captive status shall be made pursuant to such regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “captive status” means the status of a member of the armed forces who is in a missing status (as defined in <ref>section 551(2) of title 37</ref>) which occurs as the result of a hostile action and is related to the member’s military status.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> When authorized by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of a military department may, with the consent of the member, order a member of a reserve component to active duty—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to receive authorized medical care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to be medically evaluated for disability or other purposes; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to complete a required Department of Defense health care study, which may include an associated medical evaluation of the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A member ordered to active duty under this subsection may, with the member’s consent, be retained on active duty, if the Secretary concerned considers it appropriate, for medical treatment for a condition associated with the study or evaluation, if that treatment of the member is otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A member of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States may be ordered to active duty under this subsection only with the consent of the Governor or other appropriate authority of the State concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 27</ref>, § 672; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861</ref>, §§ 1(13), 33(a)(5), <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1440</ref>, 1564; <ref>Pub. L. 96–357, § 6</ref>, <date date="1980-09-24">Sept. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–584, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-12-23">Dec. 23, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title IX, § 9122]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–82</ref>, 1783–127, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title IX, § 9122]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–82</ref>, 3341–127; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 522, 524(a), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3871</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1234(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2059</ref>; renumbered § 12301 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(e)(2), 1675(c)(1), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>, 3017; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 514(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1882</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12302.</num>
<heading> Ready Reserve</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In time of national emergency declared by the President after <date date="1953-01-01">January 1, 1953</date>, or when otherwise authorized by law, an authority designated by the Secretary concerned may, without the consent of the persons concerned, order any unit, and any member not assigned to a unit organized to serve as a unit, in the Ready Reserve under the jurisdiction of that Secretary to active duty for not more than 24 consecutive months.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> To achieve fair treatment as between members in the Ready Reserve who are being considered for recall to duty without their consent, consideration shall be given to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the length and nature of previous service, to assure such sharing of exposure to hazards as the national security and military requirements will reasonably allow;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> family responsibilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> employment necessary to maintain the national health, safety, or interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe such policies and procedures as he considers necessary to carry out this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Not more than 1,000,000 members of the Ready Reserve may be on active duty, without their consent, under this section at any one time.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 28</ref>, § 673; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861</ref>, §§ 1(14), 33(a)(5), <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1441</ref>, 1564; <ref>Pub. L. 93–155, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 607</ref>; renumbered § 12302, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(61)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1603</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 514(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1883</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1061(28)</ref>, (30), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12303.</num>
<heading> Ready Reserve: members not assigned to, or participating satisfactorily in, units</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may order to active duty any member of the Ready Reserve of an armed force who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is not assigned to, or participating satisfactorily in, a unit of the Ready Reserve;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has not fulfilled his statutory reserve obligation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has not served on active duty for a total of 24 months.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A member who is ordered to active duty under this section may be required to serve on active duty until his total service on active duty equals 24 months. If his enlistment or other period of military service would expire before he has served the required period under this section, it may be extended until he has served the required period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> To achieve fair treatment among members of the Ready Reserve who are being considered for active duty under this section, appropriate consideration shall be given to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> family responsibilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> employment necessary to maintain the national health, safety, or interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–40, § 6(1)</ref>, <date date="1967-06-30">June 30, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 105</ref>, § 673a; renumbered § 12303, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12304.</num>
<heading> Selected Reserve and certain Individual Ready Reserve members; order to active duty other than during war or national emergency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the provisions of section 12302(a) or any other provision of law, when the President determines that it is necessary to augment the active forces or that it is necessary to provide assistance referred to in subsection (b), he may authorize the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, without the consent of the members concerned, to order any unit, and any member not assigned to a unit organized to serve as a unit of the Selected Reserve (as defined in <ref>section 10143(a) of this title</ref>), or any member in the Individual Ready Reserve mobilization category and designated as essential under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, under their respective jurisdictions, to active duty for not more than 365 consecutive days.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support for Responses to Certain Emergencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The authority under subsection (a) includes authority to order a unit or member to active duty to provide assistance in responding to an emergency involving—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a use or threatened use of a weapon of mass destruction; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a terrorist attack or threatened terrorist attack in the United States that results, or could result, in significant loss of life or property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority Relating to Significant Cyber Incidents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating determines that it is necessary to augment the active armed forces for the response of the Department of Defense or other department under which the Coast Guard is operating, respectively, to a covered incident, such Secretary may, without the consent of the member affected, order any unit, and any member not assigned to a unit organized to serve as a unit of the Selected Reserve (as defined in <ref>section 10143(a) of this title</ref>), under the respective jurisdiction of such Secretary, to active duty for not more than 365 consecutive days.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No unit or member of a reserve component may be ordered to active duty under this section to perform any of the functions authorized by chapter 13 or <ref>section 12406 of this title</ref> or, except as provided in subsection (b) or subsection (c), to provide assistance to either the Federal Government or a State in time of a serious natural or manmade disaster, accident, or catastrophe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not more than 200,000 members of the Selected Reserve and the Individual Ready Reserve may be on active duty under this section at any one time, of whom not more than 30,000 may be members of the Individual Ready Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No unit or member of a reserve component may be ordered to active duty under this section to provide assistance referred to in subsection (b) unless the President determines that the requirements for responding to an emergency referred to in that subsection have exceeded, or will exceed, the response capabilities of local, State, and Federal civilian agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion From Strength Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members ordered to active duty under this section shall not be counted in computing authorized strength in members on active duty or members in grade under this title or any other law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policies and Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall prescribe such policies and procedures for the armed forces under their respective jurisdictions as they consider necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the President authorizes the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security to order any unit or member of the Selected Reserve or Individual Ready Reserve to active duty, under the authority of subsection (a) or subsection (c), he shall, within 24 hours after exercising such authority, submit to Congress a report, in writing, setting forth the circumstances necessitating the action taken under this section and describing the anticipated use of these units or members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever any unit of the Selected Reserve or any member of the Selected Reserve not assigned to a unit organized to serve as a unit, or any member of the Individual Ready Reserve, is ordered to active duty under authority of subsection (a), the service of all units or members so ordered to active duty may be terminated by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> order of the President; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever any unit of the Selected Reserve or any member of the Selected Reserve not assigned to a unit organized to serve as a unit is ordered to active duty under authority of subsection (c), the service of all units or members so ordered to active duty may be terminated by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> order of the Secretary of Defense or, with respect to the Coast Guard, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to War Powers Resolution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as amending or limiting the application of the provisions of the War Powers Resolution (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1541</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations for Involuntary Order to Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In determining which members of the Selected Reserve and Individual Ready Reserve will be ordered to duty without their consent under this section, appropriate consideration shall be given to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the length and nature of previous service, to assure such sharing of exposure to hazards as the national security and military requirements will reasonably allow;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the frequency of assignments during service career;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> family responsibilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> employment necessary to maintain the national health, safety, or interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe such policies and procedures as the Secretary considers necessary to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “covered incident” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a cyber incident involving a Department of Defense information system, or a breach of a Department of Defense system that involves personally identifiable information, that the Secretary of Defense determines is likely to result in demonstrable harm to the national security interests, foreign relations, or the economy of the United States, or to the public confidence, civil liberties, or public health and safety of the people of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a cyber incident involving a Department of Homeland Security information system, or a breach of a Department of Homeland Security system that involves personally identifiable information, that the Secretary of Homeland Security determines is likely to result in demonstrable harm to the national security interests, foreign relations, or the economy of the United States or to the public confidence, civil liberties, or public health and safety of the people of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a cyber incident, or collection of related cyber incidents, that the President determines is likely to result in demonstrable harm to the national security interests, foreign relations, or economy of the United States or to the public confidence, civil liberties, or public health and safety of the people of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a significant incident declared pursuant to section 2233 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref>6 U.S.C. 677b</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Individual Ready Reserve mobilization category” means, in the case of any reserve component, the category of the Individual Ready Reserve described in <ref>section 10144(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “weapon of mass destruction” has the meaning given that term in section 1403 of the Defense Against Weapons of Mass Destruction Act of 1996 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 2302(1)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–286, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-05-14">May 14, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 517</ref>, § 673b; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–584, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-12-23">Dec. 23, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(9)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title V, § 521</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3870</ref>; renumbered § 12304 and amended, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, title XVI, §§ 1662(e)(2), 1675(c)(2), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2752</ref>, 2992, 3017; <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 511(b)</ref>–(e)(1), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1728</ref>, 1729; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2005</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 514(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2539</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 515</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1460</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 514(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1883</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 522</ref>, title X, § 1076(c), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2192</ref>, 2406; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X</ref>, §§ 1063(a)(15), 1068(c), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 322</ref>, 326; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 516(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1204(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2017</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XV, § 1532</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 563</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12304a.</num>
<heading> Army Reserve, Navy Reserve, Marine Corps Reserve, and Air Force Reserve: order to active duty to provide assistance in response to a major disaster or emergency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When a Governor requests Federal assistance in responding to a major disaster or emergency (as those terms are defined in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5122</ref>)), the Secretary of Defense may, without the consent of the member affected, order any unit, and any member not assigned to a unit organized to serve as a unit, of the Army Reserve, Navy Reserve, Marine Corps Reserve, and Air Force Reserve to active duty for a continuous period of not more than 120 days to respond to the Governor’s request.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion From Strength Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members ordered to active duty under this section shall not be counted in computing authorized strength of members on active duty or members in grade under this title or any other law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever any unit or member of the reserve components is ordered to active duty under this section, the service of all units or members so ordered to active duty may be terminated by order of the Secretary of Defense or law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 515(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12304b.</num>
<heading> Selected Reserve: order to active duty for preplanned missions in support of the combatant commands</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>When the Secretary of a military department determines that it is necessary to augment the active forces for a preplanned mission in support of a combatant command, the Secretary may, subject to subsection (b), order any unit of the Selected Reserve (as defined in <ref>section 10143(a) of this title</ref>), without the consent of the members, to active duty for not more than 365 consecutive days.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided under subparagraph (B), units may be ordered to active duty under this section only if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the manpower and associated costs of such active duty are specifically included and identified in the defense budget materials for the fiscal year or years in which such units are anticipated to be ordered to active duty; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the budget information on such costs includes a description of the mission for which such units are anticipated to be ordered to active duty and the anticipated length of time of the order of such units to active duty on an involuntary basis.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the event the President’s budget is delivered later than April 1st in the year prior to the year of the mobilization of one or more units under this section, the Secretary concerned may submit to Congress the information required under subparagraph (A) in a separate notice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not more than 60,000 members of the reserve components of the armed forces may be on active duty under this section at any one time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion From Strength Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members ordered to active duty under this section shall not be counted in computing authorized strength in members on active duty or total number of members in grade under this title or any other law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the Secretary of a military department orders any unit of the Selected Reserve to active duty under subsection (a), such Secretary shall submit to Congress a report, in writing, setting forth the circumstances necessitating the action taken under this section and describing the anticipated use of such unit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination of Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Whenever any unit of the Selected Reserve is ordered to active duty under subsection (a), the service of all units so ordered to active duty may be terminated—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by order of the Secretary of the military department concerned; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to War Powers Resolution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as amending or limiting the application of the provisions of the War Powers Resolution (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1541</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations for Involuntary Order to Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In determining which units of the Selected Reserve will be ordered to duty without their consent under this section, appropriate consideration shall be given to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the length and nature of previous service, to assure such sharing of exposure to hazards as national security and military requirements will reasonably allow;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the frequency of assignments during service career;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> family responsibilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> employment necessary to maintain the national health, safety, or interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policies and Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretaries of the military departments shall prescribe policies and procedures to carry out this section, including on determinations with respect to orders to active duty under subsection (g). Such policies and procedures shall not go into effect until approved by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Defense Budget Materials Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “defense budget materials” has the meaning given that term in section 231(f)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002187">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 516(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1395</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1014(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 513</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12305.</num>
<heading> Authority of President to suspend certain laws relating to promotion, retirement, and separation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during any period members of a reserve component are serving on active duty pursuant to an order to active duty under authority of section 12301, 12302, or 12304 of this title, the President may suspend any provision of law relating to promotion, retirement, or separation applicable to any member of the armed forces who the President determines is essential to the national security of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A suspension made under the authority of subsection (a) shall terminate (1) upon release from active duty of members of the reserve component ordered to active duty under the authority of section 12301, 12302, or 12304 of this title, as the case may be, or (2) at such time as the President determines the circumstances which required the action of ordering members of the reserve component to active duty no longer exist, which­ever is earlier.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Upon the termination of a suspension made under the authority of subsection (a) of a provision of law otherwise requiring the separation or retirement of officers on active duty because of age, length of service or length of service in grade, or failure of selection for promotion, the Secretary concerned shall extend by up to 90 days the otherwise required separation or retirement date of any officer covered by the suspended provision whose separation or retirement date, but for the suspension, would have been before the date of the termination of the suspension or within 90 days after the date of such termination.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title X, § 1021(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 670</ref>, § 673c; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(16)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2622</ref>; renumbered § 12305 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(e)(2), 1675(c)(3), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>, 3017; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 508(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12306.</num>
<heading> Standby Reserve</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Units and members in the Standby Reserve may be ordered to active duty only as provided in <ref>section 12301 of this title</ref>, but subject to the limitations in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In time of emergency—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> no unit in the Standby Reserve organized to serve as a unit or any member thereof may be ordered to active duty under <ref>section 12301(a) of this title</ref>, unless the Secretary concerned, with the approval of the Secretary of Defense in the case of a Secretary of a military department, determines that there are not enough of the required kinds of units in the Ready Reserve that are readily available; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> notwithstanding <ref>section 12301(a) of this title</ref>, no other member in the Standby Reserve may be ordered to active duty as an individual under such section without his consent, unless the Secretary concerned, with the approval of the Secretary of Defense in the case of a Secretary of a military department, determines that there are not enough qualified members in the Ready Reserve in the required category who are readily available.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 29</ref>, § 674; <ref>Pub. L. 87–651, title I, § 130</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 514</ref>; renumbered § 12306 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(e)(2), 1675(c)(4), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>, 3017; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 514(d)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1883</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12307.</num>
<heading> Retired Reserve</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A member in the Retired Reserve may, if qualified, be ordered to active duty without his consent, but only as provided in section 688 or 12301(a) of this title. A member of the Retired Reserve (other than a member transferred to the Retired Reserve under <ref>section 12641(b) of this title</ref>) who is ordered to active duty or other appropriate duty in a retired status may be credited under chapter 1223 of this title with service performed pursuant to such order. A member in a retired status is not eligible for promotion (or for consideration for promotion) as a Reserve.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 29</ref>, § 675; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title X, § 1017(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 669</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VI, § 651(d)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1461</ref>; renumbered § 12307 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(e)(2), 1675(c)(5), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>, 3017; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(17)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12308.</num>
<heading> Retention after becoming qualified for retired pay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who has qualified for retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title may, with his consent and by order of the Secretary concerned, be retained on active duty, or in service in a reserve component other than that listed in <ref>section 12732(b) of this title</ref>. A member so retained shall be credited with that service for all purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 29</ref>, § 676; renumbered § 12308 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(e)(2), 1675(c)(6), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>, 3017.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12309.</num>
<heading> Reserve officers: use of in expansion of armed forces</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When an expansion of the active armed forces requires that officers of the reserve components who are not members of units organized to serve as such be ordered as individuals to active duty (other than for training) without their consent, the services of qualified and available reserve officers in all grades shall be used, so far as practicable, according to the needs of the branches, grades, or specialties concerned.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 29</ref>, § 677; renumbered § 12309, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12310.</num>
<heading> Reserves: for organizing, administering, etc., reserve components</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary concerned may order a member of a reserve component under the Secretary’s jurisdiction to active duty pursuant to <ref>section 12301(d) of this title</ref> to perform Active Guard and Reserve duty organizing, administering, recruiting, instructing, or training the reserve components.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A Reserve ordered to active duty under paragraph (1) shall be ordered in the Reserve’s reserve grade. While so serving, the Reserve continues to be eligible for promotion as a Reserve, if otherwise qualified.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A Reserve on active duty under subsection (a) may perform the following additional duties to the extent that the performance of those duties does not interfere with the performance of the Reserve’s primary Active Guard and Reserve duties described in subsection (a)(1):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Supporting operations or missions assigned in whole or in part to the reserve components.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Supporting operations or missions performed or to be performed by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a unit composed of elements from more than one component of the same armed force; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a joint forces unit that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> one or more reserve component units; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a member of a reserve component whose reserve component assignment is in a position in an element of the joint forces unit.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Advising the Secretary of Defense, the Secretaries of the military departments, the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and the commanders of the combatant commands regarding reserve component matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Instructing or training in the United States or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico or possessions of the United States of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> active-duty members of the armed forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> members of foreign military forces (under the same authorities and restrictions applicable to active-duty members providing such instruction or training);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Department of Defense contractor personnel; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Department of Defense civilian employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operations Relating to Defense Against Weapons of Mass Destruction and Terrorist Attacks</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding subsection (b), a Reserve on active duty as described in subsection (a), or a Reserve who is a member of the National Guard serving on full-time National Guard duty under <ref>section 502(f) of title 32</ref> in connection with functions referred to in subsection (a), may, subject to paragraph (3), perform duties in support of emergency preparedness programs to prepare for or to respond to any emergency involving any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The use or threatened use of a weapon of mass destruction (as defined in section 1403 of the Defense Against Weapons of Mass Destruction Act of 1996 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 2302(1)</ref>)) in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A terrorist attack or threatened terrorist attack in the United States that results, or could result, in catastrophic loss of life or property.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The intentional or unintentional release of nuclear, biological, radiological, or toxic or poisonous chemical materials in the United States that results, or could result, in catastrophic loss of life or property.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A natural or manmade disaster in the United States that results in, or could result in, catastrophic loss of life or property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The costs of the pay, allowances, clothing, subsistence, gratuities, travel, and related expenses for a Reserve performing duties under the authority of paragraph (1) shall be paid from the appropriation that is available to pay such costs for other members of the reserve component of that Reserve who are performing duties as described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A Reserve may perform duty described in paragraph (1) only while assigned to a reserve component weapons of mass destruction civil support team.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Reserves on active duty who are performing duties described in paragraph (1) shall be counted against the annual end strength authorizations required by section 115(a)(1)(B) and 115(a)(2) of this title. The justification material for the defense budget request for a fiscal year shall identify the number and component of the Reserves programmed to be performing duties described in paragraph (1) during that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A reserve component weapons of mass destruction civil support team, and any Reserve assigned to such a team, may not be used to respond to an emergency described in paragraph (1) unless the Secretary of Defense has certified to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives that that team, or that Reserve, possesses the requisite skills, training, and equipment to be proficient in all mission requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> If the Secretary of Defense submits to Congress any request for the enactment of legislation to modify the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (3), the Secretary shall provide with the request—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> justification for each such requested modification; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary’s plan for sustaining the qualifications of the personnel and teams described in paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> In this subsection, the term “United States” includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Reserve on active duty as described in subsection (a) may be provided training consistent with training provided to other members on active duty, as the Secretary concerned sees fit.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 30</ref>, § 678; renumbered § 12310 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(e)(2), 1675(c)(7), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>, 3017; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 541</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 511(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2006</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 555(a), (b), 556, title X, § 1067(1), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 617–619</ref>, 774; <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 514(b)</ref>, title IX, § 933, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2539</ref>, 2626; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 525(a), 527, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2193</ref>, 2196; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(34)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2474</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12311.</num>
<heading> Active duty agreements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> To provide definite terms of active duty (other than for training) for Reserves with their consent, the Secretary concerned may make a standard written agreement with any member of a reserve component under his jurisdiction requiring the member to serve for a period of active duty (other than for training) of not more than five years. When such an agreement expires, a new one may be made. This subsection does not apply in time of war declared by Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An agreement may not be made under subsection (a) unless the specified period of duty is at least 12 months longer than any period of active duty that the member is otherwise required to perform.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Agreements made under subsection (a) shall be uniform so far as practicable, and are subject to such standards and policies as may be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for the armed forces under his jurisdiction or by the Secretary of Homeland Security for the Coast Guard when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If an agreement made under subsection (a) expires during a war or during a national emergency declared by Congress or the President after <date date="1953-01-01">January 1, 1953</date>, the Reserve concerned may be kept on active duty, without his consent, as otherwise prescribed by law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 30</ref>, § 679; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(19)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2921</ref>; renumbered § 12311, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12312.</num>
<heading> Active duty agreements: release from duty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Each agreement made under <ref>section 12311(a) of this title</ref> shall provide that the member may not be released from active duty without his consent during the period of the agreement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> because of a reduction in the actual personnel strength of the armed force concerned, unless the release is in accordance with the recommendation of a board of officers appointed by an authority designated by the Secretary concerned to determine the members to be released from active duty under regulations prescribed by the Secretary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for any other reason, without an opportunity to be heard by a board of officers before the release, unless he is (A) dismissed or discharged under the sentence of a court-martial, (B) released because of an unexplained absence without leave for at least three months, (C) released because he is convicted and sentenced to confinement in a Federal or State penitentiary or correctional institution and the sentence has become final, or (D) released because he has been considered at least twice and has not been recommended for promotion to the next higher grade or because he is considered as having failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade and has not been recommended for promotion to that grade, under conditions that would require the release or separation of a reserve officer who is not serving under such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A member who is released from active duty without his consent before the end of his agreement made under <ref>section 12311(a) of this title</ref> is entitled to an amount computed by multiplying the number of years and fractions of a year of his unexpired period of service under the agreement by the sum of one month’s basic pay, special pay, and allowances to which he is entitled on the day of his release. The amount to which a member is entitled under this subsection is in addition to any pay and allowances to which he is otherwise entitled. For the purposes of this subsection, a fraction of a month of 15 days or more is counted as a whole month, and a fraction of a month of less than 15 days is disregarded. This subsection does not apply to a member if he is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> released for a reason described in subsection (a)(2)(A)–(C);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> released because of a physical disability resulting from his intentional misconduct or wilful neglect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> eligible for retired pay, separation pay, or severance pay under another provision of law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> placed on a temporary disability retired list; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> released to accept an appointment, or to be enlisted, in a regular component of an armed force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 30</ref>, § 680; <ref>Pub. L. 87–509, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 533(b)</ref>, title XIV, § 1405(17), <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2528</ref>, 2622; renumbered § 12312 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(e)(2), 1675(c)(8), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>, 3017.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12313.</num>
<heading> Reserves: release from active duty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this title, the Secretary concerned may at any time release a Reserve under his jurisdiction from active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In time of war or of national emergency declared by Congress or the President after <date date="1953-01-01">January 1, 1953</date>, a member of a reserve component may be released from active duty (other than for training) only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a board of officers convened at his request by an authority designated by the Secretary concerned recommends the release and the recommendation is approved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the member does not request that a board be convened; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> his release is otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">This subsection does not apply to an armed force during a period of demobilization or reduction in strength of that armed force.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 31</ref>, § 681; renumbered § 12313, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12314.</num>
<heading> Reserves: kinds of duty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a member of a reserve component who is on active duty other than for training may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, be detailed or assigned to any duty authorized by law for members of the regular component of the armed force concerned.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 31</ref>, § 682; renumbered § 12314, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12315.</num>
<heading> Reserves: duty with or without pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to other provisions of this title, any Reserve may be ordered to active duty or other duty—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> with the pay and allowances provided by law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with his consent, without pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Duty without pay shall be considered for all purposes as if it were duty with pay.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A Reserve who is kept on active duty after his term of service expires is entitled to pay and allowances while on that duty, except as they may be forfeited under the approved sentence of a court-martial or by non-judicial punishment by a commanding officer or when he is otherwise in a non-pay status.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 31</ref>, § 683; renumbered § 12315, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12316.</num>
<heading> Payment of certain Reserves while on duty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided by subsection (c), a Reserve of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard who because of the Reserve’s earlier military service is entitled to retired or retainer pay, and who performs duty for which the Reserve is entitled to compensation, may elect to receive for that duty either—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the pay and allowances authorized by law for the duty that the Reserve is performing; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the Reserve specifically waives those payments, the retired or retainer pay to which the Reserve is entitled because of the Reserve’s earlier military service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided by subsection (c), a Reserve of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard who because of the Reserve’s earlier military service is entitled to a pension or disability compensation, and who performs duty for which the Reserve is entitled to compensation, may elect to receive for that duty either—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the pension or disability compensation to which the Reserve is entitled because of the Reserve’s earlier military service; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the Reserve specifically waives those payments, the pay and allowances authorized by law for the duty that the Reserve is performing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Unless the payments because of a Reserve’s earlier military service are greater than the compensation prescribed by subsection (a)(1) or (b)(2), as applicable,, a Reserve of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard who because of the Reserve’s earlier military service is entitled to a pension, retired or retainer pay, or disability compensation, and who upon being ordered to active duty for a period of more than 30 days in time of war or national emergency is found physically qualified to perform that duty, ceases to be entitled to the payments because of the Reserve’s earlier military service until the period of active duty ends. While on that active duty, the Reserve is entitled to the compensation prescribed by subsection (a)(1) or (b)(2), as applicable,. Other rights and benefits of the Reserve or the Reserve’s dependents are unaffected by this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations under which a Reserve of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard may waive the pay and allowances authorized by law for the duty the Reserve is performing under subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(15)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1441</ref>, § 684; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–586, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1920</ref>; renumbered § 12316, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VI, § 621(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3675</ref>, 3676.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12317.</num>
<heading> Reserves: theological students; limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Reserve may not be required to serve on active duty, or to participate in inactive duty training, while preparing for the ministry in a recognized theological or divinity school.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(15)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1441</ref>, § 685; renumbered § 12317, <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12318.</num>
<heading> Reserves on active duty: duties; funding</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> During a period that members of a reserve component are serving on active duty pursuant to an order under section 12302 or 12304 of this title, members of reserve components serving on active duty may perform duties in connection with either such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Funds available for the pay and allowances of Reserves referred to <ref>section 12310 of this title</ref> shall be available for the pay and allowances of such Reserves who perform duties in connection with section 12302 or 12304 of this title under the authority of subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IV, § 412(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3861</ref>, § 686; renumbered § 12318 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(e)(2), 1675(c)(9), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>, 3017.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12319.</num>
<heading> Ready Reserve: muster duty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, a member of the Ready Reserve may be ordered without his consent to muster duty one time each year. A member ordered to muster duty under this section shall be required to perform a minimum of two hours of muster duty on the day of muster.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The period which a member may be required to devote to muster duty under this section, including round-trip travel to and from the location of that duty, may not total more than one day each calendar year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Except as specified in subsection (d), muster duty (and travel directly to and from that duty) under this section shall be treated as the equivalent of inactive-duty training (and travel directly to and from that training) for the purposes of this title and the provisions of title 37 (other than section 206(a)) and title 38, including provisions relating to the determination of eligibility for and the receipt of benefits and entitlements provided under those titles for Reserves performing inactive-duty training and for their dependents and survivors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Muster duty under this section shall not be credited in determining entitlement to, or in computing, retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1436</ref>, § 687; renumbered § 12319 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1662(e)(2), 1675(c)(10), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>, 3018.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12320.</num>
<heading> Reserve officers: grade in which ordered to active duty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A reserve officer who is ordered to active duty or full-time National Guard duty shall be ordered to active duty or full-time National Guard duty in his reserve grade, except that a reserve officer who is credited with service under <ref>section 12207 of this title</ref> and is ordered to active duty and placed on the active-duty list may be ordered to active duty in a reserve grade and with a date of rank and position on the active-duty list determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense based upon the amount of service credited.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2868</ref>, § 689; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(g)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 127</ref>; renumbered § 12320 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1625, 1662(e)(2), 1675(c)(11), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2962</ref>, 2992, 3018; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 495</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12321.</num>
<heading> Reserve Officer Training Corps units: limitation on number of Reserves assigned</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The number of members of the reserve components serving on active duty or full-time National Guard duty for the purpose of organizing, administering, recruiting, instructing, or training the reserve components who are assigned to duty with a unit of the Reserve Officer Training Corps program may not exceed 275.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 559(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1571</ref>, § 687; renumbered § 690 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 704(a)(3)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1649</ref>; renumbered § 12321 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12322.</num>
<heading> Active duty for health care</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A member of a uniformed service described in paragraph (1)(B) or (2)(B) of <ref>section 1074a(a) of this title</ref> may be ordered to active duty, and a member of a uniformed service described in paragraph (1)(A) or (2)(A) of such section may be continued on active duty, for a period of more than 30 days while the member is being treated for (or recovering from) an injury, illness, or disease incurred or aggravated in the line of duty as described in any of such paragraphs.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title VII, § 705(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 683</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12323.</num>
<heading> Active duty pending line of duty determination required for response to sexual assault</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuation on Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a member of a reserve component who is the alleged victim of sexual assault committed while on active duty and who is expected to be released from active duty before the determination is made regarding whether the member was assaulted while in the line of duty (in this section referred to as a “line of duty determination”), the Secretary concerned, upon the request of the member, may order the member to be retained on active duty until completion of the line of duty determination. A member eligible for continuation on active duty under this subsection shall be informed as soon as practicable after the alleged assault of the option to request continuation on active duty under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Return to Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a member of a reserve component not on active duty who is the alleged victim of a sexual assault that occurred while the member was on active duty and when the line of duty determination is not completed, the Secretary concerned, upon the request of the member, may order the member to active duty for such time as necessary for completion of the line of duty determination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretaries of the military departments shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section, subject to guidelines prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. The guidelines of the Secretary of Defense shall provide that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a request submitted by a member described in subsection (a) or (b) to continue on active duty, or to be ordered to active duty, respectively, must be decided within 30 days from the date of the request; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the request is denied, the member may appeal to the first general officer or flag officer in the chain of command of the member, and in the case of such an appeal a decision on the appeal must be made within 15 days from the date of the appeal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 571(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1753</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>