<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1608—</num>
<heading>HEALTH PROFESSIONS STIPEND PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 16201.</num>
<heading> Financial assistance: health-care professionals in reserve components</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purpose of obtaining adequate numbers of commissioned officers in the reserve components who are qualified in health professions, the Secretary of each military department may establish and maintain a program to provide financial assistance under this chapter to persons engaged in training that leads to a degree in medicine or dentistry or training in a health professions specialty that is critically needed in wartime. Under such a program, the Secretary concerned may agree to pay a financial stipend to persons engaged in health care education and training in return for a commitment to subsequent service in the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Medical and Dental School Students</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under the stipend program under this chapter, the Secretary of the military department concerned may enter into an agreement with a person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is eligible to be appointed as an officer in a reserve component;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is enrolled or has been accepted for enrollment in an institution in a course of study that results in a degree in medicine or dentistry;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> signs an agreement that, unless sooner separated, the person will—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> complete the educational phase of the program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> accept a reappointment or redesignation within the person’s reserve component, if tendered, based upon the person’s health profession, following satisfactory completion of the educational and intern programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> participate in a residency program; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> if required by regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, agrees to apply for, if eligible, and accept, if offered, residency training in a health profession skill which has been designated by the Secretary of Defense as a critically needed wartime skill.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Under the agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the military department concerned shall agree to pay the participant a stipend, in the amount determined under subsection (g), for the period or the remainder of the period that the student is satisfactorily progressing toward a degree in medicine or dentistry while enrolled in an accredited medical or dental school;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the participant shall not be eligible to receive such stipend before appointment, designation, or assignment as an officer for service in the Ready Reserve;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the participant shall be subject to such active duty requirements as may be specified in the agreement and to active duty in time of war or national emergency as provided by law for members of the Ready Reserve; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the participant shall agree to serve in the Selected Reserve, upon successful completion of the program, for the period of service applicable under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), the period for which a participant is required to serve in the Selected Reserve under the agreement pursuant to paragraph (2)(D) shall be one year for each period of six months, or part thereof, for which the participant is provided a stipend pursuant to the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of a participant who enters into a subsequent agreement under subsection (c) and successfully completes residency training in a specialty designated by the Secretary of Defense as a specialty critically needed by the military department in wartime, the requirement to serve in the Selected Reserve may be reduced to one year for each year, or part thereof, for which the stipend was provided while enrolled in medical or dental school.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Physicians and Dentists in Critical Wartime Specialties</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under the stipend program under this chapter, the Secretary of the military department concerned may enter into an agreement with a person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a graduate of a medical school or dental school;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is eligible for appointment, designation, or assignment as a medical officer or dental officer in the Reserve of the armed force concerned or has been appointed as a medical or dental officer in the Reserve of the armed force concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is enrolled or has been accepted for enrollment in a residency program for physicians or dentists in a medical or dental specialty designated by the Secretary concerned as a specialty critically needed by that military department in wartime.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Under the agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary shall agree to pay the participant a stipend, in an amount determined under subsection (g), for the period or the remainder of the period of the residency program in which the participant enrolls or is enrolled;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the participant shall not be eligible to receive such stipend before appointment, designation, or assignment as a medical officer or dental officer for service in the Ready Reserve;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the participant shall be subject to such active duty requirements as may be specified in the agreement and to active duty in time of war or national emergency as provided by law for members of the Ready Reserve; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the participant shall agree to serve, upon successful completion of the program, one year in the Selected Reserve for each six months, or part thereof, for which the stipend is provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Registered Nurses in Critical Specialties</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under the stipend program under this chapter, the Secretary of the military department concerned may enter into an agreement with a person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a registered nurse;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is eligible for appointment as a Reserve officer for service in a reserve component in a Nurse Corps or as a nurse; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is enrolled or has been accepted for enrollment in an accredited program in nursing in a specialty designated by the Secretary concerned as a specialty critically needed by that military department in wartime.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Under the agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary shall agree to pay the participant a stipend, in an amount determined under subsection (g), for the period or the remainder of the period of the nursing program in which the participant enrolls or is enrolled;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the participant shall not be eligible to receive such stipend before being appointed as a Reserve officer for service in the Ready Reserve in a Nurse Corps or as a nurse;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the participant shall be subject to such active duty requirements as may be specified in the agreement and to active duty in time of war or national emergency as provided by law for members of the Ready Reserve; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the participant shall agree to serve, upon successful completion of the program, one year in the Selected Reserve for each six months, or part thereof, for which the stipend is provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Baccalaureate Students in Nursing or Other Health Professions</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under the stipend program under this chapter, the Secretary of the military department concerned may enter into an agreement with a person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> will, upon completion of the program, be eligible to be appointed, designated, or assigned as a Reserve officer for duty as a nurse or other health professional; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is enrolled, or has been accepted for enrollment in the third or fourth year of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an accredited baccalaureate nursing program; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any other accredited baccalaureate program leading to a degree in a health-care profession designated by the Secretary concerned as a profession critically needed by that military department in wartime.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Under the agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary shall agree to pay the participant a monthly stipend in an amount not to exceed the stipend rate in effect under <ref>section 2121(d) of this title</ref> for the period or the remainder of the period of the baccalaureate program in which the participant enrolls or is enrolled;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the participant shall not be eligible to receive such stipend before enlistment in the Ready Reserve;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the participant shall be subject to such active duty requirements as may be specified in the agreement and to active duty in time of war or national emergency as provided by law for members of the Ready Reserve; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the participant shall agree to serve, upon graduation from the baccalaureate program, one year in the Selected Reserve for each year, or part thereof, for which the stipend is paid.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mental Health Professionals in Critical Wartime Specialties</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Under the stipend program under this chapter, the Secretary of the military department concerned may enter into an agreement with a person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is eligible to be appointed as an officer in a reserve component;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is enrolled or has been accepted for enrollment in an institution in a course of study that results in a degree in clinical psychology or social work;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> signs an agreement that, unless sooner separated, the person will—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> complete the educational phase of the program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> accept a reappointment or redesignation within the person’s reserve component, if tendered, based upon the person’s health profession, following satisfactory completion of the educational and intern programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> participate in a residency program if required for clinical licensure in a mental health profession skill; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> if required by regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, agrees to apply for, if eligible, and accept, if offered, residency training in a mental health profession skill that has been designated by the Secretary as a critically needed wartime skill.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Under the agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the military department concerned shall agree to pay the participant a stipend, in the amount determined under subsection (g), for the period or the remainder of the period that the student is satisfactorily progressing toward a degree in clinical psychology or social work while enrolled in a school accredited in the designated mental health discipline;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the participant shall not be eligible to receive such stipend before appointment, designation, or assignment as an officer for service in the Selected Reserve;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the participant shall be subject to such active duty requirements as may be specified in the agreement and to active duty in time of war or national emergency as provided by law for members of the Selected Reserve; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the participant shall agree to serve, upon successful completion of the program, one year in the Selected Reserve for each six months, or part thereof, for which the stipend is provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount of Stipend</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The amount of a stipend under an agreement under subsection (b), (c), (d), or (f) shall be the stipend rate in effect for participants in the Armed Forces Health Professions Scholarship Program under <ref>section 2121(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VII, § 711(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1108</ref>, § 2128; renumbered § 16201 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1663(c)(2)</ref>, (5), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3007</ref>, 3008; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VII, § 736</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 383</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 539</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(WW)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VI, § 616(c), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4486</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 556</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1416</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VI, § 618</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 782</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16202.</num>
<heading> Reserve service: required active duty for training</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Selected Reserve</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person who is required under an agreement under <ref>section 16201 of this title</ref> to serve in the Selected Reserve shall serve not less than 12 days of active duty for training each year during the period of service required by the agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">IRR Service</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A person who is required under an agreement under <ref>section 16201 of this title</ref> to serve in the Individual Ready Reserve shall serve—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not less than 30 days of initial active duty for training; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not less than five days of active duty for training each year during the period of service required by the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VII, § 711(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1111</ref>, § 2129; renumbered § 16202 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1663(c)(3)</ref>, (6), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3007</ref>, 3008.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16203.</num>
<heading> Penalties and limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Failure to Complete Program of Training</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A member of the program who, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, is dropped from the program for deficiency in training, or for other reasons, shall be required, at the discretion of the Secretary concerned—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to perform one year of active duty for each year (or part thereof) for which such person was provided financial assistance under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to comply with the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of a military department, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, may relieve a member participating in the program who is dropped from the program from any requirement that may be imposed under paragraph (1), but such relief shall not relieve him from any military obligation imposed by any other law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibitions of Duplicate Benefits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Financial assistance may not be provided under this section to a member receiving financial assistance under <ref>section 2107 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VII, § 711(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1111</ref>, § 2130; renumbered § 16203 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1663(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3008</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI, § 687(c)(13)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3335</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VI, § 618(a)(1)(O)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16204.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall be administered under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1663(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3007</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>