<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 767—</num>
<heading>UTILITIES AND SERVICES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7591.</num>
<heading> Utilities: proceeds from overseas operations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During actual or threatened hostilities, proceeds from operating a public utility in connection with operations of the Corps of Engineers in the field overseas are available for that utility until the close of the fiscal year following that in which they are received.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 257</ref>, § 4591; renumbered § 7591, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7592.</num>
<heading> Radiograms and telegrams: forwarding charges due connecting commercial facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the operation of telegraph lines, cables, or radio stations, members of the Signal Corps may, in the discretion of the Secretary of the Army, collect forwarding charges due connecting commercial telegraph or radio companies for sending radiograms or telegrams over their lines. Under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, they may present a voucher to a disbursing official for payment of the forwarding charge.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 257</ref>, § 4592; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1052</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–316, title I, § 105(e)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3830</ref>; renumbered § 7592, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7593.</num>
<heading> Quarters: heat and light</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The heat and light necessary for the authorized quarters of members of the Army shall be furnished at the expense of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 257</ref>, § 4593; renumbered § 7593, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7594.</num>
<heading> Furnishing of heraldic services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of the Army, an authority designated by him may, upon the request of, and subject to approval by, the Secretary of another military department, design flags, insignia, badges, medals, seals, decorations, guidons, streamers, finial pieces for flagstaffs, buttons, buckles, awards, trophies, marks, emblems, rosettes, scrolls, braids, ribbons, knots, tabs, cords, and similar items for the requesting department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Upon request the Secretary of the Army may advise other departments and agencies of the United States on matters of heraldry.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army may prescribe regulations providing for reimbursement for services furnished under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–263, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1957-09-02">Sept. 2, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 589</ref>, § 4594; renumbered § 7594, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7595.</num>
<heading> Army Military History Institute: fee for providing historical information to the public</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary of the Army may charge a person a fee for providing the person with information from the United States Army Military History Institute that is requested by that person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A fee may not be charged under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to a person for information that the person requests to carry out a duty as a member of the armed forces or an officer or employee of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for a release of information under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A fee charged for providing information under this section may not exceed the cost of providing the information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention of Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts received under subsection (a) for providing information in any fiscal year shall be credited to the appropriation or appropriations charged the costs of providing information to the public from the United States Army Military History Institute during that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “United States Army Military History Institute” means the archive for historical records and materials of the Army that the Secretary of the Army designates as the primary archive for such records and materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The terms “officer of the United States” and “employee of the United States” have the meanings given the terms “officer” and “employee”, respectively, in sections 2104 and 2105, respectively, of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1085(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–287, § 4595; renumbered § 7595, <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7596.</num>
<heading> Provision of goods and services at Kwajalein Atoll</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of the Army, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, may provide goods and services, including interatoll transportation, to the Government of the Republic of the Marshall Islands and other eligible patrons, as determined by the Secretary of the Army, at Kwajalein Atoll.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army may not provide goods or services under this section if doing so would be inconsistent, as determined by the Secretary of State, with the Compact of Free Association between the Government of the United States and the Government of the Republic of the Marshall Islands or any subsidiary agreement or implementing arrangement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Army may collect reimbursement from the Government of the Republic of the Marshall Islands and eligible patrons for the provision of goods or services under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The amount collected for goods or services under this subsection may not be greater than the total amount of actual costs to the United States for providing the goods or services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Necessary Expenses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts appropriated to the Department of the Army may be used for necessary expenses associated with providing goods and services under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Army shall issue regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299A(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3997</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>