<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 387—</num>
<heading>SMALL BUSINESS PROGRAMS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4901.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense small business strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall implement a small business strategy for the Department of Defense that meets the requirements of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unified Management Structure</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>As part of the small business strategy described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure that there is a unified management structure within the Department for the functions of the Department relating to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> programs and activities related to small business concerns (as defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> manufacturing and industrial base policy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any procurement technical assistance program established under chapter 388 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose of Small Business Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that programs and activities of the Department of Defense related to small business concerns are carried out so as to further national defense programs and priorities and the statements of purpose for Department of Defense acquisition set forth in section 801 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 (<ref>Public Law 115–91</ref>; <ref>131 Stat. 1449</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Points of Entry Into Defense Market</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that opportunities for small business concerns to contract with the Department of Defense are identified clearly; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that small business concerns are able to have access to program managers, contracting officers, and other persons using the products or services of such concern to the extent necessary to inform such persons of emerging and existing capabilities of such concerns.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enhanced Outreach Under Procurement Technical Assistance Program Market</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall enable and promote activities to provide coordinated outreach to small business concerns through any procurement technical assistance program established under chapter 388 of this title to facilitate small business contracting with the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 851(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1883</ref>, § 2283; renumbered § 4901 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1871(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4902.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense Mentor-Protege Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program to be known as the “Mentor-Protege Program”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The purpose of the program is to provide incentives for major Department of Defense contractors to furnish disadvantaged small business concerns with assistance designed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enhance the capabilities of disadvantaged small business concerns to perform as subcontractors and suppliers under Department of Defense contracts and other contracts and subcontracts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> increase the participation of such business concerns as subcontractors and suppliers under Department of Defense contracts, other Federal Government contracts, and commercial contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Participants</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A business concern meeting the eligibility requirements set out in subsection (d) may enter into agreements under subsection (e) and furnish assistance to disadvantaged small business concerns upon making application to the Secretary of Defense and being approved for participation in the program by the Secretary. A business concern participating in the program pursuant to such an approval shall be known, for the purposes of the program, as a “mentor firm”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A disadvantaged small business concern eligible for the award of Federal contracts may obtain assistance from a mentor firm upon entering into an agreement with the mentor firm as provided in subsection (e). A disadvantaged small business concern may not be a party to more than one agreement concurrently, and the authority to enter into agreements under subsection (e) shall only be available to such concern during the 5-year period beginning on the date such concern enters into the first such agreement. A disadvantaged small business concern receiving such assistance shall be known, for the purposes of the program, as a “protege firm”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In entering into an agreement pursuant to subsection (e), a mentor firm may rely in good faith on a written representation of a business concern that such business concern is a disadvantaged small business concern. The Small Business Administration shall determine the status of such business concern as a disadvantaged small business concern in the event of a protest regarding the status of such business concern. If at any time the business concern is determined by the Small Business Administration not to be a disadvantaged small business concern, assistance furnished such business concern by the mentor firm after the date of the determination may not be considered assistance furnished under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Mentor Firm Eligibility.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to subsection (c)(1), a mentor firm may enter into an agreement with one or more protege firms under subsection (e) and provide assistance under the program pursuant to that agreement if the mentor firm—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is eligible for award of Federal contracts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> demonstrates that it—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is qualified to provide assistance that will contribute to the purpose of the program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is of good financial health and character and does not appear on a Federal list of debarred or suspended contractors; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> can impart value to a protege firm because of experience gained as a Department of Defense contractor or through knowledge of general business operations and government contracting, as demonstrated by evidence that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> during the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year in which the mentor firm enters into the agreement, the total amount of the Department of Defense contracts awarded such mentor firm and the subcontracts awarded such mentor firm under Department of Defense contracts was equal to or greater than $25,000,000; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the mentor firm demonstrates the capability to assist in the development of protege firms, and is approved by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to criteria specified in the regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (j).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A mentor firm may not enter into an agreement with a protege firm if the Administrator of the Small Business Administration has made a determination finding affiliation between the mentor firm and the protege firm.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Administrator of the Small Business Administration has not made such a determination and if the Secretary has reason to believe (based on the regulations promulgated by the Administrator regarding affiliation) that the mentor firm is affiliated with the protege firm, the Secretary shall request a determination regarding affiliation from the Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mentor-Protege Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Before providing assistance to a protege firm under the program, a mentor firm shall enter into a mentor-protege agreement with the protege firm regarding the assistance to be provided by the mentor firm. The agreement shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A developmental program for the protege firm, in such detail as may be reasonable, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> factors to assess the protege firm’s developmental progress under the program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a description of the quantitative and qualitative benefits to the Department of Defense from the agreement, if applicable;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> goals for additional awards that the protege firm can compete for outside the Mentor-Protege Program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the assistance the mentor firm will provide to the protege firm in understanding contract regulations of the Federal Government and the Department of Defense (including the Federal Acquisition Regulation and the Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement) after award of a subcontract under this section, if applicable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A program participation term for any period of not more than three years, except that the term may be a period of up to five years if the Secretary of Defense determines in writing that unusual circumstances justify a program participation term in excess of three years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Procedures for the protege firm to terminate the agreement voluntarily and for the mentor firm to terminate the agreement for cause.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An agreement under this subsection may be a contract, cooperative agreement, or a partnership intermediary agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forms of Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A mentor firm may provide a protege firm the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Assistance, by using mentor firm personnel, in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> general business management, including organizational management, financial management, and personnel management, marketing, and overall business planning;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> engineering and technical matters such as production, inventory control, manufacturing, test and evaluation, and quality assurance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other assistance designed to develop the capabilities of the protege firm under the developmental program referred to in subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Award of subcontracts on a noncompetitive basis to the protege firm under the Department of Defense or other contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Payment of progress payments for performance of the protege firm under such a subcontract in amounts as provided for in the subcontract, but in no event may any such progress payment exceed 100 percent of the costs incurred by the protege firm for the performance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Advance payments under such subcontracts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Loans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Assistance obtained by the mentor firm for the protege firm from one or more of the following—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> small business development centers established pursuant to section 21 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 648</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> entities providing procurement technical assistance pursuant to chapter 388 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a historically Black college or university or a minority institution of higher education; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> women’s business centers described in section 29 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 656</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Incentives for Mentor Firms</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may provide to a mentor firm reimbursement for the total amount of any progress payment or advance payment made under the program by the mentor firm to a protege firm in connection with a Department of Defense contract awarded the mentor firm.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may provide to a mentor firm reimbursement for the costs of the assistance furnished to a protege firm pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (6) of subsection (f) (except as provided in subparagraph (D)) as provided for in a line item in a Department of Defense contract under which the mentor firm is furnishing products or services to the Department, subject to a maximum amount of reimbursement specified in such contract, except that this sentence does not apply in a case in which the Secretary of Defense determines in writing that unusual circumstances justify reimbursement using a separate contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The determinations made in annual performance reviews of a mentor firm’s mentor-protege agreement shall be a major factor in the determinations of amounts of reimbursement, if any, that the mentor firm is eligible to receive in the remaining years of the program participation term under the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The total amount reimbursed under this paragraph to a mentor firm for costs of assistance furnished in a fiscal year to a protege firm may not exceed $1,000,000, except in a case in which the Secretary of Defense determines in writing that unusual circumstances justify a reimbursement of a higher amount.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not reimburse any fee assessed by the mentor firm for services provided to the protege firm pursuant to subsection (f)(6) or for business development expenses incurred by the mentor firm under a contract awarded to the mentor firm while participating in a joint venture with the protege firm.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Costs incurred by a mentor firm in providing assistance to a protege firm that are not reimbursed pursuant to paragraph (2) shall be recognized as credit in lieu of subcontract awards for purposes of determining whether the mentor firm attains a subcontracting participation goal applicable to such mentor firm under a Department of Defense contract, under a contract with another executive agency, or under a divisional or company-wide subcontracting plan negotiated with the Department of Defense or another executive agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The amount of the credit given a mentor firm for any such unreimbursed costs shall be equal to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> four times the total amount of such costs attributable to assistance provided by entities described in subsection (f)(6);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> three times the total amount of such costs attributable to assistance furnished by the mentor firm’s employees; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> two times the total amount of any other such costs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (j), the Secretary of Defense shall adjust the amount of credit given a mentor firm pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) if the Secretary determines that the firm’s performance regarding the award of subcontracts to disadvantaged small business concerns has declined without justifiable cause.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> A mentor firm shall receive credit toward the attainment of a subcontracting participation goal applicable to such mentor firm for each subcontract for a product or service awarded under such contract by a mentor firm to a business concern that, except for its size, would be a small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, but only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the size of such business concern is not more than two times the maximum size specified by the Administrator of the Small Business Administration for purposes of determining whether a business concern furnishing such product or service is a small business concern; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the business concern formerly had a mentor-protege agreement with such mentor firm that was not terminated for cause.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Small Business Act</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For purposes of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 631</ref> et seq.), no determination of affiliation or control (either direct or indirect) may be found between a protege firm and its mentor firm on the basis that the mentor firm has agreed to furnish (or has furnished) to its protege firm pursuant to a mentor-protege agreement any form of developmental assistance described in subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding section 8 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637</ref>), the Small Business Administration may not determine a disadvantaged small business concern to be ineligible to receive any assistance authorized under the Small Business Act on the basis that such business concern has participated in the Mentor-Protege Program or has received assistance pursuant to any developmental assistance agreement authorized under such program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Small Business Administration may not require a firm that is entering into, or has entered into, an agreement under subsection (e) as a protege firm to submit the agreement, or any other document required by the Secretary of Defense in the administration of the Mentor-Protege Program, to the Small Business Administration for review, approval, or any other purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation in Mentor-Protege Program not To Be a Condition for Award of a Contract or Subcontract</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A mentor firm may not require a business concern to enter into an agreement with the mentor firm pursuant to subsection (e) as a condition for being awarded a contract by the mentor firm, including a subcontract under a contract awarded to the mentor firm.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out the Mentor-Protege Program. Such regulations shall include the requirements set forth in section 8(d) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(d)</ref>) and shall prescribe procedures by which the parties may terminate participation in the program. The Department of Defense policy regarding the Mentor-Protege Program shall be published and maintained as an appendix to the Department of Defense Supplement to the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report by Mentor Firms</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To comply with section 8(d)(7) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(d)(7)</ref>), each mentor firm shall submit a report to the Secretary not less than once each fiscal year that includes, for the preceding fiscal year—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all technical or management assistance provided by mentor firm personnel for the purposes described in subsection (f)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any new awards of subcontracts on a competitive or noncompetitive basis to the protege firm under Department of Defense contracts or other contracts, including the value of such subcontracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any extensions, increases in the scope of work, or additional payments not previously reported for prior awards of subcontracts on a competitive or noncompetitive basis to the protege firm under Department of Defense contracts or other contracts, including the value of such subcontracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the amount of any payment of progress payments or advance payments made to the protege firm for performance under any subcontract made under the Mentor-Protege Program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any loans made by the mentor firm to the protege firm;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> all Federal contracts awarded to the mentor firm and the protege firm as a joint venture, designating whether the award was a restricted competition or a full and open competition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> any assistance obtained by the mentor firm for the protege firm from one or more—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> small business development centers established pursuant to section 21 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 648</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> entities providing procurement technical assistance pursuant to chapter 388 of this title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> historically Black colleges or universities or minority institutions of higher education;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> whether there have been any changes to the terms of the mentor-protege agreement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> a narrative describing the success assistance provided under subsection (f) has had in addressing the developmental needs of the protege firm, the impact on Department of Defense contracts, and addressing any problems encountered.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of Report by the Office of Small Business Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Office of Small Business Programs of the Department of Defense shall review the report required by subsection (k) and, if the Office finds that the mentor-protege agreement is not furthering the purpose of the Mentor-Protege Program, decide not to approve any continuation of the agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual Collection of Performance Data</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director of the Office of Small Business Programs shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maintain outcome-based performance goals and annually collect data through an automated information system (if practicable) assessing such goals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conduct an independent review of the Mentor-Protege Program established under this section at least once every three years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(n)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “affiliation”, with respect to a relationship between a mentor firm and a protege firm, means a relationship described under section 121.103 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “disadvantaged small business concern” means a firm that is not more than the size standard corresponding to its primary North American Industry Classification System code, is not owned or managed by individuals or entities that directly or indirectly have stock options or convertible securities in the mentor firm, and is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a business entity owned and controlled by an Indian tribe as defined by section 8(a)(13) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(a)(13)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a business entity owned and controlled by a Native Hawaiian Organization as defined by section 8(a)(15) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(a)(15)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a qualified organization employing severely disabled individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a small business concern owned and controlled by women, as defined in section 8(d)(3)(D) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(d)(3)(D)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a small business concern owned and controlled by service–disabled veterans (as defined in section 8(d)(3) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(d)(3)</ref>));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a qualified HUBZone small business concern (as defined in section 31(b) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 657a(b)</ref>)); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> a small business concern that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is a nontraditional defense contractor, as such term is defined in <ref>section 3014 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> currently provides goods or services in the private sector that are critical to enhancing the capabilities of the defense supplier base and fulfilling key Department of Defense needs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “historically Black college and university” means any of the historically Black colleges and universities referred to in <ref>section 2323 of this title</ref>, as in effect on <date date="2018-03-01">March 1, 2018</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “minority institution of higher education” means an institution of higher education with a student body that reflects the composition specified in section 312(b)(3), (4), and (5) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1058(b)(3)</ref>, (4), and (5)).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002145">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “qualified organization employing the severely disabled” means a business entity operated on a for-profit or nonprofit basis that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> uses rehabilitative engineering to provide employment opportunities for severely disabled individuals and integrates severely disabled individuals into its workforce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> employs severely disabled individuals at a rate that averages not less than 20 percent of its total workforce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> employs each severely disabled individual in its workforce generally on the basis of 40 hours per week; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> pays not less than the minimum wage prescribed pursuant to section 6 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 206</ref>) to those employees who are severely disabled individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “severely disabled individual” means an individual who is blind (as defined in <ref>section 8501 of title 41</ref>) or a severely disabled individual (as defined in such section).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “small business concern” has the meaning given such term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 632</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals” has the meaning given such term in section 8(d)(3)(C) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(d)(3)(C)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “subcontracting participation goal”, with respect to a Department of Defense contract, means a goal for the extent of the participation by disadvantaged small business concerns in the subcontracts awarded under such contract, as established pursuant to section 8(d) of the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 637(d)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 856(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2723</ref>, 2724; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VIII, § 852</ref>, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(37), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 344</ref>, 685; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(42)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>[RESERVED]</heading>
</subchapter>
</chapter>