<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 983—</num>
<heading>ACCOUNTABILITY AND RESPONSIBILITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9831.</num>
<heading> Custody of departmental records and property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Air Force has custody and charge of all books, records, papers, furniture, fixtures, and other property under the lawful control of the executive part of the Department of the Air Force.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 9832.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title III, § 375(c)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 84</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 9833.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–480, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1962-06-08">June 8, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 94</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 9835.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1006(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2633</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 9836.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title III, § 375(c)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 84</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9837.</num>
<heading> Settlement of accounts: remission or cancellation of indebtedness of members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Air Force may have remitted or cancelled any part of the indebtedness of a person to the United States or any instrumentality of the United States incurred while the person was serving as a member of the Air Force or the Space Force, whether as a regular or a reserve in active status, but only if the Secretary considers such action to be in the best interest of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retroactive Applicability to Certain Debts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority in subsection (a) may be exercised with respect to any debt covered by that subsection that is incurred on or after <date date="2001-10-07">October 7, 2001</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall be administered under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 594</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–861, § 33(a)(45)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1567</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–649, § 14c(58)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 514(22)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2936</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI, § 683(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VI, § 673(c)(1)</ref>, (2), (e)(3), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2271</ref>, 2272; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1063(c)(7)(C)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VI, § 671(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2173</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(e)(22)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9838.</num>
<heading> Settlement of accounts: affidavit of squadron commander</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the settlement of the accounts of the commanding officer of a squadron for clothing and other military supplies, his affidavit may be received to show—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that vouchers or squadron books were lost;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> anything tending to prove that any apparent deficiency of those articles was caused by unavoidable accident, or by loss in actual service without his fault; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that all or part of the clothing and supplies was properly used.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The affidavit may be used as evidence of the facts set forth, with or without other evidence, as determined by the Secretary of the Air Force to be just and proper under the circumstances.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 595</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9839.</num>
<heading> Settlement of accounts: oaths</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Air Force may detail any employee of the Department of the Air Force to administer oaths required by law in the settlement of an officer’s accounts for clothing and other military supplies. An oath administered under this section shall be without expense to the person to whom it is administered.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 595</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9840.</num>
<heading> Final settlement of officer’s accounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before final payment upon discharge may be made to an officer of the Air Force or the Space Force who has been accountable or responsible for public property, the officer must obtain a certificate of nonindebtedness to the United States from each officer to whom the officer was accountable or responsible for property. The officer must also make an affidavit, certified by the officer’s commanding officer to be correct, that the officer is not accountable or responsible for property to any other officer. An officer who has not been responsible for public property must make an affidavit of that fact, certified by the officer’s commanding officer. Compliance with this section warrants the final payment of the officer concerned.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 595</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(e)(23)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3819</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(37)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1922</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9841.</num>
<heading> Payment of small amounts to public creditors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When authorized by the Secretary of the Air Force, a disbursing official of Air Force or Space Force subsistence funds may keep a limited amount of those funds in the personal possession and at the risk of the disbursing official to pay small amounts to public creditors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(b)(14)(B)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1058</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(e)(24)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9842.</num>
<heading> Settlement of accounts of line officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Comptroller General shall settle the account of a line officer of the Air Force or the Space Force for pay due the officer even if the officer cannot account for property entrusted to the officer or cannot make a monthly report or return, when the Comptroller General is satisfied that the inability to account for property or make a report or return was the result of the officer having been a prisoner, or of an accident or casualty of war.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(b)(14)(B)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1058</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(e)(25)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>