<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 83—</num>
<heading>CIVILIAN DEFENSE INTELLIGENCE EMPLOYEES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>DEFENSE-WIDE INTELLIGENCE PERSONNEL POLICY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1601.</num>
<heading> Civilian intelligence personnel: general authority to establish excepted positions, appoint personnel, and fix rates of pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> establish, as positions in the excepted service, such defense intelligence positions in the Department of Defense as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the intelligence functions of the Department, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Intelligence Senior Level positions designated under <ref>section 1607 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> positions in the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> appoint individuals to those positions (after taking into consideration the availability of preference eligibles for appointment to those positions); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> fix the compensation of such individuals for service in those positions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction With Other Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary of Defense under subsection (a) applies without regard to the provisions of any other law relating to the appointment, number, classification, or compensation of employees.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2746</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1141(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–318.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1602.</num>
<heading> Basic pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Fix Rates of Basic Pay</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense (subject to the provisions of this section) shall fix the rates of basic pay for positions established under <ref>section 1601 of this title</ref> in relation to the rates of pay provided for comparable positions in the Department of Defense and subject to the same limitations on maximum rates of pay established for employees of the Department of Defense by law or regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prevailing Rate Systems</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may, consistent with <ref>section 5341 of title 5</ref>, adopt such provisions of that title as provide for prevailing rate systems of basic pay and may apply those provisions to positions for civilian employees in or under which the Department of Defense may employ individuals described by section 5342(a)(2)(A) of that title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2746</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title XI, § 1103(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2072</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(g)(12)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2403</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1603.</num>
<heading> Additional compensation, incentives, and allowances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Compensation Based on Title </inline>5 <inline class="small-caps">Authorities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may provide employees in defense intelligence positions compensation (in addition to basic pay), including benefits, incentives, and allowances, consistent with, and not in excess of the level authorized for, comparable positions authorized by title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allowances Based on Living Costs and Environment</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In addition to basic pay, employees in defense intelligence positions who are citizens or nationals of the United States and are stationed outside the continental United States or in Alaska may be paid an allowance, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, while they are so stationed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An allowance under this subsection shall be based on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> living costs substantially higher than in the District of Columbia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conditions of environment which (i) differ substantially from conditions of environment in the continental United States, and (ii) warrant an allowance as a recruitment incentive; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> both of the factors specified in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An allowance under this subsection may not exceed the allowance authorized to be paid by <ref>section 5941(a) of title 5</ref> for employees whose rates of basic pay are fixed by statute.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Allowances and Benefits for Certain Employees of the Defense Clandestine Service</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Defense submits the report under paragraph (3)(A), in addition to the authority to provide compensation under subsection (a), the Secretary may provide a covered employee allowances and benefits under paragraph (1) of <ref>section 9904 of title 5</ref> without regard to the limitations in that section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that the employee be assigned to activities outside the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that the activities to which the employee is assigned be in support of Department of Defense activities abroad.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may not provide allowances and benefits under paragraph (1) to more than 125 covered employees per year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing a strategy addressing the mission of the Defense Clandestine Service during the period covered by the most recent future-years defense program submitted under <ref>section 221 of this title</ref>, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> how such mission will evolve during such period;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> how the authority provided by paragraph (1) will assist the Secretary in carrying out such mission; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an implementation plan for carrying out paragraph (1), including a projection of how much the amount of the allowances and benefits provided under such paragraph compare with the amount of the allowances and benefits provided before the date of the report.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>, and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report, with respect to the fiscal year preceding the date on which the report is submitted—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identifying the number of covered employees for whom the Secretary provided allowances and benefits under paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> evaluating the efficacy of such allowances and benefits in enabling the execution of the objectives of the Defense Intelligence Agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The reports under subparagraphs (A) and (B) may be submitted in classified form.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the congressional defense committees; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The term “covered employee” means an employee in a defense intelligence position who is assigned to the Defense Clandestine Service at a location in the United States that the Secretary determines has living costs equal to or higher than the District of Columbia.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2746</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XI, § 1108</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1597</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1604.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2745</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1605.</num>
<heading> Benefits for certain employees assigned outside the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may provide to civilian personnel described in subsection (d) allowances and benefits comparable to those provided by the Secretary of State to officers and employees of the Foreign Service under paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), (7), (8), and (13) of section 901 and sections 705 and 903 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 4081(2)</ref>, (3), (4), (5), (6), (7), (8), and (13), 4025, 4083) and under <ref>section 5924(4) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may also provide to any such civilian personnel special retirement accrual benefits in the same manner provided for certain officers and employees of the Central Intelligence Agency in section 303 of the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 2153</ref>) and in section 18 of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3518</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The authority of the Secretary of Defense to make payments under subsection (a) is effective for any fiscal year only to the extent that appropriated funds are available for such purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Regulations prescribed under subsection (a) may not take effect until the Secretary of Defense has submitted such regulations to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) applies to civilian personnel of the Department of Defense who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are United States nationals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of employees of the Defense Intelligence Agency, are assigned to duty outside the United States and, in the case of other employees, are assigned to Defense Attaché Offices or Defense Intelligence Agency Liaison Offices outside the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> are designated by the Secretary of Defense for the purposes of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–215, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-12-09">Dec. 9, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1478</ref>, § 192; renumbered § 1605 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1302(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–335, title V, § 507(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–569, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3198</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–193, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–496, title VIII, § 803(d)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3253</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1182(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1771</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–93, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-01-06">Jan. 6, 1996</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 972</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1633(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2751</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(11)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1606.</num>
<heading> Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may establish a Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service for defense intelligence positions established pursuant to <ref>section 1601(a) of this title</ref> that are equivalent to Senior Executive Service positions. The number of positions in the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service may not exceed 594.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations Consistent With Title</inline> 5 <inline class="small-caps">Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service which are consistent with the requirements set forth in sections 3131, 3132(a)(2), 3396(c), 3592, 3595(a), 5384, and 6304 of title 5, subsections (a), (b), and (c) of section 7543 of such title (except that any hearing or appeal to which a member of the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service is entitled shall be held or decided pursuant to those regulations), and subchapter II of chapter 43 of such title. To the extent that the Secretary determines it practicable to apply to members of, or applicants for, the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service other provisions of title 5 that apply to members of, or applicants for, the Senior Executive Service, the Secretary shall also prescribe regulations to implement those provisions with respect to the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Award of Rank to Members of the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President, based on the recommendations of the Secretary of Defense, may award a rank referred to in <ref>section 4507 of title 5</ref> to members of the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service. The award of such rank shall be made in a manner consistent with the provisions of that section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance Appraisals</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service shall be subject to a performance appraisal system which, as designed and applied, is certified by the Secretary of Defense under <ref>section 5307 of title 5</ref> as making meaningful distinctions based on relative performance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The performance appraisal system applicable to the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service under paragraph (1) may be the same performance appraisal system that is established and implemented within the Department of Defense for members of the Senior Executive Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2747</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1142], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–319; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XI, § 1121</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title XI, § 1103(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2073</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XI, § 1125</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3454</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1607.</num>
<heading> Intelligence Senior Level positions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may designate as an Intelligence Senior Level position any defense intelligence position that, as determined by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is classifiable above grade GS–15 of the General Schedule;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> does not satisfy functional or program management criteria for being designated a Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service position; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has no more than minimal supervisory responsibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a) shall be carried out in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Award of Rank to Employees in Intelligence Senior Level Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President, based on the recommendations of the Secretary of Defense, may award a rank referred to in <ref>section 4507a of title 5</ref> to employees in Intelligence Senior Level positions designated under subsection (a). The award of such rank shall be made in a manner consistent with the provisions of that section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2747</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–306, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2407</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1608.</num>
<heading> Time-limited appointments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority for Time-Limited Appointments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense may by regulation authorize appointing officials to make time-limited appointments to defense intelligence positions specified in the regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of Use of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall review each time-limited appointment in a defense intelligence position at the end of the first year of the period of the appointment and determine whether the appointment should be continued for the remainder of the period. The continuation of a time-limited appointment after the first year shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Condition on Permanent Appointment to Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An employee serving in a defense intelligence position pursuant to a time-limited appointment is not eligible for a permanent appointment to a Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service position (including a position in which the employee is serving) unless the employee is selected for the permanent appointment on a competitive basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time-Limited Appointment Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “time-limited appointment” means an appointment (subject to the condition in subsection (b)) for a period not to exceed two years.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1609.</num>
<heading> Termination of defense intelligence employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Termination Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Defense may terminate the employment of any employee in a defense intelligence position if the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> considers that action to be in the interests of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> determines that the procedures prescribed in other provisions of law that authorize the termination of the employment of such employee cannot be invoked in a manner consistent with the national security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Finality</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A decision by the Secretary of Defense to terminate the employment of an employee under this section is final and may not be appealed or reviewed outside the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification to Congressional Committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the Secretary of Defense terminates the employment of an employee under the authority of this section, the Secretary shall promptly notify the congressional oversight committees of such termination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preservation of Right To Seek Other Employment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any termination of employment under this section does not affect the right of the employee involved to seek or accept employment with any other department or agency of the United States if that employee is declared eligible for such employment by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority of the Secretary of Defense under this section may be delegated only to the Deputy Secretary of Defense, the head of an intelligence component of the Department of Defense (with respect to employees of that component), or the Secretary of a military department (with respect to employees of that department). An action to terminate employment of such an employee by any such official may be appealed to the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1610.</num>
<heading> Reductions and other adjustments in force</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the separation of employees in defense intelligence positions, including members of the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service and employees in Intelligence Senior Level positions, during a reduction in force or other adjustment in force. The regulations shall apply to such a reduction in force or other adjustment in force notwithstanding sections 3501(b) and 3502 of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matters To Be Given Effect</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The regulations shall give effect to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Tenure of employment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Military preference, subject to sections 3501(a)(3) and 3502(b) of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The veteran’s preference under <ref>section 3502(b) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Performance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Length of service computed in accordance with the second sentence of <ref>section 3502(a) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations Relating to Defense Intelligence SES</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The regulations relating to removal from the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service in a reduction in force or other adjustment in force shall be consistent with <ref>section 3595(a) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Right of Appeal</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The regulations shall provide a right of appeal regarding a personnel action under the regulations. The appeal shall be determined within the Department of Defense. An appeal determined at the highest level provided in the regulations shall be final and not subject to review outside the Department of Defense. A personnel action covered by the regulations is not subject to any other provision of law that provides appellate rights or procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), a preference eligible referred to in <ref>section 7511(a)(1)(B) of title 5</ref> may elect to have an appeal of a personnel action taken against the preference eligible under the regulation determined by the Merit Systems Protection Board instead of having the appeal determined within the Department of Defense. <ref>Section 7701 of title 5</ref> shall apply to any such appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation With OPM</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Regulations under this section shall be prescribed in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2749</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1611.</num>
<heading> Postemployment assistance: certain terminated intelligence employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense may, in the case of any individual who is a qualified former intelligence employee, use appropriated funds—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to assist that individual in finding and qualifying for employment other than in a defense intelligence position;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist that individual in meeting the expenses of treatment of medical or psychological disabilities of that individual; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to provide financial support to that individual during periods of unemployment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified Former Intelligence Employees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section, a qualified former intelligence employee is an individual who was employed as a civilian employee of the Department of Defense in a sensitive defense intelligence position—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who has been found to be ineligible for continued access to information designated as “Sensitive Compartmented Information” and employment in a defense intelligence position; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whose employment in a defense intelligence position has been terminated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Assistance may be provided to a qualified former intelligence employee under subsection (a) only if the Secretary determines that such assistance is essential to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maintain the judgment and emotional stability of the qualified former intelligence employee; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> avoid circumstances that might lead to the unlawful disclosure of classified information to which the qualified former intelligence employee had access.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration of Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Assistance may not be provided under this section in the case of any individual after the end of the five-year period beginning on the date of the termination of the employment of the individual in a defense intelligence position.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title VIII, § 806(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3441</ref>, § 1599; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 503</ref>; renumbered § 1611 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2749</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1141(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–318; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–306, title VIII, § 811(b)(4)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2423</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–177, title III, § 361(h)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-13">Dec. 13, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2625</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1612.</num>
<heading> Merit system principles and civil service protections: applicability</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Merit System Principles</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 2301 of title 5</ref> shall apply to the exercise of authority under this subchapter (other than sections 1605 and 1611).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil Service Protections</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If, in the case of a position established under authority other than <ref>section 1601(a)(1) of this title</ref> that is reestablished as an excepted service position under that section, the provisions of law referred to in paragraph (2) applied to the person serving in that position immediately before the position is so reestablished and such provisions of law would not otherwise apply to the person while serving in the position as so reestablished, then such provisions of law shall, subject to paragraph (3), continue to apply to the person with respect to service in that position for as long as the person continues to serve in the position without a break in service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of law referred to in paragraph (1) are the following provisions of title 5:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Section 2302, relating to prohibited personnel practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Chapter 75, relating to adverse actions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any provision of chapter 75 of title 5, an appeal of an adverse action by an individual employee covered by paragraph (1) shall be determined within the Department of Defense if the employee so elects.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe the procedures for initiating and determining appeals of adverse actions pursuant to elections made under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1613.</num>
<heading> Miscellaneous provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Collective Bargaining Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in sections 1601 through 1603 and 1606 through 1610 may be construed to impair the continued effectiveness of a collective bargaining agreement with respect to an agency or office that is a successor to an agency or office covered by the agreement before the succession.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to Congress of Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense shall notify Congress of any regulations prescribed to carry out this subchapter (other than sections 1605 and 1611). Such notice shall be provided by submitting a copy of the regulations to the congressional oversight committees not less than 60 days before such regulations take effect.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2750</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(32)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1902</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1614.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “defense intelligence position” means a civilian position as an intelligence officer or intelligence employee of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “intelligence component of the Department of Defense” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The National Security Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Defense Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Any other component of the Department of Defense that performs intelligence functions and is designated by the Secretary of Defense as an intelligence component of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any successor to a component specified in, or designated pursuant to, this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “congressional oversight committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “excepted service” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 2103 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “preference eligible” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 2108(3) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “Senior Executive Service position” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 3132(a)(2) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “collective bargaining agreement” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 7103(8) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2750</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1141(c)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–319; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(7)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1569</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>DEFENSE INTELLIGENCE AGENCY PERSONNEL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1621.</num>
<heading> Defense Intelligence Agency merit pay system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may by regulation establish a merit pay system for such employees of the Defense Intelligence Agency as the Secretary considers appropriate. The merit pay system shall be designed to carry out purposes consistent with those set forth in <ref>section 5401 of title 5</ref>, as in effect on <date date="1993-10-31">October 31, 1993</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–89, title VII, § 701(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-04">Dec. 4, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1160</ref>, § 1602; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–615, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3216</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–89, § 3(b)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 982</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title V, § 501(b)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3428</ref>; renumbered § 1621 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1632(a)(1), 1633(d), <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2745</ref>, 2752.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1622.</num>
<heading> Uniform allowance: civilian employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may pay an allowance under this section to any civilian employee of the Defense Intelligence Agency who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is assigned to a Defense Attaché Office outside the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is required by regulation to wear a prescribed uniform in performance of official duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding <ref>section 5901(a) of title 5</ref>, the amount of any such allowance shall be the greater of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The amount provided for employees of the Department of State assigned to positions outside the United States and required by regulation to wear a prescribed uniform in performance of official duties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The maximum allowance provided under <ref>section 1593(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An allowance paid under this section shall be treated in the same manner as is provided in subsection (c) of <ref>section 5901 of title 5</ref> for an allowance paid under that section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–178, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-02">Dec. 2, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1015</ref>, § 1606; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 336(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1419</ref>; renumbered § 1622, <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2745</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1623.</num>
<heading> Financial assistance to certain employees in acquisition of critical skills</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish an undergraduate training program with respect to civilian employees of the Defense Intelligence Agency that is similar in purpose, conditions, content, and administration to the program which the Secretary of Defense is authorized to establish under section 16 of the National Security Agency Act of 1959 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3614</ref>) for civilian employees of the National Security Agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any payments made by the Secretary to carry out the program required to be established by subsection (a) may be made in any fiscal year only to the extent that appropriated funds are available for that purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–193, title V, § 507(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1709</ref>, § 1608; renumbered § 1623, <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2745</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(9)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>