<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 113—</num>
<heading>DEFENSE CIVILIAN TRAINING CORPS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2200g.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall establish and maintain a Defense Civilian Training Corps program, organized into one or more units, at any accredited civilian educational institution authorized to grant baccalaureate degrees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The purpose of the Defense Civilian Training Corps is to target critical skills gaps necessary to achieve the objectives of the national defense strategies required by <ref>section 113(g) of this title</ref> and the national security strategies required by section 108 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3043</ref>) by preparing students selected for the Defense Civilian Training Corps for Department of Defense careers relating to acquisition, digital technologies, critical technologies, science, engineering, finance, and other civilian occupations determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Resources and Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment may leverage the resources and programs of the acquisition research organization within a civilian college or university that is described under <ref>section 4142(a) of this title</ref> (commonly referred to as the “Acquisition Innovation Research Center”) to carry out the requirements of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 860(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1513</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3870</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 833</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2713</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(18)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 684</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(26)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2200h.</num>
<heading> Program elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In establishing the program, the Secretary of Defense shall determine the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A methodology to identify and target critical skills gaps in Department of Defense occupations relating to acquisition, science, engineering, or other civilian occupations determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A mechanism to track and report the success of the program in eliminating any critical skills gaps identified under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Criteria for an accredited civilian educational institution to participate in the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The eligibility of a student to become a member of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Criteria required for a member of the program to receive financial assistance from the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term of service as an employee of the Department of Defense required for a member of the program to receive such financial assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Criteria required for a member of the program to be released from a term of service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The method by which a successful graduate of the program may gain immediate employment in the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Resources required for implementation of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 860(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1514</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3870</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2200i.</num>
<heading> Model authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making determinations under <ref>section 2200h of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Defense shall use the authorities under chapters 103 and 111 of this title as guides.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 860(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1514</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3870</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2200j.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “program” means the Defense Civilian Training Corps program established under section 2200g.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “member of the program” means a student at an accredited civilian educational institution who is enrolled in the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 860(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1514</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3870</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>