<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 65—</num>
<heading>SENATE OFFICERS AND ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6501.</num>
<heading> Appointment of consultants by Majority Leader, Minority Leader, Secretary of Senate, and Legislative Counsel of Senate; compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Majority Leader and the Minority Leader, are each authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of not more than 12 individual consultants, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of the per diem equivalent of the highest gross rate of annual compensation which may be paid to employees of a standing committee of the Senate. The President pro tempore of the Senate is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of not more than three individual consultants, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of that specified in the first sentence of this subsection. The President pro tempore emeritus of the Senate is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of one individual consultant, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of that specified in the first sentence of this subsection. The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of not more than two individual consultants, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of the per diem equivalent of the highest gross rate of annual compensation which may be paid to employees of a standing committee of the Senate. The Legislative Counsel of the Senate (subject to the approval of the President pro tempore) is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of not more than two consultants, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of that specified in the first sentence of this section. The provisions of sections 8344 and 8468 of title 5 shall not apply to any individual serving in a position under this authority. Expenditures under this authority shall be paid from the contingent fund of the Senate upon vouchers approved by the President pro tempore, President pro tempore emeritus, Majority Leader, Minority Leader, Secretary of the Senate, or Legislative Counsel of the Senate, as the case may be.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any or all appointments under this section may be at an annual rate of compensation rather than at a daily rate of compensation, but such annual rate shall not be in excess of the highest gross rate of annual compensation which may be paid to employees of a standing committee of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002118">1</ref> Title of position</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each appointing authority under subsection (a) may designate the title of the position of any individual appointed under that subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–26, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1977-05-04">May 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 82</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 110(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–458, title I</ref>, §§ 4, 9, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2161</ref>, 2162; <ref>Pub. L. 101–302, title III, § 314(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-05-25">May 25, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–90, title I, § 3</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–2</ref>, <date date="1995-02-09">Feb. 9, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 45</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 4(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–20, title II, § 2803</ref>, <date date="2001-07-24">July 24, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 185</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 350</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. G, title I, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–47, div. E, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2024-03-23">Mar. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 712</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6502.</num>
<heading> Procurement of temporary help</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to regulations that the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate may prescribe, the Secretary of the Senate and the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate may procure temporary help services from a private sector source that offers such services. Each procurement of services under this subsection shall be for no longer than 30 days.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A person performing services procured under paragraph (1) shall not, during the period of the performance of the services, be an employee of the United States or be considered to be an employee of the United States for any purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect on <date date="2001-10-01">October 1, 2001</date>, and shall apply in fiscal year 2002 and successive fiscal years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 569</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6503.</num>
<heading> Payments from Senate contingent fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No payment shall be made from the contingent fund of the Senate unless sanctioned by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate. Payments made upon vouchers or abstracts of disbursements of salaries approved by said Committee shall be deemed, held, and taken, and are declared to be conclusive upon all the departments and officers of the Government: <i>Provided</i>, That no payment shall be made from said contingent fund as additional salary or compensation to any officer or employee of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 2, 1888, ch. 1069</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 546</ref>; <ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title I, § 102, <ref>60 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–554, title I</ref>, <date date="1974-12-27">Dec. 27, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1776</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title I, § 105(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1722</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6504.</num>
<heading> Committee on Rules and Administration; designation of employees to approve vouchers for payments from Senate contingent fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee on Rules and Administration may authorize its chairman to designate any employee or employees of such Committee to approve in his behalf, all vouchers making payments from the contingent fund of the Senate, such approval to be deemed and held to be approval by the Committee on Rules and Administration for all intents and purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–145</ref>, <date date="1973-11-01">Nov. 1, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–51, § 126</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 965</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title I, § 123A(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6505.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for contingent expenses of Senate; restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations made for contingent expenses of the Senate shall not be used for the payment of personal services except upon the express and specific authorization of the Senate in whose behalf such services are rendered. Nor shall such appropriations be used for any expenses not intimately and directly connected with the routine legislative business of the Senate, and the Government Accountability Office shall apply the provisions of this section in the settlement of the accounts of expenditures from said appropriations incurred for services or materials.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1902, ch. 17, § 1</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 26</ref>; <ref>June 10, 1921, ch. 18</ref>, title III, § 304, <ref>42 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(45)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6506.</num>
<heading> Separate accounts for “Secretary of the Senate” and for “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”; establishment within Senate contingent fund; inclusion of funds in existing accounts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Effective <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> there shall be, within the contingent fund of the Senate, a separate account for the “Secretary of the Senate”, and a separate account for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the account for “Automobiles and Maintenance”, within the contingent fund of the Senate, is abolished, and funds for the purchase, lease, exchange, maintenance, and operation of vehicles for the Senate shall be included in the separate account, established by paragraph (1), for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the account for “Postage Stamps”, within the contingent fund of the Senate, is abolished; and funds for special delivery postage of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate shall be included in the separate account, established by paragraph (1), for the “Secretary of the Senate”; funds for special delivery postage of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate shall be included in the separate account, established by paragraph (1), for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”; and postage stamps for the Secretaries for the Majority and the Minority and other offices and officers of the Senate, as authorized by law, shall be included in the account for “Miscellaneous Items”, within the contingent fund of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any provision of law which was enacted, or any Senate resolution which was agreed to, prior to <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, and which authorizes moneys in the contingent fund of the Senate to be expended by or for the use of the Secretary of the Senate, or his office (whether generally or from a specified account within such fund) may on and after <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, be construed to authorize such moneys to be expended from the separate account, within such fund, established by subsection (a)(1) for the “Secretary of the Senate”; and any provision of law which was enacted prior to <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, and which authorizes moneys in the contingent fund of the Senate to be expended by or for the use of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, or his office (whether generally or from a specified account within such fund) may on and after <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, be construed to authorize such moneys to be expended from the separate account, within such fund, established by subsection (a)(1) for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–51, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1983-07-14">July 14, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6507.</num>
<heading> Insurance of office funds of Secretary of Senate and Sergeant at Arms; payment of premiums</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate and the Sergeant at Arms on and after <date date="1956-06-27">June 27, 1956</date>, are authorized and directed to protect the funds of their respective offices by purchasing insurance in an amount necessary to protect said funds against loss. Premiums on such insurance shall be paid out of the contingent fund of the Senate, upon vouchers approved by the chairman of the Committee on Rules and Administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 27, 1956, ch. 453</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6508.</num>
<heading> Transfers from appropriations account for expenses of Office of Secretary of Senate and Office of Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Senate is authorized, with the approval of the Senate Committee on Appropriations, to transfer, during any fiscal year (1) from the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for expenses of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate, such sums as he shall specify to the Senate appropriations account, appropriated under the headings “Salaries, Officers and Employees” and “Office of the Secretary”, and (2) from the Senate appropriations account, appropriated under the headings “Salaries, Officers and Employees” and “Office of the Secretary” to the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for expenses of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate, such sums as he shall specify; and any funds so transferred shall be available in like manner and for the same purposes as are other funds in the account to which the funds are transferred.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized, with the approval of the Senate Committee on Appropriations, to transfer, during any fiscal year, from the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for expenses of the Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, such sums as he shall specify to the appropriations account, appropriated under the headings “Salaries, Officers and Employees” and “Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper”; and any funds so transferred shall be available in like manner and for the same purposes as are other funds in the account to which the funds are transferred.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–458, title I, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2161</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–302, title III, § 317</ref>, <date date="1990-05-25">May 25, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6509.</num>
<heading> Vouchering Senate office charges</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Senate support office charges</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Charges for expenses of any office, the funds of which are disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate, may be vouchered by a Senate support office paying such expenses or to which such charges are owed for goods or services provided, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such charges are paid on behalf of the office incurring such expenses by such Senate support office; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such charges are payable to such Senate support office for goods or services provided by such office to the office incurring such expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment charged to official funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments under this section shall be charged to the official funds of the office on whose behalf the expenses were paid, or which received the goods or services for which payment is required.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any voucher submitted by a Senate support office pursuant to this section shall be accompanied by a certification from such office of the amount and that such purchases were of the nature that they could be charged to the official funds of the office on whose behalf charges were paid, or to which goods or services were provided.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Vouchers under this section shall be submitted and paid subject to such regulations as may be promulgated by the Committee on Rules and Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–69, title I, § 1</ref>, <date date="1993-08-11">Aug. 11, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6510.</num>
<heading> Materials, supplies, and fuel payments from Senate contingent fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments from the contingent fund of the Senate for materials and supplies (including fuel) purchased on and after <date date="1935-07-08">July 8, 1935</date>, through the Administrator of General Services shall be made by check upon vouchers approved by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 8, 1935, ch. 374</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 463</ref>; <ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title I, § 102, <ref>60 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>June 30, 1949, ch. 288</ref>, title I, § 102(a), <ref>63 Stat. 380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6511.</num>
<heading> Liquidation from appropriations of any unpaid obligations chargeable to rescinded unexpended balances of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If at the close of any fiscal year there is an unexpended balance of funds which were appropriated for such year (or for prior fiscal years) and which are subject to disbursement by the Secretary of the Senate for any purpose, then, if such unexpended balance is by law rescinded, any unpaid obligations chargeable to the balance so rescinded (or to appropriations for such purpose for prior years) shall be liquidated from any appropriations for the same general purpose, which, at the time of payment, are available for disbursement.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–257, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1982-09-10">Sept. 10, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 849</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6512.</num>
<heading> Expense allowance for Secretary of Senate, Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate, and Secretaries for Senate Majority and Minority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, there is hereby established an account, within the Senate, to be known as the “Expense Allowance for the Secretary of the Senate, Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate and Secretaries for the Majority and for the Minority, of the Senate” (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Expense Allowance”). For each fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>) there shall be available from the Expense Allowance an expense allotment not to exceed $6,000 for each of the above specified officers. Amounts paid from the expense allotment of any such officer shall be paid to him only as reimbursement for actual expenses incurred by him and upon certification and documentation by him of such expenses. Amounts paid to any such officer pursuant to this section shall not be reported as income and shall not be allowed as a deduction under title 26.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, and the succeeding fiscal year, the Secretary of the Senate shall transfer, for each such year, $8,000 to the Expense Allowance from “Miscellaneous Items” in the contingent fund of the Senate. For the fiscal year ending <date date="1983-09-30">September 30, 1983</date>, and for each fiscal year thereafter, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Expense Allowance such funds as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–51, § 119</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 964</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–63, title I</ref>, <date date="1983-07-30">July 30, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 334</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1013</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6513.</num>
<heading> Per diem and subsistence expenses from Senate contingent fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No part of the appropriations made under the heading “Contingent Expenses of the Senate” on and after <date date="1956-06-27">June 27, 1956</date> may be expended for per diem and subsistence expenses (as defined in <ref>section 5701 of title 5</ref>) at rates in excess of the rates prescribed by the Committee on Rules and Administration; except that (1) higher rates may be established by the Committee on Rules and Administration for travel beyond the limits of the continental United States, and (2) in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, reimbursement for such expenses may be made on an actual expense basis of not to exceed the daily rate prescribed by the Committee on Rules and Administration in the case of travel within the continental limits of the United States. This section shall not apply with respect to per diem or actual travel expenses incurred by Senators and employees in the office of a Senator which are reimbursed under <ref>section 6314 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 27, 1956, ch. 453</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–139, § 7</ref>, <date date="1961-08-14">Aug. 14, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 340</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–114, § 3</ref>, <date date="1969-11-10">Nov. 10, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 190</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–22, § 8</ref>, <date date="1975-05-19">May 19, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 86</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 112(e)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–355, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1978-09-08">Sept. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 533</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–304, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-07-08">July 8, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 889</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6514.</num>
<heading> Orientation seminars, etc., for new Senators, Senate officials, or members of staffs of Senators or Senate officials; payment of expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, there is authorized an expense allowance for the Office of the Secretary of the Senate and the Office of Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate which shall not exceed $30,000 each fiscal year for each such office. Payments made under this section shall be reimbursements only for actual expenses (including meals and food-related expenses) incurred in the course of conducting orientation seminars for Senators, Senate officials, or members of the staffs of Senators or Senate officials and other similar meetings, in the Capitol Building or the Senate Office Buildings. Such payments shall be made upon certification and documentation of such expenses by the Secretary and Sergeant at Arms, respectively, and shall be made out of the contingent fund of the Senate upon vouchers signed by the Secretary and the Sergeant at Arms, respectively. Amounts received as reimbursement of such expenses shall not be reported as income, and the expenses so reimbursed shall not be allowed as a deduction, under title 26.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–38, title I, § 107(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-25">July 25, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 112</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–88, title I, § 193</ref>, <date date="1985-08-15">Aug. 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(i) [title I, § 6]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329–290</ref>, 1329–294; <ref>Pub. L. 102–392, title I, § 3</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 4</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1013</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6515.</num>
<heading> Payment of fees for services of Attending Physician and for use of Senate health and fitness facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Senate Committee on Rules and Administration shall promulgate regulations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pertaining to the services provided by the Attending Physician and the operation and use of the Senate health and fitness facilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> requiring the payment of fees for services received from the Attending Physician and for the use of the Senate health and fitness facilities pursuant to such regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding of fees from salary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to withhold fees from the salary of an individual authorized by such regulations to receive such services from the Attending Physician and to use the Senate health and fitness facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit in General Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate shall remit all fees required by subsection (a)(2) that are collected pursuant to subsection (b) or by direct payment to the General Fund of the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts unless otherwise provided by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provision <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002119">1</ref> of this section shall take effect on <date date="1992-04-09">April 9, 1992</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–392, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1723</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6516.</num>
<heading> Sale of waste paper and condemned furniture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the Secretary and Sergeant at Arms of the Senate to cause to be sold all waste paper and useless documents and condemned furniture that may accumulate, in their respective departments or offices, under the direction of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and cover the proceeds thereof into the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 7, 1882, ch. 433, § 1</ref>, <ref>22 Stat. 337</ref>; <ref>May 29, 1928, ch. 901, § 1(122)</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 995</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(62)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1739</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6517.</num>
<heading> Receipts from sale of used or surplus furniture and furnishings of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>, receipts from the sale of used or surplus furniture and furnishings shall be deposited in the United States Treasury for credit to the appropriation for “Senate Office Buildings” under the heading “Architect of the Capitol.”</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–276, § 101(e)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-02">Oct. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6518.</num>
<heading> Workers compensation payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Available balances of expired appropriations which are subject to disbursement by the Secretary of the Senate shall be available to the Secretary of the Senate to make the deposit to the credit of the Employees’ Compensation Fund required by <ref>section 8147(b) of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to appropriations for fiscal year 2014, and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. I, title I, § 1</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 420</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6519.</num>
<heading> McCain-Mansfield and SFC Sean Cooley and SPC Christopher Horton Congressional Gold Star Family Fellowships Programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “appropriate committees of the Senate” means the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Fellowships Programs” means the SFC Sean Cooley and SPC Christopher Horton Congressional Gold Star Family Fellowship Program (commonly referred to as the “Green and Gold Congressional Aide Program”) established under Senate Resolution 442 (117th Congress), agreed to <date date="2021-11-04">November 4, 2021</date>, and the McCain-Mansfield Fellowship Program established under Senate Resolution 443 (117th Congress), agreed to <date date="2021-11-04">November 4, 2021</date>, or any successor program to such programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “Fund” means the Sergeant at Arms Fellowships Fund established under subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “Sergeant at Arms” means the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">Contingent Expenses of the Senate</inline>” an account to be known as the “<inline class="small-caps">sergeant at arms fellowships fund</inline>”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts in the Fund shall be available to the Sergeant at Arms for the costs of compensation of fellows under the Fellowships Programs and the administration of the Fellowships Programs, except as provided in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency contributions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Agency contributions for the Fellowships Programs shall be paid from the appropriations account for “Salaries, Officers and Employees” of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oversight</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms shall provide to the appropriate committees of the Senate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a plan regarding the administration of the Fund by the Sergeant at Arms prior to obligation of any funds, to be updated and resubmitted following any changes to the plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> annual reports regarding the costs of the Fellowships Programs paid from the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Fund for fiscal year 2023, and each fiscal year thereafter, such sums as are necessary for the compensation of fellows under the Fellowships Programs during the fiscal year and for the administration of the Fellowships Programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion for purposes of staffing limits on the Office of the Sergeant at Arms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The payment of compensation to any individual serving in a fellowship under the Fellowships Programs by the Sergeant at Arms shall not be included for purposes of any limitation on staffing levels of the Office of the Sergeant at Arms.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. I, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4917</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>SECRETARY OF THE SENATE</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Organization and Personnel</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6531.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(H)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2776</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6532.</num>
<heading> Death, resignation, or disability of Secretary and Assistant Secretary of Senate; Financial Clerk deemed successor as disbursing officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For any period during which both the Secretary and the Assistant Secretary of the Senate are unable (because of death, resignation, or disability) to discharge such Secretary’s duties as disbursing officer of the Senate, the Financial Clerk of the Senate shall be deemed to be the successor of such Secretary as disbursing officer.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1926, ch. 44, § 1</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 162</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–105, § 2</ref>, <date date="1969-10-31">Oct. 31, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 169</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–382</ref>, <date date="1970-08-18">Aug. 18, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 810</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 220(g)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 204</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 474</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6533.</num>
<heading> Death, resignation, or disability of Secretary of Senate; Assistant Secretary of Senate to act as Secretary; written designation of absent status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the event of the death, resignation, or disability of the Secretary of the Senate, the Assistant Secretary of the Senate shall act as Secretary in carrying out the duties and responsibilities of that office in all matters until such time as a new Secretary shall have been elected and qualified or such disability shall have been ended. For purposes of this section and <ref>section 6532 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the Senate shall be considered as disabled only during such period of time as the Majority and Minority Leaders and the President pro tempore of the Senate certify jointly to the Senate that the Secretary is unable to perform his duties. In the event that the Secretary of the Senate is absent or is to be absent for reasons other than disability (as provided in this section), and makes a written designation that he is or will be so absent, the Assistant Secretary shall act during such absence as the Secretary in carrying out the duties and responsibilities of the office in all matters. The designation may be revoked in writing at any time by the Secretary, and is revoked whenever the Secretary making the designation dies, resigns, or is considered disabled in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–184</ref>, ch. IV, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 635</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–371, § 1</ref>, <date date="1974-08-13">Aug. 13, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 427</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 474</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6534.</num>
<heading> Compensation of Assistant Secretary of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary of the Senate may be paid at a maximum annual rate of compensation not to exceed $39,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–145</ref>, <date date="1969-12-12">Dec. 12, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 340</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–371, § 4</ref>, <date date="1974-08-13">Aug. 13, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–59, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6535.</num>
<heading> Compensation of Parliamentarian of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Parliamentarian of the Senate may be paid at a maximum annual rate of compensation not to exceed $39,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 5, 1955, ch. 568</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref>June 27, 1956, ch. 453</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–371, § 4</ref>, <date date="1974-08-13">Aug. 13, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–59, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6536.</num>
<heading> Compensation of Financial Clerk of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Financial Clerk of the Senate may be paid at a maximum annual rate of compensation not to exceed $39,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–371, § 4</ref>, <date date="1974-08-13">Aug. 13, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–59, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6537.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2775</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6538.</num>
<heading> Employment of additional administrative assistants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to employ such administrative assistants as may be necessary in order to carry out the provisions of this Act under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title II, § 244, <ref>60 Stat. 839</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(18)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1732</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6539.</num>
<heading> Abolition of statutory positions in Office of Secretary of Senate; Secretary’s authority to establish and fix compensation for positions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, all statutory positions in the Office of the Secretary (other than the positions of the Secretary of the Senate, Assistant Secretary of the Senate, Parliamentarian, Financial Clerk, and Director of the Office of Classified National Security Information) are abolished, and in lieu of the positions hereby abolished the Secretary of the Senate is authorized to establish such number of positions as he deems appropriate and appoint and fix the compensation of employees to fill the positions so established; except that the annual rate of compensation payable to any employee appointed to fill any position established by the Secretary of the Senate shall not, for any period of time, be in excess of $1,000 less than the annual rate of compensation of the Secretary of the Senate for that period of time; and except that nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any position authorized by statute, if the compensation for such position is to be paid from the contingent fund of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–51, § 114</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 963</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6540.</num>
<heading> Adjustment of rate of compensation by Secretary of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any specific rate of compensation established by law, as such rate has been increased or may hereafter be increased by or pursuant to law, for any position under the jurisdiction of the Secretary shall be considered as the maximum rate of compensation for that position, and the Secretary is authorized to adjust the rate of compensation of an individual occupying any such position to a rate not exceeding such maximum rate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–382</ref>, <date date="1970-08-18">Aug. 18, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 808</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6541.</num>
<heading> Professional archivist; Secretary’s authority to obtain services from General Services Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each fiscal year (beginning with the fiscal year which ends <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>), the Secretary of the Senate is authorized to expend from the contingent fund of the Senate such amount as may be necessary to enable the Secretary to obtain from the General Services Administration the services of a professional archivist. Such services shall be obtained on a reimbursable basis and shall not be obtained except with the consent of the General Services Administration and the Committee on Rules and Administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–92, title I, § 125</ref>, <date date="1981-12-15">Dec. 15, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1198</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6542.</num>
<heading> Employees of Senate Disbursing Office; designation by Secretary of Senate to administer oaths and affirmations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is on and after <date date="1973-11-01">November 1, 1973</date>, authorized to designate, in writing, employees of the Disbursing Office of the Senate to administer oaths and affirmations, with respect to matters relating to that Office, authorized or required by law or rules or orders of the Senate (including the oath of office required by <ref>section 3331 of title 5</ref>). During any period in which he is so designated, any such employee may administer such oaths and affirmations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–145</ref>, <date date="1973-11-01">Nov. 1, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 532</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6543.</num>
<heading> Designation of reporters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reporters of debates in the office of the Secretary of the Senate are hereby designated the official reporters of debates of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–545</ref>, <date date="1966-08-27">Aug. 27, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6544.</num>
<heading> Substitute reporters of debates and expert transcribers; temporary reporters of debates and expert transcribers; payments from Senate contingent fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is on and after <date date="1981-06-05">June 5, 1981</date>, authorized to employ, by contract or otherwise, substitute reporters of debates and expert transcribers at daily rates of compensation, or temporary reporters of debates and expert transcribers at annual rates of compensation; no temporary reporters of debates or expert transcribers may be employed under authority of this provision for more than ninety days in any fiscal year; and payments made under authority of this section shall be made from the contingent fund of the Senate upon vouchers approved by the Secretary of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–90</ref>, <date date="1965-07-27">July 27, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 266</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–12, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1981-06-05">June 5, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 61</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">General Powers and Duties</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6561.</num>
<heading> Advance payments by Secretary of Senate</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For fiscal year 1998, and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary of the Senate is authorized to make advance payments under a contract or other agreement to provide a service or deliver an article for the United States Government without regard to the provisions of <ref>section 3324 of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An advance payment authorized by subsection (a) shall be made in accordance with regulations issued by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority granted by subsection (a) shall not take effect until regulations are issued pursuant to subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title I, § 1</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1179</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6562.</num>
<heading> Transfers of funds by Secretary of Senate; approval of Committee on Appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During any fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year beginning <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>) the Secretary of the Senate is authorized to make such transfers between appropriations of funds available for disbursement by him during such year, subject to the approval of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–276, § 101(e)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-02">Oct. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6563.</num>
<heading> Payment of certain expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the approval of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, if in any fiscal year amounts in any appropriations account under the heading “SENATE” under the heading “LEGISLATIVE BRANCH” are available for more than 1 fiscal year, the Secretary of the Senate may establish procedures for the payment of expenses with respect to that account from any amounts available for that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2012 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. G, title I, § 1</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1118</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6564.</num>
<heading> Travel expenses of Secretary of Senate; advancement of travel funds to designated employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out his duties, the Secretary of the Senate is authorized to incur official travel expenses. The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to advance, in his discretion, to any designated employee under his jurisdiction, such sums as may be necessary, not exceeding $1,000, to defray official travel expenses in assisting the Secretary in carrying out his duties. Any such employee shall, as soon as practicable, furnish to the Secretary a detailed voucher for such expenses incurred and make settlement with respect to any amount so advanced. Payments to carry out the provisions of this section shall be made from funds included in the appropriation “Miscellaneous Items” under the heading “Contingent Expenses of the Senate” upon vouchers approved by the Secretary of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–59, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–355, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1978-09-08">Sept. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 533</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–12, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1981-06-05">June 5, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 61</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 1</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 474</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6565.</num>
<heading> Advancement by Secretary of Senate of travel funds to employees under his jurisdiction for Federal Election Campaign Act travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is hereafter authorized to advance, in his discretion, to any designated employee under his jurisdiction, such sums as may be necessary, not exceeding $1,500, to defray official travel expenses in assisting the Secretary in carrying out his duties under the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 [<ref>52 U.S.C. 30101</ref> et seq.]. Any such employee shall, as soon as practicable, furnish to the Secretary a detailed voucher for such expenses incurred and make settlement with respect to any amount so advanced.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–607</ref>, ch. V, § 504, <date date="1972-10-31">Oct. 31, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1505</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6566.</num>
<heading> Authority to procure technical support and other services and incur travel expenses; payment of such expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out his duties under the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 [<ref>52 U.S.C. 30101</ref> et seq.], the Secretary of the Senate is authorized, from and after <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>, (1) to procure technical support services, (2) to procure the temporary or intermittent services of individual technicians, experts, or consultants, or organizations thereof, in the same manner and under the same conditions, to the extent applicable, as a standing committee of the Senate may procure such services under <ref>section 4301(i) of this title</ref>, (3) with the prior consent of the Government department or agency concerned and the Committee on Rules and Administration, to use on a reimbursable basis the services of personnel of any such department or agency, and (4) to incur official travel expenses. Payments to carry out the provisions of this paragraph shall be made from funds included in the appropriation “Miscellaneous Items” under the heading “Contingent Expenses of the Senate” upon vouchers approved by the Secretary of the Senate. All sums received by the Secretary under authority of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–342, § 101</ref>, <date date="1972-07-10">July 10, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 435</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6567.</num>
<heading> Funds for Secretary of Senate to assist in proper discharge within United States of responsibilities to foreign parliamentary groups or other foreign officials</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1987-07-11">July 11, 1987</date>, the Secretary of the Senate is authorized to use any available funds (but not in excess of $50,000 for any fiscal year), out of the appropriation account (within the Contingent Fund of the Senate) for the Secretary of the Senate, to assist him in the proper discharge, within the United States, of his appropriate responsibilities to members of foreign parliamentary groups or other foreign officials.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of subsection (a) shall be effective in the case of expenditures for fiscal years ending after <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the written request of the Secretary of the Senate, and upon notification to the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, there shall be transferred any amount of funds available under subsection (a) specified in the request, but not to exceed $15,000 in any fiscal year, from the appropriation account (within the contingent fund of the Senate) for expenses of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate to the appropriation account for the expense allowance of the Secretary of the Senate. Any funds so transferred shall be available in like manner and for the same purposes as are other funds in the account to which the funds are transferred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–71, title I, § 2</ref>, <date date="1987-07-11">July 11, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 423</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–90, title I, § 4</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–18, title II, § 7003(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-06-12">June 12, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 192</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 6</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XV, § 1501</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6568.</num>
<heading> Banking and financial transactions of Secretary of Senate</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement of banks for costs of clearing items for Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to reimburse any bank which clears items for the United States Senate for the costs incurred therein. Such reimbursements shall be made from the contingent fund of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Check cashing regulations for Disbursing Office of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to prescribe such regulations as he deems necessary to govern the cashing of personal checks by the Disbursing Office of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts withheld from disbursements for employee indebtedness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever an employee whose compensation is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate becomes indebted to the Senate and such employee fails to pay such indebtedness, the Secretary of the Senate is authorized to withhold the amount of the indebtedness from any amount which is disbursed by him and which is due to, or on behalf of, such employee. Whenever an amount is withheld under this section, the appropriate account shall be credited in an amount equal to the amount so withheld.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–440, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1976-10-01">Oct. 1, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1443</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 6569 to 6571.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2525</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6572.</num>
<heading> Purchases of stationery and materials for folding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Purchases of stationery and materials for folding shall be made in accordance with <ref>section 4104 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p class="indent0">All contracts and bonds for purchases made under the authority of this section shall be filed with the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1887, ch. 392, § 1</ref>, <ref>24 Stat. 596</ref>; <ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title I, § 102, <ref>60 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(58)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1738</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2525</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6573.</num>
<heading> Senate revolving fund for stationery allowances; availability of unexpended balances; withdrawals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Contingent Fund of the Senate a revolving fund which shall consist of (1) the unexpended balance of the appropriation “Contingent Expenses, Senate, Stationery, fiscal year 1957”, (2) any amounts hereafter appropriated for stationery allowances of the President of the Senate, and for stationery for use of officers of the Senate and the Conference of the Majority and the Conference of the Minority of the Senate, and (3) any undeposited amounts heretofore received, and any amounts hereafter received as proceeds of sales by the stationery room of the Senate. Any moneys in the fund shall be available until expended for use in the same manner and for the same purposes as funds heretofore appropriated to the Contingent Fund of the Senate for stationery, except that (1) the balance of any amount appropriated for stationery for use of committees and officers of the Senate which remains unexpended at the end of any fiscal year and (2) allowances which are not available for obligation due to vacancies or waiver of entitlement thereto, shall be withdrawn from the revolving fund. Disbursements from the fund shall be made upon vouchers approved by the Secretary of the Senate, or his designee.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–58</ref>, ch. XI, <date date="1957-06-21">June 21, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 188</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–607</ref>, ch. V, § 506(<i>l</i>), formerly § 506(i), <date date="1972-10-31">Oct. 31, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1508</ref>, renumbered § 506(j), <ref>Pub. L. 95–391, title I, § 108(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 773</ref>, renumbered § 506(k) and amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–304, title I</ref>, §§ 101, 112(b)(3), <date date="1980-07-08">July 8, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 889</ref>, 892, renumbered § 506(<i>l</i>), <ref>Pub. L. 97–276, § 101(e)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-02">Oct. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1189</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title I, § 7</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6574.</num>
<heading> Senate Office of Public Records Revolving Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund within the contingent fund of the Senate to be known as the “Senate Office of Public Records Revolving Fund” (hereafter in this section referred to as the “revolving fund”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Source of moneys for deposit in Fund; availability of moneys in Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All moneys received on and after <date date="1989-10-01">October 1, 1989</date>, by the Senate Office of Public Records from fees and other charges for services shall be deposited to the credit of the revolving fund. Moneys in the revolving fund shall be available without fiscal year limitation for disbursement by the Secretary of the Senate for use in connection with the operation of the Senate Office of Public Records, including supplies, equipment, and other expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vouchers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Disbursements from the revolving fund shall be made upon vouchers approved by the Secretary of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of moneys into Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To provide capital for the revolving fund, the Secretary of the Senate is authorized to transfer, from moneys appropriated for fiscal year 1990 to the account “Miscellaneous Items” in the contingent fund of the Senate, to the revolving fund such sum as he may determine necessary, not to exceed $30,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title I, § 13</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1047</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6575.</num>
<heading> Fees for copies from Senate journals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is entitled, for transcribing and certifying extracts from the journal of the Senate or the executive Journal of the Senate when the injunction of secrecy has been removed, except when such transcripts are required by an officer of the United States in a matter relating to the duties of his office, to receive from the persons for whom such transcripts are prepared the sum of 10 cents for each sheet containing one hundred words.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 71; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(61)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6576.</num>
<heading> Senate Gift Shop</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to establish a Senate Gift Shop for the purpose of providing for the sale of gift items to Members of the Senate, staff, and the general public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of receipts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All moneys received from sales and other services by the Senate Gift Shop shall be deposited in the revolving fund established by subsection (c) and shall be available for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revolving fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund within the contingent fund of the Senate to be known as the Senate Gift Shop Revolving Fund (hereafter referred to in this section as the “fund”). The fund shall consist of all amounts collected or received by the Secretary of the Senate from sales and services by the Senate Gift Shop. All moneys in the fund shall be available without fiscal year limitation for disbursement by the Secretary of the Senate in connection with the operation of the Senate Gift Shop, including supplies, equipment, and other expenses. In addition, such moneys may be used by the Secretary of the Senate to reimburse the Senate appropriations account, appropriated under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">Salaries, Officers and Employees</inline>” and “<inline class="small-caps">Office of the Secretary</inline>”, for amounts used from such account to pay the salaries of employees of the Senate Gift Shop.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Senate may transfer from the fund to the Capitol Preservation Fund the net profits (as determined by the Secretary) from sales of items by the Senate Gift Shop which are intended to benefit the Capitol Visitor Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Senate may transfer from the fund to the Senate Employee Child Care Center proceeds from the sale of holiday ornaments by the Senate Gift Shop for the purpose of funding necessary activities and expenses of the Center, including scholarships, educational supplies, and equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception to prohibition of sale or solicitation on Capitol Grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of <ref>section 5104(c) of title 40</ref> shall not be applicable to any activity carried out pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of moneys from Stationery Revolving Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To provide capital for the fund, the Secretary of the Senate is authorized to transfer, from moneys in the Stationery Revolving Fund in the contingent fund of the Senate, to the fund such sum as he may determine necessary, not to exceed $300,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization to expend from appropriations account for initial expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of acquiring supplies, equipment, and meeting other initial expenses in implementing subsection (a), the Secretary of the Senate is authorized, upon <date date="1992-10-06">October 6, 1992</date>, to expend, from moneys appropriated to the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for expenses of the Secretary of the Senate, by the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991, such amounts as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disbursement on approved voucher</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Disbursements from the fund shall be made upon vouchers approved by the Secretary of the Senate, or his designee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–392, title I, § 2</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 107(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–39, § 1</ref>, <date date="2007-06-21">June 21, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 231</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6577.</num>
<heading> Senate legislative information system</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development and implementation by Secretary of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate, with the oversight and approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, shall oversee the development and implementation of a comprehensive Senate legislative information system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperative effort</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the Secretary of the Senate shall consult and work with officers and employees of the House of Representatives. Legislative branch agencies and departments and agencies of the executive branch shall provide cooperation, consultation, and assistance as requested by the Secretary of the Senate to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any funds that were appropriated under the heading “Secretary of the Senate” for expenses of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate by the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1995, to remain available until <date date="1998-09-30">September 30, 1998</date>, and that the Secretary determines are not needed for development of a financial management system for the Senate may, with the approval of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, be used to carry out the provisions of this section, and such funds shall be available through <date date="2000-09-30">September 30, 2000</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall be effective for fiscal years beginning on or after <date date="1996-10-01">October 1, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title I, § 8</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6578.</num>
<heading> Senate Leader’s Lecture Series</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the Senate Leader’s Lecture Series (hereinafter referred to as the “lecture series”). Expenses incurred in connection with the lecture series shall be paid from the appropriations account “Secretary of the Senate” within the contingent fund of the Senate and shall not exceed $30,000 in any fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenses covered</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments for expenses in connection with the lecture series may cover expenses incurred by speakers, including travel, subsistence, and per diem, and the cost of receptions, including food, food related items, and hospitality.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments for expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments for expenses of the lecture series shall be made on vouchers approved by the Secretary of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section is effective on and after <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 5</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>SERGEANT AT ARMS AND DOORKEEPER OF SENATE</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Organization and Personnel</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6591.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(H)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2776</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6592.</num>
<heading> Limitation on compensation of Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate shall receive, directly or indirectly, no fees or other compensation or emolument whatever for performing the duties of the office, or in connection therewith, other than the salary prescribed by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 20, 1874, ch. 328</ref>, <ref>18 Stat. 85</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6593.</num>
<heading> Deputy Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper to act on death, resignation, disability, or absence of Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the event of the death, resignation, or disability of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, the Deputy Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper shall act as Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate in carrying out the duties and responsibilities of that office in all matters until such time as a new Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate shall have been elected and qualified or such disability shall have been ended. For purposes of this section, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate shall be considered as disabled only during such period of time as the Majority and Minority Leaders and the President Pro Tempore of the Senate certify jointly to the Senate that the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is unable to perform his duties. In the event that the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is absent, the Deputy Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper shall act during such absence as the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate in carrying out the duties and responsibilities of the office in all matters.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–51, § 128</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6594.</num>
<heading> Compensation of Deputy Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1979-08-01">August 1, 1979</date>, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper may fix the compensation of the Deputy Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper at an annual rate not to exceed the maximum annual rate of compensation of the Assistant Secretary of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–226, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-03-09">Mar. 9, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 203</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–38, title I, § 106(1)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-25">July 25, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 112</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6595.</num>
<heading> Compensation of Administrative Assistant to Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Effective <date date="1979-08-01">August 1, 1979</date>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the maximum annual rate of compensation of the Administrative Assistant to the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate shall be the same as the highest maximum annual rate of compensation that may be paid to an employee in the office of a Senator; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Omitted</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–38, title I, § 106(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1979-07-25">July 25, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 112</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6596.</num>
<heading> Employment of personnel by Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate at daily rates of compensation; authorization; limitation on amount of compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, in carrying out the duties of his office, is authorized to employ personnel at daily rates of compensation; no individual so employed shall be paid at a daily rate of compensation which is in excess of the per diem equivalent of the highest gross rate of annual compensation which may be paid to employees of a standing committee of the Senate; and payments under authority of this section shall be made from the account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”, upon vouchers approved by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 6</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 475</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6597.</num>
<heading> Abolition of statutory positions in Office of Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate; authority to establish and fix compensation for positions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, all statutory positions in the Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate (other than the positions of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, Deputy Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper, and Administrative Assistant) are abolished, and in lieu of the positions hereby abolished the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to establish such number of positions as he deems appropriate and appoint and fix the compensation of employees to fill the positions so established; except that the annual rate of compensation payable to any employee appointed to fill any position established by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate shall not, for any period of time, be in excess of $1,000 less than the annual rate of compensation of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate for that period of time; and except that nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any position authorized by statute, if the compensation for such position is to be paid from the contingent fund of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–51, § 116</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 963</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6598.</num>
<heading> Designation by Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate of persons to approve vouchers for payment of moneys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Sergeant at Arms”) may designate one or more employees in the Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate to approve, on his behalf, any voucher for payment of moneys, payroll action, or personnel action which the Sergeant at Arms is authorized to approve. Whenever the Sergeant at Arms makes a designation under the authority of the preceding sentence, he shall immediately notify the Committee on Rules and Administration in writing of the designation, and thereafter any approval of any voucher for payment of moneys, payroll action, or personnel action by an employee so designated shall (until such designation is revoked and the Sergeant at Arms notifies the Committee on Rules and Administration in writing of the revocation) be deemed and held to be approved by the Sergeant at Arms for all intents and purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–181, title I, § 1201</ref>, <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–344, § 1</ref>, <date date="2021-01-13">Jan. 13, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 5141</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6599.</num>
<heading> Use by Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate of individual consultants or organizations, and department and agency personnel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For each fiscal year (beginning with the fiscal year which ends <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>), the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is hereby authorized to expend from the account for the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, within the contingent fund of the Senate, an amount not to exceed $300,000:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the procurement of the services, on a temporary basis, of individual consultants, or organizations thereof, with the prior consent of the Committee on Rules and Administration; such services may be procured by contract with the providers acting as independent contractors, or in the case of individuals, by employment at daily rates of compensation not in excess of the per diem equivalent of the highest gross rate of annual compensation which may be paid to employees of a standing committee of the Senate; and any such contract shall not be subject to the provisions of <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref> or any other provision of law requiring advertising; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with the prior consent of the Government department or agency concerned and the Committee on Rules and Administration, use on a reimbursable basis (with reimbursement payable at the end of each calendar quarter for services rendered during such quarter) of the services of personnel of any such department or agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Payments made under this section shall be made upon vouchers approved by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–51, § 117</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 964</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–257, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1982-09-10">Sept. 10, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 849</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 7</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–458, title I, § 7</ref>, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2162</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">General Powers and Duties</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6611.</num>
<heading> Transfer authority and Sergeant at Arms Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized, with the approval of the Senate Committee on Appropriations, to transfer, during any fiscal year, from the appropriations account, appropriated under the headings “Salaries, Officers and Employees” and “Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper”, such sums as he shall specify to the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for expenses of the Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate; and any funds so transferred shall be available in like manner and for the same purposes as are other funds in the account to which the funds are transferred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sergeant at Arms Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “Fund” means the Sergeant at Arms Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery Fund established under paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “Sergeant at Arms” means the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">Contingent Expenses of the Senate</inline>” an account to be known as the “Sergeant at Arms Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery Fund”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts in the Fund shall be available to the Sergeant at Arms for purposes of the business continuity and disaster recovery needs of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to transfer</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (C), prior to the date of the withdrawal of amounts appropriated under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">Contingent Expenses of the Senate—sergeant at arms and doorkeeper of the senate</inline>” in accordance with <ref>section 4107 of this title</ref>, any unobligated balances of expired discretionary appropriations of such amounts may be transferred by the Sergeant at Arms to the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Amounts transferred under subparagraph (A) shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Sergeant at Arms intends to transfer amounts under subparagraph (A), the Sergeant at Arms shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate written notice not later than 15 days before the date of the withdrawal of such amounts in accordance with <ref>section 4107 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The authority to transfer amounts under this paragraph shall apply with respect to amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2022, or any fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Fund such sums as are necessary for fiscal year 2022 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title I, § 5</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2258</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. I, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 505</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6612.</num>
<heading> Travel expenses of Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out his duties, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to incur official travel expenses during each fiscal year not to exceed the sums made available for such purpose under appropriations Acts. With the approval of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate and in accordance with such regulations as may be promulgated by the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, the Secretary of the Senate is authorized to advance to the Sergeant at Arms or to any designated employee under the jurisdiction of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper, such sums as may be necessary to defray official travel expenses incurred in carrying out the duties of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper. The receipt of any such sum so advanced to the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper or to any designated employee shall be taken and passed by the accounting officers of the Government as a full and sufficient voucher; but it shall be the duty of the traveler, as soon as practicable, to furnish to the Secretary of the Senate a detailed voucher of the expenses incurred for the travel with respect to which the sum was so advanced, and make settlement with respect to such sum. Payments under this section shall be made from funds included in the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, upon vouchers approved by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–303, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="1976-06-01">June 1, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 615</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–391, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–86, § 111(c)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-12">Oct. 12, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–12, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1981-06-05">June 5, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 62</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–458, title I, § 6</ref>, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2161</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title I, § 6</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6613.</num>
<heading> Advances to Sergeant at Arms of Senate for extraordinary expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate on and after <date date="1958-07-31">July 31, 1958</date>, is authorized, in his discretion, to advance to the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate such sums as may be necessary, not exceeding $4,000, to meet any extraordinary expenses of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–570</ref>, <date date="1958-07-31">July 31, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–440, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1976-10-01">Oct. 1, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1445</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–26, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1977-05-04">May 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 82</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6614.</num>
<heading> Funds advanced by Secretary of Senate to Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate to defray office expenses; accountability; maximum amount; vouchers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From funds available for any fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>), the Secretary of the Senate shall advance to the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate for the purpose of defraying office expenses such sums (for which the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper shall be accountable) not in excess of $1,000 at any one time, as such Sergeant at Arms shall from time to time request; except that the aggregate of the sums so advanced during the fiscal year shall not exceed $10,000.</p>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with the provisions of this section, a detailed voucher shall be submitted to the Secretary of the Senate by such Sergeant at Arms whenever necessary, in order to replenish funds expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–51, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1983-07-14">July 14, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6615.</num>
<heading> Deposit of moneys for credit to account within Senate contingent fund for “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any provision of law which is enacted prior to <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, and which directs the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate to deposit any moneys in the United States Treasury for credit to the account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for “Miscellaneous Items”, or for “Automobiles and Maintenance” shall, on and after <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, be deemed to direct him to deposit such moneys in the United States Treasury for credit to the account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–181, title I, § 1202</ref>, <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1289</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6616.</num>
<heading> Support services for Senate during emergency; memorandum of understanding with an executive agency</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subject to paragraph (3), the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate and the head of an executive agency (as defined in <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref>) may enter into a memorandum of understanding under which the agency may provide facilities, equipment, supplies, personnel, and other support services for the use of the Senate during an emergency situation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate and the head of the agency may take any action necessary to carry out the terms of the memorandum of understanding; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate may enter into a memorandum of understanding described in paragraph (1) consistent with the Senate Procurement Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Obligations and expenditures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms of the Senate may incur obligations and make expenditures for meals, refreshments, and other support and maintenance for Members, officers, and employees of the Senate when such obligations and expenditures are necessary to respond to emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2002 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–117, div. B, § 902</ref>, <date date="2002-01-10">Jan. 10, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2316</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XV, § 1502</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6617.</num>
<heading> Law enforcement authority of Sergeant-at-Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant-at-Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate shall have the same law enforcement authority, including the authority to carry firearms, as a member of the Capitol Police. The law enforcement authority under the preceding sentence shall be subject to the requirement that the Sergeant-at-Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate have the qualifications specified in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The qualifications referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A minimum of 5 years of experience as a law enforcement officer before beginning service as the Sergeant-at-Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Current certification in the use of firearms by the appropriate Federal law enforcement entity or an equivalent non-Federal entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any other firearms qualification required for members of the Capitol Police.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate shall have authority to prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–145, § 8</ref>, <date date="2010-03-04">Mar. 4, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 56</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6618.</num>
<heading> Data processing equipment, software, and services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Sergeant at Arms, subject to the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration, is hereafter authorized to enter into multi-year contracts for data processing equipment, software, and services.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–32, title I</ref>, <date date="1975-06-12">June 12, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–26, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1977-05-04">May 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 82</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6619.</num>
<heading> Advance payments for computer programing services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, subject to the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration, is on and after <date date="1981-07-06">July 6, 1981</date>, authorized to enter into contracts which provide for the making of advance payments for computer programing services.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–20</ref>, <date date="1981-07-06">July 6, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 104</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6620.</num>
<heading> Provision of services and equipment on a reimbursable basis</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate may provide services and equipment funded by appropriations available to the Senate to persons and entities not funded by such appropriations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provision of services and equipment under subsection (a) shall be on a reimbursable basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Crediting of reimbursed amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of services or equipment provided under subsection (a) that were procured using amounts available to the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate in the account for Contingent Expenses, Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, amounts received under subsection (b) as reimbursement for the provision of such services or equipment shall be credited to that account or, if applicable, to any subaccount of that account. Amounts credited to any such account or subaccount shall be merged with amounts in that account or subaccount and shall be available to the same extent, and subject to the same terms and conditions, as amounts in that account or subaccount.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2004 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 9</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1013</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6621.</num>
<heading> Payment for telecommunications equipment and services; definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in sections 6621 to 6623 of this title, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Sergeant at Arms” means the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the United States Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “user” means any Senator, Officer of the Senate, Committee, office, or entity provided telephone equipment and services by the Sergeant at Arms.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–123, § 1</ref>, <date date="1987-10-05">Oct. 5, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 794</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6622.</num>
<heading> Certification of telecommunications equipment and services as official</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations issued by Committee on Rules and Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to such regulations as may hereafter be issued by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms shall have the authority, with respect to telephone equipment and services provided to any user on a reimbursable basis (including repair or replacement), solely for the purposes of this section, to make such certification as may be necessary to establish such services and equipment as official, issue invoices in conjunction therewith, and receive payment for such services and equipment by certification, voucher, or otherwise.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equipment and services provided on reimbursable basis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of sections 6621 to 6623 of this title, telephone equipment and services provided to any user for which payment, prior to <date date="1987-10-01">October 1, 1987</date>, was not authorized from the contingent fund of the Senate shall, on and after <date date="1987-10-01">October 1, 1987</date>, be considered telephone equipment and services provided on a reimbursable basis for which payment may be obtained from such fund in accordance with subsection (a) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of reasonable charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration, the Sergeant at Arms may establish reasonable charges for telephone equipment and services provided to any user which may be in addition to that regularly authorized by the Committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposition of moneys received</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All moneys, derived from payments for telephone equipment and services provided from funds from the Appropriation Account within the contingent fund of the Senate for “Contingent Expenses, Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate” under the line item for Telecommunications (including receipts from carriers and others for loss or damage to such services or equipment for which repair or replacement has been provided by the Sergeant at Arms), and all other moneys received by the Sergeant at Arms as charges or commissions for telephone services, shall be deposited in and made a part of such Appropriation Account and under such line item, and shall be available for expenditure or obligation, or both, in like manner and subject to the same limitations as any other moneys in such account and under such line item.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Committee authority to classify or reclassify equipment and services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in sections 6621 to 6623 of this title shall be construed as limiting or otherwise affecting the authority of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate to classify or reclassify telephone equipment and services provided to any user as equipment or services for which reimbursement may or may not be required.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–123, § 2</ref>, <date date="1987-10-05">Oct. 5, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 794</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title I, § 3</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1044</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6623.</num>
<heading> Report on telecommunications to Committee on Rules and Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms shall report to the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, at such time or times, and in such form and manner, as the Committee may direct, on expenditures made, and revenues received, pursuant to sections 6621 to 6623 of this title. It shall be the function of the Sergeant at Arms to advise the Committee, as soon as possible, of any dispute regarding payments to and from such Appropriation Account as related to the line item for Telecommunications, including any amounts due and unpaid by any user, if any such dispute has remained unresolved for a period of at least 60 days.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–123, § 3</ref>, <date date="1987-10-05">Oct. 5, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 795</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6624.</num>
<heading> Metered charges on copiers; “Sergeant at Arms” and “user” defined; certification of services and equipment as official; deposit of payments; availability for expenditure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Sergeant at Arms” means the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the United States Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “user” means any Senator, Officer of the Senate, Committee, office, or entity provided copiers by the Sergeant at Arms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to such regulations as may on and after <date date="1990-11-05">November 5, 1990</date>, be issued by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms shall have the authority, with respect to metered charges on copying equipment provided by the Sergeant at Arms, solely for the purposes of this section, to make such certification as may be necessary to establish such services and equipment as official, issue invoices in conjunction therewith, and receive payment for such services and equipment by certification, voucher, or otherwise.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> All moneys, derived from the payment of metered charges on copying equipment provided from funds from the Appropriation Account within the contingent fund of the Senate for “Contingent Expenses, Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate” under the line item for the Service Department, shall be deposited in and made a part of such Appropriation Account and under such line item, and shall be available for expenditure or obligation, or both, in like manner and subject to the same limitations as any other moneys in such account and under such line item.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title I, § 4(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6625.</num>
<heading> Receipts from sales of items by Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate, to Senators, etc., to be credited to appropriation from which purchased</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case in which appropriated funds are used by a Senator or a committee or office of the Senate to purchase from the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate items which were purchased by him from the appropriation for “miscellaneous items” under “Contingent Expenses of the Senate” in any appropriation Act, the amounts received by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States for credit to such appropriation. This section does not apply to amounts received from the sale of used or surplus furniture and equipment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–214</ref>, <date date="1980-03-24">Mar. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 122</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6626.</num>
<heading> Reimbursements to Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate for equipment provided to Senators, etc., which has been lost, stolen, damaged, or otherwise unaccounted for; deposit of receipts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate shall deposit in the United States Treasury for credit to the appropriation account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”, all moneys received by him as reimbursement for equipment provided to Senators, committee chairmen, and other officers and employees of the Senate, which has been lost, stolen, damaged, or otherwise unaccounted for.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 5</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 475</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6627.</num>
<heading> Compensation for lost or damaged property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amounts received by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate (in this section referred to as the “Sergeant at Arms”) for compensation for damage to, loss of, or loss of use of property of the Sergeant at Arms that was procured using amounts available to the Sergeant at Arms in the account for Contingent Expenses, Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, shall be credited to that account or, if applicable, to any subaccount of that account.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts credited to any account or subaccount under subsection (a) shall be merged with amounts in that account or subaccount and shall be available to the same extent, and subject to the same terms and conditions, as amounts in that account or subaccount.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2005 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 8</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3170</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6628.</num>
<heading> Treatment of electronic services provided by Sergeant at Arms</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “agent of the Office of the SAA” includes a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service commissioned or used through the Office of the SAA by a Senate office to provide such services to the Senate office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “electronic communication service” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2510 of title 18</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “Office of the SAA” means the Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “provider for a Senate office” means a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service directly commissioned or used by a Senate office to provide such services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “remote computing service” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2711 of title 18</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “Senate data”, with respect to a Senate office, means any electronic mail or other electronic or data communication, other data (including metadata), or other information of the Senate office; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the term “Senate office” means a committee or office of the Senate, including a Senator, an officer of the Senate, or an employee of, intern at, or other agent of a committee or office of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retaining possession</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A Senate office shall be deemed to retain possession of any Senate data of the Senate office, without regard to the use by the Senate office of any individual or entity described in paragraph (2) for the purposes of any function or service described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not be construed to limit the use by an intended recipient of any Senate data from a Senate office.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sergeant at Arms and providers for a Senate office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office of the SAA, any officer, employee, or agent of the Office of the SAA, and any provider for a Senate office shall not be treated as acquiring possession, custody, or control of any Senate data by reason of its being transmitted, processed, or stored (whether temporarily or otherwise) through the use of an electronic system established, maintained, or operated, or the use of electronic services provided, in whole or in part by the Office of the SAA, the officer, employee, or agent of the Office of the SAA, or the provider for the Senate office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law or rule of civil or criminal procedure, the Office of the SAA, any officer, employee, or agent of the Office of the SAA, and any provider for a Senate office that is providing services to or used by a Senate office shall not be barred, through operation of any court order or any statutory provision, from notifying the Senate office of any legal process seeking disclosure of Senate data of the Senate office that is transmitted, processed, or stored (whether temporarily or otherwise) through the use of an electronic system established, maintained, or operated, or the use of electronic services provided, in whole or in part by the Office of the SAA, the officer, employee, or agent of the Office of the SAA, or the provider for a Senate office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Motions to quash or modify</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon a motion made promptly by a Senate office or provider for a Senate office, a court of competent jurisdiction shall quash or modify any legal process directed to the provider for a Senate office if compliance with the legal process would require the disclosure of Senate data of the Senate office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information regarding implications of using providers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of the SAA, in consultation with the Senate Legal Counsel, shall provide information to each Senate office that commissions or uses a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service to provide such services to the Senate office regarding the potential constitutional implications and the potential impact on privileges that may be asserted by the Senate office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable privileges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit or supersede any applicable privilege, immunity, or other objection that may apply to the disclosure of Senate data.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in this section, any provision of law or rule of civil or criminal procedure of any State, political subdivision, or agency thereof, which is inconsistent with this section shall be deemed to be preempted and superseded.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2005 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 10</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–289, div. B, title II, § 20701(c)(1)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–5, § 2</ref>, <date date="2007-02-15">Feb. 15, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3134</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6629.</num>
<heading> Purchase, lease, exchange, maintenance, and operation of vehicles out of account for Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate within Senate contingent fund; authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>) there is authorized to be appropriated to the account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, such funds (which shall be in addition to funds authorized to be so appropriated for other purposes) as may be necessary for the purchase, lease, exchange, maintenance, and operation of vehicles as follows: one for the Vice President, one for the President pro tempore of the Senate, one for the Majority Leader of the Senate, one for the Minority Leader of the Senate, one for the Majority Whip of the Senate, one for the Minority Whip of the Senate, one for the attending physician, one as authorized by Senate Resolution 90 of the 100th Congress <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002120">1</ref> such number as is needed for carrying mails, and for official use of the offices of the Secretary of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, the Secretary for the Majority, and the Secretary for the Minority, and such additional number as is otherwise specifically authorized by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–88, title I, § 192</ref>, <date date="1985-08-15">Aug. 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(i) [title I, § 3(a)]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329–290</ref>, 1329–294.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6630.</num>
<heading> Disposal of used or surplus furniture and equipment by Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate; procedure; deposit of receipts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to dispose of used or surplus furniture and equipment by trade-in or by sale directly or through the General Services Administration. Receipts from the sale of such furniture and equipment shall be deposited in the United States Treasury for credit to the appropriation for “Miscellaneous Items” under the heading “Contingent Expenses of the Senate”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 660</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–51, § 118</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6631.</num>
<heading> Transfer of excess or surplus educationally useful equipment to public schools</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate may directly, or through the General Services Administration, transfer title to excess or surplus educationally useful equipment to a public school. Any such transfer shall be completed at the lowest possible cost to the public school and the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate shall prescribe regulations to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of receipts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Receipts from reimbursements for the costs of transfer of excess or surplus educationally useful equipment under this section,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002121">1</ref> shall be deposited in the United States Treasury for credit to the account for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate” within the contingent fund of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “public school” means a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002122">2</ref> elementary school or secondary school, as such terms are defined in <ref>section 7801 of title 20</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “educationally useful equipment” means computers and related peripheral tools, including printers, modems, routers, servers, computer keyboards, scanners, and other telecommunications and research equipment, that are appropriate for use in public school education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect beginning with fiscal year 1997 and shall be effective each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title I, § 5</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1076(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2091</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(yy)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6632.</num>
<heading> Disposal of used or surplus automobiles and trucks by Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate; procedure; deposit of receipts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to dispose of used or surplus automobiles and trucks by trade-in or by sale through the General Services Administration. Receipts from the sale of such automobiles and trucks shall be deposited in the United States Treasury for credit to the appropriation for “Automobiles and Maintenance” under the heading “Contingent Expenses of the Senate”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–276, § 101(e)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-02">Oct. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6633.</num>
<heading> Media support services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the terms “national committee” and “political party” have the meaning given such terms in <ref>section 30101 of title 52</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The official duties of employees of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate under the Senate Daily Press Gallery, the Senate Periodical Press Gallery, the Senate Press Photographers Gallery, and the Senate Radio and Television Correspondents Gallery may include providing media support services with respect to the presidential nominating conventions of the national committees of political parties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of Sergeant at Arms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The terms and conditions under which employees perform official duties under subsection (b) shall be subject to the approval of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 7</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6634.</num>
<heading> Senate Hair Care Services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation of personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of such employees as may be necessary to operate Senate Hair Care Services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of revolving fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States within the contingent fund of the Senate a revolving fund to be known as the Senate Hair Care Services Revolving Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “revolving fund”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit and availability of moneys</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> All moneys received by Senate Hair Care Services from fees for services or from any other source shall be deposited in the revolving fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Moneys in the revolving fund shall be available without fiscal year limitation for disbursement by the Secretary of the Senate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for the payment of salaries of employees of Senate Hair Care Services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for necessary supplies, equipment, and other expenses of Senate Hair Care Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The provisions of <ref>section 5104(c) of title 40</ref>, except for the provisions relating to solicitation, shall not apply to any activity carried out pursuant to this section, subject to approval of such activities by the Committee on Rules and Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002123">1</ref> Agency contributions for employees of Senate Hair Care Services shall be paid from the appropriations account for “<inline class="small-caps">Salaries, Officers and Employees</inline>”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disbursements upon vouchers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Disbursements from the revolving fund shall be made upon vouchers signed by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, except that vouchers shall not be required for the disbursement of salaries paid at an annual rate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excess moneys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the direction of the Committee on Rules and Administration, the Secretary of the Senate shall withdraw from the revolving fund and deposit in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts all moneys in the revolving fund that the Committee may determine are in excess of the current and reasonably foreseeable needs of Senate Hair Care Services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate are authorized to prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section, subject to the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of unobligated balances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is transferred to the revolving fund established by this section any unobligated balance in the fund established by <ref>section 121a of this title</ref> on the effective date of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall be effective on and after <date date="1998-10-01">October 1, 1998</date>, or 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-21">October 21, 1998</date>], whichever is later.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 6</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–57, title I, § 4</ref>, <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(2) [title I, § 3(a)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–96.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6635.</num>
<heading> Office of Senate Health Promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to establish an Office of Senate Health Promotion.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees, assessments, and charges</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In carrying out this section, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to establish, or provide for the establishment of, exercise classes and other health services and activities on a continuing and regular basis. In providing for such classes, services, and activities, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to impose and collect fees, assessments, and other charges to defray the costs involved in promoting the health of Members, officers, and employees of the Senate. For purposes of this section, the term “employees of the Senate” shall have such meaning as the Sergeant at Arms, by regulation, may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> All fees, assessments, and charges imposed and collected by the Sergeant at Arms pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be deposited in the revolving fund established pursuant to subsection (c) and shall be available for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Senate Health Promotion Revolving Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund within the contingent fund of the Senate to be known as the Senate Health Promotion Revolving Fund (hereinafter referred to in this section as the “fund”). The fund shall consist of all amounts collected or received by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate as fees, assessments, and other charges for activities and services to carry out the provisions of this section. All moneys in the fund shall be available without fiscal year limitation for disbursement by the Secretary of the Senate for promoting the health of Members, officers, and employees of the Senate. On or before December 31 of each year, the Secretary of the Senate shall withdraw from the fund and deposit in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts all moneys in excess of $5,000 in the fund at the close of the preceding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vouchers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Disbursements from the revolving fund shall be made upon vouchers signed by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inapplicability of provisions prohibiting sales, advertisements, or solicitations in Capitol grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of <ref>section 5104(c) of title 40</ref> shall not be applicable to any class, service, or other activity carried out pursuant to the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall be carried out in accordance with regulations which shall be promulgated by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate and subject to approval at the beginning of each Congress by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title I, § 4</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1044</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–90, title I, § 2</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 450</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6636.</num>
<heading> Senate Computer Center</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Senate Computer Center Revolving Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund within the contingent fund of the Senate to be known as the Senate Computer Center Revolving Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “revolving fund”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The revolving fund shall be available only for paying the salaries of personnel employed under subsection (c), and agency contributions attributable thereto, and for paying refunds under contracts entered into under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Within 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary of the Senate shall withdraw all amounts in the revolving fund in excess of $100,000, other than amounts required to make refunds under subsection (b)(2)(B), and shall deposit the amounts withdrawn in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts for use of Senate computer; approval; terms</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2), the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to enter into contracts with any agency or instrumentality of the legislative branch for the use of any available time on the Senate computer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> No contract may be entered into under paragraph (1) unless it has been approved by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, and no such contract may extend beyond the end of the fiscal year in which it is entered into. Each contract entered into under paragraph (1) shall contain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a provision requiring full advance payment for the amount of time contracted for, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a provision requiring refund of a proportionate amount of such advance payment if the total amount of time contracted for is not used.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any agency or instrumentality of the legislative branch is authorized to make advance payments under a contract entered into under paragraph (1).</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent that the personnel of the Senate Computer Center are unable to carry out the contracts entered into under subsection (b) according to their terms and conditions, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to employ such additional personnel for the Senate Computer Center as may be necessary to carry out such contracts, and to pay the salaries of such additional personnel, and agency contributions attributable thereto, from the revolving fund. Such additional personnel may temporarily be assigned to perform the regular functions of the Senate Computer Center when their services are not needed to carry out such contracts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disbursements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Disbursements from the revolving fund under subsections (b) and (c) shall be made upon vouchers signed by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, except that vouchers shall not be required for the disbursement of salaries of employees paid at an annual rate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–303, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="1976-06-01">June 1, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 614</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>CHAPLAIN</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6651.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(G)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2776</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6652.</num>
<heading> Compensation of employees of Chaplain of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chaplain of the Senate may appoint and fix the compensation of such employees as he deems appropriate, except that the amount which may be paid for any fiscal year as gross compensation for personnel in such Office for any fiscal year shall not exceed $147,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–145</ref>, <date date="1969-12-12">Dec. 12, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 340</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(i) [title I, § 2(b)]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329–290</ref>, 1329–294; <ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title I, § 10</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1046</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6653.</num>
<heading> Postage allowance for Chaplain of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is authorized and directed to procure and furnish each fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>) to the Chaplain of the Senate, upon the request of the Chaplain of the Senate, United States postage stamps in such amounts as may be necessary for the mailing of postal matters arising in connection with his official business.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–51, § 127(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6654.</num>
<heading> Payment of expenses of the Chaplain of the Senate from the contingent fund of the Senate</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each fiscal year there is authorized to be expended from the contingent fund of the Senate an amount, not in excess of $50,000 for the Chaplain of the Senate. Payments under this section shall be made only for expenses actually incurred by the Chaplain of the Senate in carrying out his functions, and shall be made upon certification and documentation of the expenses involved, by the Chaplain claiming payment under this section and upon vouchers approved by the Chaplain and by the Committee on Rules and Administration. Funds authorized for expenditure under this section may be used to purchase food or food related items.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repeal of Revolving Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remaining funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any funds in the Chaplain Expense Revolving Fund on the date of the repeal under this section shall be remitted to the general fund of the United States Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2004, and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. H, § 155</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 450</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>