<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 31—</num>
<heading>CAPITOL VISITOR CENTER</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>IN GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2201.</num>
<heading> Designation of facility as Capitol Visitor Center; purposes of facility; treatment of the Capitol Visitor Center</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The facility authorized for construction under the heading “Capitol Visitor Center” under chapter 5 of title II of division B of the Omnibus Consolidated and Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1999 (<ref>Public Law 105–277</ref>; <ref>112 Stat. 2681–569</ref>) is designated as the Capitol Visitor Center and is a part of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes of the facility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Capitol Visitor Center shall be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide enhanced security for persons working in or visiting the United States Capitol;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to improve the visitor experience by providing a structure that will afford improved visitor orientation and enhance the educational experience of those who have come to learn about the Congress and the Capitol; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for other purposes as determined by Congress or the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of the Capitol Visitor Center</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oversight</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives shall have oversight of the Capitol Visitor Center.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of expansion space of the Senate and House of Representatives in the Capitol Visitor Center</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The expansion space of the Senate described as unassigned space under the heading “Capitol Visitor Center” under the heading “ARCHITECT OF THE CAPITOL” under title II of the Act entitled “An Act making appropriations for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year ending <date date="2002-09-30">September 30, 2002</date>, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="2001-11-12">November 12, 2001</date> (<ref>Public Law 107–68</ref>; <ref>115 Stat. 588</ref>) shall be part of the Senate wing of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> House of Representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The expansion space of the House of Representatives described as unassigned space under the heading “Capitol Visitor Center” under the heading “ARCHITECT OF THE CAPITOL” under title II of the Act entitled “An Act making appropriations for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year ending <date date="2002-09-30">September 30, 2002</date>, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="2001-11-12">November 12, 2001</date> (<ref>Public Law 107–68</ref>; <ref>115 Stat. 588</ref>) shall be part of the House of Representatives wing of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of Congressional Auditorium and related adjacent areas</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives shall jointly prescribe regulations for the assignment of the space in the Capitol Visitor Center known as the Congressional Auditorium and the related adjacent areas.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Related adjacent areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations under paragraph (1) shall include a designation of the areas that are related adjacent areas to the Congressional Auditorium.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exhibits for displays</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Loan agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the Architect of the Capitol may enter into loan agreements to place historical objects for display in the Exhibition Hall of the Capitol Visitor Center.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation and approval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Architect of the Capitol may exercise the authority under subparagraph (A) with respect to each loan agreement—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> after consultation with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Senate Commission on Art; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the House of Representatives Fine Arts Board; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> subject to the approval of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">This paragraph shall take effect on <date date="2008-12-03">December 3, 2008</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions to exhibition prohibition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1"><ref>Section 2134 of this title</ref> shall not apply to any historical object placed within an exhibit in the Exhibition Hall of the Capitol Visitor Center that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is directly related to the purpose of the Capitol Visitor Center under subsection (b)(2);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is the subject of a loan agreement entered into by the Architect of the Capitol before <date date="2008-12-02">December 2, 2008</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> has been approved by the Capitol Preservation Commission; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is the subject of a loan agreement described under paragraph (1)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substitution of historical object</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A loan agreement described under paragraph (3)(A)(ii) may provide for the removal of an historical object from exhibition for preservation purposes and the substitution of that object with another historical object having a comparable educational purpose.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4984</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2202.</num>
<heading> Designation and naming within the Capitol Visitor Center</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided under subsection (b), no part of the Capitol Visitor Center may be designated or named without the approval of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not less than ¾ of all members on the Capitol Preservation Commission who are members of the Democratic party; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not less than ¾ of all members on the Capitol Preservation Commission who are members of the Republican party.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply to any room or space under the jurisdiction of the Senate or the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2203.</num>
<heading> Use of the Emancipation Hall of the Capitol Visitor Center</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Emancipation Hall of the Capitol Visitor Center may not be used for any event, except upon the passage of a resolution agreed to by both houses of Congress authorizing the use of the Emancipation Hall for that event.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>OFFICE OF THE CAPITOL VISITOR CENTER</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2211.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Office of the Architect of the Capitol the Office of the Capitol Visitor Center (in this chapter referred to as the “Office”), to be headed by the Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services (in this chapter referred to as the “Chief Executive Officer”).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2212.</num>
<heading> Appointment and supervision of Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer shall be appointed by the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supervision and oversight</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer shall report directly to the Architect of the Capitol and shall be subject to oversight by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon removal of the Chief Executive Officer, the Architect of the Capitol shall immediately provide notice of the removal to the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate. The notice shall include the reasons for the removal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer shall be paid at an annual rate of pay equal to the annual rate of pay of the Deputy Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition for current Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The individual who serves as the Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services under <ref>section 1806 of this title</ref> as of <date date="2008-10-20">October 20, 2008</date>, shall be the first Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services appointed by the Architect under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2213.</num>
<heading> General duties of Chief Executive Officer</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration of facilities, services, and activities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except to the extent otherwise provided in this chapter, the Chief Executive Officer shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the operation, management, and budget preparation and execution of the Capitol Visitor Center, including all long term planning and daily operational services and activities provided within the Capitol Visitor Center; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in accordance with sections 2241 and 2242 of this title, the management of guided tours of the interior of the United States Capitol.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent budget consideration</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, shall submit the proposed budget for the Office for a fiscal year in the proposed budget for that year for the Office of the Architect of the Capitol (as submitted by the Architect of the Capitol to the President). The proposed budget for the Office shall be considered independently from the other components of the proposed budget for the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion of costs of general maintenance and repair of Visitor Center</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In preparing the proposed budget for the Office under subparagraph (A), the Chief Executive Officer shall exclude costs attributable to the activities and services described under <ref>section 2271(b) of this title</ref> (relating to continuing jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol for the care and superintendence of the Capitol Visitor Center).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel, disbursements, and contracts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out this chapter, the Architect of the Capitol shall have the authority to, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> appoint, hire, and fix the compensation of such personnel as may be necessary for operations of the Office, except that no employee may be paid at an annual rate in excess of the maximum rate payable for level 15 of the General Schedule;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> disburse funds as may be necessary and available for the needs of the Office (consistent with the requirements of <ref>section 2233 of this title</ref> in the case of amounts in the Capitol Visitor Center Revolving Fund); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> designate an employee of the Office to serve as contracting officer for the Office, subject to subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requiring approval of certain contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol may not enter into a contract for the operations of the Capitol Visitor Center for which the amount involved exceeds $250,000 without the prior approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Semiannual reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer shall submit a report to the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives not later than 45 days following the close of each semiannual period ending on March 31 or September 30 of each year on the financial and operational status during the period of each function under the jurisdiction of the Chief Executive Officer. Each such report shall include financial statements and a description or explanation of current operations, the implementation of new policies and procedures, and future plans for each function.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2214.</num>
<heading> Assistant to the Chief Executive Officer</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, appoint an assistant who shall perform the responsibilities of the Chief Executive Officer during the absence or disability of the Chief Executive Officer, or during a vacancy in the position of the Chief Executive Officer; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> notwithstanding <ref>section 2213(b)(1) of this title</ref>, fix the rate of basic pay for the position of the assistant appointed under subparagraph (A) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002083">1</ref> at a rate not to exceed the highest total rate of pay for the Senior Executive Service under subchapter VIII of chapter 53 of title 5 for the locality involved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition for current Assistant Chief Executive Officer</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The individual who serves as the assistant under <ref>section 1807 of this title</ref> as of <date date="2008-10-20">October 20, 2008</date>, shall be the first Assistant Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services appointed by the Architect under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4988</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2215.</num>
<heading> Gift Shop</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol, acting through the Chief Executive Officer, shall establish a Capitol Visitor Center Gift Shop within the Capitol Visitor Center for the purpose of providing for the sale of gift items. All moneys received from sales and other services by the Capitol Visitor Center Gift Shop shall be deposited in the Capitol Visitor Center Revolving Fund established under <ref>section 2231 of this title</ref> and shall be available for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception to prohibition of sale or solicitation on Capitol grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 5104(c) of title 40</ref> shall not apply to any activity carried out under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4988</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2216.</num>
<heading> Food service operations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restaurant, catering, and vending</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol, acting through the Chief Executive Officer, shall establish within the Capitol Visitor Center a restaurant and other food service facilities, including catering services and vending machines.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract for food service operations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Architect of the Capitol, acting through the Chief Executive Officer, may enter into a contract for food service operations within the Capitol Visitor Center.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing contract unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to affect any contract for food service operations within the Capitol Visitor Center in effect on <date date="2008-10-20">October 20, 2008</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All net profits from the food service operations within the Capitol Visitor Center and all commissions received from the contractor for such food service operations shall be deposited in the Capitol Visitor Center Revolving Fund established under <ref>section 2231 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception to prohibition of sale or solicitation on Capitol grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 5104(c) of title 40</ref> shall not apply to any activity carried out under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4988</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>CAPITOL VISITOR CENTER REVOLVING FUND</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2231.</num>
<heading> Establishment and accounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund to be known as the Capitol Visitor Center Revolving Fund (in this section referred to as the “Fund”), consisting of the following individual accounts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Gift Shop Account.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Miscellaneous Receipts Account.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4989</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2232.</num>
<heading> Deposits in the Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gift Shop Account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be deposited in the Gift Shop Account all monies received from sales and other services by the gift shop established under <ref>section 2215 of this title</ref>, together with any interest accrued on balances in the Account.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Miscellaneous Receipts Account</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There shall be deposited in the Miscellaneous Receipts Account each of the following (together with any interest accrued on balances in the Account):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any amounts deposited under <ref>section 2216(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any other receipts received from the operation of the Capitol Visitor Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any amounts described under <ref>section 2273(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4989</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2233.</num>
<heading> Use of monies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gift Shop Account</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">All monies in the Gift Shop Account shall be available without fiscal year limitation for disbursement by the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, in connection with the operation of the gift shop under <ref>section 2215 of this title</ref>, including supplies, inventories, equipment, and other expenses. In addition, such monies may be used by the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, to reimburse any applicable appropriations account for amounts used from such appropriations account to pay the salaries of employees of the gift shops.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of remaining funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To the extent monies in the Gift Shop Account are available after disbursements and reimbursements are made under paragraph (1), the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, may disburse such monies for the operation of the Capitol Visitor Center, after consultation with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Miscellaneous Receipts Account</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">All monies in the Miscellaneous Receipts Account shall be available without fiscal year limitation for disbursement by the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, for the operations of the Capitol Visitor Center, after consultation with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4989</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2234.</num>
<heading> Administration of Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disbursements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Disbursements from the Fund may be made by the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest any portion of the Fund that, as determined by the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, is not required to meet current expenses. Each investment shall be made in an interest-bearing obligation of the United States or an obligation guaranteed both as to principal and interest by the United States that, as determined by the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, has a maturity date suitable for the purposes of the Fund. The Secretary of the Treasury shall credit interest earned on the obligations to the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Fund shall be subject to audit by the Comptroller General at the discretion of the Comptroller General.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>CAPITOL GUIDE SERVICE AND OFFICE OF CONGRESSIONAL ACCESSIBILITY SERVICES</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Capitol Guide Service</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2241.</num>
<heading> Transfer of Capitol Guide Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of authorities and personnel to Office of the Capitol Visitor Center</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, effective on the transfer date—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Capitol Guide Service shall be an office within the Office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the contracts, liabilities, records, property, appropriations, and other assets and interests of the Capitol Guide Service, established under <ref>section 2166 of this title</ref>, and the employees of the Capitol Guide Service, are transferred to the Office, except that the transfer of any amounts appropriated to the Capitol Guide Service that remain available as of the transfer date shall occur only upon the approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Capitol Guide Service shall be subject to the direction of the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, in accordance with this part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of employees of Capitol Guide Service at time of transfer</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any individual who is an employee of the Capitol Guide Service on a non-temporary basis on the transfer date who is transferred to the Office under subsection (a) shall be subject to the authority of the Architect of the Capitol under <ref>section 2242(b) of this title</ref>, except that the individual’s grade, compensation, rate of leave, or other benefits that apply with respect to the individual at the time of transfer shall not be reduced while such individual remains continuously so employed in the same position within the Office, other than for cause.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for immediate retirement on basis of involuntary separation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of section 8336(d) and <ref>section 8414(b) of title 5</ref>, an individual described in paragraph (1) who is separated from service with the Office shall be considered to have separated from the service involuntarily if, at the time the individual is separated from service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the individual has completed 25 years of service under such title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the individual has completed 20 years of service under such title and is 50 years of age or older.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for Congressional Special Services Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section does not apply with respect to any employees, contracts, liabilities, records, property, appropriations, and other assets and interests of the Congressional Special Services Office of the Capitol Guide Service that are transferred to the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services under part B.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2242.</num>
<heading> Duties of employees of Capitol Guide Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of guided tours</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tours</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In accordance with this section, the Capitol Guide Service shall provide without charge guided tours of the interior of the United States Capitol, including the Capitol Visitor Center, for the education and enlightenment of the general public.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptance of fees prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An employee of the Capitol Guide Service shall not charge or accept any fee, or accept any gratuity, for or on account of the official services of that employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations of the Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">All such tours shall be conducted in compliance with regulations approved by the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of the Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In providing for the direction, supervision, and control of the Capitol Guide Service, the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subject to the availability of appropriations, establish and revise such number of positions of Guide in the Capitol Guide Service as the Architect of the Capitol considers necessary to carry out effectively the activities of the Capitol Guide Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> appoint, on a permanent basis without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform their duties, a Chief Guide and such deputies as the Architect of the Capitol considers appropriate for the effective administration of the Capitol Guide Service and, in addition, such number of Guides as may be authorized;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, with respect to the individuals appointed under paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prescribe the individual’s duties and responsibilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> fix, and adjust from time to time, respective rates of pay at single per annum (gross) rates;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> with respect to the individuals appointed under paragraph (2), take appropriate disciplinary action, including, when circumstances warrant, suspension from duty without pay, reduction in pay, demotion, or termination of employment with the Capitol Guide Service, against any employee who violates any provision of this section or any regulation prescribed by the Architect of the Capitol under paragraph (8);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> prescribe a uniform dress, including appropriate insignia, which shall be worn by personnel of the Capitol Guide Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> from time to time and as may be necessary, procure and furnish such uniforms to such personnel without charge to such personnel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> receive and consider advice and information from any private historical or educational organization, association, or society with respect to those operations of the Capitol Guide Service which involve the furnishing of historical and educational information to the general public; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, prescribe such regulations as the Architect of the Capitol considers necessary and appropriate for the operation of the Capitol Guide Service, including regulations with respect to tour routes and hours of operation, number of visitors per guide, staff-led tours, and non-law enforcement security and special event related support.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of accessible tours in coordination with Office of Congressional Accessibility Services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer shall coordinate the provision of accessible tours for individuals with disabilities with the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services established under part B.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detail of personnel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol shall detail personnel of the Capitol Guide Service based on a request from the Capitol Police Board to assist the United States Capitol Police by providing ushering and informational services, and other services not directly involving law enforcement, in connection with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the inauguration of the President and Vice President of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the official reception of representatives of foreign nations and other persons by the Senate or House of Representatives; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> other special or ceremonial occasions in the United States Capitol or on the United States Capitol Grounds that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> require the presence of additional Government personnel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> cause the temporary suspension of the performance of regular duties.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect on the transfer date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Office of Congressional Accessibility Services</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2251.</num>
<heading> Office of Congressional Accessibility Services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of Accessibility Services shall submit to the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives a list of the specific functions that the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services will perform in carrying out this part with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives. The Director of Accessibility Services shall submit the list not later than 30 days after the transfer date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition for current Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The individual who serves as the head of the Congressional Special Services Office as of <date date="2008-10-20">October 20, 2008</date>, shall be the first Director of Accessibility Services appointed by the Congressional Accessibility Services Board under <ref>section 2172 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2252.</num>
<heading> Transfer from Capitol Guide Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of authorities and personnel of Congressional Special Services Office of Capitol Guide Service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, effective on the transfer date—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the contracts, liabilities, records, property, appropriations, and other assets and interests of the Congressional Special Services Office of the Capitol Guide Service, and the employees of such Office, are transferred to the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services established under <ref>section 2172(a) of this title</ref> (as amended by <ref>section 2251 of this title</ref>), except that the transfer of any amounts appropriated to the Congressional Special Services Office that remain available as of the transfer date shall occur only upon the approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the employees of such Office shall be subject to the direction, supervision, and control of the Director of Accessibility Services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of employees at time of transfer</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any individual who is an employee of the Congressional Special Services Office of the Capitol Guide Service on a non-temporary basis on the transfer date who is transferred under subsection (a) shall be subject to the authority of the Director of Accessibility Services under <ref>section 2172(b) of this title</ref> (as amended by <ref>section 2251 of this title</ref>), except that the individual’s grade, compensation, rate of leave, or other benefits that apply with respect to the individual at the time of transfer shall not be reduced while such individual remains continuously so employed in the same position within the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services established under <ref>section 2172(a) of this title</ref> (as amended by <ref>section 2251 of this title</ref>), other than for cause.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for immediate retirement on basis of involuntary separation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of section 8336(d) and <ref>section 8414(b) of title 5</ref>, an individual described in paragraph (1) who is separated from service with the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services shall be considered to have separated from the service involuntarily if, at the time the individual is separated from service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the individual has completed 25 years of service under such title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the individual has completed 20 years of service under such title and is 50 years of age or older.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibiting imposition of probationary period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of Accessibility Services may not impose a period of probation with respect to the transfer of any individual who is transferred to the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Transfer Date</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2261.</num>
<heading> Transfer date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this subchapter, the term “transfer date” means the date occurring on the first day of the first pay period (applicable to employees transferred under <ref>section 2241 of this title</ref>) occurring on or after 30 days after <date date="2008-10-20">October 20, 2008</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2271.</num>
<heading> Jurisdictions unaffected</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Security jurisdiction unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter granting any authority to the Architect of the Capitol or Chief Executive Officer shall be construed to affect the exclusive jurisdiction of the Capitol Police, the Capitol Police Board, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, and the Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives to provide security for the Capitol, including the Capitol Visitor Center.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Architect of the Capitol jurisdiction unaffected</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this chapter granting any authority to the Chief Executive Officer shall be construed to affect the exclusive jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol for the care and superintendence of the Capitol Visitor Center. All maintenance services, groundskeeping services, improvements, alterations, additions, and repairs for the Capitol Visitor Center shall be made under the direction and supervision of the Architect, subject to the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the House Office Building Commission as to matters of general policy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4997</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2272.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of volunteer services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, the Architect of the Capitol, upon the recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, may accept and use voluntary and uncompensated services for the Capitol Visitor Center as the Architect of the Capitol determines necessary. No person shall be permitted to donate personal services under this section unless such person has first agreed, in writing, to waive any and all claims against the United States arising out of or connection with such services, other than a claim under the provisions of chapter 81 of title 5. No person donating personal services under this section shall be considered an employee of the United States for any purpose other than for purposes of chapter 81 of such title. In no case shall the acceptance of personal services under this subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002084">1</ref> result in the reduction of pay or displacement of any employee of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4997</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2273.</num>
<heading> Coins treated as gifts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “covered grounds” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the grounds described under <ref>section 5102 of title 40</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Capitol Buildings defined under <ref>section 5101 of title 40</ref>, including the Capitol Visitor Center; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Library of Congress buildings and grounds described under <ref>section 167j of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of coins</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of any coins in any fountains on covered grounds—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such coins shall be treated as gifts to the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the Architect of the Capitol shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collect such coins at such times and in such manner as the Architect determines appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> except as provided under subsection (c), deposit the collected coins in accordance with subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amount collected under this section shall first be used to reimburse the Architect of the Capitol for any costs incurred in the collection and processing of the coins, and maintaining fountains under the jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol. The amount of any such reimbursement is appropriated to the account from which such costs were paid and may be used for any authorized purpose of that account.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of coins</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol shall deposit coins collected under this section in the Miscellaneous Receipts Account of the Capitol Visitor Center Revolving Fund established under <ref>section 2231 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorized use and availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts deposited in the Miscellaneous Receipts Account of the Capitol Visitor Center Revolving Fund under this section shall be available as provided under <ref>section 2233(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4998</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. I, title I, § 131</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2281.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4999</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>