<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 16—</num>
<heading>CONGRESSIONAL MAILING STANDARDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> House Communications Standards Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a special commission of the House of Representatives, designated the “House Communications Standards Commission” (herein referred to as the “Commission”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership; political party representation; Chairman; vacancies; quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall be composed of six Members appointed by the Speaker of the House, three from the majority political party, and three from the minority political party, in the House. The Speaker shall designate as Chairman of the Commission, from among the members of the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the House, one of the Members appointed to the Commission. A vacancy in the membership of the Commission shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. Four members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum to do business.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance and use of personnel, including chief counsel, of Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the House</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In performing its duties and functions, the Commission may use such personnel, office space, equipment, and facilities of, and obtain such other assistance from, the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the House, as such committee shall make available to the Commission. Such personnel and assistance shall include, in all cases, the services and assistance of the chief counsel or other head of the professional staff (by whatever title designated) of such committee. All assistance so furnished to the Commission by the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service shall be sufficient to enable the Commission to perform its duties and functions efficiently and effectively.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory opinions or consultations respecting franked mail for persons entitled to franking privilege; franking privilege regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Commission shall provide guidance, assistance, advice, and counsel, through advisory opinions or consultations, in connection with the mailing or contemplated mailing of franked mail under section 3210, 3211, 3212, 3213(2), 3218, or 3219, in connection with the operation of section 3215, of title 39, and in connection with any other Federal law (other than any law which imposes any criminal penalty) or any rule of the House of Representatives relating to franked mail, upon the request of any Member of the House or Member-elect, Resident Commissioner or Resident Commissioner-elect, Delegate or Delegate-elect, any former Member of the House or former Member-elect, Resident Commissioner or Resident Commissioner-elect, Delegate or Delegate-elect, any surviving spouse of any of the foregoing (or any individual designated by the Clerk of the House under <ref>section 3218 of title 39</ref>), or any other House official or former House official, entitled to send mail as franked mail under any of those sections. The Commission shall prescribe regulations governing the proper use of the franking privilege under those sections by such persons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the guidance, assistance, advice, and counsel described in paragraph (1), the Commission shall provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> guidance, assistance, advice, and counsel, through advisory opinions or consultations, in connection with any law and with any rule or regulation of the House of Representatives governing the dissemination of mass communications other than franked mail; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> guidance, assistance, advice, and counsel in connection with any law and with any rule or regulation of the House of Representatives governing the official content of other official communications of any quantity, whether solicited or unsolicited.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Complaint of franked mail violations; investigation; notice and hearing; conclusiveness of findings; decision of Commission; judicial review; reference of certain violations to Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of the House for appropriate action and enforcement; administrative procedure regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any complaint that a violation of any provision of law or any rule or regulation of the House of Representatives to which subsection (d) applies is about to occur, or has occurred within the immediately preceding period of one year, by any person referred to in such subsection (d), shall contain pertinent factual material and shall conform to regulations prescribed by the Commission. The Commission, if it determines there is reasonable justification for the complaint, shall conduct an investigation of the matter, including an investigation of reports and statements filed by the complainant with respect to the matter which is the subject of the complaint. The Commission shall afford to the person who is the subject of the complaint due notice and, if it determines that there is substantial reason to believe that such violation has occurred or is about to occur, opportunity for all parties to participate in a hearing before the Commission. The Commission shall issue a written decision on each complaint under this subsection not later than thirty days after such a complaint has been filed or, if a hearing is held, not later than thirty days after the conclusion of such hearing. Such decision shall be based on written findings of fact in the case by the Commission. Such findings of fact by the Commission on which its decision is based are binding and conclusive for all judicial and administrative purposes, including purposes of any judicial challenge or review. Any judicial review of such decision, if ordered on any ground, shall be limited to matters of law. If the Commission finds in its written decision, that a serious and willful violation has occurred or is about to occur, it may refer such decision to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of the House of Representatives for appropriate action and enforcement by the committee concerned in accordance with applicable rules and precedents of the House and such other standards as may be prescribed by such committee. In the case of a former Member of the House or a former Member-elect, a former Resident Commissioner or Delegate or Resident Commissioner-elect or Delegate-elect, any surviving spouse of any of the foregoing (or any individual designated by the Clerk of the House under <ref>section 3218 of title 39</ref>), or any other former House official, if the Commission finds in its written decision that any serious and willful violation has occurred or is about to occur, then the Commission may refer the matter to any appropriate law enforcement agency or official for appropriate remedial action. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no court or administrative body in the United States or in any territory thereof shall have jurisdiction to entertain any civil action of any character concerning or related to a violation of any provision of law or any rule or regulation of the House of Representatives to which subsection (d) applies, except judicial review of the decisions of the Commission under this subsection. The Commission shall prescribe regulations for the holding of investigations and hearings, the conduct of proceedings, and the rendering of decisions under this subsection providing for equitable procedures and the protection of individual, public, and Government interests. The regulations shall, insofar as practicable, contain the substance of the administrative procedure provisions of sections 551–559, and 701–706, of title 5. These regulations shall govern matters under this subsection subject to judicial review thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedural considerations; sessions, place and time; subpenas, issuance and service; oaths and affirmations; testimony; printing and binding; expenditures; organizational and procedural regulations; majority assent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may sit and act at such places and times during the sessions, recesses, and adjourned periods of Congress, require by subpena or otherwise the attendance of such witnesses and the production of such books, papers, and documents, administer such oaths and affirmations, take such testimony, procure such printing and binding, and make such expenditures, as the Commission considers advisable. The Commission may make such rules respecting its organization and procedures as it considers necessary, except that no action shall be taken by the Commission unless a majority of the Commission assent. Subpenas may be issued over the signature of the Chairman of the Commission or of any member designated by him or by the Commission, and may be served by such person or persons as may be designated by such Chairman or member. The Chairman of the Commission or any member thereof may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property of Commission; records; voting record; location of records, data, and files</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall keep a complete record of all its actions, including a record of the votes on any question on which a record vote is demanded. All records, data, and files of the Commission shall be the property of the Commission and shall be kept in the offices of the Commission or such other places as the Commission may direct.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of mass communication</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “mass communication” means a mass mailing described in <ref>section 3210(a)(6)(E) of title 39</ref> or any other unsolicited communication of substantially identical content which is transmitted to 500 or more persons in a session of Congress, as provided under regulations of the Commission, except that such term does not include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any communication from an individual described in subsection (d) to another individual described in subsection (d), a Senator, or any Federal, State, local, or Tribal government official;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any news release to the communications media;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any such mass mailing or unsolicited communication made in direct response to a communication from a person to whom the mass mailing or unsolicited communication was transmitted; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in the case of any such unsolicited communication which is transmitted in a digital format, a communication for which the cost of the content is less than a threshold amount established under regulations of the House Communications Standards Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 5</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 742</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–255, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-03-27">Mar. 27, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 52</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–69, § 7</ref>, <date date="1981-10-26">Oct. 26, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. I, title I, § 116(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1637</ref>, 1638.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Select Committee on Standards and Conduct of the Senate</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory opinions or consultations respecting franked mail for persons entitled to franking privilege; franking privilege regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Select Committee on Standards and Conduct of the Senate shall provide guidance, assistance, advice and counsel, through advisory opinions or consultations, in connection with the mailing or contemplated mailing of franked mail under section 3210, 3211, 3212, 3213(2), 3218, or 3219, and in connection with the operation of section 3215, of title 39, upon the request of any Member of the Senate or Member-elect, surviving spouse of any of the foregoing, or other Senate official, entitled to send mail as franked mail under any of those sections. The select committee shall prescribe regulations governing the proper use of the franking privilege under those sections by such persons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Complaint of franked mail violations; investigation; notice and hearing; decision of select committee; enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any complaint filed by any person with the select committee that a violation of any section of title 39 referred to in subsection (a) of this section is about to occur or has occurred within the immediately preceding period of one year, by any person referred to in such subsection (a), shall contain pertinent factual material and shall conform to regulations prescribed by the select committee. The select committee, if it determines there is reasonable justification for the complaint, shall conduct an investigation of the matter, including an investigation of reports and statements filed by the complainant with respect to the matter which is the subject of the complaint. The committee shall afford to the person who is the subject of the complaint due notice and, if it determines that there is substantial reason to believe that such violation has occurred or is about to occur, opportunity for all parties to participate in a hearing before the select committee. The select committee shall issue a written decision on each complaint under this subsection not later than thirty days after such a complaint has been filed or, if a hearing is held, not later than thirty days after the conclusion of such hearing. Such decision shall be based on written findings of fact in the case by the select committee. If the select committee finds, in its written decision, that a violation has occurred or is about to occur, the committee may take such action and enforcement as it considers appropriate in accordance with applicable rules, precedents, and standing orders of the Senate, and such other standards as may be prescribed by such committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative or judicial jurisdiction of civil actions respecting franking law violations or abuses of franking privilege dependent on filing of complaint with select committee and rendition of decision by such committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no court or administrative body in the United States or in any territory thereof shall have jurisdiction to entertain any civil action of any character concerning or related to a violation of the franking laws or an abuse of the franking privilege by any person listed under subsection (a) of this section as entitled to send mail as franked mail, until a complaint has been filed with the select committee and the committee has rendered a decision under subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative procedure regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The select committee shall prescribe regulations for the holding of investigations and hearings, the conduct of proceedings, and the rendering of decisions under this subsection providing for equitable procedures and the protection of individual, public, and Government interests. The regulations shall, insofar as practicable, contain the substance of the administrative procedure provisions of sections 551 to 559 and 701 to 706, of title 5. These regulations shall govern matters under this subsection subject to judicial review thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property of Senate; records of select committee; voting record; location of records, data, and files</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The select committee shall keep a complete record of all its actions, including a record of the votes on any question on which a record vote is demanded. All records, data, and files of the select committee shall be the property of the Senate and shall be kept in the offices of the select committee or such other places as the committee may direct.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–191, § 6</ref>, <date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 744</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–255, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1974-03-27">Mar. 27, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 52</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Official mail of persons entitled to use congressional frank</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional committee regulations for expenditure of appropriations for official mail</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this section, funds appropriated by this Act or any other Act for expenses of official mail of any person entitled to use the congressional frank may be expended only in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate or the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives, as applicable. Such regulations shall require—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> individual accountability for use of official mail by each person entitled to use the congressional frank;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to the House of Representatives, allocation of funds for official mail to be made to each such person with respect to each session of Congress (with no transfer to any other session or to any other such person); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to the Senate, allocation of funds for official mail to be made to each such person with respect to each session of Congress (with no transfer to any other session, other than transfers from the first session of a Congress to the second session of that Congress, or to any other such person); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> with respect to the House of Representatives, that in addition to any other report or information made available to the public (through the House Communications Standards Commission or otherwise) regarding the use of the frank, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives shall include in the quarterly report of receipts and expenditures submitted to the House of Representatives a statement (based solely on data provided for that purpose by the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives and the House Communications Standards Commission) of costs incurred for official mail by each person entitled to use the congressional frank.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Postmaster General functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Postmaster General, in consultation with the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall monitor use of official mail by each person entitled to use the congressional frank;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at least monthly, shall notify any person with an allocation under subsection (a)(2)(A) as to the amount that has been used and any person with an allocation under subsection (a)(2)(B) as to the percentage of the allocation that has been used; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may not carry or deliver official mail the cost of which is in excess of an allocation under subsection (a)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Source of funds for expenses of official mail</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Expenses of official mail of the Senate and the House of Representatives may be paid only from funds specifically appropriated for that purpose and funds so appropriated—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may be supplemented by other appropriated funds only if such supplementation is provided for by law or by regulation under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not be supplemented by funds from any other source, public or private.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance or use of unofficial office accounts or defrayal of official expenses from certain funds prohibited</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No Senator or Member of the House of Representatives may maintain or use, directly or indirectly, an unofficial office account or defray official expenses for franked mail, employee salaries, office space, furniture, or equipment and any associated information technology services (excluding handheld communications devices) from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> funds received from a political committee or derived from a contribution or expenditure (as such terms are defined in <ref>section 30101 of title 52</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> funds received as reimbursement for expenses incurred by the Senator or Member in connection with personal services provided by the Senator or Member to the person making the reimbursement; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other funds that are not specifically appropriated for official expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Official Mail Allowance in House of Representatives</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The use of funds of the House of Representatives which are made available for official mail of Members, officers, and employees of the House of Representatives who are persons entitled to use the congressional frank shall be governed by regulations promulgated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives, with respect to allocation and expenditures relating to official mail (except as provided in subparagraph (B)); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by the House Communications Standards Commission, with respect to matters under <ref>section 3210(a)(6)(D) of title 39</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Funds used for official mail—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to a Member of the House of Representatives, shall be available, in a session of Congress, in a total amount, as determined under paragraph (1)(A), of not more than the product of (i) 3 times the single-piece rate applicable to first class mail, and (ii) the number (as determined by the Postmaster General) of addresses (other than business possible delivery stops) in the congressional district, as such addresses are described in <ref>section 3210(d)(7)(B) of title 39</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to any other person entitled to use the congressional frank in the House of Representatives (including any Member of the House of Representatives who receives an allocation under subsection (a)(2) with respect to duties as an elected officer of, or holder of another position in, the House of Representatives), shall be available, in a session of Congress, in a total amount determined under paragraph (1)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mass mailing; submission of samples or description of proposed mail matter; advisory opinion</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), a Member of the House of Representatives shall, before making any mass communication, submit a sample or description of the matter involved to the House Communications Standards Commission for an advisory opinion as to whether such proposed communication is in compliance with applicable provisions of law, rule, or regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) does not apply in the case of any type of mass communication which is designated as exempt from the requirements of such paragraph as provided under regulations of the House Communications Standards Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Member of the House of Representatives” and “person entitled to use the congressional frank” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in subsections (a) through (f)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Member of the House of Representatives” means a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “person entitled to use the congressional frank” means a Senator, Member of the House of Representatives, or other person authorized to use the frank under <ref>section 3210(b) of title 39</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “mass communication” means a mass mailing described in <ref>section 3210(a)(6)(E) of title 39</ref> or any other unsolicited communication of substantially identical content which is transmitted to 500 or more persons in a session of Congress, as provided under regulations of the House Communications Standards Commission, except that such term does not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any communication from a Member of the House of Representatives to another Member of the House of Representatives, a Senator, or any Federal, State, or local government official;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any news release to the communications media;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any such mass mailing or unsolicited communication made in direct response to a communication from a person to whom the mass mailing or unsolicited communication was transmitted; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in the case of any such unsolicited communication which is transmitted in a digital format, a communication for which the cost of the content is less than a threshold amount established under regulations of the House Communications Standards Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to sessions of Congress beginning with the first session of the One Hundred Second Congress, except that, with respect to the Senate, subsection (d) shall apply beginning on <date date="1992-05-01">May 1, 1992</date>, and the funds referred to in paragraph (3) of such subsection shall not include personal funds of a Senator or Member of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2278</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–229, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1718</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 203(22)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–19, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-04-08">Apr. 8, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 29</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–57, title I</ref>, §§ 102, 103(a)(1)–(3), (4)(B), <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 415</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. I, title I, § 116(b)(2)(B)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1637</ref>, 1639.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Mass mailings by Senate offices; quarterly statements; publication of summary tabulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Two weeks after the close of each calendar quarter, or as soon as practicable thereafter, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate shall send to each Senate office a statement of the cost of postage and paper and of the other operating expenses incurred as a result of mass mailings processed for such Senate office during such quarter. The statement shall separately identify the cost of postage and paper and other costs, and shall distinguish the costs attributable to newsletters and all other mass mailings. The statement shall also include the total cost per capita in the State. A compilation of all such statements shall be sent to the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration. A summary tabulation of such information shall be published quarterly in the Congressional Record and included in the semiannual report of the Secretary of the Senate. Such summary tabulation shall set forth for each Senate office the following information: the Senate office’s name, the total number of pieces of mass mail mailed during the quarter, the total cost of such mail, and, in the case of Senators, the cost of such mail divided by the total population of the State from which the Senator was elected, and the total number of pieces of mass mail divided by the total population of the State from which the Senator was elected, and in the case of each Senator, the allocation made to such Senator from the appropriation for official mail expenses.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title III, § 318</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2283</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–283, title I, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-22">July 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1427</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 505.</num>
<heading> Mass mailing of information by Senators under frank; quarterly registration with Secretary of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In fiscal year 1991 and thereafter, when a Senator disseminates information under the frank by a mass mailing (as defined in <ref>section 3210(a)(6)(E) of title 39</ref>), the Senator shall register quarterly with the Secretary of the Senate such mass mailings. Such registration shall be made by filing with the Secretary a copy of the matter mailed and providing, on a form supplied by the Secretary, a description of the group or groups of persons to whom the mass mailing was mailed and the number of pieces mailed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 506.</num>
<heading> Mass mailing sent by House Members</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice that mailing is at taxpayer expense</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each mass mailing sent by a Member of the House of Representatives shall bear in a prominent place on its face, or on the envelope or outside cover or wrapper in which the mail matter is sent, one of the notices described in paragraph (2) or a notice to the same effect in words which may be prescribed under subsection (c). The notice shall be printed in a type size not smaller than 7-point.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The notices described in this paragraph are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> “Paid for with official funds from the office of _____.”, with the blank filled in with the name of the Member sending the mailing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> “Paid for by the funds authorized by the House of Representatives for District __ of _____.”, with the first blank filled in with the name of the congressional district number, and the second blank filled in with the name of the State, of the Member sending the mailing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> “Paid for by official funds authorized by the House of Representatives.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of each Member’s total expense and amount</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There shall be published in the itemized report of disbursements of the House of Representatives as required by law, a summary tabulation setting forth, for the office of each Member of the House of Representatives, the total number of pieces of mass mail mailed during the period involved and the total cost of those mass mailings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each such tabulation shall also include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the total cost (as referred to in paragraph (1)) divided by the number (as determined by the Postmaster General) of addresses (other than business possible delivery stops) in the Congressional district from which the Member was elected (as such addresses are described in <ref>section 3210(d)(7)(B) of title 39</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total number of pieces of mass mail (as referred to in paragraph (1)) divided by the number (as determined by the Postmaster General) of addresses (other than business possible delivery stops) in the Congressional district from which the Member was elected (as such addresses are described in <ref>section 3210(d)(7)(B) of title 39</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee on House Oversight shall prescribe such rules and regulations and shall take such other action as the Committee considers necessary and proper for Members to conform to the provisions of this subsection and applicable rules and regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Member of the House of Representatives” means a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “mass mailing” has the meaning given such term by <ref>section 3210(a)(6)(E) of title 39</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to sessions of Congress beginning after <date date="1996-09-16">September 16, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2414</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. I, title I, § 116(d)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1640</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>