<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 28—</num>
<heading>ARCHITECT OF THE CAPITOL</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1801.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, title LVII, § 5702(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 960</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1801a.</num>
<heading> Appointment and term of service of Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol shall be appointed, without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the office, upon a majority vote of a congressional commission (referred to in this section as the “commission”) consisting of the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the majority leader of the Senate, the minority leaders of the House of Representatives and Senate, the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, and the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol shall be appointed for a term of 10 years and, upon a majority vote of the members of the commission, may be reappointed for additional 10-year terms.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol may be removed from office at any time upon a majority vote of the members of the commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall apply with respect to appointments made on or after <date date="2023-12-22">December 22, 2023</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, title LVII, § 5702</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 960</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1802.</num>
<heading> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The compensation of the Architect of the Capitol shall be at an annual rate which is equal to the annual rate of basic pay for level II of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5313 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–146, § 1</ref>, formerly § 1(1), <date date="1979-12-14">Dec. 14, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 1086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 129(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 579</ref>; renumbered § 1 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(D)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. I, title II, § 212(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 526</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1803.</num>
<heading> Delegation of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol may delegate the duties and authorities of the Architect to officers and employees of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, as the Architect determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 5, 1955, ch. 568</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 515</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1205</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 375</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1804.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, title LVII, § 5704(d)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 962</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1805.</num>
<heading> Deputy Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Deputy Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Architect”) shall appoint a suitable individual to be the Deputy Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Deputy Architect”). The Architect may delegate to the Deputy Architect such duties as the Architect determines are necessary or appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Architect shall appoint a Deputy Architect under subsection (a) not later than 120 days after—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which the Architect is appointed under <ref>section 1801a of this title</ref>, if there is no Deputy Architect on the date of the appointment; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the date on which a vacancy arises in the office of the Deputy Architect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Deputy Architect shall be paid at an annual rate of pay to be determined by the Architect but not to exceed $1,500 less than the annual rate of pay for the Architect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to appoint</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Architect does not appoint a Deputy Architect on or before the applicable date specified in subsection (b), the congressional commission described in <ref>section 1801a(a) of this title</ref> shall appoint the Deputy Architect by a majority vote of the members of the commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the position of Deputy Architect becomes vacant, the Architect shall immediately notify the members of the congressional commission described in <ref>section 1801a(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1203</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 373</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–11, title II, § 2601(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-04-16">Apr. 16, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–316, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3452</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title VII, § 701(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, title LVII, § 5703</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 961</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1805a.</num>
<heading> Deputy Architect of the Capitol to serve as acting in case of absence, disability, or vacancy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Deputy Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Deputy Architect”) shall act as Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Architect”) if the Architect is absent or disabled or there is no Architect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Absence, disability, or vacancy in Office of Deputy Architect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), if the Deputy Architect is also absent or disabled or there is no Deputy Architect, the congressional commission described in <ref>section 1801a(a) of this title</ref> shall designate, by a majority vote of the members of the commission, an individual to serve as acting Architect until—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the end of the absence or disability of the Architect or the Deputy Architect; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of vacancies in both positions, an Architect has been appointed under <ref>section 1801a(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An officer serving as acting Architect under subsection (a) or (b) shall perform all the duties and exercise all the authorities of the Architect, including the authority to delegate the duties and authorities of the Architect in accordance with <ref>section 1803 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, title LVII, § 5704</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 961</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1806.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title II, § 202(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4987</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1807.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title II, § 204(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4988</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1808.</num>
<heading> Inspector General of the Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “Architect of the Capitol Inspector General Act of 2007”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of Inspector General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is an Office of Inspector General within the Office of the Architect of the Capitol which is an independent objective office to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct and supervise audits and investigations relating to the Architect of the Capitol;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide leadership and coordination and recommend policies to promote economy, efficiency, and effectiveness; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide a means of keeping the Architect of the Capitol and the Congress fully and currently informed about problems and deficiencies relating to the administration of programs and operations of the Architect of the Capitol.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment of Inspector General; supervision; removal; pay; limits on bonuses; counsel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and supervision</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">There shall be at the head of the Office of Inspector General, an Inspector General who shall be appointed by the Architect of the Capitol, in consultation with the Inspectors General of the Library of Congress, Government Publishing Office, Government Accountability Office, and United States Capitol Police. The appointment shall be made without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations. The Inspector General shall report to, and be under the general supervision of, the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audits, investigations, reports, and other duties and responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Architect of the Capitol shall have no authority to prevent or prohibit the Inspector General from—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> initiating, carrying out, or completing any audit or investigation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> issuing any subpoena during the course of any audit or investigation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> issuing any report; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> carrying out any other duty or responsibility of the Inspector General under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal or transfer</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Inspector General may be removed from office, or transferred to another position within, or another location of, the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, by the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 30 days before the Architect of the Capitol removes or transfers the Inspector General under subparagraph (A), the Architect of the Capitol shall communicate in writing the reason for the removal or transfer to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on House Administration and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Rules and Administration and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph shall prohibit a personnel action (except for removal or transfer) that is otherwise authorized by law.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Inspector General shall be paid at an annual rate of pay equal to $1,500 less than the annual rate of pay of the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No bonuses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Inspector General may not receive any cash award or cash bonus, including a cash award under chapter 45 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Inspector General shall, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations governing selections, appointments, and employment at the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, obtain legal advice from a counsel reporting directly to the Inspector General or another Inspector General.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties, responsibilities, authority, and reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Sections 404, 405 (other than subsections (b)(13) and (f)(1)(B) thereof), 406 (other than subsection (a)(7) and (8) thereof), and 407 of title 5 shall apply to the Inspector General of the Architect of the Capitol and the Office of such Inspector General and such sections shall be applied to the Office of the Architect of the Capitol and the Architect of the Capitol by substituting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> “Office of the Architect of the Capitol” for “establishment”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> “Architect of the Capitol” for “head of the establishment”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employees</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Inspector General, in carrying out this section, is authorized, without the supervision or approval of any other employee, office, or other entity within the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, to select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees (including consultants) as may be necessary for carrying out the functions, powers, and duties of the Office of Inspector General subject to the provisions of law governing selections, appointments, and employment in the Office of the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Security and suitability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Appointments under the authority under subparagraph (A) shall be made consistent with personnel security and suitability requirements.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any appointment of a consultant under the authority under subparagraph (A) shall be made consistent with section 6(a)(8) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002067">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement authority</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), any supervisory special agent under the Inspector General and any special agent supervised by such a supervisory special agent is authorized to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> make an arrest without a warrant while engaged in official duties as authorized under this section or any other statute for any offense against the United States committed in the presence of such supervisory special agent or special agent, or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if such supervisory special agent or special agent has reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such felony;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> seek and execute warrants for arrest, search of a premises, or seizure of evidence issued under the authority of the United States upon probable cause to believe that a violation has been committed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> carry a firearm while engaged in official duties as authorized under this section or any other statute.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements to exercise authority</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required certification</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">In order to exercise the authority under subparagraph (A), a supervisory special agent or a special agent supervised by such a supervisory special agent shall certify that he or she—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> is a citizen of the United States;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> has successfully completed a basic law enforcement training program or military or other equivalent; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> is not prohibited from receiving a firearm under Federal law, including under <ref>section 922(g)(9) of title 18</ref>, because of a conviction of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">After providing notice to the appropriate committees of Congress, the Inspector General may add requirements to the certification required under subclause (I), as determined appropriate by the Inspector General.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Inspector General shall maintain firearms-related requirements (including quarterly firearms qualifications) and use of force training requirements that, except to the extent the Inspector General determines necessary to effectively carry out the duties of the Office of the Inspector General, are in accordance with the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency use of force policies, which incorporate Department of Justice guidelines.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility determination</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">The Inspector General shall—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> determine whether an individual meets the requirements under this paragraph; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> revoke any authority granted to an individual under subparagraph (A) if the individual is not in compliance with the requirements of this paragraph.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reauthorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The Inspector General may reauthorize an individual to exercise the authority granted under subparagraph (A) if the Inspector General determines the individual has achieved compliance with the requirements under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on appeal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">A revocation of the authority granted under subparagraph (A) shall not be subject to administrative, judicial, or other review, unless the revocation results in an adverse action. Such an adverse action may, at the election of the applicable individual, be reviewed in accordance with the otherwise applicable procedures.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Semiannual certification of program</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Before the first grant of authority under subparagraph (A), and semiannually thereafter as part of the report under section 5 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.),<sup>1</sup> the Inspector General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a written certification that adequate internal safeguards and management procedures exist that, except to the extent the Inspector General determines necessary to effectively carry out the duties of the Office of the Inspector General, are in compliance with standards established by the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, which incorporate Department of Justice guidelines, to ensure proper exercise of the powers authorized under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The authority granted under this paragraph (including any grant of authority to an individual under subparagraph (A), without regard to whether the individual is in compliance with subparagraph (B)) may be suspended by the Inspector General if the Office of Inspector General fails to comply with the reporting and review requirements under clause (i) of this subparagraph or subparagraph (D). Any suspension of authority under this clause shall be reported to the appropriate committees of Congress.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Peer review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To ensure the proper exercise of the law enforcement powers authorized under this paragraph, the Office of Inspector General shall submit to and participate in the external review process established by the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency for ensuring that adequate internal safeguards and management procedures continue to exist. Under the review process, the exercise of the law enforcement powers by the Office of Inspector General shall be reviewed periodically by another Office of Inspector General or by a committee of Inspectors General. The results of each review shall be communicated in writing to the Inspector General, the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, and the appropriate committees of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alleged misconduct</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any allegation of misconduct by an individual granted authority under subparagraph (A) may be reviewed by the Integrity Committee of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate committees of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on Rules and Administration and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on House Administration and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budget independence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Architect of the Capitol shall include the annual budget request of the Inspector General in the budget of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol without change.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All functions, personnel, and budget resources of the Office of the Inspector General of the Architect of the Capitol as in effect before the effective date of this section are transferred to the Office of Inspector General described under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> References</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">References in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or relating to the Inspector General of the Architect of the Capitol shall be deemed to refer to the Inspector General as set forth under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> First appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">By the date occurring 180 days after <date date="2007-12-26">December 26, 2007</date>, the Architect of the Capitol shall appoint an individual to the position of Inspector General of the Architect of the Capitol described under subparagraph (A) of subsection (c)(1) in accordance with that subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided under paragraph (2), this section shall take effect 180 days after <date date="2007-12-26">December 26, 2007</date>, and apply with respect to fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> First appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subsection (g) shall take effect on <date date="2007-12-26">December 26, 2007</date>, and the Architect of the Capitol shall take such actions as necessary after <date date="2007-12-26">December 26, 2007</date>, to carry out that subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1301</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2240</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1602(b), 1603(b), 1604(b), 1605(b), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3210</ref>, 3214, 3218, 3219; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4342</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>GENERAL POWERS AND DUTIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1811.</num>
<heading> Powers and duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol shall perform all the duties relative to the Capitol Building performed prior to <date date="1876-08-15">August 15, 1876</date>, by the Commissioner of Public Buildings and Grounds: <i>Provided</i>, That no change in the architectural features of the Capitol Building or in the landscape features of the Capitol Grounds shall be made except on plans to be approved by Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 15, 1876, ch. 287</ref>, <ref>19 Stat. 147</ref>; <ref>Feb. 14, 1902, ch. 17</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 20</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1921, ch. 124</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 1291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, title LVII, § 5702(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 961</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1812.</num>
<heading> Care and superintendence of Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol shall on and after <date date="1977-03-03">March 3, 1977</date>, have the care and superintendence of the Capitol, including lighting. His office shall be in the Capitol Building.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 15, 1876, ch. 287</ref>, <ref>19 Stat. 147</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1877, ch. 102</ref>, <ref>19 Stat. 298</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 3(14)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1813.</num>
<heading> Exterior of Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1884-07-07">July 7, 1884</date>, it shall be the duty of the Architect to clean and keep in proper order the exterior of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 7, 1884, ch. 332</ref>, <ref>23 Stat. 209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1814.</num>
<heading> Repairs of Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All improvements, alterations, additions, and repairs of the Capitol Building shall be made by the direction and under the supervision of the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 1816; <ref>Feb. 14, 1902, ch. 17</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 20</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1921, ch. 124</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 1291</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 3(15)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1815.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title I, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 606</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1816.</num>
<heading> Construction contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liquidated damages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol may not enter into or administer any construction contract with a value greater than $50,000 unless the contract includes a provision requiring the payment of liquidated damages in the amount determined under subsection (b) in the event that completion of the project is delayed because of the contractor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The amount of payment required under a liquidated damages provision described in subsection (a) shall be equal to the product of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the daily liquidated damage payment rate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of days by which the completion of the project is delayed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Daily liquidated damage payment rate</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In subsection (b), the “daily liquidated damage payment rate” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $140, in the case of a contract with a value greater than $50,000 and less than $100,000;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $200, in the case of a contract with a value equal to or greater than $100,000 and equal to or less than $500,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the sum of $200 plus $50 for each $100,000 increment by which the value of the contract exceeds $500,000, in the case of a contract with a value greater than $500,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment in rate permitted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the daily liquidated damage payment rate may be adjusted by the contracting officer involved to a rate greater or lesser than the rate described in such paragraph if the contracting officer makes a written determination that the rate described does not accurately reflect the anticipated damages which will be suffered by the United States as a result of the delay in the completion of the contract.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to contracts entered into during fiscal year 2002 or any succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 130</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 580</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1816a.</num>
<heading> Design-build contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Architect of the Capitol may use the two-phase selection procedures authorized in <ref>section 3309 of title 41</ref> for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work in the same manner and under the same terms and conditions as the head of an executive agency under such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2008 and each succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1308</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1816b.</num>
<heading> Architect of the Capitol, authority for personal services contracts with legal entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Architect of the Capitol is authorized to contract for personal services with any firm, partnership, corporation, association, or other legal entity in the same manner as he is authorized to contract for personal services with individuals under the provisions of <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–558</ref>, <date date="1980-12-19">Dec. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3263</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1817.</num>
<heading> Transfer of discontinued apparatus to other branches</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol may transfer apparatus, appliances, equipments, and supplies of any kind, discontinued or permanently out of service, to other branches of the service of the United States, or District of Columbia, whenever, in his judgment the interests of the Government service may require it.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 26, 1912, ch. 182, § 11</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 184</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1921, ch. 124</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 1291</ref>; <ref>May 29, 1928, ch. 901, § 1(120)</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 995</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 3(17)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1817a.</num>
<heading> Disposition of surplus or obsolete personal property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol shall have the authority, within the limits of available appropriations, to dispose of surplus or obsolete personal property by inter-agency transfer, donation, sale, trade-in, or discarding. Amounts received for the sale or trade-in of personal property shall be credited to funds available for the operations of the Architect of the Capitol and be available for the costs of acquiring the same or similar property. Such funds shall be available for such purposes during the fiscal year received and the following fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2010, and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–68, div. A, title I, § 1301</ref>, <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2034</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1818.</num>
<heading> Rental or lease of storage space</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Architect of the Capitol, with the approval of the House Office Building Commission and Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, is authorized to secure, through rental, lease, or other appropriate agreement, storage space in areas within the District of Columbia and its environs beyond the boundaries of the United States Capitol Grounds for use of the United States Senate, the United States House of Representatives, and the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, under such terms and conditions as such Commission and committee may authorize, and to incur any necessary incidental expenses in connection therewith.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–180, § 1</ref>, <date date="1973-12-13">Dec. 13, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 704</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1819.</num>
<heading> Computer backup facilities for legislative offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisition of buildings and facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol is authorized, subject to the availability of appropriations, to acquire (through purchase, lease, or otherwise) buildings and facilities for use as computer backup facilities (and related uses) for offices in the legislative branch.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisition subject to approval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The acquisition of a building or facility under subsection (a) shall be subject to the approval of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the House Office Building Commission, in the case of a building or facility acquired for the use of an office of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, in the case of a building or facility acquired for the use of an office of the Senate; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the House Office Building Commission in the case of a building or facility acquired for the use of any other office in the legislative branch as part of a joint facility with (1) above, or the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, in the case of a building or facility acquired for the use of any other office in the legislative branch as part of a joint facility with (2) above.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States Capitol grounds provisions applicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any building or facility acquired by the Architect of the Capitol pursuant to subsection (a) shall be a part of the United States Capitol Grounds and shall be subject to the provisions of sections 1922, 1961, 1966, 1967, and 1969 of this title and sections 5101 to 5107 and 5109 of title 40.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lease of buildings and facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of a building or facility acquired through purchase pursuant to subsection (a), the Architect of the Capitol may enter into or assume a lease with another person for the use of any portion of the building or facility that the Architect of the Capitol determines is not required to be used to carry out the purposes of this section, subject to the approval of the entity which approved the acquisition of such building or facility under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2002 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–206, title I, § 905</ref>, <date date="2002-08-02">Aug. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 877</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–55, title I, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 579</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1820.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of real property for Capitol Police</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority for acquisition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the approval of the House Office Building Commission and the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, the Architect of the Capitol is authorized to acquire (through purchase, lease, transfer from another Federal entity, or otherwise) real property, subject to the availability of appropriations and upon approval of an obligation plan by the Committees on Appropriations of the House and Senate, for the use of the United States Capitol Police.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States Capitol grounds provisions applicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any real property acquired by the Architect of the Capitol pursuant to subsection (a) shall be a part of the United States Capitol Grounds and shall be subject to the provisions of sections 1922, 1961, 1966, 1967, and 1969 of this title and sections 5101 to 5107 and 5109 of title 40.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2002 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–206, title I, § 907</ref>, <date date="2002-08-02">Aug. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 877</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1821.</num>
<heading> Small purchase contracting authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To promote efficiency and economy in contracting and to avoid unnecessary burdens, the Architect of the Capitol is granted authority to utilize special simplified procedures for purchases of property and services the aggregate amount of which does not exceed $250,000. Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content><ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref> shall apply with respect to purchases and contracts for the Architect of the Capitol as if the reference to “$25,000” in paragraph (1) of such section were a reference to “$100,000”; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Architect may procure services, equipment, and construction for security related projects in the most efficient manner he determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2003 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 372</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–244, div. B, title I, § 133(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-09-21">Sept. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2936</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1822.</num>
<heading> Leasing of space</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Funds appropriated to the Architect of the Capitol shall be available—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the leasing of space in areas within the District of Columbia and its environs beyond the boundaries of the United States Capitol Grounds to meet space requirements of the United States Senate, United States House of Representatives, United States Capitol Police, and the Architect of the Capitol under such terms and conditions as the Committee or Commission referred to under subsection (b) may authorize; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to incur any necessary expense in connection with any leasing of space under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions to lease space</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol may lease space under subsection (a) upon submission of written notice of intent to lease such space to, and approved by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committees on Appropriations and Rules and Administration of the Senate for space to be leased for the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the House Office Building Commission for space to be leased for the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and House of Representatives, for space to be leased for any other entity under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2004, and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 1102</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1027</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1306(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1823.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of real property for Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Architect of the Capitol may acquire (through purchase, lease, transfer from another Federal entity, or otherwise) real property, for the use of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate to support the operations of the Senate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subject to the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subject to the availability of appropriations and upon approval of an obligation plan by the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subject to the approval of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Secretary of the Senate may transfer funds for the acquisition or maintenance of any property under paragraph (1) from the account under the heading “Senate, Contingent Expenses of the Senate, Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate” to the account under the heading “Architect of the Capitol, Senate Office Buildings”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2007 and each fiscal year thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–289, div. B, title II, § 20701(b)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–5, § 2</ref>, <date date="2007-02-15">Feb. 15, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 37</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1823a.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of real property for Library of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permitting leasing of space</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the availability of funds, the Architect of the Capitol may acquire real property by lease for the use of the Library of Congress in any State or the District of Columbia if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Architect of the Capitol and the Librarian of Congress submit a joint request for the Architect to lease the property to the Joint Committee on the Library and to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Joint Committee on the Library and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate each approve the request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the approval of the Joint Committee on the Library and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Architect of the Capitol and the Librarian of Congress may transfer between themselves appropriations or other available funds to pay the costs incurred in acquiring real property pursuant to the authority of this section and the costs of necessary expenses incurred in connection with the acquisition of the property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit on obligations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No obligation entered into pursuant to the authority of this section shall be in advance of, or in excess of, available appropriations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2009 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. G, title I, § 1102</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 823</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1824.</num>
<heading> Energy and environmental measures in Capitol Complex Master Plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the maximum extent practicable, the Architect of the Capitol shall include energy efficiency and conservation measures, greenhouse gas emission reduction measures, and other appropriate environmental measures in the Capitol Complex Master Plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after <date date="2007-12-19">December 19, 2007</date>, the Architect of the Capitol shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, a report on the energy efficiency and conservation measures, greenhouse gas emission reduction measures, and other appropriate environmental measures included in the Capitol Complex Master Plan pursuant to subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–140, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1655</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1824a.</num>
<heading> Recyclable materials</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection and sale of recyclable materials</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Architect of the Capitol shall establish a program for the collection and sale of recyclable materials collected from or on the Capitol buildings and grounds, in accordance with the procedures applicable under subchapter III of chapter 5 of subtitle I of title 40, to the sale of surplus property by an executive agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion of materials subject to other programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The program established under this section shall not apply with respect to any materials which are subject to collection and sale under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>section 6516 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 5540 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>section 2026 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other authorized program for the collection and sale of recyclable materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revolving fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">There is established in the Treasury a revolving fund for the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, which shall consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> proceeds from the sale of recyclable materials under the program established under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such amounts as may be appropriated under law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of fund</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Amounts in the revolving fund established under paragraph (1) shall be available without fiscal year limitation to the Architect of the Capitol, subject to the Architect providing prior notice to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to carry out the program established under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to carry out authorized programs and activities of the Architect to improve the environment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to carry out authorized programs and activities of the Architect to promote energy savings.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. G, title I, § 1101</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. I, title I, § 1303</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 429</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1825.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title V, § 501(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4997</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1826.</num>
<heading> Easements for rights-of-way</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol may grant, upon such terms as the Architect of the Capitol considers advisable, including monetary consideration, easements for rights-of-way over, in, and upon the Capitol Grounds and any other public lands under the jurisdiction and control of the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No easement granted under this section may include more land than is necessary for the easement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Easement account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury an easement account for the Architect of the Capitol. The Architect of the Capitol shall deposit in the account all proceeds received relating to the granting of easements under this section. The proceeds deposited in that account shall be available to the Architect, in such amounts and for such purposes provided in appropriations acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In-kind consideration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsection (f), the Architect may accept in-kind consideration instead of, or in addition to, any monetary consideration, for any easement granted under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of easement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol may terminate all or part of any easement granted under this section for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> failure to comply with the terms of the grant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> nonuse for a 2-year period; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> abandonment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol may grant an easement for rights-of-way under subsection (a) upon submission of written notice of intent to grant that easement and the amount or type of consideration to be received, and approval by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate for easements granted on property under Senate jurisdiction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the House Office Building Commission for property under House of Representatives jurisdiction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the House Office Building Commission for easements granted on any other property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1307</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1827.</num>
<heading> Support and maintenance during emergencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> During an emergency involving the safety of human life or the protection of property, as determined or declared by the Capitol Police Board, the Architect of the Capitol—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may accept contributions of comfort and other incidental items and services to support employees of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol while such employees are on duty in response to the emergency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may incur obligations and make expenditures out of available appropriations for meals, refreshments, and other support and maintenance for the Office of the Architect of the Capitol if, in the judgment of the Architect, such obligations and expenditures are necessary to respond to the emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2010 and each succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–68, div. A, title I, § 1305</ref>, <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2035</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PERSONNEL</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">General</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1831.</num>
<heading> Human resources program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “Architect of the Capitol Human Resources Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finding and purpose</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Congress finds that the Office of the Architect of the Capitol should develop human resources management programs that are consistent with the practices common among other Federal and private sector organizations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It is the purpose of this section to require the Architect of the Capitol to establish and maintain a personnel management system that incorporates fundamental principles that exist in other modern personnel systems.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel management system</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Architect of the Capitol shall establish and maintain a personnel management system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The personnel management system shall at a minimum include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A system which ensures that applicants for employment and employees of the Architect of the Capitol are appointed, promoted, and assigned on the basis of merit and fitness after fair and equitable consideration of all applicants and employees through open competition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An equal employment opportunity program which includes an affirmative employment program for employees and applicants for employment, and procedures for monitoring progress by the Architect of the Capitol in ensuring a workforce reflective of the diverse labor force.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A system for the classification of positions which takes into account the difficulty, responsibility, and qualification requirements of the work performed, and which conforms to the principle of equal pay for substantially equal work.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A program for the training of Architect of the Capitol employees which has among its goals improved employee performance and opportunities for employee advancement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A formal performance appraisal system which will permit the accurate evaluation of job performance on the basis of objective criteria for all Architect of the Capitol employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A fair and equitable system to address unacceptable conduct and performance by Architect of the Capitol employees, including a general statement of violations, sanctions, and procedures which shall be made known to all employees, and a formal grievance procedure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> A program to provide services to deal with mental health, alcohol abuse, drug abuse, and other employee problems, and which ensures employee confidentiality.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> A formal policy statement regarding the use and accrual of sick and annual leave which shall be made known to all employees, and which is consistent with the other requirements of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of personnel management system</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Architect of the Capitol shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop a plan for the establishment and maintenance of a personnel management system designed to achieve the requirements of subsection (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submit the plan to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the House Office Building Commission, the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Joint Committee on the Library, and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than 12 months after <date date="1994-07-22">July 22, 1994</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> implement the plan not later than 90 days after the plan is submitted to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the House Office Building Commission, the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Joint Committee on the Library, and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, as specified in subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation and reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Architect of the Capitol shall develop a system of oversight and evaluation to ensure that the personnel management system of the Architect of the Capitol achieves the requirements of subsection (c) and complies with all other relevant laws, rules and regulations. The Architect of the Capitol shall report to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the House Office Building Commission, the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, and the Joint Committee on the Library on an annual basis the results of its evaluation under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter or supersede any other provision of law otherwise applicable to the Architect of the Capitol or its employees, unless expressly provided in this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–283, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1994-07-22">July 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1443</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title V, § 504(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 41</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1832.</num>
<heading> Assignment and reassignment of personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, in order to improve the economic use of the personal services of his employees, the Architect of the Capitol is authorized on and after <date date="1979-10-12">October 12, 1979</date>, to assign and reassign, without increase or decrease in basic salary or wages, any person on the employment rolls of his Office, for personal services in any buildings, facilities or grounds under his jurisdiction or for personal services in connection with any project under his jurisdiction for which appropriations have been made and are available, whenever such action, in his opinion, will be most advantageous to the interest of or result in either specific or overall savings to the Government. Exceptions may be made where there are differences in equipment. No assignment or reassignment of personnel by the Architect of the Capitol pursuant to this provision shall operate in any respect to augment or decrease any general or specific appropriation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–86, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-12">Oct. 12, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 657</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 106</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329–433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1833.</num>
<heading> Lighting, heating, and ventilating House of Representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The electrician, together with everything pertaining to the electrical machinery and apparatus, and the ventilation and heating of the House of Representatives, and all laborers and others connected with the lighting, heating, and ventilating thereof, shall be subject exclusively to the orders, and in all respects under the direction, of the Architect of the Capitol, subject to the control of the Speaker; and no removal or appointment shall be made except with his approval. And all engineers and others who are engaged in heating and ventilating the House shall be subject to the orders, and in all respects under the direction, of the Architect of the Capitol, subject to the control of the Speaker; and no removal or appointment shall be made except with his approval.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1877, ch. 105</ref>, <ref>19 Stat. 348</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1881, ch. 130, § 1</ref>, <ref>21 Stat. 388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1834.</num>
<heading> Heating and ventilating Senate wing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All engineers and others who are engaged in heating and ventilating the Senate wing of the Capitol shall be subject to the orders and in all respects under the direction of the Architect of the Capitol, subject to the approval of the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 11, 1888, ch. 615</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 258</ref>; <ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title I, § 102, title II, § 224, <ref>60 Stat. 814</ref>, 838.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1835.</num>
<heading> Interagency details</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorizing details of employees under joint agency agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to any other authority relating to the detail of employees, the Architect of the Capitol and the head of any other department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government may enter into a joint agency agreement under which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> employees of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol (including employees of the United States Botanic Garden) may be detailed to such department, agency, or instrumentality on a reimbursable or non-reimbursable basis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> employees of such department, agency, or instrumentality may be detailed to the Office of the Architect of the Capitol on a reimbursable or non-reimbursable basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The detail of an employee under a joint agency agreement under this section shall be for such duration as may be provided in the agreement, except that in the case of a detail made on a non-reimbursable basis, the duration of the detail may not exceed one year unless the Architect of the Capitol and the head of the department, agency, or instrumentality involved each determine that an extension of the detail of the employee is in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No effect on appropriations of recipient of non-reimbursable detail</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of any law, rule, or regulation, the detail of an employee on a non-reimbursable basis under a joint agency agreement under this section for a fiscal year shall not be treated as an increase or modification of the appropriation for the fiscal year of the office to whom the employee is detailed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2019 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–244, div. B, title I, § 134</ref>, <date date="2018-09-21">Sept. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2936</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Compensation</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1841.</num>
<heading> Single per annum gross rates of pay</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever the rate of pay of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an employee of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an employee of the House Restaurant, or of the Senate Restaurant, under the supervision of the Architect of the Capitol as an agent of the House or Senate, respectively, as the case may be;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is fixed or adjusted on or after the effective date of this section, that rate, as so fixed and adjusted, shall be a single per annum gross rate.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title IV, § 481</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1196</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1842.</num>
<heading> Conversion of existing pay rates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol shall convert, as of the effective date of this section, to a single per annum gross rate, the rate of pay of each employee described in subparagraph (1) or subparagraph (2) of <ref>section 1841 of this title</ref>, whose pay immediately prior to such effective date was fixed at a basic rate with respect to which additional pay was payable by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title IV, § 482</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1196</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1843.</num>
<heading> Obsolete references</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In any case in which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the rate of pay of, or any maximum or minimum rate of pay with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any employee described in subparagraph (1) or subparagraph (2) of <ref>section 1841 of this title</ref>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the position of such employee, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any class or group of such employees or positions,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">is referred to in or provided by statute or other authority; and</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the rate so referred to or provided is a basic rate with respect to which additional pay is provided by law;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">such statutory provision or authority shall be deemed to refer, in lieu of such basic rate, to the per annum gross rate which an employee receiving such basic rate immediately prior to the effective date of this section would receive, without regard to such statutory provision or authority, under <ref>section 1842 of this title</ref> on and after such date.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title IV, § 483</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1196</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1844.</num>
<heading> Savings provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The provisions of sections 1841 to 1846 of this title shall not be construed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> limit or otherwise affect any authority for the making of any appointment to, or for fixing or adjusting the pay for, the position of any employee described in subparagraph (1) or subparagraph (2) of <ref>section 1841 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> affect the continuity of employment of, or reduce the pay of, any employee holding any position referred to in subparagraph (1) of this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> modify, change, supersede, or otherwise affect the provisions of sections 5504 and 6101(a)(5) of title 5, insofar as such sections relate to the Office of the Architect of the Capitol.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title IV, § 484</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1197</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1845.</num>
<heading> Effect on existing law</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> All provisions of law inconsistent with sections 1841 to 1846 of this title are hereby superseded to the extent of the inconsistency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Sections 5504 and 6101(a)(5) of title 5 shall apply to employees of the House and Senate Restaurants who are paid at per annum rates of pay as long as such employees are under the supervision of the Architect of the Capitol as an agent of the House or Senate, respectively, as the case may be.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title IV, § 485</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1197</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1846.</num>
<heading> Exemptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of sections 1841 to 1846 of this title, the foregoing provisions of such sections do not apply to any employee described in <ref>section 1841 of this title</ref> whose pay is fixed and adjusted—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in accordance with chapter 51, and subchapter III of chapter 53, of title 5, relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in accordance with subchapter IV of chapter 53 of title 5, relating to prevailing rate pay systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at per hour or per diem rates in accordance with section 3 of the Legislative Pay Act of 1929, as amended (<ref>46 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>55 Stat. 615</ref>), relating to employees performing professional and technical services for the Architect of the Capitol in connection with construction projects and employees under the Office of the Architect of the Capitol whose tenure of employment is temporary or of uncertain duration; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in accordance with prevailing rates under authority of sections 2042 to 2047 of this title, or section 208 of the First Supplemental Civil Functions Appropriation Act, 1941 (<ref>54 Stat. 1056</ref>; Public, No. 812, Seventy-sixth Congress), relating to the duties of the Architect of the Capitol with respect to the House of Representatives Restaurant.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title IV, § 486</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1197</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1847.</num>
<heading> Authorization to fix basic rate of compensation for certain positions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1959-08-21">August 21, 1959</date>, the Architect of the Capitol is authorized, without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, to fix the compensation of four positions under the appropriation “Salaries, Office of the Architect of the Capitol”, of two positions under the appropriation “Capitol Buildings”, and of one position under the appropriation “House Office Buildings” at a basic rate of $8,200 per annum each: <i>Provided</i>, That this provision shall not be applicable to the positions of Architect or Assistant Architect.</p>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1959-08-21">August 21, 1959</date>, the Architect of the Capitol is authorized, without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, to fix the compensation of one position under the appropriation “Senate Office Buildings”, at a basic rate of $8,200 per annum.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–176</ref>, <date date="1959-08-21">Aug. 21, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–309</ref>, ch. VII, <date date="1965-10-31">Oct. 31, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–206, title II, § 214(p)</ref>, <date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 638</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–239</ref>, ch. IV, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–157, title I</ref>, ch. IV, <date date="1975-12-18">Dec. 18, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 835</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title I, § 106(c)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1056</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1848.</num>
<heading> Compensation of certain positions in Office of Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of compensation to be that specified in appropriations Acts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the pay for positions described in subsection (b) shall be the amounts specified for such positions in appropriations Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Positions covered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The positions referred to in subsection (a) are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the position of assistant referred to in the proviso in the first undesignated paragraph under the center subheadings “<inline class="small-caps">Office of the Architect of the Capitol</inline>” and “<inline class="small-caps">salaries</inline>” in the first section of the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1971 [<ref>2 U.S.C. 1804</ref>],<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002068">1</ref> and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the eight positions provided for in the third and fourth undesignated paragraphs under the center subheadings “<inline class="small-caps">Office of the Architect of the Capitol</inline>” and “<inline class="small-caps">salaries</inline>” in the first section of the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1960 [<ref>2 U.S.C. 1847</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Calculation of amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The pay for each position described in subsection (b) shall be the pay payable for such position with respect to the last pay period before this section takes effect, subject to any applicable adjustment during fiscal year 1988 under, or by reference to any applicable adjustment during fiscal year 1988 under, subchapter I of chapter 53 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply in fiscal years beginning after <date date="1987-09-30">September 30, 1987</date>, with respect to pay periods beginning after <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(i) [title III, § 308]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329–290</ref>, 1329–309; <ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title I, § 106(e)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1057</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1849.</num>
<heading> Compensation of certain positions under jurisdiction of Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol may fix the rate of basic pay for not more than 32 positions at a rate not to exceed the highest total rate of pay for the Senior Executive Service under subchapter VIII of chapter 53 of title 5 for the locality involved.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2268</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–90, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 459</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title III, § 311(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1201</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 129(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 580</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–117, div. B, § 914(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-10">Jan. 10, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2324</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–55, title I, § 1201(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 579</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–316, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3452</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1850.</num>
<heading> Compensation of registered nurses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, effective on the first day of the first applicable pay period which begins on or after <date date="1974-12-27">December 27, 1974</date>, the positions of registered nurses compensated under appropriations for Capitol Buildings, Senate Office Buildings, and House Office Buildings, shall be allocated by the Architect of the Capitol at not to exceed grade 12 of the General Schedule.</p>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, effective <date date="1975-01-01">January 1, 1975</date>, none of the funds appropriated to the Architect of the Capitol shall thereafter be available for any nursing position unless the position is occupied by a Registered Nurse: <i>Provided</i>, That such provision shall not be applicable to the present incumbents of such positions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–554, title I</ref>, ch. III, <date date="1974-12-27">Dec. 27, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2269</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–283, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1994-07-22">July 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1435</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1851.</num>
<heading> Gratuities for survivors of deceased employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Until otherwise provided by law, there is authorized to be paid out of the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives, on vouchers signed by the chairman of the Committee on House Oversight, a gratuity to the widow, widower, or heirs-at-law, of each deceased employee under the jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol who was assigned to duty in the House of Representatives at the time of his death. The payment of each such gratuity shall be in accordance with uniform rules and regulations adopted by the Committee on House Oversight except that no such gratuity shall be in excess of that payable to the widow, widower, or heirs-at-law of any deceased employee under the jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol having a comparable length of service, who was assigned to similar duties in the Senate at the time of his death.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–454, § 103</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 550</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 221(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1852.</num>
<heading> Withholding and remittance of State income tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement by Architect with appropriate State official; covered individuals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the law of any State provides for the collection of an income tax by imposing upon employers generally the duty of withholding sums from the compensation of employees and remitting such sums to the authorities of such State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such duty to withhold is imposed generally with respect to the compensation of employees who are residents of such State;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the Architect of the Capitol is authorized, in accordance with the provisions of this section, to enter into an agreement with the appropriate official of that State to provide for the withholding and remittance of sums for individuals—</continuation>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> employed by the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, the United States Botanic Garden, or the Senate Restaurant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> who request the Architect to make such withholdings for remittance to that State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Number of remittances authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any agreement entered into under subsection (a) of this section shall not require the Architect to remit such sums more often than once each calendar quarter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests for withholding and remittance; amount of withholding; number and effective date of requests; change of designated State; revocation of request; rules and regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An individual employed by the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, the United States Botanic Garden, or the Senate Restaurant may request the Architect to withhold sums from his pay for remittance to the appropriate authorities of the State that he designates. Amounts of withholdings shall be made in accordance with those provisions of the law of that State which apply generally to withholding by employers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An individual may have in effect at any time only one request for withholdings, and he may not have more than two such requests in effect with respect to different States during any one calendar year. The request for withholdings is effective on the first day of the first pay period commencing on or after the day on which the request is received in the Office of the Architect, the Botanic Garden Office, or the Senate Restaurant Accounting Office except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> when the Architect first enters into an agreement with a State, a request for withholdings shall be effective on such date as the Architect may determine; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> when an individual first receives an appointment, the request shall be effective on the day of appointment, if the individual makes the request at the time of appointment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An individual may change the State designated by him for the purposes of having withholdings made and request that the withholdings be remitted in accordance with such change, and he may also revoke his request for withholdings. Any change in the State designated or revocation is effective on the first day of the first pay period commencing on or after the day on which the request for change or the revocation is received in the appropriate office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Architect is authorized to issue rules and regulations he considers appropriate in carrying out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time or times of agreements by Architect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect may enter into agreements under subsection (a) of this section at such time or times as he considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provisions as not imposing duty, burden, requirement or penalty upon United States or any officer or employee of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section imposes no duty, burden, or requirement upon the United States, or any officer or employee of the United States, except as specifically provided in this section. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to consent to the application of any provision of law which has the effect of subjecting the United States, or any officer or employee of the United States to any penalty or liability by reason of the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “State” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, “State” means any of the States of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–59, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1853.</num>
<heading> Exemption of officers and employees of Architect of Capitol from certain Federal pay provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The classes of employees whose compensation is authorized by section 3 of the Legislative Pay Act of 1929, as amended (<ref>46 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>55 Stat. 615</ref>), to be fixed by the Architect of the Capitol without regard to the Classification Act of 1923, as amended, are authorized to be compensated without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title II, § 204(a), <ref>63 Stat. 957</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1854.</num>
<heading> Overtime compensation for certain employees of Architect of Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For overtime pay purposes, per diem and per hour employees under the Office of the Architect of the Capitol not subject to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, shall be regarded as subject to the provisions of sections 5544(a) and 6102 of title 5, and sections 60e–3 and 60e–4 of this title shall not be applicable to such employees.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 30, 1945, ch. 212</ref>, title V, § 503, <ref>59 Stat. 301</ref>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref>63 Stat. 972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>APPROPRIATIONS AND EXPENDITURES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1861.</num>
<heading> Appropriations under control of Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations under the control of the Architect of the Capitol shall be available for expenses of advertising and personal and other services.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 28, 1929, ch. 367</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 1395</ref>; <ref>June 6, 1930, ch. 407</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 513</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1862.</num>
<heading> Transfer of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">During fiscal year 1997 and fiscal years thereafter, amounts appropriated to the Architect of the Capitol (including amounts relating to the Botanic Garden) may be transferred among accounts available to the Architect of the Capitol upon the approval of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, in the case of amounts transferred from the appropriation for Capitol buildings and grounds under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">house office buildings</inline>”;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, in the case of amounts transferred from the appropriation for Capitol buildings and grounds under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">senate office buildings</inline>”; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, in the case of amounts transferred from any other appropriation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2413</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1862a.</num>
<heading> Use of construction project funds to reimburse Capitol Police for related overtime costs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of overtime costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol shall transfer amounts made available for construction projects during a fiscal year to the applicable appropriations accounts of the United States Capitol Police in order to reimburse the Capitol Police for overtime costs incurred in connection with such projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2013 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. G, title I, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1128</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1862b.</num>
<heading> Transfer of amounts appropriated for Architect of the Capitol under House Office Buildings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> During fiscal year 2019 and each succeeding fiscal year, amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for the Architect of the Capitol under the heading “House Office Buildings” may be transferred to the House of Representatives and merged with and made available under the heading “Allowances and Expenses”, subject to the approval of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The period of availability of any amounts transferred to the House of Representatives under this section shall be the same period of availability applicable to such amounts as appropriated for the Architect of the Capitol.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The aggregate amount transferred under this section in any fiscal year may not exceed $30,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–6, div. H, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2019-02-15">Feb. 15, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 476</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1863.</num>
<heading> Funds out of Contingent Expenses, Architect of the Capitol Appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any expenditures required to implement the provisions of <ref>section 1818 of this title</ref> shall be paid from the appropriation “Contingent Expenses, Architect of the Capitol” and any funds appropriated under this head shall hereafter be available for such purpose.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–180, § 2</ref>, <date date="1973-12-13">Dec. 13, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 705</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1864.</num>
<heading> Funds out of Capitol Buildings, Architect of the Capitol Appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1986-10-18">October 18, 1986</date>, the Architect of the Capitol may incur expenses authorized by <ref>section 1818 of this title</ref> to be paid from the appropriation “Capitol Buildings, Architect of the Capitol”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(j)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–287</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(j)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–287</ref>, as amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–71, title I</ref>, <date date="1987-07-11">July 11, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1865.</num>
<heading> Capitol Police Buildings and Grounds Account</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States an account for the Architect of the Capitol to be known as “Capitol Police Buildings and Grounds” (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “account”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Funds in the account shall be used by the Architect of the Capitol for all necessary expenses for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> resilience and security programs of the Architect of the Capitol; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the maintenance, care, and operation of buildings, grounds, and security enhancements for facilities of the United States Capitol Police and for other facilities associated with such resilience and security programs at any location.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of transfers of appropriations from Legislative Branch agencies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For carrying out the purposes of the account, the Architect of the Capitol may receive transfers of appropriations from any agency of the Legislative Branch upon the approval of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, in the case of a transfer from an office of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, in the case of a transfer from an office of the Senate; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, in the case of a transfer from any other office of the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts transferred under this subsection shall be merged with the account and made available under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> This subsection shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2019 and each succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date; transfer of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2002 and each succeeding fiscal year. Any amounts provided to the Architect of the Capitol prior to <date date="2002-08-02">August 2, 2002</date>, for the maintenance, care, and operation of buildings of the United States Capitol Police during fiscal year 2002 shall be transferred to the account.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–206, title I, § 906</ref>, <date date="2002-08-02">Aug. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 877</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–244, div. B, title I, § 132</ref>, <date date="2018-09-21">Sept. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2936</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1866.</num>
<heading> Certification of vouchers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall not be a duty of the Architect of the Capitol to certify any pay roll or other voucher covering any expenditure from any appropriation for the Senate Office Building, or for any other building or activity, unless the obligation involved was incurred by him or under his direction.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 8, 1942, ch. 396</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 343</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1867.</num>
<heading> Advancement and reimbursement of expenses for flying American flags and providing certification services therefor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1995-11-19">November 19, 1995</date>, expenses, based on full cost recovery, for flying American flags and providing certification services therefor shall be advanced or reimbursed upon request of the Architect of the Capitol, and amounts so received shall be deposited into the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–53, title I</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1868.</num>
<heading> Semiannual compilation and report of expenditures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Commencing with the semiannual period beginning <date date="1965-01-01">January 1, 1965</date> and for each semiannual period thereafter, the Architect of the Capitol shall compile and, not later than sixty days following the close of the semiannual period, submit to the Senate and the House of Representatives a report of all expenditures made from monies appropriated to the Architect of the Capitol, based on payrolls and other vouchers transmitted during such period to the Treasury Department for disbursement, such report to include (1) the name, title, and gross salary payment to each employee; (2) a list of government contributions to retirement, health, insurance, and other similar funds; and (3) name of payee, brief description of service rendered or items furnished under contract, purchase order or other agreement. Such report shall be printed as a Senate document.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The report by the Architect of the Capitol under paragraph (1) for the semiannual period beginning on <date date="1976-01-01">January 1, 1976</date>, shall include the period beginning on <date date="1976-07-01">July 1, 1976</date>, and ending on <date date="1976-09-30">September 30, 1976</date>, and such semiannual period shall be treated as closing on <date date="1976-09-30">September 30, 1976</date>. Thereafter, the report by the Architect of the Capitol under paragraph (1) shall be for the semiannual periods beginning on October 1 and ending on March 31 and beginning on April 1 and ending on September 30 of each year.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 88–454, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 551</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–303, title I, § 118(c)</ref>, <date date="1976-06-01">June 1, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 616</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1868a.</num>
<heading> Semiannual report of disbursements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after the last day of each semiannual period, the Architect of the Capitol shall submit to Congress, with respect to that period, a detailed, itemized report of the disbursements for the operations of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name of each person who receives a payment from the Office of the Architect of the Capitol;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the quantity and price of any item furnished to the Office of the Architect of the Capitol;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of any service rendered to the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, together with a statement of the time required for the service, and the name, title, and amount paid to each person who renders the service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a statement of all amounts appropriated to, or received or expended by, the Office of the Architect of the Capitol and any unexpended balances of such amounts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the information submitted to the Comptroller General under <ref>section 3523(b) of title 31</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> such additional information as may be required by regulation of the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Printing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each report under this section shall be printed as a House document.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to the semiannual periods of January 1 through June 30 and July 1 through December 31 of each year, beginning with the semiannual period in which this section is enacted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. I, title I, § 1301</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 428</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1869.</num>
<heading> Advance payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During fiscal year 2008 and each succeeding fiscal year, following notification of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Architect of the Capitol may make payments in advance for obligations of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol for subscription services if the Architect determines it to be more prompt, efficient, or economical to do so.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1304</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1870.</num>
<heading> House Historic Buildings Revitalization Trust Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States, as an account for the Architect of the Capitol, the House Historic Buildings Revitalization Trust Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Fund”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts in the Fund shall be used by the Architect of the Capitol for the revitalization of the major historical buildings and assets of the House of Representatives which the Architect is responsible for maintaining and preserving, except that the Architect may not obligate any amounts in the Fund without the approval of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amounts transferred to and merged with, or otherwise deposited into, the Fund shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section and the amendment made by this section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2010 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–68, div. A, title I, § 1304</ref>, <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2035</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1871.</num>
<heading> Expired appropriations available for deposit into Employees’ Compensation Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding section 1101, available balances of expired Architect of the Capitol appropriations shall be available to the Architect of the Capitol to make the deposit to the credit of the Employees’ Compensation Fund required by <ref>section 8147(b) of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to appropriations for fiscal year 2013 and each year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–6, div. F, title VI, § 1606</ref>, <date date="2013-03-26">Mar. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1872.</num>
<heading> Use of expired funds for unemployment compensation payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Available balances of expired Architect of the Capitol appropriations shall be available to the Architect of the Capitol for reimbursing the Federal Employees Compensation Account (as established by <ref>section 1109 of title 42</ref>) for any amounts paid with respect to unemployment compensation payments for former employees of the Architect of the Capitol, notwithstanding any other provision of law, without regard to the fiscal year for which the obligation to make such payments is incurred.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2017 and each succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–31, div. I, title I, § 1204</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 581</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1873.</num>
<heading> Acceptance of travel expenses from non-Federal sources</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permitting acceptance of expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Architect of the Capitol may accept payment or authorize an employee of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol to accept payment on the Office’s behalf from non-Federal sources for travel, subsistence, and related expenses with respect to attendance of the employee (or the spouse of such employee) at any meeting or similar function relating to the employee’s official duties. Any cash payment so accepted shall be credited to the appropriation applicable to such expenses. In the case of a payment in kind so accepted, a pro rata reduction shall be made in any entitlement of the employee to payment from the Government for such expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibiting acceptance from other sources</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in this section or <ref>section 7342 of title 5</ref>, the Office or an employee of the Office may not accept payment for expenses referred to in subsection (a). An employee who accepts any payment in violation of the preceding sentence—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may be required, in addition to any penalty provided by law, to repay, for deposit in the general fund of the Treasury, an amount equal to the amount of the payment so accepted; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a repayment under paragraph (1), shall not be entitled to any payment from the Government for such expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2019 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–244, div. B, title I, § 135</ref>, <date date="2018-09-21">Sept. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2937</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>CAPITOL-FLOWN FLAGS FOR FAMILIES OF FALLEN HEROES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1881.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Capitol-flown flag” means a flag of the United States flown over the Capitol in honor of the deceased individual for whom the flag is requested;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the terms “chaplain”, “firefighter”, “law enforcement officer”, “member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew”, and “public agency” have the meanings given such terms in <ref>section 10284 of title 34</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “immediate family member”, with respect to an individual, means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the spouse, parent, brother, sister, or child of the individual or a person to whom the individual stands in loco parentis; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other person related to the individual by blood or marriage;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “public safety officer” means an individual serving a public agency in an official capacity, with or without compensation, as a law enforcement officer, as a firefighter, or as a chaplain; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “Representative” includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–156, § 2</ref>, <date date="2016-05-16">May 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 391</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1881a.</num>
<heading> Providing Capitol-flown flags for families of fallen heroes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of an immediate family member of a firefighter, law enforcement officer, member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew, or public safety officer who died in the line of duty, the Representative or Senator of the family may provide to the family a Capitol-flown flag, together with the certificate described in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No cost to family</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Capitol-flown flag provided under this section shall be provided at no cost to the family.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certificate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The certificate described in this subsection is a certificate which is signed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Representative, or the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Senator, providing the Capitol-flown flag, as applicable, and which contains an expression of sympathy for the family involved from the House of Representatives or the Senate, as applicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–156, § 3</ref>, <date date="2016-05-16">May 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 391</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1881b.</num>
<heading> Regulations and procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 30 days after <date date="2016-05-16">May 16, 2016</date>, the Architect of the Capitol shall issue regulations for carrying out this subchapter, including regulations to establish procedures (including any appropriate forms, guidelines, and accompanying certificates) for requesting a Capitol-flown flag.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The regulations issued under subsection (a) shall take effect upon approval by the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–156, § 4</ref>, <date date="2016-05-16">May 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 392</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1881c.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2028 such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subchapter, to be derived from amounts appropriated in each such fiscal year for the operation of the Architect of the Capitol, except that the aggregate amount appropriated to carry out this subchapter for all such fiscal years may not exceed $40,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–156, § 5</ref>, <date date="2016-05-16">May 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. I, title I, § 131</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1881d.</num>
<heading> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter shall take effect on <date date="2016-05-16">May 16, 2016</date>, except that a Capitol-flown flag may not be provided under <ref>section 1881a of this title</ref> until the regulations issued under <ref>section 1881b(a) of this title</ref> take effect in accordance with <ref>section 1881b(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–156, § 6</ref>, <date date="2016-05-16">May 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 392</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>