<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 61—</num>
<heading>SENATE LEADERSHIP</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6101.</num>
<heading> Transfer of funds from appropriations account of the Office of the Vice President and the Offices of the Secretaries for the Majority and Minority to the Senate contingent fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of the Vice President</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the written request of the Vice President, the Secretary of the Senate shall transfer from the appropriations account appropriated under the subheading “<inline class="small-caps">office of the vice president</inline>” under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">Salaries, Officers and Employees</inline>” such amount as the Vice President shall specify to the appropriations account under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">miscellaneous items</inline>” within the contingent fund of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to incur expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Vice President may incur such expenses as may be necessary or appropriate. Expenses incurred by the Vice President shall be paid from the amount transferred under paragraph (1) by the Vice President and upon vouchers approved by the Vice President.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to advance sums</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of the Senate may advance such sums as may be necessary to defray expenses incurred in carrying out paragraphs (1) and (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offices of the Secretaries for the Majority and Minority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the written request of the Secretary for the Majority or the Secretary for the Minority, the Secretary of the Senate shall transfer from the appropriations account appropriated under the subheading “<inline class="small-caps">offices of the secretaries for the majority and minority</inline>” under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">Salaries, Officers and Employees</inline>” such amount as the Secretary for the Majority or the Secretary for the Minority shall specify to the appropriations account under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">miscellaneous items</inline>” within the contingent fund of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to incur expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary for the Majority or the Secretary for the Minority may incur such expenses as may be necessary or appropriate. Expenses incurred by the Secretary for the Majority or the Secretary for the Minority shall be paid from the amount transferred under paragraph (1) by the Secretary for the Majority or the Secretary for the Minority and upon vouchers approved by the Secretary for the Majority or the Secretary for the Minority, as applicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to advance sums</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of the Senate may advance such sums as may be necessary to defray expenses incurred in carrying out paragraphs (1) and (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2005 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 5</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3169</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6102.</num>
<heading> Expense allowance of Majority and Minority Leaders of Senate; expense allowance of Majority and Minority Whips; methods of payment; taxability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective fiscal year 1978 and each fiscal year thereafter, the expense allowances of the Majority and Minority Leaders of the Senate are increased to $40,000 each fiscal year for each leader: <i>Provided</i>, That, effective with the fiscal year 1983 and each fiscal year thereafter, the expense allowance of the Majority and Minority Whips of the Senate shall not exceed $10,000 each fiscal year for each Whip: <i>Provided further</i>, That, during the period beginning on <date date="1977-01-03">January 3, 1977</date>, and ending <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>, and during each fiscal year thereafter, the Vice President, the Majority Leader, the Minority Leader, the Majority Whip, and the Minority Whip may receive the expense allowance (a) as reimbursement for actual expenses incurred upon certification and documentation of such expenses by the Vice President, the respective Leader or the respective Whip, or (b) in equal monthly payments: <i>Provided further</i>, That effective <date date="1977-01-03">January 3, 1977</date>, the amounts paid to the Vice President, the Majority or Minority Leader of the Senate, or the Majority or Minority Whip of the Senate as reimbursement of actual expenses incurred upon certification and documentation pursuant to the second proviso of this section shall not be reported as income, and the expenses so reimbursed shall not be allowed as a deduction, under title 26.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–26, title I</ref>, <date date="1977-05-04">May 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 79</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–355, title I</ref>, <date date="1978-09-08">Sept. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 532</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–63, title I</ref>, <date date="1983-07-30">July 30, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 333</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 13(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3171</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>VICE PRESIDENT AND PRESIDENT PRO TEMPORE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6111.</num>
<heading> Compensation of President pro tempore of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever there is no Vice President, the President of the Senate for the time being is entitled to the compensation provided by law for the Vice President.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 36.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6112.</num>
<heading> Compensation of Deputy President pro tempore of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1977-01-05">January 5, 1977</date>, the compensation of a Deputy President pro tempore of the Senate shall be at a rate equal to the rate of annual compensation of the President pro tempore and the Majority and Minority Leaders of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–26, title I</ref>, <date date="1977-05-04">May 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 79</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6113.</num>
<heading> Appointment and compensation of employees by President pro tempore of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>, the President pro tempore is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of such employees as he deems appropriate: <i>Provided</i>, That the gross compensation paid to such employees shall not exceed $123,000 each fiscal year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–38, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1979-07-25">July 25, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 111</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6114.</num>
<heading> Appointment and compensation of Administrative Assistant, Legislative Assistant, and Executive Secretary for Deputy President pro tempore of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1977-04-01">April 1, 1977</date>, the Deputy President pro tempore is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of an Administrative Assistant at not to exceed $47,595 per annum; a Legislative Assistant at not to exceed $40,080 per annum, and an Executive Secretary at not to exceed $23,380 per annum.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–26, title I</ref>, <date date="1977-05-04">May 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 80</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6115.</num>
<heading> Expense allowance of President pro tempore of Senate; methods of payment; taxability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective with fiscal year 1978 and each fiscal year thereafter, there is hereby authorized an expense allowance for the President Pro Tempore which shall not exceed $40,000 each fiscal year. The President Pro Tempore may receive the expense allowance (1) as reimbursement for actual expenses incurred upon certification and documentation of such expenses by the President Pro Tempore, or (2) in equal monthly payments. Such amounts paid to the President Pro Tempore as reimbursement of actual expenses incurred upon certification and documentation pursuant to this provision, shall not be reported as income, and the expenses so reimbursed shall not be allowed as a deduction, under title 26.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–355, title I</ref>, <date date="1978-09-08">Sept. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 532</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 13(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3171</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6116.</num>
<heading> Special delivery postage allowance for President of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is authorized and directed to procure and furnish each fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>) to the President of the Senate, upon request by such person, United States special delivery postage stamps in such amount as may be necessary for the mailing of postal matters arising in connection with his official business.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–51, § 127(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6117.</num>
<heading> Stationery allowance for President of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1975-04-01">April 1, 1975</date>, and each fiscal year thereafter, the annual allowance for stationery for the President of the Senate shall be $8,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 1, 1941, ch. 268</ref>, <ref>55 Stat. 450</ref>; <ref>June 13, 1945, ch. 189</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 244</ref>; <ref>June 14, 1948, ch. 467</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 425</ref>; <ref>Oct. 11, 1951, ch. 485</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 391</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1953, ch. 304</ref>, title I, <ref>67 Stat. 320</ref>; <ref>Aug. 5, 1955, ch. 568</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–258, title IV</ref>, <date date="1964-01-06">Jan. 6, 1964</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 864</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–21, title I</ref>, <date date="1967-05-29">May 29, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–145</ref>, <date date="1969-12-12">Dec. 12, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 342</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–51</ref>, <date date="1971-07-09">July 9, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 128</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–184</ref>, ch. IV, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 635</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–607</ref>, ch. V, § 506(k)(3), formerly § 506(h)(3), <date date="1972-10-31">Oct. 31, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1508</ref>, renumbered § 506(i)(3), <ref>Pub. L. 95–391, title I, § 108(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 773</ref>, renumbered § 506(j)(3), <ref>Pub. L. 96–304, title I, § 101(e)</ref>, <date date="1980-07-08">July 8, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 889</ref>, renumbered § 506(k)(3), <ref>Pub. L. 97–276, § 101(e)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-02">Oct. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1189</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–32, title I</ref>, <date date="1975-06-12">June 12, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 349</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6118.</num>
<heading> Long-distance telephone calls for Vice President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Commencing <date date="1949-01-20">January 20, 1949</date>, the provisions of existing law relating to long-distance telephone calls for Senators shall be equally applicable to the Vice President of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 138</ref>, title I, <ref>63 Stat. 77</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>MAJORITY AND MINORITY LEADERS AND WHIPS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6131.</num>
<heading> Appointment of employees by Senate Majority and Minority Leaders; compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1977-04-01">April 1, 1977</date>, the Majority Leader and the Minority Leader are each authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of such employees as they deem appropriate: <i>Provided</i>, That the gross compensation paid to such employees shall not exceed $191,700 each fiscal year for each Leader.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–26, title I</ref>, <date date="1977-05-04">May 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 80</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6132.</num>
<heading> Assistants to Senate Majority and Minority Leaders for Floor Operations; establishment of positions; appointment; compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, there is established within the Offices of the Majority and Minority Leaders the positions of Assistant to the Majority Leader for Floor Operations and Assistant to the Minority Leader for Floor Operations, respectively. Individuals appointed to such positions by the Majority Leader and Minority Leader, respectively, shall receive compensation at a rate fixed by the appropriate Leader not to exceed the maximum annual rate of gross compensation of the Assistant Secretary of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–51, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-07-14">July 14, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6133.</num>
<heading> Chiefs of Staff for Senate Majority and Minority Leaders; appointment; compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is established within the Offices of the Majority and Minority Leaders the positions of Chief of Staff for the Majority Leader and Chief of Staff for the Minority Leader, respectively. Individuals appointed to such positions by the Majority Leader and Minority Leader, respectively, shall receive compensation at a rate fixed by the appropriate Leader.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Gross compensation for employees filling positions established by subsection (a) for the fiscal year ending <date date="1987-09-30">September 30, 1987</date>, shall be paid out of any funds available in the Senate appropriation for such year under the item “Salaries, Officers and Employees”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title I, § 9</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1046</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(F)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2776</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6134.</num>
<heading> Compensation and appointment of employees by Senate Majority and Minority Whips</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1977-04-01">April 1, 1977</date>, the Majority Whip and the Minority Whip are each authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of such employees as they deem appropriate: <i>Provided</i>, That the gross compensation paid to such employees shall not exceed $111,100 each fiscal year for each Whip.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–26, title I</ref>, <date date="1977-05-04">May 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 80</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6135.</num>
<heading> Representation Allowance Account for Majority and Minority Leaders of Senate</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established an account, within the Senate, to be known as the “Representation Allowance Account for the Majority and Minority Leaders”. Such Allowance Account shall be used by the Majority and Minority Leaders of the Senate to assist them properly to discharge their appropriate responsibilities in the United States to members of foreign legislative bodies and prominent officials of foreign governments and intergovernmental organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments; allotment; reimbursement for actual expenses; taxability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payments authorized to be made under this section shall be paid by the Secretary of the Senate. Of the funds available for expenditure from such Allowance Account for any fiscal year, one-half shall be allotted to the Majority Leader and one-half shall be allotted to the Minority Leader. Amounts paid from such Allowance Account to the Majority or Minority Leader shall be paid to him from his allotment and shall be paid to him only as reimbursement for actual expenses incurred by him and upon certification and documentation of such expenses. Amounts paid to the Majority or Minority Leader pursuant to this section shall not be reported as income and shall not be allowed as a deduction under title 26.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>) not more than $20,000 to the Allowance Account established by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–88, title I, § 197</ref>, <date date="1985-08-15">Aug. 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 350</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6136.</num>
<heading> Transfer of funds from representation allowance of Majority and Minority Leaders of Senate to expense allowance; availability; definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Senate shall, upon the written request of the Majority or Minority Leader of the Senate, transfer from any available funds in such Leader’s allotment in the Leader’s Representation Allowance (as defined in subsection (b)(1)) for any fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>) to such Leader’s Expense Allowance (as defined in subsection (b)(2)) to such year such amount as is specified in the request. Any funds so transferred for any fiscal year at the request of either such Leader shall be available to such Leader for such year for the same purposes as, and in like manner and subject to the same conditions as, are other funds which are available to him for such year as his expense allowance as Majority or Minority Leader.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “Leader’s Representation Allowance” means the Representation Allowance Account for the Majority and Minority Leaders established by <ref>section 6135 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “Leader’s Expense Allowance”, when used in reference to the Majority or Minority Leader of the Senate, refers to the moneys available, for any fiscal year, to such Leader as an expense allowance and the appropriation account from which such moneys are funded.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–71, title I, § 1</ref>, <date date="1987-07-11">July 11, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6137.</num>
<heading> Transfer of funds from appropriations account of Majority and Minority Leaders of Senate to appropriations account, Miscellaneous Items, within Senate contingent fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests for transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the written request of the Majority or Minority Leader of the Senate, the Secretary of the Senate shall transfer during any fiscal year, from the appropriations account appropriated under the headings “Salaries, Officers and Employees” and “Offices of the Majority and Minority Leaders”, such amount as either Leader shall specify to the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, “Miscellaneous Items”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to incur expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Majority and Minority Leaders of the Senate are each authorized to incur such expenses as may be necessary or appropriate. Expenses incurred by either such leader shall be paid from the amount transferred pursuant to subsection (a) by such leader and upon vouchers approved by such leader.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to advance sums</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to advance such sums as may be necessary to defray expenses incurred in carrying out subsections (a) and (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–27, title II</ref>, <date date="1991-04-10">Apr. 10, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 144</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6138.</num>
<heading> Transfer of funds from appropriations account of Majority and Minority Whips of Senate to appropriations account, Miscellaneous Items, within Senate contingent fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests for transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the written request of the Majority or Minority Whip of the Senate, the Secretary of the Senate shall transfer during any fiscal year, from the appropriations account appropriated under the headings “<inline class="small-caps">Salaries, Officers and Employees</inline>” and “<inline class="small-caps">offices of the majority and minority whips</inline>”, such amount as either whip shall specify to the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, “<inline class="small-caps">miscellaneous items</inline>”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to incur expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Majority and Minority Whips of the Senate are each authorized to incur such expenses as may be necessary or appropriate. Expenses incurred by either such whip shall be paid from the amount transferred pursuant to subsection (a) by such whip and upon vouchers approved by such whip.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to advance sums</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to advance such sums as may be necessary to defray expenses incurred in carrying out subsections (a) and (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title I, § 2</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>MAJORITY AND MINORITY SECRETARIES, CONFERENCES, AND POLICY COMMITTEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6151.</num>
<heading> Compensation of Secretaries for Senate Majority and Minority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary for the Majority of the Senate (other than the incumbent holding office on <date date="1977-04-01">April 1, 1977</date>) and the Secretary for the Minority of the Senate shall each be paid at an annual rate of compensation of $39,500.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–371, § 4</ref>, <date date="1974-08-13">Aug. 13, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–59, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–26, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-05-04">May 4, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 82</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6152.</num>
<heading> Appointment and compensation of employees by Secretaries for Senate Majority and Minority; gross compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1977-10-01">October 1, 1977</date>, the Secretary for the Majority and the Secretary for the Minority are each authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of such employees as they deem appropriate: <i>Provided</i>, That the gross compensation paid to such employees shall not exceed $143,200 each fiscal year for each Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title I</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 658</ref>, 659.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6153.</num>
<heading> Salaries and expenses for Senate Majority and Minority Policy Committees and Senate Majority and Minority Conference Committees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds for Policy Committees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Majority or Minority Policy Committee of the Senate may, during any fiscal year, at his or her election transfer funds from the appropriation account for salaries for the Majority and Minority Policy Committees of the Senate, to the account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, from which expenses are payable for such committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Majority or Minority Policy Committee of the Senate may, during any fiscal year, at his or her election transfer funds from the appropriation account for expenses, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for the Majority and Minority Policy Committees of the Senate, to the account from which salaries are payable for such committees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds for Conference Committees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Majority or Minority Conference Committee of the Senate may, during any fiscal year, at his or her election transfer funds from the appropriation account for salaries for the Majority and Minority Conference Committees of the Senate, to the account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, from which expenses are payable for such committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Majority or Minority Conference Committee of the Senate may, during any fiscal year, at his or her election transfer funds from the appropriation account for expenses, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for the Majority and Minority Conference Committees of the Senate, to the account from which salaries are payable for such committees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds by Chaplain of the Senate</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chaplain of the Senate may, during any fiscal year, at the election of the Chaplain of the Senate, transfer funds from the appropriation account for salaries for the Office of the Chaplain of the Senate to the account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, from which expenses are payable for the Office of the Chaplain.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chaplain of the Senate may, during any fiscal year, at the election of the Chaplain of the Senate, transfer funds from the appropriation account for expenses, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for the Office of the Chaplain to the account from which salaries are payable for the Office of the Chaplain of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of transferred funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any funds transferred under this section shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> available for expenditure by such committee or the Office of the Chaplain of the Senate, as the case may be, in like manner and for the same purposes as are other moneys which are available for expenditure by such committee or the Office of the Chaplain of the Senate, as the case may be, from the account to which the funds were transferred; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> made at such time or times as the Chairman or the Chaplain of the Senate, as the case may be, shall specify in writing to the Senate Disbursing Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification to Committee on Appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chairman of a committee or the Chaplain of the Senate, as the case may be, transferring funds under this section shall notify the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate of the transfer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title I, § 1</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2257</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–90, title I, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–53, title I, § 7[(a)]</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 518</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. I, title I, § 2</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2657</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6154.</num>
<heading> Offices of the Secretaries of the Conference of the Majority and the Conference of the Minority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the written request of the Secretary of the Conference of the Majority or the Secretary of the Conference of the Minority, the Secretary of the Senate shall transfer from the appropriations account appropriated under the subheading “<inline class="small-caps">offices of the secretaries of the conference of the majority and the conference of the minority</inline>” under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">Salaries, Officers and Employees</inline>” such amount as the Secretary of the Conference of the Majority or the Secretary of the Conference of the Minority shall specify to the appropriations account under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">miscellaneous items</inline>” within the contingent fund of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to incur expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Conference of the Majority or the Secretary of the Conference of the Minority may incur such expenses as may be necessary or appropriate. Expenses incurred by the Secretary of the Conference of the Majority or the Secretary of the Conference of the Minority shall be paid from the amount transferred under subsection (a) by the Secretary of the Conference of the Majority or the Secretary of the Conference of the Minority and upon vouchers approved by the Secretary of the Conference of the Majority or the Secretary of the Conference of the Minority, as applicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to advance sums</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate may advance such sums as may be necessary to defray expenses incurred in carrying out subsections (a) and (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 3</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6155.</num>
<heading> Payment of expenses of Conference of Majority and Conference of Minority from Senate contingent fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each fiscal year (beginning with the fiscal year which ends <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>) there is authorized to be expended from the contingent fund of the Senate such amount as necessary for the Conference of the Majority and an equal amount for the Conference of the Minority. Payments under this section shall be made only for expenses actually incurred by such a Conference in carrying out its functions, and shall be made upon certification and documentation of the expenses involved, by the Chairman of the Conference claiming payment hereunder and upon vouchers approved by such Chairman and by the Committee on Rules and Administration, except that vouchers shall not be required for payment of long-distance telephone calls.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–51, § 120</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 965</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–276, § 101(e)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-02">Oct. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1189</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–151, title I, § 1</ref>, <date date="1985-11-13">Nov. 13, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 794</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title I</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1043</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title I</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1010</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6156.</num>
<heading> Appointment and compensation of employees by Secretary of Conference of Majority of Senate and Secretary of Conference of Minority of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>, the Secretary of the Conference of the Majority and the Secretary of the Conference of the Minority are each authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of such employees as they deem appropriate: <i>Provided</i>, That the gross compensation paid to such employees shall not exceed $70,000 each fiscal year for each Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–38, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1979-07-25">July 25, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 111</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6157.</num>
<heading> Services of consultants to Majority and Minority Conference Committee of Senate</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of expenditure with approval of Committee on Rules and Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds authorized to be expended under <ref>section 6155 of this title</ref> may be used by the Majority or Minority Conference Committee of the Senate, with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration, to procure the temporary services (not in excess of one year) or intermittent services of individual consultants, or organizations thereof, to make studies or advise the committee with respect to any matter within its jurisdiction or with respect to the administration of the affairs of the committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procurement by contract or employment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Such services in the case of individuals or organizations may be procured by contract as independent contractors, or in the case of individuals, by employment at daily rates of compensation not in excess of the per diem equivalent of the highest gross rate of compensation which may be paid to a regular employee of such committee. Such contracts shall not be subject to the provisions of <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref> or any other provision of law requiring advertising.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of consultant or organization by Conference Committee chairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any such consultant or organization shall be selected for the Majority or Minority Conference Committee of the Senate by the chairman thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–88, title I, § 195</ref>, <date date="1985-08-15">Aug. 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title I, § 1</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2396</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6158.</num>
<heading> Utilization of funds for specialized training of professional staff for Majority and Minority Conference Committee of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds appropriated to the Conference of the Majority and funds appropriated to the Conference of the Minority for any fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="1991-09-30">September 30, 1991</date>), may be utilized in such amounts as the Chairman of each Conference deems appropriate for the specialized training of professional staff, subject to such limitations, insofar as they are applicable, as are imposed by the Committee on Rules and Administration with respect to such training when provided to professional staff of standing committees of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title I, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6159.</num>
<heading> Expense allowance for Chairmen of Majority and Minority Conference Committees of Senate; method of payment; taxability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>), there is hereby authorized an expense allowance for the Chairmen of the Majority and Minority Conference Committees which shall not exceed $5,000 each fiscal year for each such Chairman; and amounts from such allowance shall be paid to either of such Chairmen only as reimbursement for actual expenses incurred by him and upon certification and documentation of such expenses, and amounts so paid shall not be reported as income and shall not be allowed as a deduction under title 26.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–88, title I</ref>, <date date="1985-08-15">Aug. 15, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 348</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 349</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6160.</num>
<heading> Expense allowance for Chairmen of Majority and Minority Policy Committees of Senate; method of payment; taxability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="2001-09-30">September 30, 2001</date>), there is authorized an expense allowance for the Chairmen of the Majority and Minority Policy Committees which shall not exceed $5,000 each fiscal year for each such Chairman; and amounts from such allowance shall be paid to either of such Chairmen only as reimbursement for actual expenses incurred by him and upon certification and documentation of such expenses, and amounts so paid shall not be reported as income and shall not be allowed as a deduction under title 26.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(2) [title I, § 5]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–97; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1(e)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 349</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>