<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 24—</num>
<heading>CONGRESSIONAL ACCOUNTABILITY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise specifically provided in this chapter, as used in this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Board” means the Board of Directors of the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Chair” means the Chair of the Board of Directors of the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered employee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “covered employee” means any employee of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Capitol Police;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Congressional Budget Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Office of the Architect of the Capitol;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Office of the Attending Physician;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Office of Technology Assessment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the Library of Congress, except for <ref>section 1351 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “employee” includes an applicant for employment and a former employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employee of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “employee of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol” includes any employee of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol or the Botanic Garden.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employee of the Capitol Police</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “employee of the Capitol Police” includes any member or officer of the Capitol Police.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employee of the House of Representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “employee of the House of Representatives” includes an individual occupying a position the pay for which is disbursed by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, or another official designated by the House of Representatives, or any employment position in an entity that is paid with funds derived from the clerk-hire allowance of the House of Representatives but not any such individual employed by any entity listed in subparagraphs (C) through (K) of paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employee of the Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “employee of the Senate” includes any employee whose pay is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate, but not any such individual employed by any entity listed in subparagraphs (C) through (K) of paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employing office</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “employing office” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the personal office of a Member of the House of Representatives or of a Senator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate or a joint committee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other office headed by a person with the final authority to appoint, hire, discharge, and set the terms, conditions, or privileges of the employment of an employee of the House of Representatives or the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services, the United States Capitol Police, the Congressional Budget Office, the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, the Office of the Attending Physician, the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights, the Office of Technology Assessment, and the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Library of Congress, except for <ref>section 1351 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Executive Director” means the Executive Director of the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General Counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “General Counsel” means the General Counsel of the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Office” means the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Clarification of coverage of employees of certain commissions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coverage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">With respect to the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom, the China Review Commission, the Congressional-Executive China Commission, and the Helsinki Commission—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any individual who is an employee of such Commission shall be considered a covered employee for purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Commission shall be considered an employing office for purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to provide legal assistance and representation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (3), legal assistance and representation under this chapter, including assistance and representation with respect to the proposal or acceptance of the disposition of a claim under this chapter, shall be provided to the China Review Commission, the Congressional-Executive China Commission, and the Helsinki Commission—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> by the Office of House Employment Counsel of the House of Representatives, in the case of assistance and representation in connection with a claim filed under subchapter IV (including all subsequent proceedings under such subchapter in connection with the claim) at a time when the chair of the Commission is a Member of the House, and in the case of assistance and representation in connection with any subsequent claim under subchapter IV related to the initial claim where the subsequent claim involves the same parties; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by the Office of Senate Chief Counsel for Employment of the Senate, in the case of assistance and representation in connection with a claim filed under subchapter IV (including all subsequent proceedings under such subchapter in connection with the claim) at a time when the chair of the Commission is a Senator, and in the case of assistance and representation in connection with any subsequent claim under subchapter IV related to the initial claim where the subsequent claim involves the same parties.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Legal assistance and representation under this chapter, including assistance and representation with respect to the proposal or acceptance of the disposition of a claim under this chapter, shall be provided to the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom by the Office of Senate Chief Counsel for Employment of the Senate, in the case of assistance and representation in connection with a claim filed under subchapter IV (including all subsequent proceedings under such subchapter in connection with such claim).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “China Review Commission” means the United States-China Economic and Security Review Commission established under <ref>section 7002 of title 22</ref>, as enacted into law by <ref>section 1 of Public Law 106–398</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “Congressional-Executive China Commission” means the Congressional–Executive Commission on the People’s Republic of China established under title III of the U.S.–China Relations Act of 2000 (<ref>Public Law 106–286</ref>; <ref>22 U.S.C. 6911</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “Helsinki Commission” means the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe established under the Act entitled “An Act to establish a Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe”, approved <date date="1976-06-03">June 3, 1976</date> (<ref>Public Law 94–304</ref>; <ref>22 U.S.C. 3001</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the term “United States Commission on International Religious Freedom” means the Commission established under <ref>section 6431 of title 22</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 4</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–279, § 1(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-17">July 17, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2609</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title IV, § 422(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4996</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–145, § 2(a)(5)(A)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-04">Mar. 4, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 50</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 153(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 785</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title III</ref>, §§ 302(b), 305(a)–(c), 308(b)(1)–(7), <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5321</ref>, 5323, 5324, 5326; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII, § 805(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3077</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1302.</num>
<heading> Application of laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Laws made applicable</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following laws shall apply, as prescribed by this chapter, to the legislative branch of the Federal Government:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 621</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2611</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Chapter 71 (relating to Federal service labor-management relations) of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2001</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Chapter 43 (relating to veterans’ employment and reemployment) of title 38.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content><ref>Section 9202 of title 5</ref>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002055">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Laws which may be made applicable</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall review provisions of Federal law (including regulations) relating to (A) the terms and conditions of employment (including hiring, promotion, demotion, termination, salary, wages, overtime compensation, benefits, work assignments or reassignments, grievance and disciplinary procedures, protection from discrimination in personnel actions, occupational health and safety, and family and medical and other leave) of employees, and (B) access to public services and accommodations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Beginning on <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Board shall report on (A) whether or to what degree the provisions described in paragraph (1) are applicable or inapplicable to the legislative branch, and (B) with respect to provisions inapplicable to the legislative branch, whether such provisions should be made applicable to the legislative branch. The presiding officers of the House of Representatives and the Senate shall cause each such report to be printed in the Congressional Record and each such report shall be referred to the committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate with jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports of congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each report accompanying any bill or joint resolution relating to terms and conditions of employment or access to public services or accommodations reported by a committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> describe the manner in which the provisions of the bill or joint resolution apply to the legislative branch; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a provision not applicable to the legislative branch, include a statement of the reasons the provision does not apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">On the objection of any Member, it shall not be in order for the Senate or the House of Representatives to consider any such bill or joint resolution if the report of the committee on such bill or joint resolution does not comply with the provisions of this paragraph. This paragraph may be waived in either House by majority vote of that House.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of this chapter that apply to a violation of <ref>section 1311(a)(1) of this title</ref> shall be considered to apply to a violation of title II of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000ff</ref> et seq.), consistent with section 207(c) of that Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000ff–6(c)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No limitation on other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this section limits the provisions of this chapter that apply to a violation of a law described in subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A law described in this subparagraph is a law (even if not listed in subsection (a) or this subsection) that explicitly applies one or more provisions of this chapter to a violation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 5</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5320</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XI, § 1122(d)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>EXTENSION OF RIGHTS AND PROTECTIONS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Employment Discrimination, Family and Medical Leave, Fair Labor Standards, Employee Polygraph Protection, Worker Adjustment and Retraining, Employment and Reemployment of Veterans, and Intimidation</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1311.</num>
<heading> Rights and protections under title VII of Civil Rights Act of 1964, Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, Rehabilitation Act of 1973, and title I of Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discriminatory practices prohibited</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">All personnel actions affecting covered employees shall be made free from any discrimination based on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> race, color, religion, sex, or national origin, within the meaning of section 703 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e–2</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> age, within the meaning of section 15 of the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 633a</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> disability, within the meaning of section 501 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 791</ref>) and sections 102 through 104 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12112–121</ref>14).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The remedy for a violation of subsection (a)(1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under section 706(g) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e–5(g)</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such compensatory damages as would be appropriate if awarded under <ref>section 1981 of title 42</ref>, or as would be appropriate if awarded under sections 1981a(a)(1), 1981a(b)(2), and, irrespective of the size of the employing office, 1981a(b)(3)(D) of title 42.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Age discrimination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The remedy for a violation of subsection (a)(2) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under section 15(c) of the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 633a(c)</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such liquidated damages as would be appropriate if awarded under section 7(b) of such Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 626(b)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">In addition, the waiver provisions of section 7(f) of such Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 626(f)</ref>) shall apply to covered employees.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disabilities discrimination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The remedy for a violation of subsection (a)(3) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under section 505(a)(1) of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 794a(a)(1)</ref>) or section 107(a) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12117(a)</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such compensatory damages as would be appropriate if awarded under sections 1981a(a)(2), 1981a(a)(3), 1981a(b)(2), and, irrespective of the size of the employing office, 1981a(b)(3)(D) of title 42.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application to unpaid staff</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subsections (a) and (b) shall apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any staff member of an employing office who carries out official duties of the employing office but who is not paid by the employing office for carrying out such duties (referred to in this subsection as an “unpaid staff member”), including an intern, an individual detailed to an employing office, and an individual participating in a fellowship program, in the same manner and to the same extent as such subsections apply with respect to a covered employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a former unpaid staff member, if the act that may be a violation of subsection (a) occurred during the service of the former unpaid staffer for the employing office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in paragraph (1) may be construed to extend liability for a violation of subsection (a) to an employing office on the basis of an action taken by any person who is not under the supervision or control of the employing office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intern defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “intern” means an individual who performs service for an employing office which is uncompensated by the United States to earn credit awarded by an educational institution or to learn a trade or occupation, and includes any individual participating in a page program operated by any House of Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect 1 year after <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 7</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5321</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1312.</num>
<heading> Rights and protections under Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Family and medical leave rights and protections provided</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The rights and protections established by sections 101 through 105 of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2611</ref> through 2615) shall apply to covered employees. In applying section 102 of such Act [<ref>29 U.S.C. 2612</ref>] with respect to leave for an event described in subsection (a)(1)(A) or (B) of such section to covered employees, subsection (d) of this section shall apply. Paragraphs (1) and (4) of section 102(a) of such Act [<ref>29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)</ref>, (4)] shall be subject to subsection (d) of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of the application described in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “employer” as used in the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 means any employing office, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “eligible employee” as used in the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 means a covered employee who has been employed in any employing office for 12 months and for at least 1,250 hours of employment during the previous 12 months.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">The requirements of subparagraph (B) shall not apply with respect to leave under subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 102(a)(1) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)</ref>).</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy, including liquidated damages, as would be appropriate if awarded under paragraph (1) of section 107(a) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2617(a)(1)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for paid parental leave</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substitution of paid leave</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A covered employee may elect to substitute for any leave without pay under subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 102(a)(1) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)</ref>) any paid leave which is available to such employee for that purpose.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of paid leave</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The paid leave that is available to a covered employee for purposes of paragraph (1) is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of weeks of paid parental leave in connection with the birth or placement involved that corresponds to the number of administrative workweeks of paid parental leave available to employees under <ref>section 6382(d)(2)(B)(i) of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> during the 12-month period referred to in section 102(a)(1) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)</ref>) and in addition to the administrative workweeks described in subparagraph (A), any additional paid vacation, personal, family, medical, or accrued sick leave provided by the employing office to such employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section or section 102(d)(2)(A) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2612(d)(2)(A)</ref>) shall be considered to require or permit an employing office to require that an employee first use all or any portion of the leave described in paragraph (2)(B) before being allowed to use the paid parental leave described in paragraph (2)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paid parental leave under paragraph (2)(A)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be payable from any appropriation or fund available for salaries or expenses for positions within the employing office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if not used by the covered employee before the end of the 12-month period (as referred to in section 102(a)(1) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)</ref>)) to which it relates, shall not accumulate for any subsequent use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall apply without regard to the limitations in subparagraph (E), (F), or (G) of <ref>section 6382(d)(2) of title 5</ref> or section 104(c)(2) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2614(c)(2)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall, pursuant to <ref>section 1384 of this title</ref>, issue regulations to implement the rights and protections under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Labor to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsection (a) except insofar as the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subsections (a) and (b) shall be effective 1 year after <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government Accountability Office and Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subsection (c) shall be effective 1 year after transmission to the Congress of the study under <ref>section 1371 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. F, title LXXVI, § 7603(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2306</ref>, 2307; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1103(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3889</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1313.</num>
<heading> Rights and protections under Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fair labor standards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The rights and protections established by subsections (a)(1) and (d) of section 6, section 7, and section 12(c) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 206</ref> (a)(1) and (d), 207, 212(c)) shall apply to covered employees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interns</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the purposes of this section, the term “covered employee” does not include an intern as defined in regulations under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensatory time</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in regulations under subsection (c)(3) and in subsection (c)(4), covered employees may not receive compensatory time in lieu of overtime compensation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy, including liquidated damages, as would be appropriate if awarded under section 16(b) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 216(b)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations to implement section</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall, pursuant to <ref>section 1384 of this title</ref>, issue regulations to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (3), the regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Labor to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsection (a) except insofar as the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Irregular work schedules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall issue regulations for covered employees whose work schedules directly depend on the schedule of the House of Representatives or the Senate that shall be comparable to the provisions in the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 [<ref>29 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.] that apply to employees who have irregular work schedules.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Law enforcement personnel of the Capitol Police who are subject to the exemption under section 7(k) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 207(k)</ref>) may elect to receive compensatory time off in lieu of overtime compensation for hours worked in excess of the maximum for their work period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsections (a) and (b) shall be effective 1 year after <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 10</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2415</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1314.</num>
<heading> Rights and protections under Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Polygraph practices prohibited</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No employing office, irrespective of whether a covered employee works in that employing office, may require a covered employee to take a lie detector test where such a test would be prohibited if required by an employer under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of section 3 of the Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2002(1)</ref>, (2), or (3)). In addition, the waiver provisions of section 6(d) of such Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2005(d)</ref>) shall apply to covered employees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “covered employee” shall include employees of the Government Accountability Office and the term “employing office” shall include the Government Accountability Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capitol Police</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall preclude the Capitol Police from using lie detector tests in accordance with regulations under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under section 6(c)(1) of the Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2005(c)(1)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations to implement section</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall, pursuant to <ref>section 1384 of this title</ref>, issue regulations to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Labor to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsections (a) and (b) except insofar as the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), subsections (a) and (b) shall be effective 1 year after <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government Accountability Office and Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This section shall be effective with respect to the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress 1 year after transmission to the Congress of the study under <ref>section 1371 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 10</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 153(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 785</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1315.</num>
<heading> Rights and protections under Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Worker adjustment and retraining notification rights</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No employing office shall be closed or a mass layoff ordered within the meaning of section 3 of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2102</ref>) until the end of a 60-day period after the employing office serves written notice of such prospective closing or layoff to representatives of covered employees or, if there are no representatives, to covered employees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “covered employee” shall include employees of the Government Accountability Office and the term “employing office” shall include the Government Accountability Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under paragraphs (1), (2), and (4) of section 5(a) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2104(a)(1)</ref>, (2), and (4)).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations to implement section</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall, pursuant to <ref>section 1384 of this title</ref>, issue regulations to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Labor to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsection (a) except insofar as the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), subsections (a) and (b) shall be effective 1 year after <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government Accountability Office and Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This section shall be effective with respect to the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress 1 year after transmission to the Congress of the study under <ref>section 1371 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 153(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 785</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1316.</num>
<heading> Rights and protections relating to veterans’ employment and reemployment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment and reemployment rights of members of uniformed services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">It shall be unlawful for an employing office to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> discriminate, within the meaning of subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 4311 of title 38</ref>, against an eligible employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> deny to an eligible employee reemployment rights within the meaning of sections 4312 and 4313 of title 38; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> deny to an eligible employee benefits within the meaning of sections 4316, 4317, and 4318 of title 38.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “eligible employee” means a covered employee performing service in the uniformed services, within the meaning of <ref>section 4303(13) of title 38</ref>, whose service has not been terminated upon occurrence of any of the events enumerated in <ref>section 4304 of title 38</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “covered employee” includes employees of the Government Accountability Office, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “employing office” includes the Government Accountability Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under <ref>section 4323(d) of title 38</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations to implement section</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall, pursuant to <ref>section 1384 of this title</ref>, issue regulations to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Labor to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsection (a) except to the extent that the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), subsections (a) and (b) shall be effective 1 year after <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government Accountability Office and Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This section shall be effective with respect to the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress 1 year after transmission to the Congress of the study under <ref>section 1371 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 12</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–275, title VII, § 703(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2888</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 153(a)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 785</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1316a.</num>
<heading> Legislative branch appointments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the terms “covered employee” and “Board” shall each have the meaning given such term by section 101 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 1301</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights and protections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The rights and protections established under section 2108, sections 3309 through 3312, and subchapter I of chapter 35, of title 5, shall apply to covered employees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The remedy for a violation of paragraph (2) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under applicable provisions of title 5 in the case of a violation of the relevant corresponding provision (referred to in paragraph (2)) of such title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The procedure for consideration of alleged violations of paragraph (2) shall be the same as apply under section 401 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 [<ref>2 U.S.C. 1401</ref>] (and the provisions of law referred to therein) in the case of an alleged violation of part A of title II of such Act [<ref>2 U.S.C. 1311</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations to implement section</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall, pursuant to section 304 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 1384</ref>), issue regulations to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations issued under subparagraph (A) shall be the same as the most relevant substantive regulations (applicable with respect to the executive branch) promulgated to implement the statutory provisions referred to in paragraph (2) except insofar as the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations issued under subparagraph (A) shall be consistent with section 225 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 1361</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the term “covered employee” shall not, for purposes of this section, include an employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whose appointment is made by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whose appointment is made by a Member of Congress or by a committee or subcommittee of either House of Congress; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> who is appointed to a position, the duties of which are equivalent to those of a Senior Executive Service position (within the meaning of <ref>section 3132(a)(2) of title 5</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Paragraphs (2) and (3) shall be effective as of the effective date of the regulations under paragraph (4).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–339, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-31">Oct. 31, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3185</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1316b.</num>
<heading> Rights and protections relating to criminal history inquiries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the terms “agency”, “criminal history record information”, and “suspension” have the meanings given the terms in <ref>section 9201 of title 5</ref>, except as otherwise modified by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on criminal history inquiries</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), an employee of an employing office may not request that an applicant for employment as a covered employee disclose criminal history record information if the request would be prohibited under <ref>section 9202 of title 5</ref> if made by an employee of an agency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditional offer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of applying that section 9202 under subparagraph (A), a reference in that section 9202 to a conditional offer shall be considered to be an offer of employment as a covered employee that is conditioned upon the results of a criminal history inquiry.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of <ref>section 9206 of title 5</ref> shall apply to employing offices, consistent with regulations issued under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The remedy for a violation of subsection (b)(1) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under <ref>section 9204 of title 5</ref> if the violation had been committed by an employee of an agency, consistent with regulations issued under subsection (d), except that the reference in that section to a suspension shall be considered to be a suspension with the level of compensation provided for a covered employee who is taking unpaid leave under <ref>section 1312 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Process for obtaining relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An applicant for employment as a covered employee who alleges a violation of subsection (b)(1) may rely on the provisions of subchapter IV (other than section 1407 or 1408 of this title, or a provision of this subchapter that permits a person to obtain a civil action or judicial review), consistent with regulations issued under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations to implement section</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 18 months after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, the Board shall, pursuant to <ref>section 1384 of this title</ref>, issue regulations to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parallel with agency regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations issued by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management under section 2(b)(1) of the Fair Chance to Compete for Jobs Act of 2019 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002056">1</ref> to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsections (a) through (c) except to the extent that the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 1302(a)(12) of this title</ref> and subsections (a) through (c) shall take effect on the date on which <ref>section 9202 of title 5</ref> applies with respect to agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 207</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XI, § 1122(d)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1317.</num>
<heading> Prohibition of intimidation or reprisal</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for an employing office to intimidate, take reprisal against, or otherwise discriminate against, any covered employee because the covered employee has opposed any practice made unlawful by this chapter, or because the covered employee has initiated proceedings, made a charge, or testified, assisted, or participated in any manner in a hearing or other proceeding under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedy available for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such legal or equitable remedy as may be appropriate to redress a violation of subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 208</ref>, formerly § 207, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 13</ref>; renumbered § 208, <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XI, § 1122(d)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1608</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Services and Accommodations Under Americans with Disabilities Act of </inline>1990</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1331.</num>
<heading> Rights and protections under Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 relating to public services and accommodations; procedures for remedy of violations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entities subject to this section</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The requirements of this section shall apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> each office of the Senate, including each office of a Senator and each committee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> each office of the House of Representatives, including each office of a Member of the House of Representatives and each committee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> each joint committee of the Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Capitol Police;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Congressional Budget Office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the Office of the Architect of the Capitol (including the Botanic Garden);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the Office of the Attending Physician;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the Office of Technology Assessment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> the Library of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discrimination in public services and accommodations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights and protections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The rights and protections against discrimination in the provision of public services and accommodations established by sections 201 through 230, 302, 303, and 309 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12131–121</ref>50, 12182, 12183, and 12189) shall apply to the entities listed in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of the application of title II of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12131</ref> et seq.) under this section, the term “public entity” means any entity listed in subsection (a) that provides public services, programs, or activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedy for a violation of subsection (b) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under section 203 or 308(a) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12133</ref>, 12188(a)), except that, with respect to any claim of employment discrimination asserted by any covered employee, the exclusive remedy shall be under <ref>section 1311 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Available procedures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Charge filed with General Counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A qualified individual with a disability, as defined in section 201(2) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12131(2)</ref>), who alleges a violation of subsection (b) by an entity listed in subsection (a), may file a charge against any entity responsible for correcting the violation with the General Counsel within 180 days of the occurrence of the alleged violation. The General Counsel shall investigate the charge.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mediation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, upon investigation under paragraph (1), the General Counsel believes that a violation of subsection (b) may have occurred and that mediation may be helpful in resolving the dispute, the General Counsel may request, but not participate in, mediation under subsections (b) through (d) of <ref>section 1403 of this title</ref> between the charging individual and any entity responsible for correcting the alleged violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Complaint, hearing, Board review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If mediation under paragraph (2) has not succeeded in resolving the dispute, and if the General Counsel believes that a violation of subsection (b) may have occurred, the General Counsel may file with the Office a complaint against any entity responsible for correcting the violation. The complaint shall be submitted to a hearing officer for decision pursuant to subsections (b) through (h) of <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref> and any person who has filed a charge under paragraph (1) may intervene as of right, with the full rights of a party. The decision of the hearing officer shall be subject to review by the Board pursuant to <ref>section 1406 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A charging individual who has intervened under paragraph (3) or any respondent to the complaint, if aggrieved by a final decision of the Board under paragraph (3), may file a petition for review in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, pursuant to <ref>section 1407 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If new appropriated funds are necessary to comply with an order requiring correction of a violation of subsection (b), compliance shall take place as soon as possible, but no later than the fiscal year following the end of the fiscal year in which the order requiring correction becomes final and not subject to further review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations to implement section</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall, pursuant to <ref>section 1384 of this title</ref>, issue regulations to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Attorney General and the Secretary of Transportation to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsection (b) except to the extent that the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entity responsible for correction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall include a method of identifying, for purposes of this section and for categories of violations of subsection (b), the entity responsible for correction of a particular violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic inspections; report to Congress; initial study</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic inspections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On a regular basis, and at least once each Congress, the General Counsel shall inspect the facilities of the entities listed in subsection (a) to ensure compliance with subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On the basis of each periodic inspection, the General Counsel shall, at least once every Congress, prepare and submit a report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President pro tempore of the Senate, and the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, or other entity responsible,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002057">1</ref> for correcting the violation of this section uncovered by such inspection, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> containing the results of the periodic inspection, describing any steps necessary to correct any violation of this section, assessing any limitations in accessibility to and usability by individuals with disabilities associated with each violation, and the estimated cost and time needed for abatement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial period for study and corrective action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The period from <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>, until <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date>, shall be available to the Office of the Architect of the Capitol and other entities subject to this section to identify any violations of subsection (b), to determine the costs of compliance, and to take any necessary corrective action to abate any violations. The Office shall assist the Office of the Architect of the Capitol and other entities listed in subsection (a) by arranging for inspections and other technical assistance at their request. Prior to <date date="1996-07-01">July 1, 1996</date>, the General Counsel shall conduct a thorough inspection under paragraph (1) and shall submit the report under paragraph (2) for the One Hundred Fourth Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detailed personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board may, on request of the Executive Director, detail to the Office such personnel as may be necessary to advise and assist the Office in carrying out its duties under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election of remedies relating to rights to public services and accommodations for Library visitors</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of Library visitor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “Library visitor” means an individual who is eligible to bring a claim for a violation under title II or III of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 12131</ref> et seq., 12181 et seq.] (other than a violation for which the exclusive remedy is under <ref>section 1311 of this title</ref>) against the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election of remedies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A Library visitor who alleges a violation of subsection (b) by the Library of Congress may, subject to subparagraph (B)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> file a charge against the Library of Congress under subsection (d); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> use the remedies and procedures set forth in <ref>section 2000e–16 of title 42</ref>, as provided under section 510 (other than paragraph (5)) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12209</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A Library visitor that has initiated proceedings under clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) may elect to change and initiate a proceeding under the other clause—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a Library visitor who first filed a charge pursuant to subparagraph (A)(i), before the General Counsel files a complaint under subsection (d)(3); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a Library visitor who first initiated a proceeding under subparagraph (A)(ii), before the Library visitor requests a hearing under the procedures of the Library of Congress described in such subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subsections (b), (c), and (d) shall be effective on <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government Accountability Office, Government Publishing Office, and Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subsection (g) shall be effective 1 year after transmission to the Congress of the study under <ref>section 1371 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 13</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–279, § 1(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-17">July 17, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2609</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title IV, § 422(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4996</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 153(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 785</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title III</ref>, §§ 303(a), (b), 308(b)(8), <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5321</ref>, 5322, 5326.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Occupational Safety and Health Act of </inline>1970</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1341.</num>
<heading> Rights and protections under Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970; procedures for remedy of violations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Occupational safety and health protections</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each employing office and each covered employee shall comply with the provisions of section 5 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 654</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of the application under this section of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 [<ref>29 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.]—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “employer” as used in such Act means an employing office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “employee” as used in such Act means a covered employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “employing office” includes the Government Accountability Office and any entity listed in subsection (a) of <ref>section 1331 of this title</ref> that is responsible for correcting a violation of this section, irrespective of whether the entity has an employment relationship with any covered employee in any employing office in which such a violation occurs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the term “employee” includes employees of the Government Accountability Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be an order to correct the violation, including such order as would be appropriate if issued under section 13(a) of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 662(a)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests for inspections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon written request of any employing office or covered employee, the General Counsel shall exercise the authorities granted to the Secretary of Labor by subsections (a), (d), (e), and (f) of section 8 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 657(a)</ref>, (d), (e), and (f)) to inspect and investigate places of employment under the jurisdiction of employing offices.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Citations, notices, and notifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the General Counsel shall exercise the authorities granted to the Secretary of Labor in sections 9 and 10 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 658</ref> and 659), to issue—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a citation or notice to any employing office responsible for correcting a violation of subsection (a); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a notification to any employing office that the General Counsel believes has failed to correct a violation for which a citation has been issued within the period permitted for its correction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings and review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If after issuing a citation or notification, the General Counsel determines that a violation has not been corrected, the General Counsel may file a complaint with the Office against the employing office named in the citation or notification. The complaint shall be submitted to a hearing officer for decision pursuant to subsections (b) through (h) of <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref>, subject to review by the Board pursuant to <ref>section 1406 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Variance procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An employing office may request from the Board an order granting a variance from a standard made applicable by this section. For the purposes of this section, the Board shall exercise the authorities granted to the Secretary of Labor in sections 6(b)(6) and 6(d) of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 655(b)(6)</ref> and 655(d)) to act on any employing office’s request for a variance. The Board shall refer the matter to a hearing officer pursuant to subsections (b) through (h) of <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref>, subject to review by the Board pursuant to <ref>section 1406 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The General Counsel or employing office aggrieved by a final decision of the Board under paragraph (3) or (4), may file a petition for review with the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit pursuant to <ref>section 1407 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If new appropriated funds are necessary to correct a violation of subsection (a) for which a citation is issued, or to comply with an order requiring correction of such a violation, correction or compliance shall take place as soon as possible, but not later than the end of the fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the citation is issued or the order requiring correction becomes final and not subject to further review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations to implement section</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall, pursuant to <ref>section 1384 of this title</ref>, issue regulations to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Labor to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsection (a) except to the extent that the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employing office responsible for correction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall include a method of identifying, for purposes of this section and for different categories of violations of subsection (a), the employing office responsible for correction of a particular violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic inspections; report to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic inspections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On a regular basis, and at least once each Congress, the General Counsel, exercising the same authorities of the Secretary of Labor as under subsection (c)(1), shall conduct periodic inspections of all facilities of the House of Representatives, the Senate, the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services, the Capitol Police, the Congressional Budget Office, the Office of the Architect of the Capitol, the Office of the Attending Physician, the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights, the Office of Technology Assessment, the Library of Congress, and the Government Accountability Office to report on compliance with subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On the basis of each periodic inspection, the General Counsel shall prepare and submit a report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President pro tempore of the Senate, and the Office of the Architect of the Capitol or other employing office responsible for correcting the violation of this section uncovered by such inspection, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> containing the results of the periodic inspection, identifying the employing office responsible for correcting the violation of this section uncovered by such inspection, describing any steps necessary to correct any violation of this section, and assessing any risks to employee health and safety associated with any violation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action after report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a report identifies any violation of this section, the General Counsel shall issue a citation or notice in accordance with subsection (c)(2)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detailed personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Labor may, on request of the Executive Director, detail to the Office such personnel as may be necessary to advise and assist the Office in carrying out its duties under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial period for study and corrective action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The period from <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>, until <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date>, shall be available to the Office of the Architect of the Capitol and other employing offices to identify any violations of subsection (a), to determine the costs of compliance, and to take any necessary corrective action to abate any violations. The Office shall assist the Office of the Architect of the Capitol and other employing offices by arranging for inspections and other technical assistance at their request. Prior to <date date="1996-07-01">July 1, 1996</date>, the General Counsel shall conduct a thorough inspection under subsection (e)(1) and shall submit the report under subsection (e)(2) for the One Hundred Fourth Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), subsections (a), (b), (c), and (e)(3) shall be effective on <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government Accountability Office and Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This section shall be effective with respect to the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress 1 year after transmission to the Congress of the study under <ref>section 1371 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 16</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–437, title IV, § 422(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4996</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 153(a)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 785</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title III, § 308(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part D—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Labor-Management Relations</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1351.</num>
<heading> Application of chapter 71 of title 5 relating to Federal service labor-management relations; procedures for remedy of violations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Labor-management rights</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The rights, protections, and responsibilities established under sections 7102, 7106, 7111 through 7117, 7119 through 7122, and 7131 of title 5 shall apply to employing offices and to covered employees and representatives of those employees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of the application under this section of the sections referred to in paragraph (1), the term “agency” shall be deemed to include an employing office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “covered employee” does not include an employee of the Library of Congress, and the term “employing office” does not include the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy, including a remedy under <ref>section 7118(a)(7) of title 5</ref>, as would be appropriate if awarded by the Federal Labor Relations Authority to remedy a violation of any provision made applicable by subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorities and procedures for implementation and enforcement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authorities of Board; petitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section and except as otherwise provided in this section, the Board shall exercise the authorities of the Federal Labor Relations Authority under sections 7105, 7111, 7112, 7113, 7115, 7117, 7118, and 7122 of title 5 and of the President under <ref>section 7103(b) of title 5</ref>. For purposes of this section, any petition or other submission that, under chapter 71 of title 5, would be submitted to the Federal Labor Relations Authority shall, if brought under this section, be submitted to the Board. The Board shall refer any matter under this paragraph to a hearing officer for decision pursuant to subsections (b) through (h) of <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref>, subject to review by the Board pursuant to <ref>section 1406 of this title</ref>. The Board may direct that the General Counsel carry out the Board’s investigative authorities under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authorities of the General Counsel; charges of unfair labor practice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section and except as otherwise provided in this section, the General Counsel shall exercise the authorities of the General Counsel of the Federal Labor Relations Authority under sections 7104 and 7118 of title 5. For purposes of this section, any charge or other submission that, under chapter 71 of title 5, would be submitted to the General Counsel of the Federal Labor Relations Authority shall, if brought under this section, be submitted to the General Counsel. If any person charges an employing office or a labor organization with having engaged in or engaging in an unfair labor practice and makes such charge within 180 days of the occurrence of the alleged unfair labor practice, the General Counsel shall investigate the charge and may file a complaint with the Office. The complaint shall be submitted to a hearing officer for decision pursuant to subsections (b) through (h) of <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref>, subject to review by the Board pursuant to <ref>section 1406 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except for matters referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) of <ref>section 7123(a) of title 5</ref>, the General Counsel or the respondent to the complaint, if aggrieved by a final decision of the Board under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, may file a petition for judicial review in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit pursuant to <ref>section 1407 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exercise of impasses panel authority; requests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section and except as otherwise provided in this section, the Board shall exercise the authorities of the Federal Service Impasses Panel under <ref>section 7119 of title 5</ref>. For purposes of this section, any request that, under chapter 71 of title 5, would be presented to the Federal Service Impasses Panel shall, if made under this section, be presented to the Board. At the request of the Board, the Executive Director shall appoint a mediator or mediators to perform the functions of the Federal Service Impasses Panel under <ref>section 7119 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations to implement section</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall, pursuant to <ref>section 1384 of this title</ref>, issue regulations to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in subsection (e), the regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Federal Labor Relations Authority to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsection (a) except—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the extent that the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as the Board deems necessary to avoid a conflict of interest or appearance of a conflict of interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific regulations regarding application to certain offices of Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Board shall issue regulations pursuant to <ref>section 1384 of this title</ref> on the manner and extent to which the requirements and exemptions of chapter 71 of title 5 should apply to covered employees who are employed in the offices listed in paragraph (2). The regulations shall, to the greatest extent practicable, be consistent with the provisions and purposes of chapter 71 of title 5 and of this chapter, and shall be the same as substantive regulations issued by the Federal Labor Relations Authority under chapter 71 of title 5, except—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the extent that the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> that the Board shall exclude from coverage under this section any covered employees who are employed in offices listed in paragraph (2) if the Board determines that such exclusion is required because of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a conflict of interest or appearance of a conflict of interest; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Congress’ constitutional responsibilities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offices referred to</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The offices referred to in paragraph (1) include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the personal office of any Member of the House of Representatives or of any Senator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a standing, select, special, permanent, temporary, or other committee of the Senate or House of Representatives, or a joint committee of Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Office of the Vice President (as President of the Senate), the Office of the President pro tempore of the Senate, the Office of the Majority Leader of the Senate, the Office of the Minority Leader of the Senate, the Office of the Majority Whip of the Senate, the Office of the Minority Whip of the Senate, the Conference of the Majority of the Senate, the Conference of the Minority of the Senate, the Office of the Secretary of the Conference of the Majority of the Senate, the Office of the Secretary of the Conference of the Minority of the Senate, the Office of the Secretary for the Majority of the Senate, the Office of the Secretary for the Minority of the Senate, the Majority Policy Committee of the Senate, the Minority Policy Committee of the Senate, and the following offices within the Office of the Secretary of the Senate: Offices of the Parliamentarian, Bill Clerk, Legislative Clerk, Journal Clerk, Executive Clerk, Enrolling Clerk, Official Reporters of Debate, Daily Digest, Printing Services, Captioning Services, and Senate Chief Counsel for Employment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Office of the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Office of the Majority Leader of the House of Representatives, the Office of the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, the Offices of the Chief Deputy Majority Whips, the Offices of the Chief Deputy Minority Whips and the following offices within the Office of the Clerk of the House of Representatives: Offices of Legislative Operations, Official Reporters of Debate, Official Reporters to Committees, Printing Services, and Legislative Information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Office of the Legislative Counsel of the Senate, the Office of the Senate Legal Counsel, the Office of the Legislative Counsel of the House of Representatives, the Office of the General Counsel of the House of Representatives, the Office of the Parliamentarian of the House of Representatives, and the Office of the Law Revision Counsel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the offices of any caucus or party organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Congressional Budget Office, the Office of Technology Assessment, and the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> such other offices that perform comparable functions which are identified under regulations of the Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), subsections (a) and (b) shall be effective on <date date="1996-10-01">October 1, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to the offices listed in subsection (e)(2), to the covered employees of such offices, and to representatives of such employees, subsections (a) and (b) shall be effective on the effective date of regulations under subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 220</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 19</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 153(a)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 785</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title III, § 308(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part E—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">General</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1361.</num>
<heading> Generally applicable remedies and limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorney’s fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a covered employee, with respect to any claim under this chapter, or a qualified person with a disability, with respect to any claim under <ref>section 1331 of this title</ref>, is a prevailing party in any proceeding under section 1405, 1406, 1407, or 1408 of this title, the hearing officer, Board, or court, as the case may be, may award attorney’s fees, expert fees, and any other costs as would be appropriate if awarded under <ref>section 2000e–5(k) of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any proceeding under section 1405, 1406, 1407, or 1408 of this title, the same interest to compensate for delay in payment shall be made available as would be appropriate if awarded under <ref>section 2000e–16(d) of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil penalties and punitive damages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No civil penalty or punitive damages may be awarded with respect to any claim under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusive procedure</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), no person may commence an administrative or judicial proceeding to seek a remedy for the rights and protections afforded by this chapter except as provided in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Veterans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A covered employee under <ref>section 1316 of this title</ref> may also utilize any provisions of chapter 43 of title 38 that are applicable to that employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and exemptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except where inconsistent with definitions and exemptions provided in this chapter, the definitions and exemptions in the laws made applicable by this chapter shall apply under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Size limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), provisions in the laws made applicable under this chapter (other than the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act [<ref>29 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.]) determining coverage based on size, whether expressed in terms of numbers of employees, amount of business transacted, or other measure, shall not apply in determining coverage under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive branch enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This chapter shall not be construed to authorize enforcement by the executive branch of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 225</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 22</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I, § 101(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5301</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1362.</num>
<heading> Notices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Every employing office shall post and keep posted (in conspicuous places upon its premises where notices to covered employees are customarily posted) a notice provided by the Office that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describes the rights, protections, and procedures applicable to covered employees of the employing office under this chapter, concerning violations described in subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> includes contact information for the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A violation described in this subsection is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> discrimination prohibited by <ref>section 1311(a) of this title</ref> (including, in accordance with <ref>section 1302(c) of this title</ref>, discrimination prohibited by title II of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000ff</ref> et seq.)) or 1316(a) of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a violation of <ref>section 1317 of this title</ref> that is related to discrimination described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 226</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title III, § 304(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part F—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Study</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1371.</num>
<heading> Study and recommendations regarding General Accounting Office, Government Printing Office, and Library of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Board shall undertake a study of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the application of the laws listed in subsection (b) to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the General Accounting Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Government Printing Office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Library of Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the regulations and procedures used by the entities referred to in paragraph (1) to apply and enforce such laws to themselves and their employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable statutes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The study under this section shall consider the application of the following laws:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e</ref> et seq.), and related provisions of <ref>section 2302 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 621</ref> et seq.), and related provisions of <ref>section 2302 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12101</ref> et seq.), and related provisions of <ref>section 2302 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2611</ref> et seq.), and related provisions of sections 6381 through 6387 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.), and related provisions of sections 5541 through 5550a of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.), and related provisions of <ref>section 7902 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Chapter 71 (relating to Federal service labor-management relations) of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The General Accounting Office Personnel Act of 1980 (<ref>31 U.S.C. 731</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2001</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Chapter 43 (relating to veterans’ employment and reemployment) of title 38.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of study and recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The study under this section shall evaluate whether the rights, protections, and procedures, including administrative and judicial relief, applicable to the entities listed in paragraph (1) of subsection (a) and their employees are comprehensive and effective and shall include recommendations for any improvements in regulations or legislation, including proposed regulatory or legislative language.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline and delivery of study</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Board shall prepare and complete the study and recommendations required under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Board shall transmit such study and recommendations (with the Board’s comments) to the head of each entity considered in the study, and to the Congress by delivery to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and President pro tempore of the Senate for referral to the appropriate committees of the House of Representatives and of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 230</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 23</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–53, title III, § 309(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>OFFICE OF CONGRESSIONAL WORKPLACE RIGHTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1381.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Office of Congressional Workplace Rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established, as an independent office within the legislative branch of the Federal Government, the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board of Directors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office shall have a Board of Directors. The Board shall consist of 5 individuals appointed jointly by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Majority Leader of the Senate, and the Minority Leaders of the House of Representatives and the Senate, who are authorized to take such steps as they consider appropriate to ensure the timely appointment of the members of the Board consistent with the requirements of this section. Appointments of the first 5 members of the Board shall be completed not later than 90 days after <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chair shall be appointed from members of the Board jointly by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Majority Leader of the Senate, and the Minority Leaders of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board of Directors qualifications</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Selection and appointment of members of the Board shall be without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the Office. Members of the Board shall have training or experience in the application of the rights, protections, and remedies under one or more of the laws made applicable under <ref>section 1302 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualifications for appointments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lobbying</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No individual who engages in, or is otherwise employed in, lobbying of the Congress and who is required under the Federal Regulation of Lobbying Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002058">1</ref> to register with the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate shall be eligible for appointment to, or service on, the Board.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incompatible office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No member of the Board appointed under subsection (b) may hold or may have held the position of Member of the House of Representatives or Senator, may hold the position of officer or employee of the House of Representatives, Senate, or instrumentality or other entity of the legislative branch (other than the Office), or may have held such a position (other than the position of an officer or employee of the General Accounting Office Personnel Appeals Board,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002059">2</ref> an officer or employee of the Office of Fair Employment Practices of the House of Representatives, or officer or employee of the Office of Senate Fair Employment Practices) within 4 years of the date of appointment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A vacancy on the Board shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of office</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), membership on the Board shall be for 5 years. A member of the Board may be reappointed, but no individual may serve as a member for more than 2 terms.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> First appointments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Of the members first appointed to the Board—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 1 shall have a term of office of 3 years,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 2 shall have a term of office of 4 years, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 2 shall have a term of office of 5 years, 1 of whom shall be the Chair,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">as designated at the time of appointment by the persons specified in subsection (b).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permitting service until appointment of successor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A member of the Board may serve after the expiration of that member’s term until a successor has taken office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any member of the Board may be removed from office by a majority decision of the appointing authorities described in subsection (b), but only for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> disability that substantially prevents the member from carrying out the duties of the member,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> incompetence,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> neglect of duty,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> malfeasance, including a felony or conduct involving moral turpitude, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> holding an office or employment or engaging in an activity that disqualifies the individual from service as a member of the Board under subsection (d)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of reasons for removal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In removing a member of the Board, the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall state in writing to the member of the Board being removed the specific reasons for the removal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Per diem</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rate of compensation for each day</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Each member of the Board shall be compensated, for each day (including travel time) during which such member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the Board, at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the highest annual rate of compensation of any officer of the Senate; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the highest annual rate of compensation of any officer of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to prorate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The rate of pay of a member may be prorated based on the portion of the day during which the member is engaged in the performance of Board duties.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each member of the Board shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, for each day the member is engaged in the performance of duties away from the home or regular place of business of the member.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carry out a program of education for Members of Congress and other employing authorities of the legislative branch of the Federal Government respecting the laws made applicable to them and a program to inform individuals of their rights under laws applicable to the legislative branch of the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in carrying out the program under paragraph (1), distribute the telephone number and address of the Office, procedures for action under subchapter IV, and any other information appropriate for distribution, distribute such information to employing offices in a manner suitable for posting, provide such information to new employees of employing offices, distribute such information to covered employees by the end of each fiscal year, and conduct seminars and other activities designed to educate employing offices and covered employees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> compile and publish statistics on the use of the Office by covered employees, including the number and type of contacts made with the Office, on the reason for such contacts, on the number of covered employees who initiated proceedings with the Office under this chapter and the result of such proceedings, and on the number of covered employees who filed a claim, the basis for the claim, and the action taken on the claim.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional oversight</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board and the Office shall be subject to oversight (except with respect to the disposition of individual cases) by the Committee on Rules and Administration and the Committee on Governmental Affairs <sup>2</sup> of the Senate and the Committee on House Oversight <sup>2</sup> of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Opening of Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office shall be open for business, including receipt of requests for counseling under <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref>, not later than 1 year after <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial disclosure reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Board and officers and employees of the Office shall file the financial disclosure reports required under subchapter I of chapter 131 of title 5 with the Clerk of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports on awards and settlements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to the rules issued by the applicable committee pursuant to paragraph (2):</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Office shall prepare and submit to Congress, and publish on the public website of the Office, an annual report regarding payments from the account described in <ref>section 1415(a) of this title</ref> that were the result of claims alleging a violation of part A of subchapter II (referred to in this subsection as “covered payments”).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The reporting required under this paragraph shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for a covered payment, or the reimbursable portion of a covered payment, described in paragraph (2), conform to the requirements of the rules issued by the applicable committee under such paragraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> for a covered payment, or the portion of a covered payment, not described in paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> include the amount of the covered payment or portion of the covered payment and information on the employing office involved; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> identify each provision of part A of subchapter II that was the subject of a claim resulting in the covered payment or portion of the covered payment.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting periods and dates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The reporting required under this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for 2019, shall be submitted by the 60th day after the date on which the committees described in paragraph (2) issue the rules described in paragraph (2) and shall reflect covered payments made in calendar year 2019; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for 2020 and each subsequent calendar year, shall be submitted by January 31 of that year and shall reflect covered payments made in the previous calendar year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules regarding reporting of covered payments for employing offices of the House and employing offices of the Senate</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2018-12-21">December 21, 2018</date>, the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate shall each issue rules establishing the content, format, and other requirements for the reporting required under paragraph (1)(B)(i) with respect to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any covered payment made for claims involving an employing office described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (C) of <ref>section 1301(a)(9) of this title</ref> of the House of Representatives or of the Senate, respectively; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the reimbursable portion of any such covered payment for which there is a finding requiring reimbursement under <ref>section 1415(d)(1)(B) of this title</ref> from a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) or a Senator, respectively.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The rules issued under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> by the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives shall apply to covered payments made for claims involving employing offices described in subparagraph (A)(i) of the House; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate shall apply to covered payments made for claims involving employing offices described in subparagraph (A)(i) of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection of identity of individuals receiving awards and settlements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In preparing, submitting, and publishing the reports required under paragraph (1), the Office shall ensure that the identity or position of any claimant is not disclosed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to protect the identity of a claimant</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In carrying out paragraph (3), the Executive Director, in consultation with the Board, may make an appropriate redaction to the data included in the report described in paragraph (1) if the Executive Director, in consultation with the Board, determines that including the data considered for redaction may lead to the identity or position of a claimant unintentionally being disclosed. The report shall note each redaction and include a statement that the redaction was made solely for the purpose of avoiding such an unintentional disclosure of the identity or position of a claimant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recordkeeping</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Executive Director shall retain a copy of the report described in paragraph (1), without redactions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “claimant” means an individual who received an award or settlement, or who made an allegation of a violation against an employing office, under part A of subchapter II.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Record retention</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office shall establish and maintain a program for the permanent retention of its records, including the records of preliminary reviews, mediations, hearings, and other proceedings conducted under subchapter IV.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–349, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-21">Oct. 21, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1389</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1101(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2237</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–164, § 1</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2459</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1001</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2530</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–19, § 1(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="2017-04-03">Apr. 3, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 85</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title II</ref>, §§ 201(a)(1), 203, title III, § 308(a), <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5315</ref>, 5318, 5325; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1382.</num>
<heading> Officers, staff, and other personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Director</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and removal</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Chair, subject to the approval of the Board, shall appoint and may remove an Executive Director. Selection and appointment of the Executive Director shall be without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the Office. The first Executive Director shall be appointed no later than 90 days after the initial appointment of the Board of Directors.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Executive Director shall be an individual with training or expertise in the application of laws referred to in <ref>section 1302(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The disqualifications in <ref>section 1381(d)(2) of this title</ref> shall apply to the appointment of the Executive Director.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to fix compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Chair may fix the compensation of the Executive Director.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The rate of pay for the Executive Director may not exceed the maximum rate of pay in effect under <ref>section 4575(f) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term of office of the Executive Director shall be not more than 2 terms of 5 years, except that the first Executive Director shall have a single term of 7 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Executive Director shall serve as the chief operating officer of the Office. Except as otherwise specified in this chapter, the Executive Director shall carry out all of the responsibilities of the Office under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deputy Executive Directors</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chair, subject to the approval of the Board, shall appoint and may remove a Deputy Executive Director for the Senate and a Deputy Executive Director for the House of Representatives. Selection and appointment of a Deputy Executive Director shall be without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the office. The disqualifications in <ref>section 1381(d)(2) of this title</ref> shall apply to the appointment of a Deputy Executive Director.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term of office of a Deputy Executive Director shall be not more than 2 terms of 5 years, except that the first Deputy Executive Directors shall have a single term of 6 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to fix compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Chair may fix the compensation of the Deputy Executive Directors.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The rate of pay for a Deputy Executive Director may not exceed 96 percent of the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the highest annual rate of compensation of any officer of the Senate; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the highest annual rate of compensation of any officer of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Deputy Executive Director for the Senate shall recommend to the Board regulations under <ref>section 1384(a)(2)(B)(i) of this title</ref>, maintain the regulations and all records pertaining to the regulations, and shall assume such other responsibilities as may be delegated by the Executive Director. The Deputy Executive Director for the House of Representatives shall recommend to the Board the regulations under <ref>section 1384(a)(2)(B)(ii) of this title</ref>, maintain the regulations and all records pertaining to the regulations, and shall assume such other responsibilities as may be delegated by the Executive Director.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General Counsel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chair, subject to the approval of the Board, shall appoint a General Counsel. Selection and appointment of the General Counsel shall be without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the Office. The disqualifications in <ref>section 1381(d)(2) of this title</ref> shall apply to the appointment of a General Counsel.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to fix compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Chair may fix the compensation of the General Counsel.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The rate of pay for the General Counsel may not exceed the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the highest annual rate of compensation of any officer of the Senate; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the highest annual rate of compensation of any officer of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The General Counsel shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> exercise the authorities and perform the duties of the General Counsel as specified in this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> otherwise assist the Board and the Executive Director in carrying out their duties and powers, including representing the Office in any judicial proceeding under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorneys in the office of the General Counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The General Counsel shall appoint, and fix the compensation of, and may remove, such additional attorneys as may be necessary to enable the General Counsel to perform the General Counsel’s duties.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term of office of the General Counsel shall be not more than 2 terms of 5 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The General Counsel may be removed from office by the Chair but only for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> disability that substantially prevents the General Counsel from carrying out the duties of the General Counsel,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> incompetence,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> neglect of duty,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> malfeasance, including a felony or conduct involving moral turpitude, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> holding an office or employment or engaging in an activity that disqualifies the individual from service as the General Counsel under paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of reasons for removal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In removing the General Counsel, the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall state in writing to the General Counsel the specific reasons for the removal.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidential advisors</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Executive Director shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appoint, and fix the compensation of, and may remove, 1 or more confidential advisors to carry out the duties described in this subsection; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> designate 1 or more employees of the Office to serve as a confidential advisor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voluntary services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A confidential advisor appointed or designated under paragraph (1) shall offer to provide to covered employees described in paragraph (4) the services described in subparagraph (B), which a covered employee may accept or decline.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The services referred to in subparagraph (A) are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> informing, on a privileged and confidential basis, a covered employee who has been subject to a practice that may be a violation of part A of subchapter II about the employee’s rights under this chapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> consulting, on a privileged and confidential basis, with a covered employee who has been subject to a practice that may be a violation of part A of subchapter II regarding—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the roles, responsibilities, and authority of the Office; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the relative merits of securing private counsel, designating a non-attorney representative, or proceeding without representation for proceedings before the Office;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> advising and consulting with, on a privileged and confidential basis, a covered employee who has been subject to a practice that may be a violation of part A of subchapter II regarding any claims the covered employee may have under subchapter IV, the factual allegations that support each such claim, and the relative merits of the procedural options available to the employee for each such claim;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> assisting, on a privileged and confidential basis, a covered employee who seeks consideration under title IV of an allegation of a violation of part A of subchapter II in understanding the procedures, and the significance of the procedures, described in subchapter IV, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> assisting or consulting with the covered employee regarding the drafting of a claim to be filed under <ref>section 1402(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> consulting with the covered employee regarding the procedural options available to the covered employee after a claim is filed, and the relative merits of each option; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> informing, on a privileged and confidential basis, a covered employee who has been subject to a practice that may be a violation of part A of subchapter II about the option of pursuing, in appropriate circumstances, a complaint with the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives or the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuity of service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Once a covered employee has accepted and received any services offered under this section from a confidential advisor appointed or designated under paragraph (1), any other services requested under this subsection by the covered employee shall be provided, to the extent practicable, by the same confidential advisor.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A confidential advisor appointed or designated under paragraph (1) shall be a lawyer who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is admitted to practice before, and is in good standing with, the bar of a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, or a territory of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has experience representing clients in cases involving the workplace laws incorporated by part A of subchapter II.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individuals covered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The services described in paragraph (2) are available to any covered employee (which, for purposes of this subsection, shall include any staff member described in <ref>section 1311(d) of this title</ref> and any former covered employee (including any such former staff member)), except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a former covered employee may only request such services if the practice that may be a violation of part A of subchapter II occurred during the employment or service of the employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a covered employee described in this paragraph may only request such services before the expiration of the 180-day period described in <ref>section 1402(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A confidential advisor appointed or designated under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall not act as the designated representative for any covered employee in connection with the covered employee’s participation in any proceeding, including any proceeding under this chapter, any judicial proceeding, or any proceeding before any committee of Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall not offer or provide services described in paragraph (2)(B) to a covered employee if the covered employee has designated an attorney representative in connection with the covered employee’s participation in any proceeding under this chapter, except that a confidential advisor may provide general assistance and information to such attorney representative regarding this chapter and the role of the Office as the confidential advisor determines appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall not serve as a mediator in any mediation conducted pursuant to <ref>section 1403 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Executive Director shall appoint, and fix the compensation of, and may remove, such other additional staff, including hearing officers, but not including attorneys employed in the office of the General Counsel, as may be necessary to enable the Office to perform its duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detailed personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Executive Director may, with the prior consent of the department or agency of the Federal Government concerned, use on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis the services of personnel of any such department or agency, including the services of members or personnel of the Government Accountability Office Personnel Appeals Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the functions of the Office, the Executive Director may procure the temporary (not to exceed 1 year) or intermittent services of consultants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 26</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1101(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2237</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–164, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2459</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5318</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(C)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1383.</num>
<heading> Procedural rules</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Executive Director shall, subject to the approval of the Board, adopt rules governing the procedures of the Office, including the procedures of hearing officers, which shall be submitted for publication in the Congressional Record. The rules may be amended in the same manner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Executive Director shall adopt rules referred to in subsection (a) in accordance with the principles and procedures set forth in <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>. The Executive Director shall publish a general notice of proposed rulemaking under <ref>section 553(b) of title 5</ref>, but, instead of publication of a general notice of proposed rulemaking in the Federal Register, the Executive Director shall transmit such notice to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate for publication in the Congressional Record on the first day on which both Houses are in session following such transmittal. Before adopting rules, the Executive Director shall provide a comment period of at least 30 days after publication of a general notice of proposed rulemaking. Upon adopting rules, the Executive Director shall transmit notice of such action together with a copy of such rules to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate for publication in the Congressional Record on the first day on which both Houses are in session following such transmittal. Rules shall be considered issued by the Executive Director as of the date on which they are published in the Congressional Record.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 28</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1384.</num>
<heading> Substantive regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The procedures applicable to the regulations of the Board issued for the implementation of this chapter, which shall include regulations the Board is required to issue under subchapter II (including regulations on the appropriate application of exemptions under the laws made applicable in subchapter II) are as prescribed in this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rulemaking procedure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Such regulations of the Board—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be adopted, approved, and issued in accordance with subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> shall consist of 3 separate bodies of regulations, which shall apply, respectively, to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Senate and employees of the Senate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the House of Representatives and employees of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> all other covered employees and employing offices.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adoption by Board</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Board shall adopt the regulations referred to in subsection (a)(1) in accordance with the principles and procedures set forth in <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref> and as provided in the following provisions of this subsection:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall publish a general notice of proposed rulemaking under <ref>section 553(b) of title 5</ref>, but, instead of publication of a general notice of proposed rulemaking in the Federal Register, the Board shall transmit such notice to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate for publication in the Congressional Record on the first day on which both Houses are in session following such transmittal. Such notice shall set forth the recommendations of the Deputy Director for the Senate in regard to regulations under subsection (a)(2)(B)(i), the recommendations of the Deputy Director for the House of Representatives in regard to regulations under subsection (a)(2)(B)(ii), and the recommendations of the Executive Director for regulations under subsection (a)(2)(B)(iii).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Before adopting regulations, the Board shall provide a comment period of at least 30 days after publication of a general notice of proposed rulemaking.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adoption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After considering comments, the Board shall adopt regulations and shall transmit notice of such action together with a copy of such regulations to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate for publication in the Congressional Record on the first day on which both Houses are in session following such transmittal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendation as to method of approval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall include a recommendation in the general notice of proposed rulemaking and in the regulations as to whether the regulations should be approved by resolution of the Senate, by resolution of the House of Representatives, by concurrent resolution, or by joint resolution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Regulations referred to in paragraph (2)(B)(i) of subsection (a) may be approved by the Senate by resolution or by the Congress by concurrent resolution or by joint resolution. Regulations referred to in paragraph (2)(B)(ii) of subsection (a) may be approved by the House of Representatives by resolution or by the Congress by concurrent resolution or by joint resolution. Regulations referred to in paragraph (2)(B)(iii) may be approved by Congress by concurrent resolution or by joint resolution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referral</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon receipt of a notice of adoption of regulations under subsection (b)(3), the presiding officers of the House of Representatives and the Senate shall refer such notice, together with a copy of such regulations, to the appropriate committee or committees of the House of Representatives and of the Senate. The purpose of the referral shall be to consider whether such regulations should be approved, and, if so, whether such approval should be by resolution of the House of Representatives or of the Senate, by concurrent resolution or by joint resolution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint referral and discharge in the Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The presiding officer of the Senate may refer the notice of issuance of regulations, or any resolution of approval of regulations, to one committee or jointly to more than one committee. If a committee of the Senate acts to report a jointly referred measure, any other committee of the Senate must act within 30 calendar days of continuous session, or be automatically discharged.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> One-House resolution or concurrent resolution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a resolution of the House of Representatives or the Senate or a concurrent resolution referred to in paragraph (1), the matter after the resolving clause shall be the following: “The following regulations issued by the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights on ________ are hereby approved:” (the blank space being appropriately filled in, and the text of the regulations being set forth).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint resolution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a joint resolution referred to in paragraph (1), the matter after the resolving clause shall be the following: “The following regulations issued by the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights on ________ are hereby approved and shall have the force and effect of law:” (the blank space being appropriately filled in, and the text of the regulations being set forth).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance and effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After approval of regulations under subsection (c), the Board shall submit the regulations to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate for publication in the Congressional Record on the first day on which both Houses are in session following such transmittal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Date of issuance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The date of issuance of regulations shall be the date on which they are published in the Congressional Record under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Regulations shall become effective not less than 60 days after the regulations are issued, except that the Board may provide for an earlier effective date for good cause found (within the meaning of <ref>section 553(d)(3) of title 5</ref>) and published with the regulation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amendment of regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Regulations may be amended in the same manner as is described in this section for the adoption, approval, and issuance of regulations, except that the Board may, in its discretion, dispense with publication of a general notice of proposed rulemaking of minor, technical, or urgent amendments that satisfy the criteria for dispensing with publication of such notice pursuant to <ref>section 553(b)(B) of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right to petition for rulemaking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any interested party may petition to the Board for the issuance, amendment, or repeal of a regulation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Executive Director, the Deputy Directors, and the Board—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> shall consult, with regard to the development of regulations, with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Chair of the Administrative Conference of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Labor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Federal Labor Relations Authority; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Director of the Office of Personnel Management; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may consult with any other persons with whom consultation, in the opinion of the Board, the Executive Director, or Deputy Directors, may be helpful.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 29</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title III, § 308(b)(12)</ref>, (13), <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1385.</num>
<heading> Expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Beginning in fiscal year 1995, and for each fiscal year thereafter, there are authorized to be appropriated for the expenses of the Office such sums as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the Office. Until sums are first appropriated pursuant to the preceding sentence, but for a period not exceeding 12 months following <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> one-half of the expenses of the Office shall be paid from funds appropriated for allowances and expenses of the House of Representatives, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> one-half of the expenses of the Office shall be paid from funds appropriated for allowances and expenses of the Senate,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">upon vouchers approved by the Executive Director, except that a voucher shall not be required for the disbursement of salaries of employees who are paid at an annual rate. The Clerk of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate are authorized to make arrangements for the division of expenses under this subsection, including arrangements for one House of Congress to reimburse the other House of Congress.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial and administrative services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Executive Director may place orders and enter into agreements for goods and services with the head of any agency, or major organizational unit within an agency, in the legislative or executive branch of the United States in the same manner and to the same extent as agencies are authorized under sections 1535 and 1536 of title 31 to place orders and enter into agreements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Witness fees and allowances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except for covered employees, witnesses before a hearing officer or the Board in any proceeding under this chapter other than rulemaking shall be paid the same fee and mileage allowances as are paid subpoenaed witnesses in the courts of the United States. Covered employees who are summoned, or are assigned by their employer, to testify in their official capacity or to produce official records in any proceeding under this chapter shall be entitled to travel expenses under subchapter I and section 5751 of chapter 57 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 31</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1386.</num>
<heading> Disposition of surplus or obsolete personal property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Executive Director may, within the limits of available appropriations, dispose of surplus or obsolete personal property by interagency transfer, donation, or discarding.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title III, § 306</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–68, div. A, title I, § 1101(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2031</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1387.</num>
<heading> Semiannual report of disbursements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after the last day of each semiannual period of a fiscal year, the Executive Director of the Office of Compliance <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002060">1</ref> shall submit to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate, with respect to that period, a detailed, itemized report of the disbursements for the operations of the Office of Compliance.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002060">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the identification of each person who receives a payment from the Office of Compliance,<sup>1</sup> except that in the case of an individual, the identification shall be provided in a manner that does not identify the individual by name;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the quantity and price of any item furnished to the Office of Compliance; <sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of any service rendered to the Office of Compliance,<sup>1</sup> together with a statement of the time required for the service, and the name, title, and amount paid to each person who renders the service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a statement of all amounts appropriated to, or received or expended by, the Office of Compliance <sup>1</sup> and any unexpended balances of such amounts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> such additional information as may be required by regulation of the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, or the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives or Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for confidential information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Executive Director of the Office of Compliance <sup>1</sup> may exclude from any report required by subsection (a) any information the disclosure of which would violate confidentiality policies of the Office of Compliance.<sup>1</sup></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to the semiannual periods of October 1 through March 31 and April 1 through September 30 of each fiscal year, beginning with fiscal year 2014.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. I, title I, § 1102</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 425</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1388.</num>
<heading> Workplace climate surveys of employing offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to conduct secure surveys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-12-21">December 21, 2018</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Office shall conduct a secure survey of employing offices under this chapter regarding the workplace environment of such offices. Employee responses to the survey shall be voluntary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special inclusion of information on sexual harassment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In each survey conducted under this section, the Office shall survey respondents on attitudes regarding sexual harassment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methodology</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office shall conduct each survey under this section in accordance with methodologies established by the Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Under the methodologies established under paragraph (1), all responses to all portions of the survey shall be anonymous and confidential, and each respondent shall be told throughout the survey that all responses shall be anonymous and confidential.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Survey form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office shall limit the use of any information code or information on the survey form that makes a respondent to the survey, or the respondent’s employing office, individually identifiable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of results of surveys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office shall furnish the information obtained from the surveys conducted under this section to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office shall carry out this section, including establishment of methodologies and procedures under subsection (c), in consultation with the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title III, § 307</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5317</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATIVE AND JUDICIAL DISPUTE-RESOLUTION PROCEDURES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1401.</num>
<heading> Procedure for consideration of alleged violations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing and review of claims</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, the procedure for consideration of an alleged violation of part A of subchapter II consists of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the filing of a claim by the covered employee alleging the violation, as provided in <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the preliminary review of the claim, to be conducted by a hearing officer as provided in <ref>section 1402a of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> mediation as provided in <ref>section 1403 of this title</ref>, if requested and agreed to by the parties under that section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a formal hearing as provided in <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref>, subject to Board review as provided in <ref>section 1406 of this title</ref> and judicial review in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit as provided in <ref>section 1407 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right of employee to file civil action</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Only a covered employee who has filed a claim timely as provided in <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref> and who has not submitted a request for a hearing on the claim pursuant to <ref>section 1405(a) of this title</ref> may, during the period described in paragraph (3), file a civil action in a District Court of the United States with respect to the violation alleged in the claim, as provided in <ref>section 1408 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of filing civil action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (a), if the covered employee files such a civil action—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the preliminary review of the claim by the hearing officer as provided in <ref>section 1402a of this title</ref> shall terminate upon the filing of the action by the covered employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the procedure for consideration of the alleged violation shall not include any further review of the claim by the hearing officer as provided in <ref>section 1402a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period for filing civil action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The period described in this paragraph with respect to a claim is the 70-day period which begins on the date the covered employee files the claim under <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for employees who fail to state a claim for which relief may be granted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (3), if a covered employee receives a written notice from the hearing officer under <ref>section 1402a(d)(2) of this title</ref> that the employee has the right to file a civil action with respect to the claim in accordance with <ref>section 1408 of this title</ref>, the covered employee may file the civil action not later than 90 days after receiving such written notice.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for Architect of the Capitol and Capitol Police</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of an employee of the Office of the Architect of the Capitol or of the Capitol Police, the Office, after receiving a claim filed under <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref>, may recommend that the employee use the grievance procedures of the Architect of the Capitol or the Capitol Police for resolution of the employee’s grievance for a specific period of time. Any deadline in this chapter relating to a claim for which the employee is using the grievance procedures, that has not already passed by the first day of that specific period, shall be stayed during that specific period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election of remedies for Library of Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Direct Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “direct Act” means an Act (other than this Act), or provision of the Revised Statutes, that is specified in section 1311, 1312, or 1313 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Direct provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “direct provision” means a provision (including a definitional provision) of a direct Act that applies the rights or protections of a direct Act (including rights and protections relating to nonretaliation or noncoercion) to a Library claimant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Library claimant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Library claimant” means, with respect to a direct provision, an employee of the Library of Congress who is covered by that direct provision.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election after proceedings initially brought under this chapter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A Library claimant who initially files a claim for an alleged violation as provided in <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref> may, at any time before the date that is 10 days after a hearing officer submits the report on the preliminary review of the claim under <ref>section 1402a(c) of this title</ref>, elect to bring the claim for a proceeding before the corresponding Federal agency under the corresponding direct provision, instead of continuing with the procedures applicable to the claim under this subchapter or filing a civil action in accordance with <ref>section 1408 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election after proceedings initially brought under other civil rights or labor law</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A Library claimant who initially brings a claim, complaint, or charge under a direct provision for a proceeding before a Federal agency may, prior to requesting a hearing under the agency’s procedures, elect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> continue with the agency’s procedures and preserve the option (if any) to bring any civil action relating to the claim, complaint, or charge, that is available to the Library claimant; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> file a claim with the Office under <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref> and continue with the corresponding procedures of this title available and applicable to a covered employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A Library claimant who meets the initial deadline under <ref>section 1402(d) of this title</ref> for filing a claim under this subchapter, or any initial deadline for bringing a claim, complaint, or charge under the applicable direct provision, and then elects to change to alternative procedures as described in paragraph (2) or (3)(B), shall be considered to meet any initial deadline for the alternative procedures.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This subsection shall take effect and shall apply as described in section 153(c) of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2018 (<ref>Public Law 115–141</ref>) (except to the extent such section applies to any violation of <ref>section 1331 of this title</ref> or a provision of an Act specified in <ref>section 1331 of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of parties to retain private counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter may be construed to limit the authority of any individual (including a covered employee, the head of an employing office, or an individual who is alleged to have committed personally an act which consists of a violation of part A of subchapter II) to retain counsel to protect the interests of the individual at any point during any of the procedures provided under this title for the consideration of an alleged violation of part A of subchapter II, including as provided under <ref>section 1415(d)(8) of this title</ref> with respect to individuals subject to a reimbursement requirement of <ref>section 1415(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards for assertions made by parties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any party in any of the procedures provided under this subchapter, as well as any counsel or other person representing a party in any of such procedures, shall have an obligation to ensure that, to the best of the party’s knowledge, information, and belief, as formed after an inquiry which is reasonable under the circumstances, each of the following is correct:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No pleading, written motion, or other paper is presented for any improper purpose, such as to harass, cause unnecessary delay, or needlessly increase the cost of resolution of the matter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The claims, defenses, and other legal contentions the party advocates are warranted by existing law or by a nonfrivolous argument for extending, modifying, or reversing existing law or for establishing new law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The factual contentions have evidentiary support or, if specifically so identified, will likely have evidentiary support after a reasonable opportunity for further review or discovery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The denials of factual contentions are warranted on the evidence or, if specifically so identified, are reasonably based on belief or a lack of information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to supersede or limit <ref>section 1361(d)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 153(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 786</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5298</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1402.</num>
<heading> Initiation of procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Claim</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of claim</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To commence a proceeding under this subchapter, a covered employee alleging a violation of law made applicable under part A of subchapter II shall file a claim with the Office. The Office shall not accept a claim which is filed after the deadline applicable under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of claim</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The claim filed under this section shall be made in writing under oath or affirmation, shall describe the facts that form the basis of the claim and the violation that is being alleged, shall identify the employing office alleged to have committed the violation or in which the violation is alleged to have occurred, and shall be in such form as the Office requires.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No effect on ability of covered employee to seek information from office or pursue relief</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in paragraph (2), or subsection (b) or (c), may be construed to limit the ability of a covered employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to contact the Office or any other appropriate office prior to filing a claim under this section to seek information regarding the employee’s rights under this chapter and the procedures available under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a covered employee of an employing office of the House of Representatives or Senate, to refer information regarding an alleged violation of part A of subchapter II to the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives or the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate (as the case may be); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to file a civil action in accordance with <ref>section 1401(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial processing of claim</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intake and recording; notification to employing office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the filing of a claim by a covered employee under subsection (a), the Office shall take such steps as may be necessary for the initial intake and recording of the claim, including providing each party with all relevant information with respect to the rights of the party under this chapter, and shall transmit immediately a copy of the claim to the head of the employing office and the designated representative of that office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special notification requirements for claims based on acts by members of Congress</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a claim alleging a violation described in subparagraph (B) which consists of a violation described in <ref>section 1415(d)(1)(A) of this title</ref> by an individual, upon the filing of the claim under subsection (a), the Office shall notify immediately such individual of the claim, the possibility that the individual may be required to reimburse the account described in <ref>section 1415(a) of this title</ref> for the reimbursable portion of any award or settlement in connection with the claim, and the right of the individual under <ref>section 1415(d)(8) of this title</ref> to intervene in any mediation, hearing, or civil action under this subchapter with respect to the claim.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violations described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A violation described in this subparagraph is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> harassment that is unlawful under section 1311(a) or 1316(a) of this title; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> intimidation, reprisal, or discrimination that is unlawful under <ref>section 1317 of this title</ref> and is taken against a covered employee because of a claim alleging a violation described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of secure electronic reporting and tracking system</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and operation of secure system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office shall establish and operate a secure electronic reporting system through which a covered employee may initiate a proceeding under this subchapter, and which will keep an electronic record of the date and time at which the proceeding is initiated and will track all subsequent actions or proceedings occurring with respect to the proceeding under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accessibility to all parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The system shall be accessible to all parties to such actions or proceedings, but only until the completion of such actions or proceedings.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment of effectiveness of procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office shall use the information contained in the system to make regular assessments of the effectiveness of the procedures under this subchapter in providing for the timely resolution of claims, and shall submit semi-annual reports on such assessments each year to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A covered employee may not file a claim under this section with respect to an allegation of a violation of law after the expiration of the 180-day period which begins on the date of the alleged violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5301</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1402a.</num>
<heading> Preliminary review of claims</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preliminary review by hearing officer</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 7 days after transmission to the employing office of a claim pursuant to <ref>section 1402(b) of this title</ref>, the Executive Director shall appoint a hearing officer to conduct a preliminary review of the claim.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Process for appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Executive Director shall appoint a hearing officer under this subsection in the same manner and in accordance with the same requirements and procedures applicable to the appointment of a hearing officer under <ref>section 1405(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessments required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In conducting a preliminary review of a claim under this section, the hearing officer shall assess each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whether the claimant is a covered employee authorized to obtain relief relating to the claim under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Whether the office which is the subject of the claim is an employing office under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Whether the individual filing the claim has met the applicable deadlines for filing the claim under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The identification of factual and legal issues involved with respect to the claim.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The specific relief sought by the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Whether, on the basis of the assessments made under paragraphs (1) through (5), the individual filing the claim is a covered employee who has stated a claim for which, if the allegations contained in the claim are true, relief may be granted under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The potential for the settlement of the claim without a formal hearing as provided under <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref> or a civil action as provided under <ref>section 1408 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after a claim is filed under <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref>, the hearing officer shall submit to the individual filing the claim and the office which is the subject of the claim a report on the preliminary review conducted under this section, and shall include in the report the hearing officer’s determination as to whether the individual is a covered employee who has stated a claim for which relief may be granted under this subchapter (as described in paragraph (6) of subsection (b)). The submission of the report shall conclude the preliminary review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The hearing officer may (upon notice to the individual filing the claim and the employing office which is the subject of the claim) use an additional period of not to exceed 30 days to conclude the preliminary review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of determination of failure to state claim for which relief may be granted</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the hearing officer’s report on the preliminary review of a claim under subsection (c) includes the determination that the individual filing the claim is not a covered employee or has not stated a claim for which relief may be granted under this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the individual (including an individual who is a Library claimant, as defined in <ref>section 1401(d)(1) of this title</ref>) may not obtain a formal hearing with respect to the claim as provided under <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the hearing officer shall provide the individual and the Executive Director with a written notice that the individual may file a civil action with respect to the claim in accordance with <ref>section 1408 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmission of report on preliminary review of certain claims to congressional ethics committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of a hearing officer’s report under subsection (c) on the preliminary review of a claim alleging a violation described in <ref>section 1415(d)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, the hearing officer shall transmit the report to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives, in the case of such an act by a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate, in the case of such an act by a Senator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 403</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1403.</num>
<heading> Mediation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of mediation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification regarding mediation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered employee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Upon receipt of a claim under <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref>, the Office shall notify the covered employee who filed the claim about the process for mediation under this section and the deadlines applicable to such mediation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employing office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Upon transmission to the employing office of the claim pursuant to <ref>section 1402(b) of this title</ref>, the Office shall notify the employing office about the process for mediation under this section and the deadlines applicable to such mediation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">During the period described in subparagraph (B), either the covered employee who filed a claim under <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref> or the employing office named in the claim may file a request for mediation with the Office, which shall promptly notify the other party. If the other party agrees to the request, the Office shall promptly assign a mediator to the claim, and conduct mediation under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A covered employee or an employing office may file a request for mediation under subparagraph (A) during the period beginning on the date that the covered employee or employing office, respectively, receives a notification under paragraph (1) regarding a claim under <ref>section 1402 of this title</ref> and ending on the date on which a hearing officer issues a written decision relating to the claim under <ref>section 1405(g) of this title</ref> or the covered employee files a civil action with respect to the claim in accordance with <ref>section 1408 of this title</ref>, as applicable.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to request or accept mediation to have no effect on treatment of claim</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The failure of a party to request mediation under this section with respect to a claim, or the failure of a party to agree to a request for mediation under this section, may not be taken into consideration under any procedure under this title with respect to the claim, including a preliminary review under <ref>section 1402a of this title</ref>, a formal hearing under <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref>, or a civil action under <ref>section 1408 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Process</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Mediation under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may include the Office, the covered employee, the employing office, and one or more individuals appointed by the Executive Director from the master list developed and maintained under subsection (e), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall involve meetings with the parties during which, at the request of any of the parties, the parties shall be separated, for the purpose of resolving the dispute between the covered employee and the employing office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mediation period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The mediation period shall be 30 days, beginning on the first day after the second party agrees to the request for the mediation. The mediation period may be extended for one additional period of 30 days at the joint request of the covered employee and employing office. Any deadline in this chapter relating to a claim for which mediation has been agreed to in this section, that has not already passed by the first day of the mediation period, shall be stayed during the mediation period. The Office shall notify in writing the covered employee and the employing office when the mediation period has ended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independence of mediation process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No individual, who is appointed by the Executive Director to mediate, may conduct or aid in a hearing conducted under <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref> with respect to the same matter or shall be subject to subpoena or any other compulsory process with respect to the same matter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Master list of mediators</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development and maintenance of master list</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Executive Director shall develop and maintain a master list of individuals who are experienced in adjudicating, arbitrating, or mediating the kinds of personnel and other matters for which mediation may be held under this section. Such list may include, but not be limited to, members of the bar of a State or the District of Columbia and retired judges of the United States courts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of candidates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In developing the master list under this subsection, the Executive Director shall consider candidates recommended by the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service or the Administrative Conference of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 404</ref>, formerly § 403, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–6, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-03-20">Mar. 20, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 81</ref>; renumbered § 404 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I</ref>, §§ 101(c)(2), 104, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5301</ref>, 5305.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1404.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I, § 101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5301</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1405.</num>
<heading> Hearing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for hearings to commence in Office</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearing required upon request</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, not later than 10 days after a hearing officer submits the report on the preliminary review of a claim under <ref>section 1402a(c) of this title</ref>, a covered employee submits a request to the Executive Director for a hearing under this section, the Executive Director shall appoint an independent hearing officer pursuant to subsection (c) to consider the claim and render a decision, and a hearing shall be commenced in the Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to the claim if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the hearing officer’s report on the preliminary review of the claim under <ref>section 1402a(c) of this title</ref> includes the determination that the individual filing the claim is not a covered employee who has stated a claim for which relief may be granted under this title (as described in <ref>section 1402a(d) of this title</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the covered employee files a civil action as provided in <ref>section 1408 of this title</ref> with respect to the claim.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dismissal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A hearing officer may dismiss any claim that the hearing officer finds to be frivolous or that fails to state a claim upon which relief may be granted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearing officer</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the filing of a request for a hearing under subsection (a), the Executive Director shall appoint an independent hearing officer to consider the request for a hearing under subsection (a) and render a decision. No Member of the House of Representatives, Senator, officer of either the House of Representatives or the Senate, head of an employing office, member of the Board, or covered employee may be appointed to be a hearing officer. The Executive Director shall select hearing officers on a rotational or random basis from the lists developed under paragraph (2). Nothing in this section shall prevent the appointment of hearing officers as full-time employees of the Office or the selection of hearing officers on the basis of specialized expertise needed for particular matters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lists</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Executive Director shall develop master lists, composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> members of the bar of a State or the District of Columbia and retired judges of the United States courts who are experienced in adjudicating or arbitrating the kinds of personnel and other matters for which hearings may be held under this chapter, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> individuals expert in technical matters relating to accessibility and usability by persons with disabilities or technical matters relating to occupational safety and health.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">In developing lists, the Executive Director shall consider candidates recommended by the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service or the Administrative Conference of the United States.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibiting hearing officer conducting preliminary review from conducting hearing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Executive Director may not appoint a hearing officer to conduct a hearing under this section with respect to a claim if the hearing officer conducted the preliminary review with respect to the claim under <ref>section 1402a of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Unless a claim is dismissed before a hearing, a hearing shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conducted in closed session on the record by the hearing officer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> commenced no later than 90 days after the Executive Director receives the covered employee’s request for the hearing under subsection (a), except that, upon mutual agreement of the parties or for good cause, the Office shall extend the time for commencing a hearing for not more than an additional 30 days; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> conducted, except as specifically provided in this chapter and to the greatest extent practicable, in accordance with the principles and procedures set forth in sections 554 through 557 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discovery</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Reasonable prehearing discovery may be permitted at the discretion of the hearing officer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subpoenas</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the request of a party, a hearing officer may issue subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses and for the production of correspondence, books, papers, documents, and other records. The attendance of witnesses and the production of records may be required from any place within the United States. Subpoenas shall be served in the manner provided under rule 45(b) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Objections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a person refuses, on the basis of relevance, privilege, or other objection, to testify in response to a question or to produce records in connection with a proceeding before a hearing officer, the hearing officer shall rule on the objection. At the request of the witness or any party, the hearing officer shall (or on the hearing officer’s own initiative, the hearing officer may) refer the ruling to the Board for review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a person fails to comply with a subpoena, the Board may authorize the General Counsel to apply, in the name of the Office, to an appropriate United States district court for an order requiring that person to appear before the hearing officer to give testimony or produce records. The application may be made within the judicial district where the hearing is conducted or where that person is found, resides, or transacts business. Any failure to obey a lawful order of the district court issued pursuant to this section may be held by such court to be a civil contempt thereof.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Process in an action or contempt proceeding pursuant to subparagraph (A) may be served in any judicial district in which the person refusing or failing to comply, or threatening to refuse or not to comply, resides, transacts business, or may be found, and subpoenas for witnesses who are required to attend such proceedings may run into any other district.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The hearing officer shall issue a written decision as expeditiously as possible, but in no case more than 90 days after the conclusion of the hearing. The written decision shall be transmitted by the Office to the parties. The decision shall state the issues raised in the claim, describe the evidence in the record, contain findings of fact and conclusions of law, contain a determination of whether a violation has occurred, and order such remedies as are appropriate pursuant to subchapter II. The decision shall be entered in the records of the Office. If a decision is not appealed under <ref>section 1406 of this title</ref> to the Board, the decision shall be considered the final decision of the Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Precedents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A hearing officer who conducts a hearing under this section shall be guided by judicial decisions under the laws made applicable by <ref>section 1302 of this title</ref> and by Board decisions under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 33</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I, § 103(b)</ref>–(e), <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5304</ref>, 5305.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1406.</num>
<heading> Appeal to Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any party aggrieved by the decision of a hearing officer under <ref>section 1405(g) of this title</ref> may file a petition for review by the Board not later than 30 days after entry of the decision in the records of the Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parties’ opportunity to submit argument</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The parties to the hearing upon which the decision of the hearing officer was made shall have a reasonable opportunity to be heard, through written submission and, in the discretion of the Board, through oral argument.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standard of review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Board shall set aside a decision of a hearing officer if the Board determines that the decision was—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not consistent with law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not made consistent with required procedures; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> unsupported by substantial evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Record</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making determinations under subsection (c), the Board shall review the whole record, or those parts of it cited by a party, and due account shall be taken of the rule of prejudicial error.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall issue a written decision setting forth the reasons for its decision. The decision may affirm, reverse, or remand to the hearing officer for further proceedings. A decision that does not require further proceedings before a hearing officer shall be entered in the records of the Office as a final decision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 35</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1407.</num>
<heading> Judicial review of Board decisions and enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall have jurisdiction over any proceeding commenced by a petition of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a party aggrieved by a final decision of the Board under <ref>section 1406(e) of this title</ref> in cases arising under part A of subchapter II,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a charging individual or a respondent before the Board who files a petition under <ref>section 1331(d)(4) of this title</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the General Counsel or a respondent before the Board who files a petition under <ref>section 1341(c)(5) of this title</ref>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the General Counsel or a respondent before the Board who files a petition under <ref>section 1351(c)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">The court of appeals shall have exclusive jurisdiction to set aside, suspend (in whole or in part), to determine the validity of, or otherwise review the decision of the Board.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall have jurisdiction over any petition of the General Counsel, filed in the name of the Office and at the direction of the Board, to enforce a final decision under section 1405(g) or 1406(e) of this title with respect to a violation of part A, B, C, or D of subchapter II.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Respondents</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In any proceeding commenced by a petition filed under subsection (a)(1)(A) or (B), or filed by a party other than the General Counsel under subsection (a)(1)(C) or (D), the Office shall be named respondent and any party before the Board may be named respondent by filing a notice of election with the court within 30 days after service of the petition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In any proceeding commenced by a petition filed by the General Counsel under subsection (a)(1)(C) or (D), the prevailing party in the final decision entered under <ref>section 1406(e) of this title</ref> shall be named respondent, and any other party before the Board may be named respondent by filing a notice of election with the court within 30 days after service of the petition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In any proceeding commenced by a petition filed under subsection (a)(2), the party under section 1405 or 1406 of this title that the General Counsel determines has failed to comply with a final decision under section 1405(g) or 1406(e) of this title shall be named respondent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intervention</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any party that participated in the proceedings before the Board under <ref>section 1406 of this title</ref> and that was not made respondent under paragraph (1) may intervene as of right.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law applicable</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Chapter 158 of title 28 shall apply to judicial review under paragraph (1) of subsection (a), except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> with respect to <ref>section 2344 of title 28</ref>, service of a petition in any proceeding in which the Office is a respondent shall be on the General Counsel rather than on the Attorney General;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the provisions of <ref>section 2348 of title 28</ref>, on the authority of the Attorney General, shall not apply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the petition for review shall be filed not later than 90 days after the entry in the Office of a final decision under <ref>section 1406(e) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Office shall be an “agency” as that term is used in chapter 158 of title 28.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standard of review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To the extent necessary for decision in a proceeding commenced under subsection (a)(1) and when presented, the court shall decide all relevant questions of law and interpret constitutional and statutory provisions. The court shall set aside a final decision of the Board if it is determined that the decision was—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not consistent with law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not made consistent with required procedures; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> unsupported by substantial evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Record</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making determinations under subsection (d), the court shall review the whole record, or those parts of it cited by a party, and due account shall be taken of the rule of prejudicial error.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 35</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1408.</num>
<heading> Civil action</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction over any civil action commenced under <ref>section 1401 of this title</ref> and this section by a covered employee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The defendant shall be the employing office alleged to have committed the violation, or in which the violation is alleged to have occurred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jury trial</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any party may demand a jury trial where a jury trial would be available in an action against a private defendant under the relevant law made applicable by this chapter. In any case in which a violation of <ref>section 1311 of this title</ref> is alleged, the court shall not inform the jury of the maximum amount of compensatory damages available under section 1311(b)(1) or 1311(b)(3) of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appearances by House Employment Counsel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The House Employment Counsel of the House of Representatives and any other counsel in the Office of House Employment Counsel of the House of Representatives, including any counsel specially retained by the Office of House Employment Counsel, shall be entitled, for the purpose of providing legal assistance and representation to employing offices of the House of Representatives under this chapter, to enter an appearance in any proceeding before any court of the United States or of any State or political subdivision thereof without compliance with any requirements for admission to practice before such court, except that the authorization conferred by this paragraph shall not apply with respect to the admission of any such person to practice before the United States Supreme Court.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> House Employment Counsel defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “Office of House Employment Counsel of the House of Representatives” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Office of House Employment Counsel established and operating under the authority of the Clerk of the House of Representatives as of <date date="2001-11-12">November 12, 2001</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any successor office to the Office of House Employment Counsel which is established after <date date="2001-11-12">November 12, 2001</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other person authorized and directed in accordance with the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide legal assistance and representation to employing offices of the House of Representatives in connection with actions brought under this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 37</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 119(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5300</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1409.</num>
<heading> Judicial review of regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any proceeding brought under section 1407 or 1408 of this title in which the application of a regulation issued under this chapter is at issue, the court may review the validity of the regulation in accordance with the provisions of subparagraphs (A) through (D) of <ref>section 706(2) of title 5</ref>, except that with respect to regulations approved by a joint resolution under <ref>section 1384(c) of this title</ref>, only the provisions of <ref>section 706(2)(B) of title 5</ref> shall apply. If the court determines that the regulation is invalid, the court shall apply, to the extent necessary and appropriate, the most relevant substantive executive agency regulation promulgated to implement the statutory provisions with respect to which the invalid regulation was issued. Except as provided in this section, the validity of regulations issued under this chapter is not subject to judicial review.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 409</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 37</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1410.</num>
<heading> Other judicial review prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as expressly authorized by sections 1407, 1408, and 1409 of this title, the compliance or noncompliance with the provisions of this chapter and any action taken pursuant to this chapter shall not be subject to judicial review.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 410</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 37</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1411.</num>
<heading> Effect of failure to issue regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any proceeding under section 1405, 1406, 1407, or 1408 of this title, except a proceeding to enforce <ref>section 1351 of this title</ref> with respect to offices listed under <ref>section 1351(e)(2) of this title</ref>, if the Board has not issued a regulation on a matter for which this chapter requires a regulation to be issued, the hearing officer, Board, or court, as the case may be, shall apply, to the extent necessary and appropriate, the most relevant substantive executive agency regulation promulgated to implement the statutory provision at issue in the proceeding.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 37</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1412.</num>
<heading> Expedited review of certain appeals</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An appeal may be taken directly to the Supreme Court of the United States from any interlocutory or final judgment, decree, or order of a court upon the constitutionality of any provision of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Supreme Court shall, if it has not previously ruled on the question, accept jurisdiction over the appeal referred to in subsection (a), advance the appeal on the docket, and expedite the appeal to the greatest extent possible.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 38</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1413.</num>
<heading> Privileges and immunities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authorization to bring judicial proceedings under sections 1405(f)(3), 1407, and 1408 of this title shall not constitute a waiver of sovereign immunity for any other purpose, or of the privileges of any Senator or Member of the House of Representatives under article I, section 6, clause 1, of the Constitution, or a waiver of any power of either the Senate or the House of Representatives under the Constitution, including under article I, section 5, clause 3, or under the rules of either House relating to records and information within its jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 38</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1414.</num>
<heading> Settlement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any settlement entered into by the parties to a process described in section 1331, 1341, 1351, or 1401 of this title shall be in writing and not become effective unless it is approved by the Executive Director. Nothing in this chapter shall affect the power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, to establish rules governing the process by which a settlement may be entered into by such House or by any employing office of such House.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 414</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I, § 103(f)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5305</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1415.</num>
<heading> Payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Awards and settlements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (c), only funds which are appropriated to an account of the Office in the Treasury of the United States for the payment of awards and settlements may be used for the payment of awards and settlements under this chapter. There are appropriated for such account such sums as may be necessary to pay such awards and settlements. Funds in the account are not available for awards and settlements involving the Government Accountability Office or the Government Publishing Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (c), there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for administrative, personnel, and similar expenses of employing offices which are needed to comply with this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> OSHA, accommodation, and access requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds to correct violations of section 1311(a)(3), 1331, or 1341 of this title may be paid only from funds appropriated to the employing office or entity responsible for correcting such violations. There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for such funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement by Members of Congress of amounts paid as settlements and awards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement required for certain violations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (D), if a payment is made from the account described in subsection (a) for an award or settlement in connection with a claim alleging a violation described in subparagraph (C) committed personally by an individual who, at the time of committing the violation, was a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) or a Senator, the individual shall reimburse the account for the amount of the award or settlement for the claim involved.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of an award made pursuant to a decision of a hearing officer under <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref>, or a court in a civil action, subparagraph (A) shall apply only if the hearing officer or court makes a separate finding that a violation described in subparagraph (C) occurred which was committed personally by an individual who, at the time of committing the violation, was a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) or a Senator, and such individual shall reimburse the account for the amount of compensatory damages included in the award as would be available if awarded under <ref>section 1981a(b)(3) of title 42</ref> irrespective of the size of the employing office. In the case of a settlement for a claim described in <ref>section 1416(d)(3) of this title</ref>, subparagraph (A) shall apply only if the conditions specified in <ref>section 1416(d)(3) of this title</ref> for requesting reimbursement are met.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violations described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A violation described in this subparagraph is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> harassment that is unlawful under section 1311(a) or 1316(a) of this title; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> intimidation, reprisal, or discrimination that is unlawful under <ref>section 1317 of this title</ref> and is taken against a covered employee because of a claim alleging a violation described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiple claims</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If an award or settlement is made for multiple claims, some of which do not require reimbursement under this subsection, the individual described in subparagraph (A) shall only be required to reimburse for the amount (referred to in this chapter as the “reimbursable portion”) that is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> described in subparagraph (A), subject to subparagraph (B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> included in the portion of the award or settlement attributable to a claim requiring reimbursement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding amounts from compensation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of timetable and procedures by committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of carrying out subparagraph (B), the applicable Committee shall establish a timetable and procedures for the withholding of amounts from the compensation of an individual who is a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The payroll administrator shall withhold from an individual’s compensation and transfer to the account described in subsection (a) (after making any deposit required under <ref>section 8432(f) of title 5</ref>) such amounts as may be necessary to reimburse the account described in subsection (a) for the reimbursable portion of the award or settlement described in paragraph (1) if the individual has not reimbursed the account as required under paragraph (1) prior to the expiration of the 90-day period which begins on the date a payment is made from the account for such an award or settlement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable Committee defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “applicable Committee” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, in the case of an individual who, at the time of the withholding, is a Member of the House; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, in the case of an individual who, at the time of the withholding, is a Senator.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts in Thrift Savings Fund as source of reimbursement</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If, by the expiration of the 180-day period that begins on the date a payment is made from the account described in subsection (a) for an award or settlement described in paragraph (1), an individual who is subject to a reimbursement requirement of this subsection has not reimbursed the account for the entire reimbursable portion as required under paragraph (1), withholding and transfers of amounts shall continue under paragraph (2) if the individual remains employed in the same position, and the Executive Director of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board shall make a transfer described in subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The transfer by such Executive Director is a transfer, from the account of the individual in the Thrift Savings Fund to the account described in subsection (a), of an amount equal to the amount of that reimbursable portion of the award or settlement, reduced by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any amount the individual has reimbursed, taking into account any amounts withheld under paragraph (2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the individual remains employed in the same position, any amount that the individual is scheduled to reimburse, taking into account any amounts to be withheld under the individual’s timetable under paragraph (2).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiation of transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding <ref>section 8435 of title 5</ref>, the Executive Director described in subparagraph (A) shall make the transfer under subparagraph (A) upon receipt of a written request to the Executive Director from the Secretary of the Treasury, in the form and manner required by the Executive Director.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination between payroll administrator and the Executive Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The payroll administrator and the Executive Director described in subparagraph (A) shall carry out this paragraph in a manner that ensures the coordination of the withholding and transferring of amounts under this paragraph, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Board under <ref>section 1383 of this title</ref> and such Executive Director.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative wage garnishment or other collection of wages from a subsequent position</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individual subject to garnishment or other collection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subparagraph (B) shall apply to an individual who is subject to a reimbursement requirement of this subsection if, at any time after the expiration of the 270-day period that begins on the date a payment is made from the account described in subsection (a) for an award or settlement described in paragraph (1), the individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has not reimbursed the account for the entire reimbursable portion as required under paragraph (1), through withholdings or transfers under paragraphs (2) and (3);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is not serving in a position as a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is employed in a subsequent non-Federal position.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Garnishment or other collection of wages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On the expiration of that 270-day period, the amount of the reimbursable portion of an award or settlement described in paragraph (1) (reduced by any amount the individual has reimbursed, taking into account any amounts withheld or transferred under paragraph (2) or (3)) shall be treated as a claim of the United States and transferred to the Secretary of the Treasury for collection. Upon that transfer, the Secretary of the Treasury shall collect the claim, in accordance with <ref>section 3711 of title 31</ref>, including by administrative wage garnishment of the wages of the individual described in subparagraph (A) from the position described in subparagraph (A)(iii). The Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer the collected amount to the account described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification to Office of Personnel Management and Secretary of the Treasury</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individual subject to annuity or social security withholding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subparagraph (B) shall apply to an individual subject to a reimbursement requirement of this subsection if, at any time after the expiration of the 270-day period described in paragraph (4)(A), the individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has not served in a position as a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator during the preceding 90 days; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is not employed in a subsequent non-Federal position.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annuity or social security withholding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If, at any time after the 270-day period described in paragraph (4)(A), the individual described in subparagraph (A) has not reimbursed the account described in subsection (a) for the entire reimbursable portion of the award or settlement described in paragraph (1) (as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury), through withholdings, transfers, or collections under paragraphs (2) through (4), the Secretary of the Treasury (after consultation with the payroll administrator)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall notify the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, who shall take such actions as the Director considers appropriate to withhold from any annuity payable to the individual under chapter 83 or chapter 84 of title 5 and transfer to the account described in subsection (a), such amounts as may be necessary to reimburse the account for the remainder of the reimbursable portion of an award or settlement described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall (if necessary), notwithstanding section 207 of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 407</ref>), take such actions as the Secretary of the Treasury considers appropriate to withhold from any payment to the individual under title II of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.) and transfer to the account described in subsection (a), such amounts as may be necessary to reimburse the account for the remainder of the reimbursable portion of an award or settlement described in paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination between OPM and Treasury</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the Secretary of the Treasury shall carry out paragraph (5) in a manner that ensures the coordination of the withholding and transferring of amounts under such paragraph, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Director and the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Once the Executive Director determines that an individual who is subject to a reimbursement requirement of this subsection has reimbursed the account described in subsection (a) for the entire reimbursable portion, the Executive Director shall prepare a certification that the individual has completed that reimbursement, and submit the certification to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committees on House Administration and Ethics of the House of Representatives, in the case of an individual who, at the time of committing the act involved, was a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate, in the case of an individual who, at the time of committing the act involved, was a Senator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right to intervene</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An individual who is subject to a reimbursement requirement of this subsection shall have the unconditional right to intervene in any mediation, hearing, or civil action under this subchapter to protect the interests of the individual in the determination of whether an award or settlement described in paragraph (1) should be made, and the amount of any such award or settlement, except that nothing in this paragraph may be construed to require the covered employee who filed the claim to be deposed by counsel for the individual in a deposition that is separate from any other deposition taken from the employee in connection with the hearing or civil action.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Federal position</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “non-Federal position” means a position other than the position of an employee, as defined in <ref>section 2105(a) of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payroll administrator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “payroll administrator” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of an individual who is a Member of the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, or an employee of the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer who is designated by the Chief Administrative Officer to carry out this subsection; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of an individual who is a Senator, the Secretary of the Senate, or an employee of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate who is designated by the Secretary to carry out this subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement by employing offices</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of payments made from account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As soon as practicable after the Executive Director is made aware that a payment of an award or settlement under this chapter has been made from the account described in subsection (a) in connection with a claim alleging a violation of section 1311(a) or 1316(a) of this title by an employing office (other than an employing office of the House of Representatives or an employing office of the Senate), the Executive Director shall notify the head of the employing office that the payment has been made, and shall include in the notification a statement of the amount of the payment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement by office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after receiving a notification from the Executive Director under paragraph (1), the head of the employing office involved shall transfer to the account described in subsection (a), out of any funds available for operating expenses of the office, a payment equal to the amount specified in the notification.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timetable and procedures for reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The head of an employing office shall transfer a payment under paragraph (2) in accordance with such timetable and procedures as may be established under regulations promulgated by the Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 415</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. I, title I, § 1101(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 425</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 153(a)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 786</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I</ref>, §§ 111(a), 115(a), <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5306</ref>, 5314.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1416.</num>
<heading> Confidentiality</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mediation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All information discussed or disclosed in the course of any mediation shall be strictly confidential, and the Executive Director shall notify each person participating in the mediation of the confidentiality requirement and of the sanctions applicable to any person who violates the confidentiality requirement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings and deliberations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsections (c), (d), and (e), all proceedings and deliberations of hearing officers and the Board, including any related records, shall be confidential. This subsection shall not apply to proceedings under <ref>section 1341 of this title</ref>, but shall apply to the deliberations of hearing officers and the Board under that section. The Executive Director shall notify each person participating in a proceeding or deliberation to which this subsection applies of the requirements of this subsection and of the sanctions applicable to any person who violates the requirements of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release of records for judicial action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The records of hearing officers and the Board may be made public if required for the purpose of judicial review under <ref>section 1407 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Automatic referral to Congressional Ethics Committee of dispositions of claims involving Members of Congress and senior staff</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referral</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Upon the final disposition under this subchapter (as described in paragraph (6)) of a claim alleging a violation described in <ref>section 1415(d)(1)(C) of this title</ref> committed personally by a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) or a Senator, or by a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate, the Executive Director shall refer the claim to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives, in the case of a Member or senior staff of the House; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate, in the case of a Senator or senior staff of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to records and information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Executive Director refers a claim to a Committee under paragraph (1), the Executive Director shall provide the Committee with access to the records of any preliminary reviews, hearings, or decisions of the hearing officers and the Board under this chapter, and any information relating to an award or settlement paid, in response to such claim.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review by Senate ethics committee of settlements of certain claims</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">After the receipt of a settlement agreement for a claim that includes an allegation of a violation described in <ref>section 1415(d)(1)(C) of this title</ref> committed personally by a Senator, the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not later than 90 days after that receipt, review the settlement agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> determine whether an investigation of the claim is warranted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if the Select Committee determines, after the investigation, that the claim that resulted in the settlement involved an actual violation described in <ref>section 1415(d)(1)(C) of this title</ref> committed personally by the Senator, then the Select Committee shall notify the Executive Director to request the reimbursement described in <ref>section 1415(d) of this title</ref> and include the settlement in the report required by section 1381(<i>l</i>) of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection of personally identifiable information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a Committee to which a claim is referred under paragraph (1) issues a report with respect to the claim, the Committee shall ensure that the report does not directly disclose the identity or position of the individual who filed the claim.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Committee authority to protect identity of a claimant</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If a Committee to which a claim is referred under paragraph (1) issues a report as described in paragraph (4) concerning a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) or a Senator, or a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate, the Committee may make an appropriate redaction to the information or data included in the report if the Chairman and Vice Chairman of the Committee reach agreement—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that including the information or data considered for redaction may lead to the unintentional disclosure of the identity or position of a claimant; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on the precise information or data to be redacted.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notation and statement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The report including any such redaction shall note each redaction and include a statement that the redaction was made solely for the purpose of avoiding such an unintentional disclosure of the identity or position of a claimant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retention of reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Committee making a redaction in accordance with this paragraph shall retain a copy of the report, without a redaction.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final disposition described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the “final disposition” of a claim means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An order or agreement to pay an award or settlement, including an agreement reached pursuant to mediation under <ref>section 1403 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A final decision of a hearing officer under <ref>section 1405(g) of this title</ref> that is no longer subject to review by the Board under <ref>section 1406 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A final decision of the Board under <ref>section 1406(e) of this title</ref> that is no longer subject to appeal to the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit under <ref>section 1407 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A final decision in a civil action under <ref>section 1408 of this title</ref> that is no longer subject to appeal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Senior staff defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “senior staff” means any individual who, at the time a violation occurred, was required to file a report under title I of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App. 101 et seq.).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002061">1</ref></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final decisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A final decision entered under section 1405(g) or 1406(e) of this title shall be made public if it is in favor of the complaining covered employee, or in favor of the charging party under <ref>section 1331 of this title</ref>, or if the decision reverses a decision of a hearing officer which had been in favor of the covered employee or charging party. The Board may make public any other decision at its discretion.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit a covered employee from disclosing the factual allegations underlying the covered employee’s claim, or to prohibit an employing office from disclosing the factual allegations underlying the employing office’s defense to the claim, in the course of any proceeding under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 416</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–6, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-03-20">Mar. 20, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 81</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I</ref>, §§ 112, 114, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5311</ref>, 5313.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1417.</num>
<heading> Option to request remote work assignment or paid leave of absence during pendency of procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Options for employees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remote work assignment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the request of a covered employee who files a claim alleging a violation of part A of subchapter II by the covered employee’s employing office, during the pendency of any of the procedures available under this subchapter for consideration of the claim, the employing office may permit the covered employee to carry out the employee’s responsibilities from a remote location (referred to in this section as “permitting a remote work assignment”) where such relocation would have the effect of materially reducing interactions between the covered employee and any person alleged to have committed the violation, instead of from a location of the employing office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for work assignments required to be carried out onsite</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If, in the determination of the covered employee’s employing office, a covered employee who makes a request under this subsection cannot carry out the employee’s responsibilities from a remote location or such relocation would not have the effect described in paragraph (1), the employing office may during the pendency of the procedures described in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> grant a paid leave of absence to the covered employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> permit a remote work assignment and grant a paid leave of absence to the covered employee; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> make another workplace adjustment, or permit a remote work assignment, that would have the effect of reducing interactions between the covered employee and any person alleged to have committed the violation described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ensuring no retaliation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An employing office may not grant a covered employee’s request under this subsection in a manner which would constitute a violation of <ref>section 1317 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No impact on vacation or personal leave</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In granting leave for a paid leave of absence under this section, an employing office shall not require the covered employee to substitute, for that leave, any of the accrued paid vacation or personal leave of the covered employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for arrangements subject to collective bargaining agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) does not apply to the extent that it is inconsistent with the terms and conditions of any collective bargaining agreement which is in effect with respect to an employing office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title IV, § 417</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title I, § 113(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5313</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1431.</num>
<heading> Exercise of rulemaking powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The provisions of sections 1302(b)(3), section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002062">1</ref> 1381(<i>l</i>), and 1384(c) of this title are enacted—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the House of Representatives and the Senate, respectively, and as such they shall be considered as part of the rules of such House, respectively, and such rules shall supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent therewith; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change such rules (so far as relating to such House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of each House.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 39</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title II, § 201(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5317</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1432.</num>
<heading> Political affiliation and place of residence</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall not be a violation of any provision of <ref>section 1311 of this title</ref> to consider the—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> party affiliation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> domicile; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> political compatibility with the employing office;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">of an employee referred to in subsection (b) with respect to employment decisions.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Employee” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), the term “employee” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an employee on the staff of the leadership of the House of Representatives or the leadership of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> an employee on the staff of a committee or subcommittee of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Senate; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a joint committee of the Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an employee on the staff of a Member of the House of Representatives or on the staff of a Senator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an officer of the House of Representatives or the Senate or a congressional employee who is elected by the House of Representatives or Senate or is appointed by a Member of the House of Representatives or by a Senator (in addition an employee described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3)); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an applicant for a position that is to be occupied by an individual described in any of paragraphs (1) through (4).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 39</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1433.</num>
<heading> Nondiscrimination rules of House and Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate and the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of the House of Representatives retain full power, in accordance with the authority provided to them by the Senate and the House, with respect to the discipline of Members, officers, and employees for violating rules of the Senate and the House on nondiscrimination in employment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 40</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1434.</num>
<heading> Judicial branch coverage study</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Judicial Conference of the United States shall prepare a report for submission by the Chief Justice of the United States to the Congress on the application to the judicial branch of the Federal Government of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12101</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 621</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2611</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> chapter 71 (relating to Federal service labor-management relations) of title 5;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2001</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 2101</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> chapter 43 (relating to veterans’ employment and reemployment) of title 38.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The report shall be submitted to Congress not later than <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date>, and shall include any recommendations the Judicial Conference may have for legislation to provide to employees of the judicial branch the rights, protections, and procedures under the listed laws, including administrative and judicial relief, that are comparable to those available to employees of the legislative branch under subchapters I through IV of this chapter.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 41</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1435.</num>
<heading> Savings provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition provisions for employees of House of Representatives and of Senate</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Claims arising before effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, as of the date on which <ref>section 1311 of this title</ref> takes effect, an employee of the Senate or the House of Representatives has or could have requested counseling under section 305 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002063">1</ref> of the Government Employees Rights Act of 1991 or Rule LI of the House of Representatives, including counseling for alleged violations of family and medical leave rights under title V of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, the employee may complete, or initiate and complete, all procedures under the Government Employees Rights Act of 1991 and Rule LI, and the provisions of that Act and Rule shall remain in effect with respect to, and provide the exclusive procedures for, those claims until the completion of all such procedures.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Claims arising between effective date and opening of Office</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a claim by an employee of the Senate or House of Representatives arises under section 1311 or 1312 of this title after the effective date of such sections, but before the opening of the Office for receipt of requests for counseling or mediation under sections 1402 and 1403 of this title, the provisions of the Government Employees Rights Act of 1991 and Rule LI of the House of Representatives relating to counseling and mediation shall remain in effect, and the employee may complete under that Act or Rule the requirements for counseling and mediation under sections 1402 and 1403 of this title. If, after counseling and mediation is completed, the Office has not yet opened for the filing of a timely complaint under <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref>, the employee may elect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to file a complaint under section 307 of the Government Employees Rights Act of 1991 <sup>1</sup> or Rule LI of the House of Representatives, and thereafter proceed exclusively under that Act or Rule, the provisions of which shall remain in effect until the completion of all proceedings in relation to the complaint, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to commence a civil action under <ref>section 1408 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold">
<ref>Section 1207a of this title</ref>
</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to payments of awards and settlements relating to Senate employees under paragraph (1) of this subsection, section 1207a <sup>1</sup> of this title remains in effect.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition provisions for employees of Architect of Capitol</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Claims arising before effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, as of the date on which <ref>section 1311 of this title</ref> takes effect, an employee of the Architect of the Capitol has or could have filed a charge or complaint regarding an alleged violation of section 1831(e)(2) <sup>1</sup> of this title, the employee may complete, or initiate and complete, all procedures under section 1831(e) <sup>1</sup> of this title, the provisions of which shall remain in effect with respect to, and provide the exclusive procedures for, that claim until the completion of all such procedures.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Claims arising between effective date and opening of Office</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a claim by an employee of the Architect of the Capitol arises under section 1311 or 1312 of this title after the effective date of those provisions, but before the opening of the Office for receipt of requests for counseling or mediation under sections 1402 and 1403 of this title, the employee may satisfy the requirements for counseling and mediation by exhausting the requirements prescribed by the Architect of the Capitol in accordance with section 1831(e)(3) <sup>1</sup> of this title. If, after exhaustion of those requirements the Office has not yet opened for the filing of a timely complaint under <ref>section 1405 of this title</ref>, the employee may elect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to file a charge with the General Accounting Office Personnel Appeals Board <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002064">2</ref> pursuant to section 1831(e)(3) <sup>1</sup> of this title, and thereafter proceed exclusively under section 1831(e) <sup>1</sup> of this title, the provisions of which shall remain in effect until the completion of all proceedings in relation to the charge, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to commence a civil action under <ref>section 1408 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition provision relating to matters other than employment under <ref>section 12209 of title 42</ref></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to matters other than employment under section 12209 <sup>1</sup> of title 42, the rights, protections, remedies, and procedures of section 12209 <sup>1</sup> of title 42 shall remain in effect until <ref>section 1331 of this title</ref> takes effect with respect to each of the entities covered by section 12209 <sup>1</sup> of title 42.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 42</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1436.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 106–57, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 428</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1437.</num>
<heading> Sense of Senate regarding adoption of simplified and streamlined acquisition procedures for Senate acquisitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of the Senate that the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate should review the rules applicable to purchases by Senate offices to determine whether they are consistent with the acquisition simplification and streamlining laws enacted in the Federal Acquisition Streamlining Act of 1994 (<ref>Public Law 103–355</ref>).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title V, § 508</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 44</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1437a.</num>
<heading> Training and education programs of employing offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requiring offices to develop and implement programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each employing office shall develop and implement a program to train and educate covered employees of the office in the rights and protections provided under this chapter, including the procedures available under subchapter IV to consider alleged violations of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to committees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 45 days after the beginning of each Congress (beginning with the One Hundred Seventeenth Congress), each employing office shall submit a report to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate on the implementation of the program required under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for first report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2018-12-21">December 21, 2018</date>, each employing office shall submit the report described in paragraph (1) to the Committees described in such paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for offices of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section does not apply to an employing office of the House of Representatives or an employing office of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title V, § 509</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title III, § 306(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5324</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1437b.</num>
<heading> Support for out-of-area covered employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All covered employees whose location of employment is outside of the Washington, DC area (referred to in this section as “out-of-area covered employees”) shall have equitable access to the resources and services provided by the Office and under this chapter as is provided to covered employees who work in the Washington, DC area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of Congressional Workplace Rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish a method by which out-of-area covered employees may communicate securely with the Office, which shall include an option for real-time audiovisual communication; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide guidance to employing offices regarding how each office can facilitate equitable access to the resources and services provided under this chapter for its out-of-area covered employees, including information regarding the communication methods described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employing offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that each employing office with out-of-area covered employees should use its best efforts to facilitate equitable access to the resources and services provided under this chapter for those employees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title V, § 510</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title III, § 307(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5325</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1438.</num>
<heading> Severability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be invalid, the remainder of this chapter and the application of the provisions of the remainder to any person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title V, § 511</ref>, formerly § 509, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 44</ref>; renumbered § 510, renumbered § 511, <ref>Pub. L. 115–397, title III</ref>, §§ 306(a)(1), 307(a)(1), <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5324</ref>, 5325.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>