<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 43—</num>
<heading>CONGRESSIONAL COMMITTEES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4301.</num>
<heading> Committee staffs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment of professional members; number; qualifications; termination of employment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each standing committee of the Senate (other than the Committee on Appropriations) is authorized to appoint, by majority vote of the committee, not more than six professional staff members in addition to the clerical staffs. Such professional staff members shall be assigned to the chairman and the ranking minority member of such committee as the committee may deem advisable, except that whenever a majority of the minority members of such committee so request, two of such professional staff members may be selected for appointment by majority vote of the minority members and the committee shall appoint any staff members so selected. A staff member or members appointed pursuant to a request by the minority members of the committee shall be assigned to such committee business as such minority members deem advisable. Services of professional staff members appointed by majority vote of the committee may be terminated by a majority vote of the committee and services of professional staff members appointed pursuant to a request by the minority members of the committee shall be terminated by the committee when a majority of such minority members so request. Professional staff members authorized by this subsection shall be appointed on a permanent basis, without regard to political affiliation, and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of their respective positions. Such professional staff members shall not engage in any work other than committee business and no other duties may be assigned to them.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Professional members for Committee on Appropriations; examinations of executive agencies’ operation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to appropriations which it shall be in order to include in appropriation bills, the Committee on Appropriations of each House is authorized to appoint such staff, in addition to the clerk thereof and assistants for the minority, as each such committee, by a majority vote, shall determine to be necessary, such personnel, other than the minority assistants, to possess such qualifications as the committees respectively may prescribe, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House also is authorized to conduct studies and examinations of the organization and operation of any executive agency (including any agency the majority of the stock of which is owned by the Government of the United States) as it may deem necessary to assist it in connection with the determination of matters within its jurisdiction and in accordance with procedures authorized by the committee by a majority vote, including the rights and powers conferred by House Resolution Numbered 50, adopted <date date="1945-01-09">January 9, 1945</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Clerical employees; appointment; number; duties; termination of employment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The clerical staff of each standing committee of the Senate (other than the Committee on Appropriations), which shall be appointed by a majority vote of the committee, shall consist of not more than six clerks to be attached to the office of the chairman, to the ranking minority member, and to the professional staff, as the committee may deem advisable, except that whenever a majority of the minority members of such committee so requests, one of the members of the clerical staff may be selected for appointment by majority vote of such minority members and the committee shall appoint any staff member so selected. The clerical staff shall handle committee correspondence and stenographic work, both for the committee staff and for the chairman and ranking minority member on matters related to committee work, except that if a member of the clerical staff is appointed pursuant to a request by the minority members of the committee, such clerical staff member shall handle committee correspondence and stenographic work for the minority members of the committee and for any members of the committee staff appointed under subsection (a) pursuant to request by such minority members, on matters related to committee work. Services of clerical staff members appointed by majority vote of the committee may be terminated by majority vote of the committee and services of clerical staff members appointed pursuant to a request by the minority members of the committee shall be terminated by the committee when a majority of such minority members so request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recordation of committee hearings, data, etc.; access to records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All committee hearings, records, data, charts, and files shall be kept separate and distinct from the congressional office records of the Member serving as chairman of the committee; and such records shall be the property of the Congress and all members of the committee and the respective Houses shall have access to such records. Each committee is authorized to have printed and bound such testimony and other data presented at hearings held by the committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title IV, § 477(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1195</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on appointment of professional members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No committee shall appoint to its staff any experts or other personnel detailed or assigned from any department or agency of the Government, except with the written permission of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate or the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives, as the case may be.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointments when no vacancy exists; payment from Senate contingent fund</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In any case in which a request for the appointment of a minority staff member under subsection (a) or subsection (c) is made at any time when no vacancy exists to which the appointment requested may be made—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the person appointed pursuant to such a request under subsection (a) may serve in addition to any other professional staff members authorized by such subsection and may be paid from the contingent fund of the Senate until such time as such a vacancy occurs, at which time such person shall be considered to have been appointed to such vacancy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the person appointed pursuant to such a request under subsection (c) may serve in addition to any other clerical staff members authorized by such subsection and may be paid, until otherwise provided, from the contingent fund of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Salary rates, assignment of facilities, and accessibility of committee records for minority staff appointees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Staff members appointed pursuant to a request by minority members of a committee under subsection (a) or subsection (c), and staff members appointed to assist minority members of subcommittees pursuant to authority of Senate resolution, shall be accorded equitable treatment with respect to the fixing of salary rates, the assignment of facilities, and the accessibility of committee records.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultants for Senate and House standing committees; procurement of temporary or intermittent services; contracts; advertisement requirements inapplicable; selection method; qualifications report to Congressional committees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each standing committee of the Senate or House of Representatives is authorized, with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration in the case of standing committees of the Senate, or the Committee on House Oversight in the case of standing committees of the House of Representatives, within the limits of funds made available from the contingent fund of the Senate or the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives pursuant to resolutions which, in the case of the Senate, shall specify the maximum amounts which may be used for such purpose, approved by the appropriate House, to procure the temporary services (not in excess of one year) or intermittent services of individual consultants, or organizations thereof, to make studies or advise the committee with respect to any matter within its jurisdiction or with respect to the administration of the affairs of the committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such services in the case of individuals or organizations may be procured by contract as independent contractors, or in the case of individuals by employment at daily rates of compensation not in excess of the per diem equivalent of the highest gross rate of compensation which may be paid to a regular employee of the committee. Such contracts shall not be subject to the provisions of <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref> or any other provision of law requiring advertising.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> With respect to the standing committees of the Senate, any such consultant or organization shall be selected by the chairman and ranking minority member of the committee, acting jointly. With respect to the standing committees of the House of Representatives, the standing committee concerned shall select any such consultant or organization. The committee shall submit to the Committee on Rules and Administration in the case of standing committees of the Senate, and the Committee on House Oversight in the case of standing committees of the House of Representatives, information bearing on the qualifications of each consultant whose services are procured pursuant to this subsection, including organizations, and such information shall be retained by that committee and shall be made available for public inspection upon request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specialized training for professional staffs of Senate and House standing committees, Senate Appropriations Committee, Senate Majority and Minority Policy Committees, and joint committees whose funding is disbursed by Secretary of Senate or Chief Administrative Officer of House; assistance: pay, tuition, etc. while training; continued employment agreement; service credit: retirement, life insurance and health insurance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each standing committee of the Senate or House of Representatives is authorized, with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration in the case of standing committees of the Senate, and the committee involved in the case of standing committees of the House of Representatives, and within the limits of funds made available from the contingent fund of the Senate or the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives pursuant to resolutions, which, in the case of the Senate, shall specify the maximum amounts which may be used for such purpose, approved by the appropriate House, to provide assistance for members of its professional staff in obtaining specialized training, whenever that committee determines that such training will aid the committee in the discharge of its responsibilities. Any joint committee of the Congress whose expenses are paid out of funds disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate or by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Majority Policy Committee and Minority Policy Committee of the Senate are each authorized to expend, for the purpose of providing assistance in accordance with paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection for members of its staff in obtaining such training, any part of amounts appropriated to that committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such assistance may be in the form of continuance of pay during periods of training or grants of funds to pay tuition, fees, or such other expenses of training, or both, as may be approved by the Committee on Rules and Administration or the Committee on House Administration, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A committee providing assistance under this subsection shall obtain from any employee receiving such assistance such agreement with respect to continued employment with the committee as the committee may deem necessary to assure that it will receive the benefits of such employee’s services upon completion of his training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> During any period for which an employee is separated from employment with a committee for the purpose of undergoing training under this subsection, such employee shall be considered to have performed service (in nonpay status) as an employee of the committee at the rate of compensation received immediately prior to commencing such training (including any increases in compensation provided by law during the period of training) for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subchapter III (relating to civil service retirement) of chapter 83 of title 5,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> chapter 87 (relating to Federal employees group life insurance) of title 5, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> chapter 89 (relating to Federal employees group health insurance) of title 5.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title II, § 202, <ref>60 Stat. 834</ref>; <ref>July 30, 1947, ch. 361</ref>, title I, § 101, <ref>61 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref>Feb. 24, 1949, ch. 8</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 6</ref>; <ref>Aug. 5, 1955, ch. 568, § 12</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–462, § 4</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1958-06-20">June 20, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–426, title II, § 202(j)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 414</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title III</ref>, §§ 301(a)–(c), 303, 304, title IV, § 477(a)(3), <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1175</ref>, 1176, 1179, 1180, 1195; <ref>Pub. L. 92–136, § 5</ref>, <date date="1971-10-11">Oct. 11, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 378</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–458, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2184</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(10)</ref>, (11), <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4302.</num>
<heading> Maximum annual rate of compensation of Chief of Staff of Joint Committee on Taxation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The maximum annual rate of compensation of the Chief of Staff of the Joint Committee on Taxation shall not exceed the greater of $173,900 or the rate of pay in effect for such position under an order issued by the Speaker of the House of Representatives pursuant to the authority of <ref>section 4532 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 90–206, title II, § 214(e)</ref>, <date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 636</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4581</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2778</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4303.</num>
<heading> Preparation and contents of statement of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The statement of all appropriations made during each session of Congress shall be prepared under the direction of the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and House of Representatives, and said statement shall contain a chronological history of the regular appropriation bills passed during the session for which it is prepared. The statement shall indicate the amount of contracts authorized by appropriation Acts in addition to appropriations made therein, and shall also contain specific reference to all indefinite appropriations made each session and shall contain such additional information concerning estimates and appropriations as the committees may deem necessary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 19, 1888, ch. 1210, § 1</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 587</ref>; <ref>July 19, 1897, ch. 9</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 136</ref>; <ref>June 7, 1924, ch. 303, § 1</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 586</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4311.</num>
<heading> Approval of employment and compensation of committee employees by House standing committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Standing committees of the House shall have authority to approve the employment and compensation of committee employees (other than special and select committee employees) from the effective date of the beginning of each Congress, or such subsequent date as their service commenced.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–130, § 103</ref>, <date date="1961-08-10">Aug. 10, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 334</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4312.</num>
<heading> Regulations governing availability of appropriations for House committee employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations for committee employees shall be available in such amounts and under such regulations as may be approved by the Committee on House Oversight for compensation of employees of the standing committees of the House of Representatives, except the Committee on Appropriations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 17, 1947, ch. 262</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 367</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(12)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1731</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4313.</num>
<heading> Adjustment of House of Representatives allowances by Committee on House Oversight</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the provision of law specified in subsection (b), the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives may, by order of the Committee, fix and adjust the amounts, terms, and conditions of, and other matters relating to, allowances of the House of Representatives within the following categories:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For Members of the House of Representatives, the Members’ Representational Allowance, including all aspects of official mail within the jurisdiction of the Committee under <ref>section 503 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For committees, the Speaker, the Majority and Minority Leaders, the Clerk, the Sergeant at Arms, and the Chief Administrative Officer, allowances for official mail (including all aspects of official mail within the jurisdiction of the Committee under <ref>section 503 of this title</ref>), stationery, and telephone and telegraph and other communications.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision specified</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provision of law referred to in subsection (a) is <ref>section 4314 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Member of the House of Representatives” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “Member of the House of Representatives” means a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–184</ref>, ch. IV, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 636</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–57, title I, § 103(a)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 415</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4314.</num>
<heading> Limitation on allowance authority of Committee on House Oversight</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An order under the provision of law specified in subsection (c) may fix or adjust the allowances of the House of Representatives only by reason of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a change in the price of materials, services, or office space;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a technological change or other improvement in office equipment; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an increase under <ref>section 5303 of title 5</ref> in rates of pay under the General Schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resolution requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of reasons other than the reasons specified in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a), the fixing and adjustment of the allowances of the House of Representatives in the categories described in the provision of law specified in subsection (c) may be carried out only by resolution of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision specified</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provision of law referred to in subsections (a) and (b) is <ref>section 4313 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–440, title II, § 101</ref>, <date date="1976-10-01">Oct. 1, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1448</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1720</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4315.</num>
<heading> Overtime pay for FBI employees detailed to House Committee on Appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Bureau of Investigation, notwithstanding any other provision of law, may in any fiscal year pay all administrative uncontrollable overtime accrued by its employees while on detail to the Committee on Appropriations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–283, title I</ref>, <date date="1994-07-22">July 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1430</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4316.</num>
<heading> Allowances for compensation of interns in House committee offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of allowances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are established for the House of Representatives the following allowances:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An allowance which shall be available for the compensation of interns who serve in offices of a standing, special, or select committee of the House (other than the Committee on Appropriations).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An allowance which shall be available for the compensation of interns who serve in offices of the Committee on Appropriations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benefit exclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 5321(b) of this title</ref> shall apply with respect to an intern who is compensated under an allowance under this section in the same manner as such section applies with respect to an intern who is compensated under the Members’ Representational Allowance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “intern”, with respect to a committee of the House, has the meaning given such term with respect to a Member of the House of Representatives in <ref>section 5321(c)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2022 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. I, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 510</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>SENATE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4331.</num>
<heading> Computation of compensation for stenographic assistance of committees payable from Senate contingent fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Compensation for stenographic assistance of committees paid out of the items under “Contingent Expenses of the Senate” on and after <date date="1956-06-27">June 27, 1956</date> shall be computed at such rates and in accordance with such regulations as may be prescribed by the Committee on Rules and Administration, notwithstanding, and without regard to any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 27, 1956, ch. 453</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4332.</num>
<heading> Assistance to Senators with committee memberships by employees in office of Senator</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Senator may designate employees in his office to assist him in connection with his membership on committees of the Senate. An employee may be designated with respect to only one committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification; professional staff privileges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employee designated by a Senator under this section shall be certified by him to the chairman and ranking minority member of the committee with respect to which such designation is made. Such employee shall be accorded all privileges of a professional staff member (whether permanent or investigatory) of such committee including access to all committee sessions and files, except that any such committee may restrict access to its sessions to one staff member per Senator at a time and require, if classified material is being handled or discussed, that any staff member possess the appropriate security clearance before being allowed access to such material or to discussion of it. Nothing contained in this paragraph shall be construed to prohibit a committee from adopting policies and practices with respect to the application of this section which are similar to the policies and practices adopted with respect to the application of section 705(c)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002089">1</ref> of Senate Resolution 4, 95th Congress, and section 72a–1d(c)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002089">1</ref> of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Senator shall notify the chairman and ranking minority member of a committee whenever a designation of an employee under this section with respect to such committee is terminated.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 111(c)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 662</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4333.</num>
<heading> Expenses of committees payable from Senate contingent fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When any duty is imposed upon a committee involving expenses that are ordered to be paid out of the contingent fund of the Senate, upon vouchers to be approved by the chairman of the committee charged with such duty, the receipt of such chairman for any sum advanced to him or his order out of said contingent fund by the Secretary of the Senate for committee expenses not involving personal services shall be taken and passed by the accounting officers of the Government as a full and sufficient voucher; but it shall be the duty of such chairman, as soon as practicable, to furnish to the Secretary of the Senate vouchers in detail for the expenses so incurred.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1879, ch. 183</ref>, <ref>20 Stat. 419</ref>; <ref>June 10, 1921, ch. 18</ref>, title III, § 304, <ref>42 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>June 22, 1949, ch. 235, § 101</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 218</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4334.</num>
<heading> Availability of funds for franked mail expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds in the account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, available for the expenses of inquiries and investigations shall be available for franked mail expenses incurred by committees of the Senate the other expenses of which are paid from that account.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title I, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4335.</num>
<heading> Employment of civilian employees of executive branch of Government by Senate Committee on Appropriations; restoration to former position</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever any person has left or leaves any civilian position in any department or agency in the executive branch of the Government in order to accept employment by the Senate Committee on Appropriations, he shall be carried on the rolls of such committee and shall be solely employed by such committee, and responsible only to it; but he shall be entitled upon making application to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management within thirty days after the termination of his employment by such committee (unless such employment is terminated for cause) to be restored to a position in the same or any other department or agency where an opening exists, comparable to the position which, according to the records of the department or agency which he left to accept employment by the Senate Committee on Appropriations or in the judgment of the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, such person would be occupying if he had remained in the employ of such department or agency during the time he was employed by such committee; and such person shall be restored to such position with the same seniority, status, and pay as if he had remained in the employ of the department or agency which he left, during such time. This section shall not be construed to require any person to be restored to a position in any department or agency after the expiration of the time for which he was appointed to the position which he left to accept employment by such committee.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 13, 1945, ch. 189, § 1</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 243</ref>; <ref>July 1, 1946, ch. 530</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 392</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref>92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4336.</num>
<heading> Discretionary authority of Senate Committee on Appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Committee on Appropriations is authorized in its discretion—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to hold hearings, report such hearings, and make investigations as authorized by paragraph 1 of rule XXVI of the Standing Rules of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to make expenditures from the contingent fund of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to employ personnel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> with the prior consent of the Government department or agency concerned and the Committee on Rules and Administration to use, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, the services of personnel of any such department or agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to procure the services of individual consultants, or organizations thereof (as authorized by <ref>section 4301(i) of this title</ref> and Senate Resolution 140, agreed to <date date="1975-05-14">May 14, 1975</date>, except that any approval (and related reporting requirement) shall not apply); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to provide for the training of the professional staff of such committee (under procedures specified by <ref>section 4301(j) of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall be effective on and after <date date="1998-10-01">October 1, 1998</date>, or the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-21">October 21, 1998</date>], whichever is later.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 10</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2435</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–55, title I, § 6</ref>, <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4337.</num>
<heading> Transfer of funds by Chairman of Senate Committee on Appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Appropriations Committee of the Senate may, during any fiscal year, at his or her election transfer funds from the appropriation account for salaries for the Appropriations Committee of the Senate, to the account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, from which expenses are payable for such committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Appropriations Committee of the Senate may, during any fiscal year, at his or her election transfer funds from the appropriation account for expenses, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for the Appropriations Committee of the Senate, to the account from which salaries are payable for such committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds; times of transfer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any funds transferred under this section shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> available for expenditure by such committee in like manner and for the same purposes as are other moneys which are available for expenditure by such committee from the account to which the funds were transferred; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> made at such time or times as the Chairman shall specify in writing to the Senate Disbursing Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect on <date date="1998-10-01">October 1, 1998</date>, and shall be effective with respect to fiscal years beginning on or after that date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 11</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2435</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4338.</num>
<heading> Designation by Senator who is Chairman or Vice Chairman of Senate Select Committee on Ethics of employee in office of that Senator to perform part-time service for Committee; amount reimbursable; procedure applicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, a Senator who is the Chairman or Vice Chairman of the Senate Select Committee on Ethics may designate one employee employed in his Senate office to perform part-time service for such Committee, and such Committee shall reimburse such Senator for such employee’s services for the Committee by transferring from the contingent fund of the Senate, upon vouchers approved by the Chairman of such Committee, to such Senator’s Administrative, Clerical, and Legislative Assistance Allowance, with respect to each pay period of such employee, an amount which bears the same ratio to such employee’s salary (but not more than one-half of such salary) for such period, as the portion of the time spent (or to be spent) by such employee in performing services for such Committee during such period bears to the total time for which such employee worked (or will work) during such period (as determined by the Chairman of such Committee) for such Committee and in such Senator’s office. Any funds transferred under authority of the preceding sentence to a Senator’s Administrative, Clerical, and Legislative Assistance <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002090">1</ref> shall be available for the same purposes and in like manner as funds therein which were not transferred thereto under such authority. For purposes of any law of the United States, a State, a territory, or a political subdivision thereof, an employee designated by a Senator pursuant to this section shall be considered to be an employee of such Senator’s Senate office and not an employee of the Senate Select Committee on Ethics.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 10</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 476</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>