<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>OFFICE OF TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 471.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declaration of purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress hereby finds and declares that:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> As technology continues to change and expand rapidly, its applications are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> large and growing in scale; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> increasingly extensive, pervasive, and critical in their impact, beneficial and adverse, on the natural and social environment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Therefore, it is essential that, to the fullest extent possible, the consequences of technological applications be anticipated, understood, and considered in determination of public policy on existing and emerging national problems.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress further finds that:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Federal agencies presently responsible directly to the Congress are not designed to provide the legislative branch with adequate and timely information, independently developed, relating to the potential impact of technological applications, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the present mechanisms of the Congress do not and are not designed to provide the legislative branch with such information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Accordingly, it is necessary for the Congress to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> equip itself with new and effective means for securing competent, unbiased information concerning the physical, biological, economic, social, and political effects of such applications; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> utilize this information, whenever appropriate, as one factor in the legislative assessment of matters pending before the Congress, particularly in those instances where the Federal Government may be called upon to consider support for, or management or regulation of, technological applications.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–484, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 797</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 472.</num>
<heading> Office of Technology Assessment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Creation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In accordance with the findings and declaration of purpose in <ref>section 471 of this title</ref>, there is hereby created the Office of Technology Assessment (hereinafter referred to as the “Office”) which shall be within and responsible to the legislative branch of the Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office shall consist of a Technology Assessment Board (hereinafter referred to as the “Board”) which shall formulate and promulgate the policies of the Office, and a Director who shall carry out such policies and administer the operations of the Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions and duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The basic function of the Office shall be to provide early indications of the probable beneficial and adverse impacts of the applications of technology and to develop other coordinate information which may assist the Congress. In carrying out such function, the Office shall:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify existing or probable impacts of technology or technological programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> where possible, ascertain cause-and-effect relationships;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify alternative technological methods of implementing specific programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> identify alternative programs for achieving requisite goals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> make estimates and comparisons of the impacts of alternative methods and programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> present findings of completed analyses to the appropriate legislative authorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> identify areas where additional research or data collection is required to provide adequate support for the assessments and estimates described in paragraph (1) through (5) of this subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> undertake such additional associated activities as the appropriate authorities specified under subsection (d) may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiation of assessment activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Assessment activities undertaken by the Office may be initiated upon the request of:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the chairman of any standing, special, or select committee of either House of the Congress, or of any joint committee of the Congress, acting for himself or at the request of the ranking minority member or a majority of the committee members;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Board; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Director, in consultation with the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Assessments made by the Office, including information, surveys, studies, reports, and findings related thereto, shall be made available to the initiating committee or other appropriate committees of the Congress. In addition, any such information, surveys, studies, reports, and findings produced by the Office may be made available to the public except where—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to do so would violate security statutes; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Board considers it necessary or advisable to withhold such information in accordance with one or more of the numbered paragraphs in <ref>section 552(b) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–484, § 3</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 797</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 473.</num>
<heading> Technology Assessment Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Board shall consist of thirteen members as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> six Members of the Senate, appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate, three from the majority party and three from the minority party;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> six Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, three from the majority party and three from the minority party; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Director, who shall not be a voting member.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Execution of functions during vacancies; filling of vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Vacancies in the membership of the Board shall not affect the power of the remaining members to execute the functions of the Board and shall be filled in the same manner as in the case of the original appointment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairman and vice chairman; selection procedure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall select a chairman and a vice chairman from among its members at the beginning of each Congress. The vice chairman shall act in the place and stead of the chairman in the absence of the chairman. The chairmanship and the vice chairmanship shall alternate between the Senate and the House of Representatives with each Congress. The chairman during each even-numbered Congress shall be selected by the Members of the House of Representatives on the Board from among their number. The vice chairman during each Congress shall be chosen in the same manner from that House of Congress other than the House of Congress of which the chairman is a Member.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings; powers of Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board is authorized to sit and act at such places and times during the sessions, recesses, and adjourned periods of Congress, and upon a vote of a majority of its members, to require by subpena or otherwise the attendance of such witnesses and the production of such books, papers, and documents, to administer such oaths and affirmations, to take such testimony, to procure such printing and binding, and to make such expenditures, as it deems advisable. The Board may make such rules respecting its organization and procedures as it deems necessary, except that no recommendation shall be reported from the Board unless a majority of the Board assent. Subpenas may be issued over the signature of the chairman of the Board or of any voting member designated by him or by the Board, and may be served by such person or persons as may be designated by such chairman or member. The chairman of the Board or any voting member thereof may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–484, § 4</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 798</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 474.</num>
<heading> Director of Office of Technology Assessment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment; term; compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Technology Assessment shall be appointed by the Board and shall serve for a term of six years unless sooner removed by the Board. He shall receive basic pay at the rate provided for level III of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers and duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the powers and duties vested in him by this chapter, the Director shall exercise such powers and duties as may be delegated to him by the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deputy Director; appointment; functions; compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may appoint with the approval of the Board, a Deputy Director who shall perform such functions as the Director may prescribe and who shall be Acting Director during the absence or incapacity of the Director or in the event of a vacancy in the office of Director. The Deputy Director shall receive basic pay at the rate provided for level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on outside employment activities of Director and Deputy Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Neither the Director nor the Deputy Director shall engage in any other business, vocation, or employment than that of serving as such Director or Deputy Director, as the case may be; nor shall the Director or Deputy Director, except with the approval of the Board, hold any office in, or act in any capacity for, any organization, agency, or institution with which the Office makes any contract or other arrangement under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–484, § 5</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 799</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 475.</num>
<heading> Powers of Office of Technology Assessment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of public and private personnel and organizations; formation of special ad hoc task forces; contracts with governmental, etc., agencies and instrumentalities; advance, progress, and other payments; utilization of services of voluntary and uncompensated personnel; acquisition, holding, and disposal of real and personal property; promulgation of rules and regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office shall have the authority, within the limits of available appropriations, to do all things necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter, including, but without being limited to, the authority to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make full use of competent personnel and organizations outside the Office, public or private, and form special ad hoc task forces or make other arrangements when appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enter into contracts or other arrangements as may be necessary for the conduct of the work of the Office with any agency or instrumentality of the United States, with any State, territory, or possession or any political subdivision thereof, or with any person, firm, association, corporation, or educational institution, with or without reimbursement, without performance or other bonds, and without regard to <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make advance, progress, and other payments which relate to technology assessment without regard to the provisions of section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> accept and utilize the services of voluntary and uncompensated personnel necessary for the conduct of the work of the Office and provide transportation and subsistence as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>, for persons serving without compensation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> acquire by purchase, lease, loan, or gift, and hold and dispose of by sale, lease, or loan, real and personal property of all kinds necessary for or resulting from the exercise of authority granted by this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> prescribe such rules and regulations as it deems necessary governing the operation and organization of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recordkeeping by contractors and other parties entering into contracts and other arrangements with Office; availability of books and records to Office and Comptroller General for audit and examination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Contractors and other parties entering into contracts and other arrangements under this section which involve costs to the Government shall maintain such books and related records as will facilitate an effective audit in such detail and in such manner as shall be prescribed by the Office, and such books and rec­ords (and related documents and papers) shall be available to the Office and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, for the purpose of audit and examination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operation of laboratories, pilot plants, or test facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office, in carrying out the provisions of this chapter, shall not, itself, operate any laboratories, pilot plants, or test facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests to executive departments or agencies for information, suggestions, estimates, statistics, and technical assistance; duty of executive departments and agencies to furnish information, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office is authorized to secure directly from any executive department or agency information, suggestions, estimates, statistics, and technical assistance for the purpose of carrying out its functions under this chapter. Each such executive department or agency shall furnish the information, suggestions, estimates, statistics, and technical assistance directly to the Office upon its request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requests to heads of executive departments or agencies for detail of personnel; reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On request of the Office, the head of any executive department or agency may detail, with or without reimbursement, any of its personnel to assist the Office in carrying out its functions under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation of personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall, in accordance with such policies as the Board shall prescribe, appoint and fix the compensation of such personnel as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–484, § 6</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 799</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 476.</num>
<heading> Technology Assessment Advisory Council</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office shall establish a Technology Assessment Advisory Council (hereinafter referred to as the “Council”). The Council shall be composed of the following twelve members:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ten members from the public, to be appointed by the Board, who shall be persons eminent in one or more fields of the physical, biological, or social sciences or engineering or experienced in the administration of technological activities, or who may be judged qualified on the basis of contributions made to educational or public activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Comptroller General; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Director of the Congressional Research Service of the Library of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council, upon request by the Board, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review and make recommendations to the Board on activities undertaken by the Office or on the initiation thereof in accordance with <ref>section 472(d) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> review and make recommendations to the Board on the findings of any assessment made by or for the Office; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> undertake such additional related tasks as the Board may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairman and Vice Chairman; election by Council from members appointed from public; terms and conditions of service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council by majority vote, shall elect from its members appointed under subsection (a)(1) of this section a Chairman and a Vice Chairman, who shall serve for such time and under such conditions as the Council may prescribe. In the absence of the Chairman, or in the event of his incapacity, the Vice Chairman shall act as Chairman.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of office of members appointed from public; reappointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term of office of each member of the Council appointed under subsection (a)(1) shall be four years except that any such member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. No person shall be appointed a member of the Council under subsection (a)(1) more than twice. Terms of the members appointed under subsection (a)(1) shall be staggered so as to establish a rotating membership according to such method as the Board may devise.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment to Comptroller General and Director of Congressional Research Service of travel and other necessary expenses; payment to members appointed from public of compensation and reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The members of the Council other than those appointed under subsection (a)(1) shall receive no pay for their services as members of the Council, but shall be allowed necessary travel expenses (or, in the alternative, mileage for use of privately owned vehicles and payments when traveling on official business at not to exceed the payment prescribed in regulations implementing section 5702 and in <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002022">1</ref> 5704 of title 5), and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of duties vested in the Council, without regard to the provisions of subchapter 1 of chapter 57 and <ref>section 5731 of title 5</ref>, and regulations promulgated thereunder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The members of the Council appointed under subsection (a)(1) shall receive compensation for each day engaged in the actual performance of duties vested in the Council at rates of pay not in excess of the daily equivalent of the highest rate of basic pay set forth in the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332(a) of title 5</ref>, and in addition shall be reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses in the manner provided for other members of the Council under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–484, § 7</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 800</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–234, title I, § 107(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-01-02">Jan. 2, 1986</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1759</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 477.</num>
<heading> Utilization of services of Library of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Librarian to make available services and assistance of Congressional Research Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out the objectives of this chapter, the Librarian of Congress is authorized to make available to the Office such services and assistance of the Congressional Research Service as may be appropriate and feasible.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of services and assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Such services and assistance made available to the Office shall include, but not be limited to, all of the services and assistance which the Congressional Research Service is otherwise authorized to provide to the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Services or responsibilities performed by Congressional Research Service for Congress not altered or modified; authority of Librarian to establish within Congressional Research Service additional divisions, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall alter or modify any services or responsibilities, other than those performed for the Office, which the Congressional Research Service under law performs for or on behalf of the Congress. The Librarian is, however, authorized to establish within the Congressional Research Service such additional divisions, groups, or other organizational entities as may be necessary to carry out the purpose of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for services and assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Services and assistance made available to the Office by the Congressional Research Service in accordance with this section may be provided with or without reimbursement from funds of the Office, as agreed upon by the Board and the Librarian of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–484, § 8</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 801</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 478.</num>
<heading> Utilization of the Government Accountability Office</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Government Accountability Office to furnish financial and administrative services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Financial and administrative services (including those related to budgeting, accounting, financial reporting, personnel, and procurement) and such other services as may be appropriate shall be provided the Office by the Government Accountability Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of services and assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Such services and assistance to the Office shall include, but not be limited to, all of the services and assistance which the Government Accountability Office is otherwise authorized to provide to the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Services or responsibilities performed by Government Accountability Office for Congress not altered or modified</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall alter or modify any services or responsibilities, other than those performed for the Office, which the Government Accountability Office under law performs for or on behalf of the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for services and assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Services and assistance made available to the Office by the Government Accountability Office in accordance with this section may be provided with or without reimbursement from funds of the Office, as agreed upon by the Board and the Comptroller General.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–484, § 9</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 802</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 479.</num>
<heading> Coordination of activities with National Science Foundation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office shall maintain a continuing liaison with the National Science Foundation with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> grants and contracts formulated or activated by the Foundation which are for purposes of technology assessment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the promotion of coordination in areas of technology assessment, and the avoidance of unnecessary duplication or overlapping of research activities in the development of technology assessment techniques and programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–484, § 10(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 802</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 480.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 481.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations; availability of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> To enable the Office to carry out its powers and duties, there is hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Office, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, not to exceed $5,000,000 in the aggregate for the two fiscal years ending <date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>, and <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>, and thereafter such sums as may be necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Appropriations made pursuant to the authority provided in subsection (a) shall remain available for obligation, for expenditure, or for obligation and expenditure for such period or periods as may be specified in the Act making such appropriations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 92–484, § 12</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 803</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>