<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 17—</num>
<heading>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 601.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is established an office of the Congress to be known as the Congressional Budget Office (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “Office”). The Office shall be headed by a Director; and there shall be a Deputy Director who shall perform such duties as may be assigned to him by the Director and, during the absence or incapacity of the Director or during a vacancy in that office, shall act as Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Director shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate after considering recommendations received from the Committees on the Budget of the House and the Senate, without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of his fitness to perform his duties. The Deputy Director shall be appointed by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term of office of the Director shall be 4 years and shall expire on January 3 of the year preceding each Presidential election. Any individual appointed as Director to fill a vacancy prior to the expiration of a term shall serve only for the unexpired portion of that term. An individual serving as Director at the expiration of a term may continue to serve until his successor is appointed. Any Deputy Director shall serve until the expiration of the term of office of the Director who appointed him (and until his successor is appointed), unless sooner removed by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Director may be removed by either House by resolution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Director shall receive compensation at an annual rate of pay that is equal to the maximum rate of pay in effect under <ref>section 4575(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Deputy Director shall receive compensation at an annual rate of pay that is $1,000 less than the annual rate of pay received by the Director, as determined under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall appoint and fix the compensation of such personnel as may be necessary to carry out the duties and functions of the Office. All personnel of the Office shall be appointed without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of their fitness to perform their duties. The Director may prescribe the duties and responsibilities of the personnel of the Office, and delegate to them authority to perform any of the duties, powers, and functions imposed on the Office or on the Director. For purposes of pay (other than pay of the Director and Deputy Director) and employment benefits, rights, and privileges, all personnel of the Office shall be treated as if they were employees of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Experts and consultants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the duties and functions of the Office, the Director may procure the temporary (not to exceed one year) or intermittent services of experts or consultants or organizations thereof by contract as independent contractors, or, in the case of individual experts or consultants, by employment at rates of pay not in excess of the daily equivalent of the highest rate of basic pay payable under the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to executive branch</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director is authorized to secure information, data, estimates, and statistics directly from the various departments, agencies, and establishments of the executive branch of Government and the regulatory agencies and commissions of the Government. All such departments, agencies, establishments, and regulatory agencies and commissions shall furnish the Director any available material which he determines to be necessary in the performance of his duties and functions (with or without written agreement) provided that the Director maintains the level of confidentiality required by law of the department, agency, establishment, or regulatory agency or commission from which it is obtained in accordance with <ref>section 603(e) of this title</ref>. The Director is also authorized, upon agreement with the head of any such department, agency, establishment, or regulatory agency or commission, to utilize its services, facilities, and personnel with or without reimbursement; and the head of each such department, agency, establishment, or regulatory agency or commission is authorized to provide the Office such services, facilities, and personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No provision of law enacted after <date date="2024-09-30">September 30, 2024</date>, shall be construed to supersede, limit, or otherwise modify the authority of the Director to obtain any material under this subsection unless such provision specifically provides, by specific reference to this paragraph, that such authority is to be superseded, limited, or otherwise modified.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to other agencies of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the duties and functions of the Office, and for the purpose of coordinating the operations of the Office with those of other congressional agencies with a view to utilizing most effectively the information, services, and capabilities of all such agencies in carrying out the various responsibilities assigned to each, the Director is authorized to obtain information, data, estimates, and statistics developed by the Government Accountability Office,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002023">1</ref> and the Library of Congress, and (upon agreement with them) to utilize their services, facilities, and personnel with or without reimbursement. The Comptroller General,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002023">1</ref> and the Librarian of Congress are authorized to provide the Office with the information, data, estimates, and statistics, and the services, facilities, and personnel, referred to in the preceding sentence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revenue estimates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of revenue legislation which is income, estate and gift, excise, and payroll taxes (i.e., Social Security), considered or enacted in any session of Congress, the Congressional Budget Office shall use exclusively during that session of Congress revenue estimates provided to it by the Joint Committee on Taxation. During that session of Congress such revenue estimates shall be transmitted by the Congressional Budget Office to any committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate requesting such estimates, and shall be used by such Committees in determining such estimates. The Budget Committees of the Senate and House shall determine all estimates with respect to scoring points of order and with respect to the execution of the purposes of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Office for each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to enable it to carry out its duties and functions. Until sums are first appropriated pursuant to the preceding sentence, but for a period not exceeding 12 months following the effective date of this subsection, the expenses of the Office shall be paid from the contingent fund of the Senate, in accordance with <ref>section 6503 of this title</ref>, and upon vouchers approved by the Director.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–344, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–177, title II, § 273</ref>, <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1098</ref>, renumbered <ref>§ 201(g) of Pub. L. 93–344</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13202(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–615</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13202(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–615</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–33, title X, § 10102</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 678</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(5) [title II, § 224]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–299; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(a)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–89, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-09-30">Sept. 30, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1557</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 602.</num>
<heading> Duties and functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to budget committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the primary duty and function of the Office to provide to the Committees on the Budget of both Houses information which will assist such committees in the discharge of all matters within their jurisdictions, including (1) information with respect to the budget, appropriation bills, and other bills authorizing or providing new budget authority or tax expenditures, (2) information with respect to revenues, receipts, estimated future revenues and receipts, and changing revenue conditions, and (3) such related information as such Committees may request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to Committees on Appropriations, Ways and Means, and Finance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of the Committee on Appropriations of either House, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, or the Committee on Finance of the Senate, the Office shall provide to such Committee any information which will assist it in the discharge of matters within its jurisdiction, including information described in clauses (1) and (2) of subsection (a) and such related information as the Committee may request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to other committees and Members</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> At the request of any other committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate or any joint committee of the Congress, the Office shall provide to such committee or joint committee any information compiled in carrying out clauses (1) and (2) of subsection (a), and, to the extent practicable, such additional information related to the foregoing as may be requested.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> At the request of any committee of the Senate or the House of Representatives, the Office shall, to the extent practicable, consult with and assist such committee in analyzing the budgetary or financial impact of any proposed legislation that may have—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a significant budgetary impact on State, local, or tribal governments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a significant financial impact on the private sector; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a significant employment impact on the private sector.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> At the request of any Member of the House or Senate, the Office shall provide to such Member any information compiled in carrying out clauses (1) and (2) of subsection (a), and, to the extent available, such additional information related to the foregoing as may be requested.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment of office personnel to committees and joint committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of the Committee on the Budget of either House, personnel of the Office shall be assigned, on a temporary basis, to assist such committee. At the request of any other committee of either House or any joint committee of the Congress, personnel of the Office may be assigned, on a temporary basis, to assist such committee or joint committee with respect to matters directly related to the applicable provisions of subsection (b) or (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to budget committees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> On or before February 15 of each year, the Director shall submit to the Committees on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report, for the fiscal year commencing on October 1 of that year, with respect to fiscal policy, including (A) alternative levels of total revenues, total new budget authority, and total outlays (including related surpluses and deficits), (B) the levels of tax expenditures under existing law, taking into account projected economic factors and any changes in such levels based on proposals in the budget submitted by the President for such fiscal year, and (C) a statement of the levels of budget authority and outlays for each program assumed to be extended in the baseline, as provided in <ref>section 907(b)(2)(A) of this title</ref> and for excise taxes assumed to be extended under <ref>section 907(b)(2)(C) of this title</ref>. Such report shall also include a discussion of national budget priorities, including alternative ways of allocating new budget authority and budget outlays for such fiscal year among major programs or functional categories, taking into account how such alternative allocations will meet major national needs and affect balanced growth and development of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Director shall from time to time submit to the Committees on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Senate such further reports (including reports revising the report required by paragraph (1)) as may be necessary or appropriate to provide such Committees with information, data, and analyses for the performance of their duties and functions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> On or before January 15 of each year, the Director, after consultation with the appropriate committees of the House of Representatives and Senate, shall submit to the Congress a report listing (A) all programs and activities funded during the fiscal year ending September 30 of that calendar year for which authorizations for appropriations have not been enacted for that fiscal year, and (B) all programs and activities for which authorizations for appropriations have been enacted for the fiscal year ending September 30 of that calendar year, but for which no authorizations for appropriations have been enacted for the fiscal year beginning October 1 of that calendar year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of computers and other techniques</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may equip the Office with up-to-date computer capability (upon approval of the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate), obtain the services of experts and consultants in computer technology, and develop techniques for the evaluation of budgetary requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Studies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing studies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall conduct continuing studies to enhance comparisons of budget outlays, credit authority, and tax expenditures.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal mandate studies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> At the request of any Chairman or ranking member of the minority of a Committee of the Senate or the House of Representatives, the Director shall, to the extent practicable, conduct a study of a legislative proposal containing a Federal mandate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> In conducting a study on intergovernmental mandates under subparagraph (A), the Director shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> solicit and consider information or comments from elected officials (including their designated representatives) of State, local, or tribal governments as may provide helpful information or comments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> consider establishing advisory panels of elected officials or their designated representatives, of State, local, or tribal governments if the Director determines that such advisory panels would be helpful in performing responsibilities of the Director under this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> if, and to the extent that the Director determines that accurate estimates are reasonably feasible, include estimates of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the future direct cost of the Federal mandate to the extent that such costs significantly differ from or extend beyond the 5-year period after the mandate is first effective; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any disproportionate budgetary effects of Federal mandates upon particular industries or sectors of the economy, States, regions, and urban or rural or other types of communities, as appropriate.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> In conducting a study on private sector mandates under subparagraph (A), the Director shall provide estimates, if and to the extent that the Director determines that such estimates are reasonably feasible, of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> future costs of Federal private sector mandates to the extent that such mandates differ significantly from or extend beyond the 5-year time period referred to in subparagraph (B)(iii)(I);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any disproportionate financial effects of Federal private sector mandates and of any Federal financial assistance in the bill or joint resolution upon any particular industries or sectors of the economy, States, regions, and urban or rural or other types of communities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the effect of Federal private sector mandates in the bill or joint resolution on the national economy, including the effect on productivity, economic growth, full employment, creation of productive jobs, and international competitiveness of United States goods and services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–344, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 304</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–177, title II, § 221</ref>, <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1060</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13112(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–608</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–4, title I, § 102(1)</ref>, <date date="1995-03-22">Mar. 22, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 60</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–33, title X, § 10103</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 603.</num>
<heading> Public access to budget data</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right to copy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsections (c), (d), and (e), the Director shall make all information, data, estimates, and statistics obtained under section 601(d) and (e) of this title available for public copying during normal business hours, subject to reasonable rules and regulations, and shall to the extent practicable, at the request of any person, furnish a copy of any such information, data, estimates, or statistics upon payment by such person of the cost of making and furnishing such copy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Index</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall develop and maintain filing, coding, and indexing systems that identify the information, data, estimates, and statistics to which subsection (a) applies and shall make such systems available for public use during normal business hours.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply to information, data, estimates, and statistics—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which are specifically exempted from disclosure by law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> which the Director determines will disclose—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> matters necessary to be kept secret in the interests of national defense or the confidential conduct of the foreign relations of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information relating to trade secrets or financial or commercial information pertaining specifically to a given person if the information has been obtained by the Government on a confidential basis, other than through an application by such person for a specific financial or other benefit, and is required to be kept secret in order to prevent undue injury to the competitive position of such person; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> personnel or medical data or similar data the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">unless the portions containing such matters, information, or data have been excised.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information obtained for committees and Members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall apply to any information, data, estimates, and statistics obtained at the request of any committee, joint committee, or Member unless such committee, joint committee, or Member has instructed the Director not to make such information, data, estimates, or statistics available for public copying.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Level of confidentiality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to information, data, estimates, and statistics obtained under sections 601(d) and 601(e) of this title, the Director shall maintain the same level of confidentiality as is required by law of the department, agency, establishment, or regulatory agency or commission from which it is obtained. Officers and employees of the Congressional Budget Office shall be subject to the same statutory penalties for unauthorized disclosure or use as officers or employees of the department, agency, establishment, or regulatory agency or commission from which it is obtained.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 93–344, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 305</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(7) [title III, § 310(b)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–639.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 604.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 605.</num>
<heading> Sale or lease of property, supplies, or services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any sale or lease of property, supplies, or services to the Congressional Budget Office shall be deemed to be a sale or lease to the Congress subject to <ref>section 4103 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) shall apply with respect to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2404</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 605a.</num>
<heading> Contracting parity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In fiscal year 2018 and thereafter, for all contracts for goods and services to which the Congressional Budget Office is a party, the following Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) clauses will apply: FAR 52.232–39 and FAR 52.233–4.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 130</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 779</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 606.</num>
<heading> Disposition of surplus or obsolete property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall have the authority, within the limits of available appropriations, to dispose of surplus or obsolete personal property by inter-agency transfer, donation, sale, trade-in, or discarding. Amounts received for the sale or trade-in of personal property shall be credited to funds available for the operations of the Congressional Budget Office and be available for the costs of acquiring the same or similar property. Such funds shall be available for such purposes during the fiscal year in which received and the following fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) shall apply with respect to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2404</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 126</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 577</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 607.</num>
<heading> Lump-sum payments for annual leave to separated employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall have the authority to make lump-sum payments to separated employees of the Congressional Budget Office for unused annual leave.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) shall apply with respect to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2404</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 608.</num>
<heading> Lump-sum payments to enhance staff recruitment and to reward exceptional performance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall have the authority to make lump-sum payments to enhance staff recruitment and to reward exceptional performance by an employee or a group of employees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) shall apply with respect to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1999-09-30">September 30, 1999</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–57, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 609.</num>
<heading> Employee training</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Congressional Budget Office may, by regulation, make applicable such provisions of chapter 41 of title 5 as the Director determines necessary to provide on and after <date date="2001-11-12">November 12, 2001</date>, for training of individuals employed by the Congressional Budget Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The implementing regulations shall provide for training that, in the determination of the Director, is consistent with the training provided by agencies subject to chapter 41 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery of debt</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any recovery of debt owed to the Congressional Budget Office under this section and its implementing regulations shall be credited to the appropriations account available for salaries and expenses of the Office at the time of recovery.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2002 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 125</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 577</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 610.</num>
<heading> Repayment of student loan on behalf of employee</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Congressional Budget Office may, in order to recruit or retain qualified personnel, establish and maintain on and after <date date="2001-11-12">November 12, 2001</date>, a program under which the Office may agree to repay (by direct payments on behalf of the employee) all or a portion of any student loan previously taken out by such employee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may, by regulation, make applicable such provisions of <ref>section 5379 of title 5</ref> as the Director determines necessary to provide for such program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The regulations shall provide the amount paid by the Office may not exceed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $6,000 for any employee in any calendar year; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a total of $40,000 in the case of any employee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office may not reimburse an employee for any repayments made by such employee prior to the Office entering into an agreement under this section with such employee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accounting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amount repaid by, or recovered from, an individual under this section and its implementing regulations shall be credited to the appropriation account available for salaries and expenses of the Office at the time of repayment or recovery.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2002 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 127</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 577</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 611.</num>
<heading> Employee development program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Congressional Budget Office may, by regulation, make applicable such provisions of <ref>section 3396 of title 5</ref> as the Director determines necessary to establish a program providing opportunities for employees of the Office to engage in details or other temporary assignments in other agencies, study, or uncompensated work experience which will contribute to the employees’ development and effectiveness.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2003 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1101</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 612.</num>
<heading> Executive exchange program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Congressional Budget Office may establish and conduct an executive exchange program under which employees of the Office may be assigned to private sector organizations, and employees of private sector organizations may be assigned to the Office, for 1-year periods to further the institutional interests of the Office or Congress, including for the purpose of providing training to officers and employees of the Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations and conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> limit the number of officers and employees who are assigned to private sector organizations at any one time to not more than 5;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> limit the number of employees from private sector organizations who are assigned to the Office at any one time to not more than 5;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> require that an employee of a private sector organization assigned to the Office may not have access to any trade secrets or to any other nonpublic information which is of commercial value to the private sector organization from which such employee is assigned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> approve employees to be detailed from the private sector without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of their fitness to perform their assigned duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of private employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An employee of a private sector organization assigned to the Office under the executive exchange program shall be considered to be an employee of the Office for purposes of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> chapter 73 of title 5;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> sections 201, 203, 205, 207, 208, 209, 603, 606, 607, 643, 654, 1905, and 1913 of title 18;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> sections 1343, 1344, and 1349(b) of title 31;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> chapter 171 of title 28 (commonly referred to as the “Federal Tort Claims Act”) and any other Federal tort liability statute;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> chapter 131 of title 5; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content><ref>section 1043 of title 26</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–68, div. A, title I, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2032</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 613.</num>
<heading> Establishment of senior level positions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the fourth sentence of <ref>section 601(b) of this title</ref>, the Director of the Congressional Budget Office may establish and fix the compensation of senior level positions in the Congressional Budget Office to meet critical scientific, technical, professional, or executive needs of the Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The annual rate of pay for any position established under this section may not exceed the annual rate of pay for level II of the Executive Schedule.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2017 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–31, div. I, title I, § 1101</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 578</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>