<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5—</num>
<heading>LIBRARY OF CONGRESS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 131.</num>
<heading> Collections composing Library; location</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Library of Congress, composed of the books, maps, and other publications which on <date date="1873-12-01">December 1, 1873</date>, remained in existence, from the collections theretofore united under authority of law and those added from time to time by purchase, exchange, donation, reservation from publications ordered by Congress, acquisition of material under the copyright law, and otherwise, shall be preserved in the Library Building.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 80; <ref>Feb. 19, 1897, ch. 265, § 1</ref>, <ref>29 Stat. 545</ref>, 546; <ref>Pub. L. 94–553, title I, § 105(g)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(i) [title III, § 310]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329–290</ref>, 1329–310.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 132.</num>
<heading> Departments of Library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Library of Congress shall be arranged in two departments, a general library and a law library.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 81.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 132a.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for increase of general library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The unexpended balance of any sums appropriated by Congress for the increase of the general library, together with such sums as may hereafter be appropriated to the same purpose, shall be laid out under the direction of the Joint Committee of Congress on the Library.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 82; <date date="1902-02-07">Feb. 7, 1902</date>, No. 5, <ref>32 Stat. 735</ref>; <ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title II, § 223, <ref>60 Stat. 838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 132a–1.</num>
<heading> Obligations for reimbursable and revolving fund activities; limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective for fiscal years beginning with fiscal year 1995, obligations for any reimbursable and revolving fund activities performed by the Library of Congress are limited to the total amounts provided (1) in the annual regular appropriations Act making appropriations for the legislative branch, or (2) in a supplemental appropriations Act that makes appropriations for the legislative branch.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–69, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1993-08-11">Aug. 11, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 132a–2.</num>
<heading> Furniture, furnishings, and office and library equipment; transfer of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to any other transfer authority provided by law, during fiscal year 2001 and fiscal years thereafter, the Librarian of Congress may transfer to and among available accounts of the Library of Congress amounts appropriated to the Librarian from funds for the purchase, installation, maintenance, and repair of furniture, furnishings, and office and library equipment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amounts transferred pursuant to subsection (a) shall be merged with and be available for the same purpose and for the same period as the appropriation or account to which such amounts are transferred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian may transfer amounts pursuant to subsection (a) only with the approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(2) [title II, § 209]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–114.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 132a–3.</num>
<heading> Authority to transfer amounts between categories of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During fiscal year 2014 and any succeeding fiscal year, the Librarian of Congress may transfer amounts appropriated for the fiscal year between the categories of appropriations provided under law for the Library of Congress for the fiscal year, upon the approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than 10 percent of the total amount of funds appropriated to the account under any category of appropriations for the Library of Congress for a fiscal year may be transferred from that account by all transfers made under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. I, title I, § 1402</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 431</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 132b.</num>
<heading> Joint Committee on the Library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Joint Committee of Congress on the Library shall, on and after <date date="1947-01-03">January 3, 1947</date>, consist of the chairman and four members of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the chairman and four members of the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title II, § 223, <ref>60 Stat. 838</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1742</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 133.</num>
<heading> Joint Committee during recess of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The portion of the Joint Committee of Congress on the Library on the part of the Senate remaining in office as Senators shall during the recess of Congress exercise the powers and discharge the duties conferred by law upon the Joint Committee of Congress on the Library.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1883, ch. 141, § 2</ref>, <ref>22 Stat. 592</ref>; <ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title II, § 223, <ref>60 Stat. 838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 134.</num>
<heading> Incidental expenses of law library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The incidental expenses of the law library shall be paid out of the appropriations for the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 83.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 135.</num>
<heading> Purchase of books for law library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian shall make the purchases of books for the law library, under the direction of and pursuant to the catalogue furnished him by the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 84.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 135a.</num>
<heading> National library service for the blind and print disabled</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accessible materials and reproducers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Librarian of Congress is authorized to provide to eligible persons who are residents of the United States (including residents of the several States, insular possessions, and the District of Columbia) and to eligible persons who are United States citizens residing outside the United States the following items:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Literary works published in raised characters, on sound-reproduction recordings, or in any other accessible format.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Musical scores, instructional texts, and other specialized materials used in furthering educational, vocational, and cultural opportunities in the field of music published in any accessible format.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Reproducers for such formats.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ownership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any item provided under paragraph (1) shall be provided on a loan basis and shall remain the property of the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lending preference</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the lending of items under subsection (a), the Librarian shall at all times give preference to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the needs of the blind and visually disabled; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the needs of eligible persons who have been honorably discharged from the Armed Forces of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Network</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress may contract or otherwise arrange with such public or other nonprofit libraries, agencies, or organizations as the Librarian may determine appropriate to serve as local or regional centers for the circulation of items described in subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress is authorized to provide items described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1) to authorized entities located in a country that is a party to the Marrakesh Treaty, if any such items are delivered to authorized entities through online, not physical, means. The Librarian may contract or otherwise arrange with such authorized entities to deliver such items to eligible persons located in their countries in any accessible format and consistent with <ref>section 121A of title 17</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracting preference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the purchase and maintenance of items described in subsection (a), the Librarian of Congress, without regard to <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>, shall give preference to nonprofit institutions or agencies whose activities are primarily concerned with the blind and with other physically disabled persons, in all cases where, considering all the circumstances and needs involved, the Librarian determines that the prices submitted are fair and reasonable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress shall prescribe regulations for services under this section, in consultation with eligible persons and authorized entities. Such regulations shall include procedures that shall be used by an individual to establish that the individual is an eligible person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the terms “accessible format”, “authorized entity”, and “eligible person” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 121 of title 17</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Marrakesh Treaty” has the meaning given in section 121A of such title 17.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1931, ch. 400, § 1</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 1487</ref>; <ref>Mar. 4, 1933, ch. 279</ref>, <ref>47 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref>June 14, 1935, ch. 242, § 1</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 374</ref>; <ref>Apr. 23, 1937, ch. 125, § 1</ref>, <ref>50 Stat. 72</ref>; <ref>June 7, 1939, ch. 191</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 812</ref>; <ref>June 6, 1940, ch. 255</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 245</ref>; <ref>Oct. 1, 1942, ch. 575, § 1</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref>June 13, 1944, ch. 246, § 1</ref>, <ref>58 Stat. 276</ref>; <ref>Aug. 8, 1946, ch. 868, § 1</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref>July 3, 1952, ch. 566</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 326</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–308, § 1</ref>, <date date="1957-09-07">Sept. 7, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 630</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–522, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-07-30">July 30, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 330</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–219, § 1</ref>, <date date="2016-07-29">July 29, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 845</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XIV, § 1403(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 135a–1.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XIV, § 1403(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3207</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 135b.</num>
<heading> Local and regional centers; preference to blind and other physically handicapped veterans; rules and regulations; authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Librarian of Congress may contract or otherwise arrange with such public or other nonprofit libraries, agencies, or organizations as he may deem appropriate to serve as local or regional centers for the circulation of (1) books, recordings, and reproducers referred to in <ref>section 135a of this title</ref>, and (2) musical scores, instructional texts, and other specialized materials referred to in section 135a–1 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">1</ref> of this title, under such conditions and regulations as he may prescribe. In the lending of such books, recordings, reproducers, musical scores, instructional texts, and other specialized materials, preference shall at all times be given to the needs of the blind and of the other physically handicapped persons who have been honorably discharged from the Armed Forces of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1931, ch. 400, § 2</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 1487</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–522, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-07-30">July 30, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 330</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 136.</num>
<heading> Librarian of Congress; rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress shall make rules and regulations for the government of the Library.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 19, 1897, ch. 265, § 1</ref>, <ref>29 Stat. 544</ref>, 546; <ref>Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 220(f)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 204</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–86, § 3</ref>, <date date="2015-11-05">Nov. 5, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 675</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 136–1.</num>
<heading> Appointment and term of service of Librarian of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall appoint the Librarian of Congress, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress shall be appointed for a term of 10 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reappointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An individual appointed to the position of Librarian of Congress, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, may be reappointed to that position in accordance with subsections (a) and (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to appointments made on or after <date date="2015-11-05">November 5, 2015</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–86, § 2</ref>, <date date="2015-11-05">Nov. 5, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 675</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 136a, 136a–1.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 136a–2.</num>
<heading> Librarian of Congress and Deputy Librarian of Congress; compensation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Librarian of Congress shall be compensated at an annual rate of pay which is equal to the annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at level II of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5313 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Deputy Librarian of Congress shall be compensated at the greater of the rate of pay in effect for level III of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref> or the maximum annual rate of basic pay payable under section 5376 of such title for positions at agencies with a performance appraisal system certified under section 5307(d) of such title.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–63, title I, § 904</ref>, <date date="1983-07-30">July 30, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 336</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–57, title II, § 209(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 424</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XIV, § 1404(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 136b.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 136c.</num>
<heading> Authorized additional expenses and services for which Library of Congress salary appropriations are available</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From and after <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, appropriations in this Act available to the Library of Congress for salaries shall be available for expenses of personnel security and suitability investigations of Library employees; special and temporary services (including employees engaged by day or hour or in piecework); and services as authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–51, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1983-07-14">July 14, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 276</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 137.</num>
<heading> Use and regulation of law library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The justices of the Supreme Court shall have free access to the law library; and they are authorized to make regulations, not inconsistent with law, for the use of the same during the sittings of the court. But such regulations shall not restrict any person authorized to take books from the Library from having access to the law library, or using the books therein in the same manner as he may be entitled to use the books of the general Library.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 95.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 137a, 137b.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 137c.</num>
<heading> Withdrawal of books from Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chief judge and associate judges of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia and the chief judge and associate judges of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia are authorized to use and take books from the Library of Congress in the same manner and subject to the same regulations as justices of the Supreme Court of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Joint Res. No. 9, <date date="1894-01-27">Jan. 27, 1894</date>, <ref>28 Stat. 577</ref>; <ref>June 7, 1934, ch. 426</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 926</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1936, ch. 804</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1921</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 32(a)</ref>, (b), <ref>62 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 138.</num>
<heading> Law library; hours kept open</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The law library shall be kept open every day so long as either House of Congress is in session.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 11, 1888, ch. 615, § 1</ref>, <ref>25 Stat. 262</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 139.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 140.</num>
<heading> Employees; fitness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All persons employed in and about said Library of Congress under the Librarian shall be appointed solely with reference to their fitness for their particular duties.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 19, 1897, ch. 265, § 1</ref>, <ref>29 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref>June 29, 1922, ch. 251, § 1</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 715</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 141.</num>
<heading> Allocation of responsibilities for Library buildings and grounds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Architect of the Capitol shall have charge of all work at the Library of Congress buildings and grounds (as defined in <ref>section 167j of this title</ref>) that affects—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the structural integrity of the buildings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> buildings systems, including mechanical, electrical, plumbing, and elevators;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the architectural features of the buildings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> compliance with building and fire codes, laws, and regulations with respect to the specific responsibilities set for <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">1</ref> under this paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the care and maintenance of Library grounds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> purchase of all equipment necessary to fulfill the responsibilities set forth under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The employees required for the performance of the duties under paragraph (1) shall be appointed by the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Librarian of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress shall have charge of all work (other than work under subsection (a)) at the Library of Congress buildings and grounds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol and the Librarian of Congress may enter into agreements with each other to perform work under this section, and, subject to the approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate and the Joint Committee on the Library, may transfer between themselves appropriations or other available funds to pay the costs therefor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1922, ch. 251, § 1</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 715</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–280</ref>, <date date="1970-06-12">June 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 309</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title II, § 205(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–562, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2780</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1208(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 375</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 141a.</num>
<heading> Design, installation, and maintenance of security systems; transfer of responsibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The responsibility for design, installation, and maintenance of security systems to protect the physical security of the buildings and grounds of the Library of Congress is transferred from the Architect of the Capitol to the Capitol Police Board. Such design, installation, and maintenance shall be carried out under the direction of the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, and without regard to <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>. Any alteration to a structural, mechanical, or architectural feature of the buildings and grounds of the Library of Congress that is required for a security system under the preceding sentence may be carried out only with the approval of the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. B, title II</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–570</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 141b.</num>
<heading> Collections, physical security, control, and preservation of order and decorum within the library</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress shall establish standards and regulations for the physical security, control, and preservation of the Library of Congress collections and property, and for the maintenance of suitable order and decorum within Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of security systems</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility for security systems</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In accordance with the authority of the Capitol Police and the Librarian of Congress established under this Act, the amendments made by this Act, and the provisions of law referred to in paragraph (3), the Chief of the Capitol Police and the Librarian of Congress shall be responsible for the operation of security systems at the Library of Congress buildings and grounds described under <ref>section 167j of this title</ref>, in consultation and coordination with each other, subject to the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Librarian of Congress shall be responsible for the design of security systems for the control and preservation of Library collections and property, subject to the review and approval of the Chief of the Capitol Police.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Librarian of Congress shall be responsible for the operation of security systems at any building or facility of the Library of Congress which is located outside of the District of Columbia, subject to the review and approval of the Chief of the Capitol Police.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial proposal for operation of systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2008-10-01">October 1, 2008</date>, the Chief of the Capitol Police, in coordination with the Librarian of Congress, shall prepare and submit to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate an initial proposal for carrying out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provisions of law</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The provisions of law referred to in this paragraph are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>Section 141 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>Section 141a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>Section 1964 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content><ref>Section 1965 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1004(e)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–178, § 5</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2552</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–145, § 6(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-04">Mar. 4, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 54</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142a.</num>
<heading> Office of administrative assistant and disbursing officer in Library of Congress abolished; transfer of duties to appointee of Librarian</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From and after <date date="1928-06-10">June 10, 1928</date>, the office of administrative assistant and disbursing officer of the Library of Congress, created by <ref>section 142 of this title</ref>, is abolished and thereafter the duties required to be performed by the administrative assistant and disbursing officer shall be performed, under the direction of the Librarian of Congress, by such persons as the Librarian may appoint for those purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 11, 1928, ch. 521</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 220(h)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142b.</num>
<heading> Certifying officers of the Library of Congress; accountability; relief by Comptroller General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1957-06-13">June 13, 1957</date>, each officer and employee of the Library of Congress, including the Copyright Office, who has been duly authorized in writing by the Librarian of Congress to certify vouchers for payment from appropriations and funds, shall (1) be held responsible for the existence and correctness of the facts recited in the certificate or otherwise stated on the voucher or its supporting papers and for the legality of the proposed payment under the appropriation or fund involved; (2) [Repealed]; (3) be held responsible and accountable for the correctness of the computations of certified vouchers; and (4) be held accountable for and required to make good to the United States the amount of any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate made by him, as well as for any payment prohibited by law or which did not represent a legal obligation under the appropriation or fund involved: <i>Provided</i>, That the Comptroller General of the United States may, at his discretion, relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for any payment otherwise proper whenever he finds (1) that the certification was based on official records and that such certifying officer or employee did not know, and by reasonable diligence and inquiry could not have ascertained, the actual facts, or (2) that the obligation was incurred in good faith, that the payment was not contrary to any statutory provision specifically prohibiting payments of the character involved, and the United States has received value for such payment: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Comptroller General shall relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for an overpayment for transportation services made to any common carrier covered by <ref>section 3726 of title 31</ref>, whenever he finds that the overpayment occurred solely because the administrative examination made prior to payment of the transportation bill did not include a verification of transportation rates, freight classifications, or land grant deductions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–53, § 1</ref>, <date date="1957-06-13">June 13, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 81</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 220(k)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142c.</num>
<heading> Enforcement of liability of certifying officers of Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The liability of these certifying officers or employees shall be enforced in the same manner and to the same extent as now provided by law with respect to enforcement of the liability of disbursing and other accountable officers; and they shall have the right to apply for and obtain a decision by the Comptroller General on any question of law involved in a payment on any vouchers presented to them for certification.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–53, § 2</ref>, <date date="1957-06-13">June 13, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 81</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142d.</num>
<heading> Disbursing officer of the Library of Congress; disbursements in accordance with voucher; examination of vouchers; liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The disbursing officer of the Library of Congress shall (1) disburse moneys of the Library of Congress only upon, and in strict accordance with, vouchers duly certified by the Librarian of Congress or by an officer or employee of the Library of Congress duly authorized in writing by the Librarian to certify such vouchers; (2) make such examination of vouchers as may be necessary to ascertain whether they are in proper form, and duly certified and approved; and (3) be held accountable accordingly: <i>Provided</i>, That the disbursing officer shall not be held accountable or responsible for any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate, the responsibility for which, under <ref>section 142b of this title</ref>, is imposed upon a certifying officer or employee of the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–53, § 3</ref>, <date date="1957-06-13">June 13, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 81</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142e.</num>
<heading> Disbursing Officer of the Library of Congress; disbursements for Congressional Budget Office, accountability; financial management support to Congressional Budget Office under agreement of Librarian of Congress and Director of Congressional Budget Office; Congressional Budget Office certifying officers: voucher certifications, accountability, relief by Comptroller General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From and after <date date="1976-01-01">January 1, 1976</date>, the Disbursing Officer of the Library of Congress is authorized to disburse funds appropriated for the Congressional Budget Office, and the Library of Congress shall provide financial management support to the Congressional Budget Office as may be required and mutually agreed to by the Librarian of Congress and the Director of the Congressional Budget Office. The Library of Congress is further authorized to compute and disburse the basic pay of all personnel of the Congressional Budget Office pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 5504 of title 5</ref>, except the Director, who as head of an agency, shall have pay computed and disbursed pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 5505 of title 5</ref>.</p>
<p class="indent0">All vouchers certified for payment by duly authorized certifying officers of the Library of Congress shall be supported with a certification by an officer or employee of the Congressional Budget Office duly authorized in writing by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office to certify payments from appropriations of the Congressional Budget Office. The Congressional Budget Office certifying officers shall (1) be held responsible for the existence and correctness of the facts recited in the certificate or otherwise stated on the voucher or its supporting paper and the legality of the proposed payment under the appropriation or fund involved, (2) be held responsible and accountable for the correctness of the computations of certifications made, and (3) be held accountable for and required to make good to the United States the amount of any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate made by him, as well as for any payment prohibited by law which did not represent a legal obligation under the appropriation or fund involved: <i>Provided</i>, That the Comptroller General of the United States may, at his discretion, relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for any payment otherwise proper whenever he finds (1) that the certification was based on official records and that such certifying officer or employee did not know, and by reasonable diligence and inquiry could not have ascertained the actual facts, or (2) that the obligation was incurred in good faith, that the payment was not contrary to any statutory provision specifically prohibiting payments of the character involved, and the United States has received value for such payment: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Comptroller General shall relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for an overpayment for transportation services made to any common carrier covered by <ref>section 3726 of title 31</ref>, whenever he finds that the overpayment occurred solely because the administrative examination made prior to payment of the transportation bill did not include a verification of transportation rates, freight classifications, or land grant deductions.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Disbursing Officer of the Library of Congress shall not be held accountable or responsible for any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate, the responsibility for which is imposed upon a certifying officer or employee of the Congressional Budget Office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–536, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-16">Dec. 16, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142f.</num>
<heading> Office of Technology Assessment; disbursement of funds, computation and disbursement of basic pay, and provision of financial management support by Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From and after <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, the Disbursing Officer of the Library of Congress is authorized to disburse funds appropriated for the Office of Technology Assessment, and the Library of Congress shall provide financial management support to the Office of Technology Assessment as may be required and mutually agreed to by the Librarian of Congress and the Director of the Office of Technology Assessment. The Library of Congress is further authorized to compute and disburse the basic pay of all personnel of the Office of Technology Assessment pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 5504 of title 5</ref>.</p>
<p class="indent0">All vouchers certified for payment by duly authorized certifying officers of the Library of Congress shall be supported with a certification by an officer or employee of the Office of Technology Assessment duly authorized in writing by the Director of the Office of Technology Assessment to certify payments from appropriations of the Office of Technology Assessment. The Office of Technology Assessment certifying officers shall (1) be held responsible for the existence and correctness of the facts recited in the certificate or otherwise stated on the voucher or its supporting paper and the legality of the proposed payment under the appropriation or fund involved, (2) be held responsible and accountable for the correctness of the computations of certifications made, and (3) be held accountable for and required to make good to the United States the amount of any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate made by him, as well as for any payment prohibited by law which did not represent a legal obligation under the appropriation or fund involved: <i>Provided</i>, That the Comptroller General of the United States may, at his discretion, relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for any payment otherwise proper whenever he finds (1) that the certification was based on official records and that such certifying officer or employee did not know, and by reasonable diligence and inquiry could not have ascertained the actual facts, or (2) that the obligation was incurred in good faith, that the payment was not contrary to any statutory provision specifically prohibiting payments of the character involved, and the United States has received value for such payment: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Comptroller General shall relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for an overpayment for transportation services made to any common carrier covered by <ref>section 3726 of title 31</ref>, whenever he finds that the overpayment occurred solely because of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref> the administrative examination made prior to payment of the transportation bill did not include a verification of transportation rates, freight classifications, or land grant deductions.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Disbursing Officer of the Library of Congress shall not be held accountable or responsible for any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate, the responsibility for which is imposed upon a certifying officer or employee of the Office of Technology Assessment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–51, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 959</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142g.</num>
<heading> Copyright Royalty Tribunal; computation and disbursement of pay of Tribunal personnel by Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From and after <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, the Library of Congress is authorized to compute and disburse basic pay of all personnel of the Copyright Royalty Tribunal pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 5504 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–51, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1983-07-14">July 14, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142h.</num>
<heading> Biomedical Ethics Board; disbursement of funds, computation and disbursement of basic pay, and provision of financial management services and support by Library of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Effective <date date="1988-10-01">October 1, 1988</date>, and to continue thereafter, the Disbursing Officer of the Library of Congress is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> disburse funds appropriated for the Biomedical Ethics Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> compute and disburse the basic pay for all personnel of the Biomedical Ethics Board; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide financial management services and support to the Biomedical Ethics Board,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">in the same manner as provided with respect to the Office of Technology Assessment under <ref>section 142f of this title</ref>.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title I</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1054</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142i.</num>
<heading> United States Capitol Preservation Commission; provision of financial management services and support by Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1989-06-15">June 15, 1989</date>, the Library of Congress shall provide financial management services and support to the United States Capitol Preservation Commission as may be required and mutually agreed to by the Librarian of Congress and the Cochairmen of the United States Capitol Preservation Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–45, title I</ref>, <date date="1989-06-30">June 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142j.</num>
<heading> John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development; disbursement of funds, computation and disbursement of basic pay, and provision of financial management services and support by Library of Congress; payment for services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">From and after <date date="1988-10-01">October 1, 1988</date>, the Library of Congress is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> disburse funds appropriated for the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> compute and disburse the basic pay for all personnel of the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide financial management services and support to the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development, in the same manner as provided with respect to the Office of Technology Assessment under <ref>section 142f of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> collect from the funds appropriated for the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development the full costs of providing the services specified in (1), (2), and (3) above, as provided under an agreement for services ordered under <ref>31 U.S.C. 1535</ref> and 1536.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1060</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142k.</num>
<heading> Library of Congress disbursing office; payroll processing functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From and after <date date="1989-10-01">October 1, 1989</date>, the Librarian of Congress shall take appropriate action to assure that no legislative branch employee whose salary is disbursed by the Library of Congress disbursing office is adversely affected by alternative ways of performing the personnel/payroll processing function.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1060</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 142l.</num>
<heading> Disbursing Officer of Library of Congress; disbursements for Office of Congressional Workplace Rights; voucher certifications, accountability and relief by Comptroller General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From and after <date date="1996-10-01">October 1, 1996</date>, the Disbursing Officer of the Library of Congress is authorized to disburse funds appropriated for the Office of Compliance,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref> and the Library of Congress shall provide financial management support to the Office of Compliance <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref> as may be required and mutually agreed to by the Librarian of Congress and the Executive Director of the Office of Compliance.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref> The Library of Congress is further authorized to compute and disburse the basic pay of all personnel of the Office of Compliance <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref> pursuant to the provisions of <ref>section 5504 of title 5</ref>.</p>
<p class="indent0">All vouchers certified for payment by duly authorized certifying officers of the Library of Congress shall be supported with a certification by an officer or employee of the Office of Compliance <sup>1</sup> duly authorized in writing by the Executive Director of the Office of Compliance <sup>1</sup> to certify payments from appropriations of the Office of Compliance.<sup>1</sup> The Office of Compliance <sup>1</sup> certifying officers shall (1) be held responsible for the existence and correctness of the facts recited in the certificate or otherwise stated on the voucher or its supporting paper and the legality of the proposed payment under the appropriation or fund involved, (2) be held responsible and accountable for the correctness of the computations of certifications made, and (3) be held accountable for and required to make good to the United States the amount of any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate made by them, as well as for any payment prohibited by law which did not represent a legal obligation under the appropriation or fund involved: <i>Provided</i>, That the Comptroller General of the United States may, at his discretion, relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for any payment otherwise proper whenever he finds (1) that the certification was based on official records and that such certifying officer or employee did not know, and by reasonable diligence and inquiry could not have ascertained the actual facts, or (2) that the obligation was incurred in good faith, that the payment was not contrary to any statutory provision specifically prohibiting payments of the character involved, and the United States has received value for such payment: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Comptroller General shall relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for an overpayment for transportation services made to any common carrier covered by <ref>section 3726 of title 31</ref>, whenever he finds that the overpayment occurred solely because the administrative examination made prior to payment of the transportation bill did not include a verification of transportation rates, freight classifications, or land grant deductions.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Disbursing Officer of the Library of Congress shall not be held accountable or responsible for any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate, the responsibility for which is imposed upon a certifying officer or employee of the Office of Compliance.<sup>1</sup></p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2409</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 143.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for Library Building and Grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All appropriations made to the Architect of the Capitol on account of the Library Building and Grounds shall be disbursed for that purpose in the same manner as other appropriations under his control.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1922, ch. 251, § 3</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 715</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 143a.</num>
<heading> Disbursement of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From and after <date date="1978-10-01">October 1, 1978</date>, funds available to the Library of Congress may be expended to reimburse the Department of State for medical services rendered to employees of the Library of Congress stationed abroad and for contracting on behalf of and hiring alien employees for the Library of Congress under compensation plans comparable to those authorized by section 444 of the Foreign Service Act of 1946, as amended (<ref>22 U.S.C. 889(a)</ref>), for purchase or hire of passenger motor vehicles; for payment of travel, storage and transportation of household goods, and transportation and per diem expenses for families enroute (not to exceed twenty-four); for benefits comparable to those payable under sections 911(9), 911(11), and 941 of the Foreign Service Act of 1946, as amended (<ref>22 U.S.C. 1136(9)</ref>, 1136(11), and 1156, respectively); and travel benefits comparable with those which are now or hereafter may be granted single employees of the Agency for International Development, including single Foreign Service personnel assigned to A.I.D. projects, by the Administrator of the Agency for International Development—or his designee—under the authority of <ref>section 2396(b) of title 22</ref>; subject to such rules and regulations as may be issued by the Librarian of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–536, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-16">Dec. 16, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 143b.</num>
<heading> Payments in advance for subscriptions or other charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From and after <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>, payments in advance for subscriptions or other charges for bibliographical data, publications, materials in any other form, and services may be made by the Librarian of Congress whenever he determines it to be more prompt, efficient, or economical to do so in the interest of carrying out required Library programs.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 96–536, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-16">Dec. 16, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 143c.</num>
<heading> Use of other library funds to make payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to amounts transferred pursuant to <ref>section 182b(e)(2) of this title</ref>, the Librarian of Congress may transfer amounts made available for salaries and expenses of the Library of Congress during a fiscal year to the applicable appropriations accounts of the United States Capitol Police in order to reimburse the Capitol Police for services provided in connection with a special event or program described in <ref>section 182b(a)(4) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1004(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2236</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–178, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2554</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–145, § 6(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-04">Mar. 4, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 54</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 143d.</num>
<heading> Funds available for workers compensation payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Available balances of expired Library of Congress appropriations shall be available to the Library of Congress to make the deposit to the credit of the Employees’ Compensation Fund required by sub<ref>section 8147(b) of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to appropriations for fiscal year 2012 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. G, title I, § 1303</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1131</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 144.</num>
<heading> Copies of Statutes at Large</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Ten of the copies of the Statutes at Large, published by Little, Brown &amp; Co., which were deposited in the Library prior to <date date="1859-02-05">February 5, 1859</date>, shall be retained by the Librarian for the use of the justices of the Supreme Court, during the terms of court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 96.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 145.</num>
<heading> Copies of journals and documents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Two copies of the journals and documents, and of each book printed by either House of Congress, well bound in calf, shall be deposited in the Library, and must not be taken therefrom.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 97.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 145a.</num>
<heading> Periodical binding of printed hearings of committee testimony</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of the Library of Congress is authorized and directed to have bound at the end of each session of Congress the printed hearings of testimony taken by each committee of the Congress at the preceding session.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title I, § 141, <ref>60 Stat. 834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 146.</num>
<heading> Deposit of Journals of Senate and House</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Twenty-five copies of the public Journals of the Senate, and of the House of Representatives, shall be deposited in the Library of the United States, at the seat of government, to be delivered to Members of Congress during any session, and to all other persons authorized by law to use the books in the Library, upon their application to the Librarian, and giving their responsible receipts for the same, in like manner as for other books.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 98.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 147.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 25, 1951, ch. 562, § 1(l)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 638</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 148.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 1(l)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 701</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 149.</num>
<heading> Transfer of books to other libraries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress may from time to time transfer to other governmental libraries within the District of Columbia, including the Public Library, books and material in the possession of the Library of Congress in his judgment no longer necessary to its uses, but in the judgment of the custodians of such other collections likely to be useful to them, and may dispose of or destroy such material as has become useless: <i>Provided</i>, That no records of the Federal Government shall be transferred, disposed of, or destroyed under the authority granted in this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 4, 1909, ch. 297, § 1</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 858</ref>; <ref>Oct. 25, 1951, ch. 562, § 4(1)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 640</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 149a.</num>
<heading> Permitting use of proceeds from disposition of surplus or obsolete personal property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposition of property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within the limits of available appropriations, the Librarian of Congress may dispose of surplus or obsolete personal property of the Library of Congress by interagency transfer, donation, sale, trade-in, or other appropriate method.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of proceeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amounts received by the Librarian of Congress from the disposition of property under subsection (a) shall be credited to the funds available for the operations of the Library of Congress, and shall be available to acquire the same or similar property during the fiscal year in which the amounts are received and the following fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2012 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. G, title I, § 1304</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1132</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 150.</num>
<heading> Sale of copies of card indexes and other publications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress is authorized to furnish to such institutions or individuals as may desire to buy them, such copies of the card indexes and other publications of the Library as may not be required for its ordinary transactions, and charge for the same a price which will cover their cost and ten per centum added, and all moneys received by him shall be deposited in the Treasury and shall be credited to the appropriation for necessary expenses for the preparation and distribution of catalog cards and other publications of the Library.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 28, 1902, ch. 1301, § 1</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 480</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 682</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 151.</num>
<heading> Smithsonian Library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The library collected by the Smithsonian Institution under the provisions of the Act of <date date="1846-08-10">August 10, 1846</date>, chapter 25, and removed from the building of that institution, with the consent of the Regents thereof, to the Library of Congress, shall, while there deposited, be subject to the same regulations as the Library of Congress, except as hereinafter provided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 99.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 152.</num>
<heading> Care and use of Smithsonian Library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Smithsonian Institution shall have the use of the library referred to in <ref>section 151 of this title</ref> in like manner as before its removal. All the books, maps, and charts of the Smithsonian Library shall be properly cared for and preserved in like manner as are those of the Congressional Library; from which the Smithsonian Library shall not be removed except on reimbursement by the Smithsonian Institution to the Treasury of the United States of expenses incurred in binding and in taking care of the same, or upon such terms and conditions as shall be mutually agreed upon by Congress and the Regents of the Institution.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 100.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153.</num>
<heading> Control of library of House of Representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The library of the House of Representatives shall be under the control and direction of the Librarian of Congress, who shall provide all needful books of reference therefor. The librarian, two assistant librarians, and assistant in the library, shall be appointed by the Clerk of the House, with the approval of the Speaker of the House of Representatives. No removals shall be made from the said positions except for cause reported to and approved by the Committee on Rules.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1901, ch. 830, § 1</ref>, <ref>31 Stat. 964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154.</num>
<heading> Library of Congress Trust Fund Board; members; quorum; seal; rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A board is created and established, to be known as the “Library of Congress Trust Fund Board” (hereinafter referred to as the board), which shall consist of the Secretary of the Treasury (or an Assistant Secretary designated in writing by the Secretary of the Treasury), the chairman and the vice chair of the Joint Committee on the Library, the Librarian of Congress, two persons appointed by the President for a term of five years each (the first appointments being for three and five years, respectively), four persons appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives (in consultation with the minority leader of the House of Representatives) for a term of five years each (the first appointments being for two, three, four, and five years, respectively), and four persons appointed by the majority leader of the Senate (in consultation with the minority leader of the Senate) for a term of five years each (the first appointments being for two, three, four, and five years, respectively). Upon request of the chair of the Board, any member whose term has expired may continue to serve on the Trust Fund Board until the earlier of the date on which such member’s successor is appointed or the expiration of the 1-year period which begins on the date such member’s term expires. Seven members of the board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, and the board shall have an official seal, which shall be judicially noticed. The board may adopt rules and regulations in regard to its procedure and the conduct of its business.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 423, § 1</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1107</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–277</ref>, <date date="1978-05-12">May 12, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 236</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–246</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1992-02-18">Feb. 18, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–481, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2190</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 155.</num>
<heading> Compensation and expenses of Library of Congress Trust Fund Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No compensation shall be paid to the members of the board for their services as such members, but they shall be reimbursed for the expenses necessarily incurred by them, out of the income from the fund or funds in connection with which such expenses are incurred. The voucher of the chairman of the board shall be sufficient evidence that the expenses are properly allowable. Any expenses of the board, including the cost of its seal, not properly chargeable to the income of any trust fund held by it, shall be estimated for in the annual estimates of the librarian for the maintenance of the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 423, § 1</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 156.</num>
<heading> Gifts, etc., to Library of Congress Trust Fund Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board is authorized to accept, receive, hold, and administer such gifts, bequests, or devises of property for the benefit of, or in connection with, the Library, its collections, or its service, as may be approved by the Board and by the Joint Committee on the Library.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 423, § 2</ref>, formerly § 1, <ref>43 Stat. 1107</ref>, renumbered <ref>Apr. 13, 1936, ch. 213</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 157.</num>
<heading> Funds of Library of Congress Trust Fund Board; management of</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The moneys or securities composing the trust funds given or bequeathed to the board shall be receipted for by the Secretary of the Treasury, who shall invest, reinvest, or retain investments as the board may from time to time determine. The income as and when collected shall be deposited with the Treasurer of the United States, who shall enter it in a special account to the credit of the Library of Congress and subject to disbursement by the librarian for the purposes in each case specified; and the Treas­urer of the United States is authorized to honor the requisitions of the librarian made in such manner and in accordance with such regulations as the Treasurer may from time to time prescribe: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the board is not authorized to engage in any business nor to exercise any voting privilege which may be incidental to securities in its hands, nor shall the board make any investments that could not lawfully be made by a trust company in the District of Columbia, except that it may make any investments directly authorized by the instrument of gift, and may retain any investments accepted by it.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 423, § 2</ref>, formerly § 1, <ref>43 Stat. 1107</ref>, renumbered <ref>Apr. 13, 1936, ch. 213</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 158.</num>
<heading> Deposits by Library of Congress Trust Fund Board with Treasurer of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the absence of any specification to the contrary, the board may deposit the principal sum, in cash, with the Treasurer of the United States as a permanent loan to the United States Treasury, and the Treasurer shall thereafter credit such deposit with interest at a rate which is the higher of the rate of 4 per centum per annum or a rate which is 0.25 percentage points less than a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration the current average market yield on outstanding long-term marketable obligations of the United States, adjusted to the nearest one-eighth of 1 per centum, payable semi-annually, such interest, as income, being subject to disbursement by the Librarian of Congress for the purposes specified: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the total of such principal sums at any time so held by the Treasurer under this authorization shall not exceed the sum of $10,000,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 423, § 2</ref>, formerly § 1, <ref>43 Stat. 1107</ref>; renumbered § 2, <ref>Apr. 13, 1936, ch. 213</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1205</ref>; amended <ref>June 23, 1936, ch. 734</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1894</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–522</ref>, <date date="1962-07-03">July 3, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 135</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–289</ref>, <date date="1976-05-22">May 22, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 521</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 158a.</num>
<heading> Temporary possession of gifts of money or securities to Library of Congress; investment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of a gift of money or securities offered to the Library of Congress, if, because of conditions attached by the donor or similar considerations, expedited action is necessary, the Librarian of Congress may take temporary possession of the gift, subject to approval under <ref>section 156 of this title</ref>. The gift shall be receipted for and invested, reinvested, or retained as provided in <ref>section 157 of this title</ref>, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a gift of securities may not be invested or reinvested; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any investment or reinvestment of a gift of money shall be made in an interest bearing obligation of the United States or an obligation guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">If the gift is not so approved within the 12-month period after the Librarian so takes possession, the principal of the gift shall be returned to the donor and any income earned during that period shall be available for use with respect to the Library of Congress as provided by law.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 423, § 2</ref> (par.), as added <ref>Pub. L. 102–246, § 3</ref>, <date date="1992-02-18">Feb. 18, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 31</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 159.</num>
<heading> Perpetual succession and suits by or against Library of Congress Trust Fund Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The board shall have perpetual succession, with all the usual powers and obligations of a trustee, including the power to sell, except as herein limited, in respect of all property, moneys, or securities which shall be conveyed, transferred, assigned, bequeathed, delivered, or paid over to it for the purposes above specified. The board may be sued in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, which is given jurisdiction of such suits, for the purpose of enforcing the provisions of any trust accepted by it.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 423, § 3</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1108</ref>; <ref>Jan. 27, 1926, ch. 6, § 1</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 2</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1936, ch. 804</ref>, <ref>49 Stat. 1921</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 32(a)</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 160.</num>
<heading> Disbursement of gifts, etc., to Library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in sections 154 to 162 and 163 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002006">1</ref> of this title shall be construed as prohibiting or restricting the Librarian of Congress from accepting in the name of the United States gifts or bequests in the interest of the Library, its collections, or its service, of the following: (1) nonpersonal services; (2) voluntary and uncompensated personal services not to exceed $10,000 per person, per year in value; (3) gifts or bequests of money for immediate disbursement; and (4) gifts or bequests of securities or other personal property. Such gifts or bequests of money, after acceptance by the librarian, shall be paid by the donor or his representative to the Treasurer of the United States, whose receipts shall be their acquittance. In the case of a gift of securities, the Librarian shall sell the gift and provide the donor with such acknowledgment as needed for the donor to substantiate the gift. The Treasurer of the United States shall enter the gift, bequest, or proceeds in a special account to the credit of the Library of Congress and subject to disbursement by the librarian for the purposes in each case specified. The Librarian shall make an annual public report regarding gifts accepted under this section.</p>
<p class="indent0">Upon agreement by the Librarian of Congress and the Board, a gift or bequest accepted by the Librarian under the first paragraph of this section may be invested or reinvested in the same manner as provided for trust funds under <ref>section 157 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 423, § 4</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1194</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 152</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 784</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. I, title I, § 141(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 518</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 161.</num>
<heading> Tax exemption of gifts, etc., to Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Gifts or bequests or devises to or for the benefit of the Library of Congress, including those to the board, and the income therefrom, shall be exempt from all Federal taxes, including all taxes levied by the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 423, § 5</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1108</ref>; <ref>Oct. 2, 1942, ch. 576</ref>, <ref>56 Stat. 765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 162.</num>
<heading> Compensation of Library of Congress employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Employees of the Library of Congress who perform special functions for the performance of which funds have been entrusted to the board or the librarian, or in connection with cooperative undertakings in which the Library of Congress is engaged, shall not be subject to <ref>section 209 of title 18</ref>; and <ref>section 5533 of title 5</ref> shall not apply to any additional compensation so paid to such employees.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 423, § 6</ref>, <ref>43 Stat. 1108</ref>; <ref>Jan. 27, 1926, ch. 6, § 2</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 2</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–448, title IV, § 401(j)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-19">Aug. 19, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 491</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 162a.</num>
<heading> Gross salary of Library of Congress employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Hereafter the gross salary of any position in the Library which is augmented by payment of an honorarium from other than appropriated funds under terms of <ref>section 162 of this title</ref> shall not exceed an amount, which when combined with such honorarium, will exceed the maximum salary provided in chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 22, 1949, ch. 235, § 101</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 226</ref>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref>63 Stat. 972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 162b.</num>
<heading> Little Scholars Child Development Center; employee compensation and personnel matters</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election of coverage; creditable service; qualification for survivor annuities and disability benefits; contributions to thrift savings plan; certification concerning creditable service</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> This subsection shall apply to any individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is employed by the Library of Congress Child Development Center (known as the “Little Scholars Child Development Center”, in this section referred to as the “Center”) established under section 205(g)(1) of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> makes an election to be covered by this subsection with the Librarian of Congress, not later than the later of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 60 days after <date date="2000-12-21">December 21, 2000</date>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 60 days after the date the individual begins such employment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any individual described under paragraph (1) may be credited, under <ref>section 8411 of title 5</ref> for service as an employee of the Center before <date date="2000-12-21">December 21, 2000</date>, if such employee makes a payment of the deposit under section 8411(f)(2) of such title without application of section 8411(b)(3) of such title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An individual described under paragraph (1) shall be credited under <ref>section 8411 of title 5</ref> for any service as an employee of the Center on or after <date date="2000-12-21">December 21, 2000</date>, if such employee has such amounts deducted and withheld from his pay as determined by the Office of Personnel Management which would be deducted and withheld from the basic pay of an employee under <ref>section 8422 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, any service performed by an individual described under paragraph (1) as an employee of the Center is deemed to be civilian service creditable under <ref>section 8411 of title 5</ref> for purposes of qualifying for survivor annuities and disability benefits under subchapters IV and V of chapter 84 of such title, if such individual makes payment of an amount, determined by the Office of Personnel Management, which would have been deducted and withheld from the basic pay of such individual if such individual had been an employee subject to <ref>section 8422 of title 5</ref> for such period so credited, together with interest thereon.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An individual described under paragraph (1) shall be deemed an employee for purposes of chapter 84 of title 5, including subchapter III of such title,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002007">1</ref> and may make contributions under section 8432 of such title effective for the first applicable pay period beginning on or after the date such individual elects coverage under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall accept the certification of the Librarian of Congress concerning creditable service for purposes of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Health insurance coverage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any individual who is employed by the Center on or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-12-21">December 21, 2000</date>], shall be deemed an employee under <ref>section 8901(1) of title 5</ref> for purposes of health insurance coverage under chapter 89 of such title. An individual who is an employee of the Center on the date of enactment of this Act may elect coverage under this subsection before the 60th day after the date of enactment of this Act, and during such periods as determined by the Office of Personnel Management for employees of the Center employed after such date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Life insurance coverage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An individual who is employed by the Center shall be deemed an employee under <ref>section 8701(a) of title 5</ref> for purposes of life insurance coverage under chapter 87 of such title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government contributions by Librarian from available appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Government contributions for individuals receiving benefits under this section, as computed under sections 8423, 8432, 8708, and 8906 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">2</ref> shall be made by the Librarian of Congress from any appropriations available to the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payroll and personnel functions of Library of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Library of Congress, directly or by agreement with its designated representative, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> process payroll for Center employees, including making deductions and withholdings from the pay of employees in the amounts determined under sections 8422, 8432, 8707, and 8905 of title 5;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> maintain appropriate personnel and payroll records for Center employees, and transmit appropriate information and records to the Office of Personnel Management; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> transmit funds for Government and employee contributions under this section to the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of Center</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Center shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> except as provided in subsection (g), pay to the Library of Congress funds sufficient to cover the gross salary and the employer’s share of taxes under <ref>section 3111 of title 26</ref> for Center employees, in amounts computed by the Library of Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as required by the Library of Congress, reimburse the Library of Congress for reasonable administrative costs incurred under subsection (e)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> comply with regulations and procedures prescribed by the Librarian of Congress for administration of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> maintain appropriate records on all Center employees, as required by the Librarian of Congress; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> consult with the Librarian of Congress on the administration and implementation of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for certain compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of subsection (f), in the case of expenses described in such paragraph which are attributable to the compensation of the Executive Director and Deputy Executive Director of the Center, the Librarian of Congress may reimburse the Center for such expenses from amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for salaries and expenses of the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress may prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(2) [title II, § 210]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–114; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. I, title I, § 141(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4932</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 163.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 164.</num>
<heading> Index and digest of State legislation; preparation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress is authorized and directed to prepare biennially an index to the legislation of the States of the United States enacted during the biennium, together with a supplemental digest of the more important legislation of the period.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 10, 1927, ch. 99, § 1</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 1066</ref>; <ref>Feb. 28, 1929, ch. 367, § 1</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 1398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 164a.</num>
<heading> Official distribution of State legislation index and digest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress is directed to have the indexes and digests authorized by <ref>section 164 of this title</ref> printed and bound for official distribution only.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 28, 1929, ch. 367, § 1</ref>, <ref>45 Stat. 1398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 165.</num>
<heading> Authorization for appropriation for biennial index</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated annually for carrying out the provisions of <ref>section 164 of this title</ref> the sum of $30,000, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 10, 1927, ch. 99, § 2</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 1066</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 166.</num>
<heading> Congressional Research Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redesignation of Legislative Reference Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Legislative Reference Service in the Library of Congress is hereby continued as a separate department in the Library of Congress and is redesignated the “Congressional Research Service”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions and objectives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Librarian of Congress shall, in every possible way, encourage, assist, and promote the Congressional Research Service in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> rendering to Congress the most effective and efficient service,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> responding most expeditiously, effectively, and efficiently to the special needs of Congress, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> discharging its responsibilities to Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">and</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Librarian of Congress shall grant and accord to the Congressional Research Service complete research independence and the maximum practicable administrative independence consistent with these objectives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation of Director, Deputy Director, and other necessary personnel; minimum grade for Senior Specialists; classification above GS–15 of Specialists and Senior Specialists; appointment without regard to civil service laws and political affiliation and on basis of fitness to perform duties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> After consultation with the Joint Committee on the Library, the Librarian of Congress shall appoint the Director of the Congressional Research Service. The Director shall be compensated at the greater of the rate of pay in effect for level III of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref> or the maximum annual rate of basic pay payable under section 5376 of such title for positions at agencies with a performance appraisal system certified under section 5307(d) of such title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Librarian of Congress, upon the recommendation of the Director, shall appoint a Deputy Director of the Congressional Research Service and all other necessary personnel thereof. The basic pay of the Deputy Director shall be fixed in accordance with chapter 51 (relating to classification) and <ref>section 5376 of title 5</ref>. The basic pay of all other necessary personnel of the Congressional Research Service shall be fixed in accordance with chapter 51 (relating to classification) and subchapter III (relating to General Schedule pay rates) of chapter 53 of title 5, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the grade of Senior Specialist in each field within the purview of subsection (e) of this section shall not be less than the highest grade in the executive branch of the Government to which research analysts and consultants, without supervisory responsibility, are currently assigned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the positions of Specialist and Senior Specialist in the Congressional Research Service may be classified above GS–15 in accordance with <ref>section 5108(c) of title 5</ref>, and the rate of basic pay for such positions may be fixed in accordance with section 5376 of such title, subject to the prior approval of the Joint Committee on the Library.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each appointment made under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection and subsection (e) of this section shall be without regard to the civil service laws, without regard to political affiliation, and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the position.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Service; assistance to Congressional committees; list of terminating programs and subjects for analysis; legislative data, studies, etc.; information research; digest of bills, preparation; legislation, purpose and effect, and preparation of memoranda; information and research capability, development</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the Congressional Research Service, without partisan bias—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> upon request, to advise and assist any committee of the Senate or House of Representatives and any joint committee of Congress in the analysis, appraisal, and evaluation of legislative proposals within that committee’s jurisdiction, or of recommendations submitted to Congress, by the President or any executive agency, so as to assist the committee in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determining the advisability of enacting such proposals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> estimating the probable results of such proposals and alternatives thereto; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> evaluating alternative methods for accomplishing those results;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">and, by providing such other research and analytical services as the committee considers appropriate for these purposes, otherwise to assist in furnishing a basis for the proper evaluation and determination of legislative proposals and recommendations generally; and in the performance of this duty the Service shall have authority, when so authorized by a committee and acting as the agent of that committee, to request of any department or agency of the United States the production of such books, records, correspondence, memoranda, papers, and documents as the Service considers necessary, and such department or agency of the United States shall comply with such request; and further, in the performance of this and any other relevant duty, the Service shall maintain continuous liaison with all committees;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to make available to each committee of the Senate and House of Representatives and each joint committee of the two Houses, at the opening of a new Congress, a list of programs and activities being carried out under existing law scheduled to terminate during the current Congress, which are within the jurisdiction of the committee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to make available to each committee of the Senate and House of Representatives and each joint committee of the two Houses, at the opening of a new Congress, a list of subjects and policy areas which the committee might profitably analyze in depth;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> upon request, or upon its own initiative in anticipation of requests, to collect, classify, and analyze in the form of studies, reports, compilations, digests, bulletins, indexes, translations, and otherwise, data having a bearing on legislation, and to make such data available and serviceable to committees and Members of the Senate and House of Representatives and joint committees of Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> upon request, or upon its own initiative in anticipation of requests, to prepare and provide information, research, and reference materials and services to committees and Members of the Senate and House of Representatives and joint committees of Congress to assist them in their legislative and representative functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> upon request made by any committee or Member of the Congress, to prepare and transmit to such committee or Member a concise memorandum with respect to one or more legislative measures upon which hearings by any committee of the Congress have been announced, which memorandum shall contain a statement of the purpose and effect of each such measure, a description of other relevant measures of similar purpose or effect previously introduced in the Congress, and a recitation of all action taken theretofore by or within the Congress with respect to each such other measure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to develop and maintain an information and research capability, to include Senior Specialists, Specialists, other employees, and consultants, as necessary, to perform the functions provided for in this subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to comply with the requirements of, and provide information and technological assistance consistent with, section 124 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">1</ref> of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2018.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specialists and Senior Specialists; appointment; fields of appointment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress is authorized to appoint in the Congressional Research Service, upon the recommendation of the Director, Specialists and Senior Specialists in the following broad fields:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> American government and public administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> American public law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conservation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> engineering and public works;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> housing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> industrial organization and corporation finance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> international affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> international trade and economic geography;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> labor and employment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> mineral economics;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> money and banking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> national defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> price economics;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> science;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> social welfare;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> taxation and fiscal policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> transportation and communications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> urban affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> veterans’ affairs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> such other broad fields as the Director may consider appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such Specialists and Senior Specialists, together with such other employees of the Congressional Research Service as may be necessary, shall be available for special work with the committees and Members of the Senate and House of Representatives and the joint committees of Congress for any of the purposes of subsection (d) of this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Director; establishment and change of research and reference divisions or other organizational units, or both</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to classify, organize, arrange, group, and divide, from time to time, as he considers advisable, the requests for advice, assistance, and other services submitted to the Congressional Research Service by committees and Members of the Senate and House of Representatives and joint committees of Congress, into such classes and categories as he considers necessary to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> expedite and facilitate the handling of the individual requests submitted by Members of the Senate and House of Representatives,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promote efficiency in the performance of services for committees of the Senate and House of Representatives and joint committees of Congress, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide a basis for the efficient performance by the Congressional Research Service of its legislative research and related functions generally,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">and</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to establish and change, from time to time, as he considers advisable, within the Congressional Research Service, such research and reference divisions or other organizational units, or both, as he considers necessary to accomplish the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budget estimates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Congressional Research Service will submit to the Librarian of Congress for review, consideration, evaluation, and approval, the budget estimates of the Congressional Research Service for inclusion in the Budget of the United States Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Experts or consultants, individual or organizational, and persons and organizations with specialized knowledge; procurement of temporary or intermittent assistance; contracts, nonpersonal and personal service; advertisement requirements inapplicable; end product; pay; travel time</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Director of the Congressional Research Service may procure the temporary or intermittent assistance of individual experts or consultants (including stenographic reporters) and of persons learned in particular or specialized fields of knowledge—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by nonpersonal service contract, without regard to any provision of law requiring advertising for contract bids, with the individual expert, consultant, or other person concerned, as an independent contractor, for the furnishing by him to the Congressional Research Service of a written study, treatise, theme, discourse, dissertation, thesis, summary, advisory opinion, or other end product; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by employment (for a period of not more than one year) in the Congressional Research Service of the individual expert, consultant, or other person concerned, by personal service contract or otherwise, without regard to the position classification laws, at a rate of pay not in excess of the per diem equivalent of the highest rate of basic pay then currently in effect for the General Schedule of <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>, including payment of such rate for necessary travel time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Director of the Congressional Research Service may procure by contract, without regard to any provision of law requiring advertising for contract bids, the temporary (for respective periods not in excess of one year) or intermittent assistance of educational, research, or other organizations of experts and consultants (including stenographic reporters) and of educational, research, and other organizations of persons learned in particular or specialized fields of knowledge.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special report to Joint Committee on the Library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Congressional Research Service shall prepare and file with the Joint Committee on the Library at the beginning of each regular session of Congress a separate and special report covering, in summary and in detail, all phases of activity of the Congressional Research Service for the immediately preceding fiscal year, and shall include in the report a description of the efforts made by the Director to make additional Congressional Research Service products that are not confidential products or services available to the Librarian of Congress for publication on the website established and maintained under section 124 <sup>1</sup> of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2018.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Congressional Research Service each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to carry on the work of the Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title II, § 203, <ref>60 Stat. 836</ref>; <ref>Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref>63 Stat. 972</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title III, § 321(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1181</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–190, § 133</ref>, <date date="1985-12-19">Dec. 19, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1322</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–57, title II, § 209(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 424</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 154(b)(7)</ref>, (d), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 789</ref>, 790; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XIV, § 1404(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 166a.</num>
<heading> Equal access to Congressional Research Service Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> CRS product</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this section, the term “CRS product” means any final written work product of CRS containing research or analysis in any format that is available for general congressional access on the CRS Congressional Intranet.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> CRS Report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this section, the term “CRS Report” means any written CRS product, including an update to a previous written CRS product, consisting of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a Congressional Research Service Report; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a Congressional Research Service Authorization of Appropriations Product and Appropriations Product, which is available for general congressional access on the CRS Congressional Intranet.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “CRS Report” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any CRS product that is determined by the CRS Director to be a confidential product or service because it was prepared in response to a congressional request or requests for confidential analysis or research and is not available for general congressional access on the CRS Congressional Intranet;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any Congressional Research Service Report or any Congressional Research Service Authorization of Appropriations Product and Appropriations Product reported or produced before the effective date of this Act which, as of such effective date, is not available for general congressional access on the CRS Congressional Intranet; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a written CRS product that has been made available by CRS for publication on a public website maintained by the GPO Director (other than the Website) or the Library of Congress.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “CRS” means the Congressional Research Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “CRS Congressional Intranet” means the Website maintained by CRS at www.crs.gov, or a successor website, for the purpose of providing to Members and employees of Congress access to information from CRS;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “CRS Director” means the Director of CRS;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the term “Librarian of Congress” means the Librarian of Congress appointed pursuant to <ref>2 U.S.C. 136–1</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the term “Member of Congress” includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the term “Website” means the website established and maintained under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of CRS Reports through Library of Congress Website</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Website</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and maintenance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Librarian of Congress, in consultation with the CRS Director, shall establish and maintain a public website containing CRS Reports and an index of all CRS Reports contained on the website, in accordance with this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Format</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On the Website, CRS Reports shall be searchable, sortable, and downloadable, including downloadable in bulk.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Free access</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Librarian of Congress may not charge a fee for access to the Website.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updates; disclaimer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Librarian of Congress, in consultation with the CRS Director, shall ensure that the Website—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is updated contemporaneously, automatically, and electronically to include each new or updated CRS Report released on or after the effective date of this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shows the status of each CRS Report as new, updated, or archived; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> displays the following statement in reference to the CRS Reports included on the Website: “These documents were prepared by the Congressional Research Service (CRS). CRS serves as nonpartisan shared staff to congressional committees and Members of Congress. It operates solely at the behest of and under the direction of Congress. Information in a CRS Report should not be relied upon for purposes other than public understanding of information that has been provided by CRS to Members of Congress in connection with CRS’s institutional role. CRS Reports, as a work of the United States Government, are not subject to copyright protection in the United States. Any CRS Report may be reproduced and distributed in its entirety without permission from CRS. However, as a CRS Report may include copyrighted images or material from a third party, you may need to obtain the permission of the copyright holder if you wish to copy or otherwise use copyrighted material.”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Furnishing of necessary information and technology</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The CRS Director shall consult with and provide assistance to the Librarian of Congress to ensure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that the Librarian of Congress is provided with all of the information necessary to carry out this section, including all of the information described in clauses (i) through (iv) of subsection (c)(1)(A), in such format and manner as the Librarian of Congress considers appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that CRS makes available any information and assistance as may be necessary to facilitate the contemporaneous, automatic, and electronic provision of CRS Reports to the Librarian of Congress as required under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonexclusivity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Librarian of Congress may publish other information on the Website.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternative techniques</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Librarian of Congress and the CRS Director may use additional techniques to make CRS Reports available to the public, if such techniques are consistent with this section and any other applicable laws.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The CRS Director is encouraged to make additional CRS products that are not confidential products or services available to the Librarian of Congress for publication on the Website, and the Librarian of Congress is encouraged to publish such CRS products on the Website.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Website contents</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific requirements for Reports posted on Website</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of Librarian of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">With respect to each CRS Report included on the Website, the Librarian of Congress shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the name and identification number of the CRS Report;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an indication as to whether the CRS Report is new, updated, or archived;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the date of release of the CRS Report; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other information the Librarian of Congress, in consultation with the CRS Director, considers appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of CRS Director</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">With respect to each CRS Report included on the Website, the CRS Director shall, prior to transmitting the Report to the Librarian of Congress—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> at the discretion of the CRS Director, remove the name of and any contact information for any employee of CRS; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> include in the CRS Report the following written statement: “This document was prepared by the Congressional Research Service (CRS). CRS serves as nonpartisan shared staff to congressional committees and Members of Congress. It operates solely at the behest of and under the direction of Congress. Information in a CRS Report should not be relied upon for purposes other than public understanding of information that has been provided by CRS to Members of Congress in connection with CRS’s institutional role. CRS Reports, as a work of the United States Government, are not subject to copyright protection in the United States. Any CRS Report may be reproduced and distributed in its entirety without permission from CRS. However, as this CRS Report may include copyrighted images or material from a third party, you may need to obtain the permission of the copyright holder if you wish to copy or otherwise use copyrighted material.”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific requirements for index on Website</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Librarian of Congress shall ensure that the index of all CRS Reports published on the Website is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> comprehensive;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contemporaneously updated;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> searchable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> sortable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> maintained in a human-readable format;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> maintained in a structured data format;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> downloadable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> inclusive of each item of information described in paragraph (1)(A) with respect to each CRS Report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules of construction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No effect on Speech or Debate Clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section may be construed to diminish, qualify, condition, waive, or otherwise affect the applicability of clause 1 of section 6 of article I of the Constitution of the United States (commonly known as the “Speech or Debate Clause”) or any other privilege available to Congress or Members, offices, or employees of Congress with respect to any CRS Report made available online under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidential communications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section may be construed to waive the requirement that any confidential communication by CRS to a Member, office, or committee of Congress shall remain under the custody and control of Congress and may be released only by Congress and its Houses, Members, offices, and committees, in accordance with the rules and privileges of each House and the requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dissemination of CRS products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section may be construed to limit or otherwise affect the ability of a Member, office, or committee of Congress to disseminate CRS products on a website of the Member, office, or committee or to otherwise provide CRS products to the public, including as part of constituent service activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2)(C), this section and the amendments made by this section shall take effect 90 days after the date on which the Librarian of Congress submits the certification described in paragraph (2)(B).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of information and technology</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> CRS deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2018-03-23">March 23, 2018</date>, the CRS Director shall provide the Librarian of Congress with the information necessary for the Librarian of Congress to begin the initial operation of the Website.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Upon provision of the information described in subparagraph (A), the Librarian of Congress shall submit to Congress a certification that the CRS Director has provided the information necessary for the Librarian of Congress to begin the initial operation of the Website.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical delays</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the event of technical difficulties encountered in planning or implementing the requirements of this section and the amendments made by this section, upon providing a detailed report submitted by the Librarian of Congress or the CRS Director to the Committees on Appropriations of the House and the Senate detailing the nature of the technical difficulties and the timeline for resolving such technical difficulties, the effective date established by subsection (f)(1) shall be extended for up to 90 additional days.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 154</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 787</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 167 to 167h.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1004(d)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)(B), <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2233</ref>, 2234, and <ref>Pub. L. 110–178, § 4(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2551</ref>, 2552; <ref>Pub. L. 111–145, § 6(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-04">Mar. 4, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 54</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 167i.</num>
<heading> Suspension of prohibitions against use of Library buildings and grounds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to permit the observance of authorized ceremonies within the Library of Congress buildings and grounds, the Librarian of Congress may suspend for such occasions so much of the prohibitions contained in sections 5103 and 5104 of title 40 as may be necessary for the occasion, but only if responsible officers shall have been appointed, and arrangements determined which are adequate, in the judgment of the Librarian, for the maintenance of suitable order and decorum in the proceedings, and for the protection of the Library buildings and grounds and of persons and property therein.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1950, ch. 561, § 10</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1004(d)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–178, § 4(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2552</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–145, § 6(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-04">Mar. 4, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 54</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 167j.</num>
<heading> Area comprising Library of Congress grounds; “buildings and grounds” defined</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Library of Congress grounds shall be held to extend to the line of the face of the east curb of First Street Southeast, between B Street Southeast and East Capitol Street; to the line of the face of the south curb of East Capitol Street, between First Street Southeast and Second Street Southeast; to the line of the face of the west curb of Second Street Southeast, between East Capitol Street and B Street Southeast; to the line of the face of the north curb of B Street Southeast, between First Street Southeast and Second Street Southeast; and to the line of the face of the east curb of Second Street Southeast, between Pennsylvania Avenue Southeast and the north side of the alley separating the Library Annex Building and the Folger Shakespeare Library; to the line of the north side of the same alley, between Second Street Southeast and Third Street Southeast; to the line of the face of the west curb of Third Street Southeast, between the north side of the same alley and B Street Southeast; to the line of the face of the north curb of B Street Southeast, between Third Street Southeast and Pennsylvania Avenue Southeast; to the line of the face of the northeast curb of Pennsylvania Avenue Southeast, between B Street Southeast and Second Street Southeast.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The term “Library of Congress buildings and grounds” shall include (1) the whole or any part of any building or structure which is occupied under lease or otherwise by the Library of Congress and is subject to supervision and control by the Librarian of Congress, (2) the land upon which there is situated any building or structure which is occupied wholly by the Library of Congress, and (3) any subway or enclosed passageway connecting two or more buildings or structures occupied in whole or in part by the Library of Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The term “Library of Congress buildings and grounds” shall include (1) all real property in lot 51 in square 869 in the District of Columbia, as that lot appears on the records in the office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia on <date date="1990-08-01">August 1, 1990</date>, extending to the outer face of the curbs of the square in which it is located and including all alleys or parts of alleys and streets within the lot lines and curb lines surrounding such real property, and (2) improvements to such real property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The term “Library of Congress buildings and grounds” shall include the following property:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Three parcels totaling approximately 45 acres, more or less, located in Culpeper County, Virginia, and identified as Culpeper County Tax Parcel Numbers 51–80B, 51–80C, and 51–80D, further described as real estate (consisting of 40.949 acres) conveyed to David and Lucile Packard Foundation by deed from Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond, dated <date date="1998-05-15">May 15, 1998</date>, and recorded <date date="1998-05-19">May 19, 1998</date>, in the Clerk’s Office, Circuit Court of Culpeper County, Virginia, in Deed Book 644, page 372; and real estate (consisting of 4.181 acres) conveyed to Packard Humanities Institute by deed from Russell H. Inskeep, dated <date date="2002-02-13">February 13, 2002</date>, and recorded <date date="2002-02-13">February 13, 2002</date>, in the Clerk’s Office, Circuit Court of Culpeper County, Virginia, as instrument number 020001299.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Improvements to such real property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1950, ch. 561, § 11</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–281</ref>, <date date="1970-06-17">June 17, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 309</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–520, title II, § 205(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–562, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2780</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–144, § 2</ref>, <date date="1997-12-15">Dec. 15, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2667</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 1203(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1031</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1004(d)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–178, § 4(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2552</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–145, § 6(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-04">Mar. 4, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 54</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 168.</num>
<heading> Constitution of the United States; preparation and publication of revised edition; annotations; supplements; decennial editions and supplements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress shall have prepared—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a hardbound revised edition of the Constitution of the United States of America—Analysis and Interpretation, published as Senate Document Numbered 39, Eighty-eighth Congress (referred to hereinafter as the “Constitution Annotated”), which shall contain annotations of decisions of the Supreme Court of the United States through the end of the October 1971 term of the Supreme Court, construing provisions of the Constitution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> upon the completion of each of the October 1973, October 1975, October 1977, and October 1979 terms of the Supreme Court, a cumulative pocket-part supplement to the hardbound revised edition of the Constitution Annotated prepared pursuant to clause (1), which shall contain cumulative annotations of all such decisions rendered by the Supreme Court after the end of the October 1971 term;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> upon the completion of the October 1981 term of the Supreme Court, and upon the completion of each tenth October term of the Supreme Court thereafter, a hardbound decennial revised edition of the Constitution Annotated, which shall contain annotations of all decisions theretofore rendered by the Supreme Court construing provisions of the Constitution; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> upon the completion of the October 1983 term of the Supreme Court, and upon the completion of each subsequent October term of the Supreme Court beginning in an odd-numbered year (the final digit of which is not a 1), a cumulative pocket-part supplement to the most recent hardbound decennial revised edition of the Constitution Annotated, which shall contain cumulative annotations of all such decisions rendered by the Supreme Court which were not included in that hardbound decennial revised edition of the Constitution Annotated.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–589, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1586</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 168a.</num>
<heading> Printing of Constitution Annotated as Senate documents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All hardbound revised editions and all cumulative pocket-part supplements shall be printed as Senate documents.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–589, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1586</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 168b.</num>
<heading> Printing and distribution of additional copies of Constitution Annotated</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be printed four thousand eight hundred and seventy additional copies of the hardbound revised editions prepared pursuant to clause (1) of <ref>section 168 of this title</ref> and of all cumulative pocket-part supplements thereto, of which two thousand six hundred and thirty-four copies shall be for the use of the House of Representatives, one thousand two hundred and thirty-six copies shall be for the use of the Senate, and one thousand copies shall be for the use of the Joint Committee on Printing. All Members of the Congress, Vice Presidents of the United States, and Delegates and Resident Commissioners, newly elected subsequent to the issuance of the hardbound revised edition prepared pursuant to such clause and prior to the first hardbound decennial revised edition, who did not receive a copy of the edition prepared pursuant to such clause, shall, upon timely request, receive one copy of such edition and the then current cumulative pocket-part supplement and any further supplements thereto. All Members of the Congress, Vice Presidents of the United States, and Delegates and Resident Commissioners, no longer serving after the issuance of the hardbound revised edition prepared pursuant to such clause and who received such edition, may receive one copy of each cumulative pocket-part supplement thereto upon timely request.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–589, § 3</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1586</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 168c.</num>
<heading> Printing and distribution of decennial editions and supplements to Constitution Annotated</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Additional copies of each hardbound decennial revised edition and of the cumulative pocket-part supplements thereto shall be printed and distributed in accordance with the provisions of any concurrent resolution hereafter adopted with respect thereto.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–589, § 4</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1587</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 168d.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations for Constitution Annotated</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums, to remain available until expended, as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of sections 168 to 168d of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–589, § 5</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1587</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 169.</num>
<heading> Positions in Library of Congress exempt from citizenship requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From and after <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, not to exceed fifteen positions in the Library of Congress may be exempt from the provisions of appropriation Acts concerning the employment of aliens during the current fiscal year, but the Librarian shall not make any appointment to any such position until he has ascertained that he cannot secure for such appointments a person in any of the categories specified in such provisions who possesses the special qualifications for the particular position and also otherwise meets the general requirements for employment in the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–51, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1983-07-14">July 14, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 276</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 170.</num>
<heading> American Television and Radio Archives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment and maintenance in Library of Congress; purpose; determination of composition, cataloging, indexing and availability by Librarian</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress (hereinafter referred to as the “Librarian”) shall establish and maintain in the Library of Congress a library to be known as the American Television and Radio Archives (hereinafter referred to as the “Archives”). The purpose of the Archives shall be to preserve a permanent record of the television and radio programs which are the heritage of the people of the United States and to provide access to such programs to historians and scholars without encouraging or causing copyright infringement.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Librarian, after consultation with interested organizations and individuals, shall determine and place in the Archives such copies and phonorecords of television and radio programs transmitted to the public in the United States and in other countries which are of present or potential public or cultural interest, historical significance, cognitive value, or otherwise worthy of preservation, including copies and phonorecords of published and unpublished transmission programs—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> acquired in accordance with sections 407 and 408 of title 17; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transferred from the existing collections of the Library of Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> given to or exchanged with the Archives by other libraries, archives, organizations, and individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> purchased from the owner thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Librarian shall maintain and publish appropriate catalogs and indexes of the collections of the Archives, and shall make such collections available for study and research under the conditions prescribed under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reproduction, compilation, and distribution for research of regularly scheduled newscasts or on-the-spot coverage of news events by Librarian; promulgation of regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 106 of title 17</ref>, the Librarian is authorized with respect to a transmission program which consists of a regularly scheduled newscast or on-the-spot coverage of news events and, under standards and conditions that the Librarian shall prescribe by regulation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to reproduce a fixation of such a program, in the same or another tangible form, for the purposes of preservation or security or for distribution under the conditions of clause (3) of this subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to compile, without abridgment or any other editing, portions of such fixations according to subject matter, and to reproduce such compilations for the purpose of clause (1) of this subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to distribute a reproduction made under clause (1) or (2) of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by loan to a person engaged in research; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for deposit in a library or archives which meets the requirements of <ref>section 108(a) of title 17</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">in either case for use only in research and not for further reproduction or performance.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability for copyright infringement by Librarian or any employee of Librarian</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian or any employee of the Library who is acting under the authority of this section shall not be liable in any action for copyright infringement committed by any other person unless the Librarian or such employee knowingly participated in the act of infringement committed by such person. Nothing in this section shall be construed to excuse or limit liability under title 17 for any act not authorized by that title or this section, or for any act performed by a person not authorized to act under that title or this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “American Television and Radio Archives Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–553, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2601</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 171.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of findings and purpose as to Center for the Book</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress hereby finds and declares—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the Congress of the United States on <date date="1800-04-24">April 24, 1800</date>, established for itself a library of the Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that in 1815, the Congress purchased the personal library of the third President of the United States which contained materials on every science known to man and described such a collection as a “substratum of a great national library”;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that the Congress of the United States in recognition of the importance of printing and its impact on America purchased the Gutenberg Bible in 1930 for the Nation for placement in the Library of Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> that the Congress of the United States has through statute and appropriations made this library accessible to any member of the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> that this collection of books and other library materials has now become one of the greatest libraries in civilization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> that the book and the printed word have had the most profound influence on American civilization and learning and have been the very foundation on which our democratic principles have survived through our two hundred-year history;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> that in the year 1977, the Congress of the United States assembled hereby declares its reaffirmation of the importance of the printed word and the book and recognizes the importance of a Center for the Book to the continued study and development of written record as central to our understanding of ourselves and our world.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">It is therefore the purpose of sections 171 to 175 of this title to establish a Center for the Book in the Library of Congress to provide a program for the investigation of the transmission of human knowledge and to heighten public interest in the role of books and printing in the diffusion of this knowledge.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–129, § 1</ref>, <date date="1977-10-13">Oct. 13, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 172.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in sections 171 to 175 of this title—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term Center means the Center for the Book;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term Librarian means the Librarian of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–129, § 2</ref>, <date date="1977-10-13">Oct. 13, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 173.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Center for the Book</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Library of Congress a Center for the Book.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Center shall be under the direction of the Librarian of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–129, § 3</ref>, <date date="1977-10-13">Oct. 13, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1151</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 174.</num>
<heading> Function of Center for the Book</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian through the Center shall stimulate public interest and research in the role of the book in the diffusion of knowledge through such activities as a visiting scholar program accompanied by lectures, exhibits, publications, and any other related activities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–129, § 4</ref>, <date date="1977-10-13">Oct. 13, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 175.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress, in carrying out the Center’s functions, is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prescribe such regulations as he deems necessary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> receive money and other property donated, bequeathed, or devised for the purposes of the Center, and to use, sell, or otherwise dispose of such property for the purposes of carrying out the Center’s functions, without reference to Federal disposal statutes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> accept and utilize the services of voluntary and noncompensated personnel and reimburse them for travel expenses, including per diem, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–129, § 5</ref>, <date date="1977-10-13">Oct. 13, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 176.</num>
<heading> Mass Book Deacidification Facility; operation by Librarian of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Librarian of Congress shall equip, furnish, operate, and maintain the Library of Congress Mass Book Deacidification Facility.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–427, § 2</ref>, <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1656</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 177.</num>
<heading> Poet Laureate Consultant in Poetry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recognition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress recognizes that the Consultant in Poetry to the Library of Congress has for some time occupied a position of prominence in the life of the Nation, has spoken effectively for literary causes, and has occasionally performed duties and functions sometimes associated with the position of poet laureate in other nations and societies. Individuals are appointed to the position of Consultant in Poetry by the Librarian of Congress for one- or two-year terms solely on the basis of literary merit, and are compensated from endowment funds administered by the Library of Congress Trust Fund Board. The Congress further recognizes this position is equivalent to that of Poet Laureate of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Position established</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is established in the Library of Congress the position of Poet Laureate Consultant in Poetry. The Poet Laureate Consultant in Poetry shall be appointed by the Librarian of Congress pursuant to the same procedures of appointment as established on <date date="1985-12-20">December 20, 1985</date>, for the Consultant in Poetry to the Library of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each department and office of the Federal Government is encouraged to make use of the services of the Poet Laureate Consultant in Poetry for ceremonial and other occasions of celebration under such procedures as the Librarian of Congress shall approve designed to assure that participation under this paragraph does not impair the continuation of the work of the individual chosen to fill the position of Poet Laureate Consultant in Poetry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Poetry program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Arts, with the advice of the National Council on the Arts, shall annually sponsor a program at which the Poet Laureate Consultant in Poetry will present a major work or the work of other distinguished poets.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Endowment for the Arts $10,000 for the fiscal year 1987 and for each succeeding fiscal year ending prior to <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>, for the purpose of carrying out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–194, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1985-12-20">Dec. 20, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1347</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 178 to 178l.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 102–307, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="1992-06-26">June 26, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 272</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 179 to 179k.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3382</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179l.</num>
<heading> National Film Registry of Library of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress (hereafter in sections 179<i>l</i> to 179w of this title referred to as the “Librarian”) shall continue the National Film Registry established and maintained under the National Film Preservation Act of 1988 (<ref>Public Law 100–446</ref>), and the National Film Preservation Act of 1992 (<ref>Public Law 102–307</ref>) pursuant to the provisions of sections 179<i>l</i> to 179w of this title, for the purpose of maintaining and preserving films that are culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3377</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179m.</num>
<heading> Duties of Librarian of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Librarian shall, after consultation with the Board established pursuant to <ref>section 179n of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> continue the implementation of the comprehensive national film preservation program for motion pictures established under the National Film Preservation Act of 1992, in conjunction with other film archivists, educators and historians, copyright owners, film industry representatives, and others involved in activities related to film preservation, taking into account the objectives of the national film preservation study and the comprehensive national plan conducted under the National Film Preservation Act of 1992. This program shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> coordinate activities to assure that efforts of archivists and copyright owners, and others in the public and private sector, are effective and complementary;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> generate public awareness of and support for these activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> increase accessibility of films for educational purposes; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> undertake studies and investigations of film preservation activities as needed, including the efficacy of new technologies, and recommend solutions to improve these practices;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish criteria and procedures under which films may be included in the National Film Registry, except that no film shall be eligible for inclusion in the National Film Registry until 10 years after such film’s first publication;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> establish procedures under which the general public may make recommendations to the Board regarding the inclusion of films in the National Film Registry; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> determine which films satisfy the criteria established under subparagraph (B) and qualify for inclusion in the National Film Registry, except that the Librarian shall not select more than 25 films each year for inclusion in the Registry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of films in Registry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Librarian shall publish in the Federal Register the name of each film that is selected for inclusion in the National Film Registry.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Seal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Librarian shall provide a seal to indicate that a film has been included in the National Film Registry and is the Registry version of that film. The Librarian shall establish guidelines for approval of the use of the seal in accordance with subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of seal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The seal provided under subsection (a)(3) may only be used on film or other approved copies of the Registry version of a film. Such seal may be used only after the Librarian has given approval to those persons seeking to apply the seal in accordance with the guidelines under subsection (a)(3). In the case of copyrighted, mass distributed, broadcast, or published works, only the copyright owner or an authorized licensee of the copyright owner may place or authorize the placement of the seal on any film or other approved copy of a Registry version of a film selected for inclusion in the National Film Registry, and the Librarian may place the seal on any film or other approved copy of the Registry version of any film that is maintained in the National Film Registry Collection in the Library of Congress. Anyone authorized to place the seal on any film or other approved copy of any Registry version of a film may accompany such seal with the following language: “This film was selected for inclusion in the National Film Registry by the National Film Preservation Board of the Library of Congress because of its cultural, historical, or aesthetic significance.”. The Librarian may authorize the use of the seal by the Library or by others for other limited purposes in order to promote in the National Film Registry when exhibiting, showing, or otherwise disseminating films in the Registry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of program with other collection, preservation, and accessibility activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the comprehensive national film preservation program for motion pictures established under the National Film Preservation Act of 1992, the Librarian, in consultation with the Board established pursuant to <ref>section 179n of this title</ref>, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carry out activities to make films included in the National Film registry more broadly accessible for research and educational purposes, and to generate public awareness and support of the Registry and the comprehensive national film preservation program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> review the comprehensive national film preservation plan, and amend it to the extent necessary to ensure that it addresses technological advances in the preservation and storage of, and access to film collections in multiple formats; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> wherever possible, undertake expanded initiatives to ensure the preservation of the moving image heritage of the United States, including film, videotape, television, and born digital moving image formats, by supporting the work of the National Audio-Visual Conservation Center of the Library of Congress, and other appropriate nonprofit archival and preservation organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3377</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–9, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-27">Apr. 27, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–336, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-02">Oct. 2, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179n.</num>
<heading> National Film Preservation Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Number and appointment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Librarian shall establish in the Library of Congress a National Film Preservation Board to be comprised of 22 members, who shall be selected by the Librarian in accordance with this section. Subject to subparagraphs (C) and (N), the Librarian shall request each organization listed in subparagraphs (A) through (Q) to submit a list of three candidates qualified to serve as a member of the Board. Except for the members-at-large appointed under subparagraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002011">1</ref> (2), the Librarian shall appoint one member from each such list submitted by such organizations, and shall designate from that list an alternate who may attend at Board expense those meetings to which the individual appointed to the Board cannot attend. The organizations are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Directors Guild of America.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Writers Guild of America. The Writers Guild of America East and the Writers Guild of America West shall each nominate three candidates, and a representative from one organization shall be selected as the member and a representative from the other organization as the alternate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The National Society of Film Critics.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Society for Cinema and Media Studies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The American Film Institute.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Department of Film, Television, and Digital Media of the School of Theater, Film and Television at the University of California, Los Angeles.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The Department of Cinema Studies of the Tisch School of the Arts at New York University.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The University Film and Video Association.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> The Motion Picture Association of America.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> The Alliance of Motion Picture and Television Producers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Screen Actors Guild.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> The National Association of Theater Owners.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> The American Society of Cinematographers and the International Photographers Guild, which shall jointly submit one list of three candidates from which a member and alternate will be selected.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> The United States Members of the International Federation of Film Archives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> The Association of Moving Image Archivists.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> The Society of Composers and Lyricists.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Members-at-large</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the members appointed under paragraph (1), the Librarian shall appoint up to 5 members-at-large. The Librarian shall also select an alternate for each member <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002012">2</ref> at-large, who may attend at Board expense those meetings which the member <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002012">2</ref> at-large cannot attend.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian shall appoint one member of the Board to serve as Chair.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of office</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term of each member of the Board shall be 4 years, except that there shall be no limit to the number of terms that any individual member may serve.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of member or organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Librarian shall have the authority to remove any member of the Board, or the organization listed in subsection (a) such member represents, if the member, or organization, over any consecutive 2-year period, fails to attend at least one regularly scheduled Board meeting.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A vacancy in the Board shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made under subsection (a), except that the Librarian may fill the vacancy from a list of candidates previously submitted by the organization or organizations involved. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy before the expiration of the term for which his or her predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">12 members of the Board shall constitute a quorum but a lesser number may hold hearings.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement of expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Board shall serve without pay, but may receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with sections 5702 and 5703 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall meet at least once each fiscal year. Meetings shall be at the call of the Librarian.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conflict of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian shall establish rules and procedures to address any potential conflict of interest between a member of the Board and responsibilities of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3378</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–9, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-27">Apr. 27, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–336, § 3(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-02">Oct. 2, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179o.</num>
<heading> Responsibilities and powers of Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall review nominations of films submitted to it for inclusion in the National Film Registry and consult with the Librarian, as provided in <ref>section 179m of this title</ref>, with respect to the inclusion of such films in the Registry and the preservation of these and other films that are culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nomination of films</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall consider, for inclusion in the National Film Registry, nominations submitted by the general public as well as representatives of the film industry, such as the guilds and societies representing actors, directors, screenwriters, cinematographers, and other creative artists, producers, and film critics, archives and other film preservation organizations, and representatives of academic institutions with film study programs. The Board shall nominate not more than 25 films each year for inclusion in the Registry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board may, for the purpose of carrying out its duties, hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence, as the Librarian and the Board consider appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service on Foundation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Two sitting members of the Board shall be appointed by the Librarian, and shall serve, as Board members of the National Film Preservation Foundation, in accordance with <ref>section 151703 of title 36</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179p.</num>
<heading> National Film Registry Collection of Library of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisition of archival quality copies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian shall endeavor to obtain, by gift from the owner, an archival quality copy of the Registry version of each film included in the National Film Registry. Whenever possible, the Librarian shall endeavor to obtain the best surviving materials, including preprint materials. Copyright owners and others possessing copies of such materials are strongly encouraged, to further the preservation purposes of this Act, to provide preprint and other archival elements to the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional materials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian shall endeavor to obtain, for educational and research purposes, additional materials related to each film included in the National Film Registry, such as background materials, production reports, shooting scripts (including continuity scripts) and other similar materials.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All copies of films on the National Film Registry that are received as gifts or bequests by the Librarian and other materials received by the Librarian under subsection (b), shall become the property of the United States Government, subject to the provisions of title 17.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Film Registry Collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All copies of films on the National Film Registry that are received by the Librarian under subsection (a) of this section, and other materials received by the Librarian under subsection (b), shall be maintained in the Library of Congress and be known as the “National Film Registry Collection of the Library of Congress”. The Librarian shall, by regulation, and in accordance with title 17, provide for reasonable access to the films and other materials in such collection for scholarly and research purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Audio-Visual Conservation Center</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Librarian shall utilize the National Audio-Visual Conservation Center of the Library of Congress at Culpeper, Virginia, to ensure that preserved films included in the National Film Registry are stored in a proper manner, and disseminated to researchers, scholars, and the public as may be appropriate in accordance with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> title 17; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the terms of any agreements between the Librarian and persons who hold copyrights to such audiovisual works.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3380</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–9, title III, § 302(c)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-27">Apr. 27, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 225</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179q.</num>
<heading> Seal of National Film Registry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of seal</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on distribution and exhibition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No person shall knowingly distribute or exhibit to the public a version of a film or any copy in any format of a film which bears the seal described in <ref>section 179m(a)(3) of this title</ref> if such film—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is not included in the National Film Registry; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is included in the National Film Registry, but such film or film copy has not been approved for use of the seal by the Librarian pursuant to <ref>section 179m(a)(1)(D) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on promotion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No person shall knowingly use the seal described in <ref>section 179m(a)(3) of this title</ref> to promote any version of a film in any format other than a Registry version.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date of seal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The use of the seal described in <ref>section 179m(a)(3) of this title</ref> shall be effective for each film after the Librarian publishes in the Federal Register, in accordance with <ref>section 179m(a)(2) of this title</ref>, the name of that film as selected for inclusion in the National Film Registry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3381</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–9, title III, § 302(d)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-27">Apr. 27, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 225</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179r.</num>
<heading> Remedies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The several district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction, for cause shown, to prevent and restrain violations of <ref>section 179q(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relief</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of seal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), relief for violation of <ref>section 179q(a) of this title</ref> shall be limited to the removal of the seal of the National Film Registry from the film involved in the violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fine and injunctive relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a pattern or practice of the willful violation of <ref>section 179q(a) of this title</ref>, the United States district courts may order a civil fine of not more than $10,000 and appropriate injunctive relief.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179s.</num>
<heading> Limitations of remedies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The remedies provided in <ref>section 179r of this title</ref> shall be the exclusive remedies under sections 179<i>l</i> to 179w of this title, or any other Federal or State law, regarding the use of the seal described in <ref>section 179m(a)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179t.</num>
<heading> Staff of Board; experts and consultants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian may appoint and fix the pay of such personnel as the Librarian considers appropriate to carry out sections 179<i>l</i> to 179w of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Experts and consultants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian may, in carrying out sections 179<i>l</i> to 179w of this title, procure temporary and intermittent services under <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref>, but at rates for individuals not to exceed the daily equivalent of the maximum rate of basic pay payable for GS–15 of the General Schedule. In no case may a member of the Board or an alternate be paid as an expert or consultant under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179u.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in sections 179<i>l</i> to 179w of this title—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Librarian” means the Librarian of Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Board” means the National Film Preservation Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “film” means a “motion picture” as defined in <ref>section 101 of title 17</ref>, except that such term does not include any work not originally fixed on film stock, such as a work fixed on videotape or laser disk;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “publication” means “publication” as defined in <ref>section 101 of title 17</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “Registry version” means, with respect to a film, the version of a film first published, or as complete a version as bona fide preservation and restoration activities by the Librarian, an archivist other than the Librarian, or the copyright owner can compile in those cases where the original material has been irretrievably lost.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3382</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179v.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Librarian for the first fiscal year beginning on or after <date date="1996-10-11">October 11, 1996</date>, and each succeeding fiscal year through fiscal year 2026 such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of sections 179<i>l</i> to 179w of this title, but in no fiscal year shall such sum exceed $250,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–336, § 3(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-02">Oct. 2, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–217, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-07-29">July 29, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179w.</num>
<heading> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of sections 179<i>l</i> to 179w of this title shall apply to any copy of any film, including those copies of films selected for inclusion in the National Film Registry under the National Film Preservation Act of 1988 and the National Film Preservation Act of 1992, except that any film so selected under either Act shall be deemed to have been selected for the National Film Registry under sections 179<i>l</i> to 179w of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–285, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–9, title III, § 302(e)</ref>, <date date="2005-04-27">Apr. 27, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 226</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–336, § 3(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-02">Oct. 2, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 180.</num>
<heading> Legislative information retrieval system</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to reduce the cost of information support for the Congress by eliminating duplication among systems which provide electronic access by Congress to legislative information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Legislative information” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “legislative information” means information, prepared within the legislative branch, consisting of the text of publicly available bills, amendments, committee hearings, and committee reports, the text of the Congressional Record, data relating to bill status, data relating to legislative activity, and other similar public information that is directly related to the legislative process.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of single system to serve entire Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Pursuant to the plan approved under subsection (d) and consistent with the provisions of any other law, the Library of Congress or the entity designated by that plan shall develop and maintain, in coordination with other appropriate entities of the legislative branch, a single legislative information retrieval system to serve the entire Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development and approval of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Library shall develop a plan for creation of this system, taking into consideration the findings and recommendations of the study directed by House Report No. 103–517 to identify and eliminate redundancies in congressional information systems. This plan must be approved by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives. The Library shall provide these committees with regular status reports on the development of the plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of information to public</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In formulating its plan, the Library shall examine issues regarding efficient ways to make this information available to the public. This analysis shall be submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives as well as the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, and the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives for their consideration and possible action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–53, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 532</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 181.</num>
<heading> Program for exchange of information among legislative branch agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> On <date date="1996-09-16">September 16, 1996</date>, there shall be established a program for providing the widest possible exchange of information among legislative branch agencies with the long-range goal of improving information technology planning and evaluation. The Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate are requested to determine the structure and operation of this program and to provide appropriate oversight. All of the appropriate offices and agencies of the legislative branch as defined below shall participate in this program for information exchange, and shall report annually on the extent and nature of their participation in their budget submissions to the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “offices and agencies of the legislative branch” means, the office of the Clerk of the House, the office of the Secretary of the Senate, the office of the Architect of the Capitol, the Government Accountability Office, the Government Publishing Office, the Library of Congress, the Congressional Research Service, the Congressional Budget Office, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, and the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “technology” refers to any form of computer hardware and software; computer-based systems, services, and support for the creation, processing, exchange, and delivery of information; and telecommunications systems, and the associated hardware and software, that provide for voice, data, or image communication.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2415</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 182.</num>
<heading> Cooperative Acquisitions Program Revolving Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>, there is established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund to be known as the Cooperative Acquisitions Program Revolving Fund (in this section referred to as the “revolving fund”). Moneys in the revolving fund shall be available to the Librarian of Congress, without fiscal year limitation, for financing the cooperative acquisitions program (in this section referred to as the “program”) under which the Library acquires foreign publications and research materials on behalf of participating institutions on a cost-recovery basis. Obligations under the revolving fund are limited to amounts specified in the appropriations Act for that purpose for any fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts deposited</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The revolving fund shall consist of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any amounts appropriated by law for the purposes of the revolving fund;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any amounts held by the Librarian as of <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date> or <date date="1997-10-07">October 7, 1997</date>, whichever is later, that were collected as payment for the Library’s indirect costs of the program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the difference between (A) the total value of the supplies, equipment, gift fund balances, and other assets of the program, and (B) the total value of the liabilities (including unfunded liabilities such as the value of accrued annual leave of employees) of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credits to revolving fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The revolving fund shall be credited with all advances and amounts received as payment for purchases under the program and services and supplies furnished to program participants, at rates estimated by the Librarian to be adequate to recover the full direct and indirect costs of the program to the Library over a reasonable period of time.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unobligated balances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any unobligated and unexpended balances in the revolving fund that the Librarian determines to be in excess of amounts needed for activities financed by the revolving fund, shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts. Amounts needed for activities financed by the revolving fund means the direct and indirect costs of the program, including the costs of purchasing, shipping, binding of books and other library materials; supplies, materials, equipment and services needed in support of the program; salaries and benefits; general overhead; and travel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The revolving fund shall be subject to audit by the Comptroller General at the Comptroller General’s discretion.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1193</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1403</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 182a.</num>
<heading> Revolving fund for duplication services associated with audiovisual conservation center</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury a revolving fund for duplication and delivery services provided by the Librarian of Congress (hereafter in sections 182a to 182d of this title referred to as the “Librarian”) which are associated with the national audiovisual conservation center established under the Act entitled “An Act to authorize acquisition of certain real property for the Library of Congress, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1997-12-15">December 15, 1997</date> (<ref>Public Law 105–144</ref>; <ref>2 U.S.C. 141</ref> note).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees for services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian may charge a fee for providing services described in subsection (a), and shall deposit any such fees charged into the revolving fund under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The revolving fund under this section shall consist of the following amounts:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Amounts deposited by the Librarian under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any other amounts received by the Librarian which are attributable to the services described in subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Amounts deposited by the Librarian under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Such other amounts as may be appropriated under law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of funds during transition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Librarian shall transfer to the revolving fund under this section the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any obligated, unexpended balances existing as of the date of the transfer which are attributable to the services described in subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> An amount equal to the difference as of such date between—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the total value of the supplies, inventories, equipment, gift fund balances, and other assets attributable to such services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the total value of the liabilities attributable to such services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts in fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts in the revolving fund under this section shall be available to the Librarian, in amounts specified in appropriations Acts and without fiscal year limitation, to carry out the services described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–481, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2187</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 587</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 182b.</num>
<heading> Revolving fund for sales shop and other services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury a revolving fund for the following programs and activities of the Librarian:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Decimal classification development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The operation of a gift shop or other sales of items associated with collections, exhibits, performances, and special events of the Library of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Document reproduction and microfilming services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Special events and programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individual accounting requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A separate account shall be maintained in the revolving fund under this section with respect to the programs and activities described in each of the paragraphs of subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees for services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian may charge a fee for services under any of the programs and activities described in subsection (a), and shall deposit any such fees charged into the account of the revolving fund under this section for such program or activity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of accounts in fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each account of the revolving fund under this section shall consist of the following amounts:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Amounts deposited by the Librarian under subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any other amounts received by the Librarian which are attributable to the programs and activities covered by such account.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Amounts deposited by the Librarian under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Such other amounts as may be appropriated under law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of funds during transition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Librarian shall transfer to each account of the revolving fund under this section the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any obligated, unexpended balances existing as of the date of the transfer which are attributable to the programs and activities covered by such account.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> An amount equal to the difference as of such date between—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the total value of the supplies, inventories, equipment, gift fund balances, and other assets attributable to such programs and activities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the total value of the liabilities attributable to such programs and activities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), amounts in the accounts of the revolving fund under this section shall be available to the Librarian, in amounts specified in appropriations Acts and without fiscal year limitation, to carry out the programs and activities covered by such accounts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for payments for certain Capitol Police services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of any amount in the revolving fund consisting of a payment received for services of the United States Capitol Police in connection with a special event or program described in subsection (a)(4), the Librarian shall transfer such amount upon receipt to the Capitol Police for deposit into the applicable appropriations accounts of the Capitol Police.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–481, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2188</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 587</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1004(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2235</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–178, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2553</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–145, § 6(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-04">Mar. 4, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 54</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 151(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 784</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 182c.</num>
<heading> Revolving fund for FEDLINK program and Federal Research program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury a revolving fund for the Federal Library and Information Network program (hereafter in sections 182a to 182d of this title referred to as the “FEDLINK program”) of the Library of Congress (as described in subsection (f)(1)) and the Federal Research program of the Library of Congress (as described in subsection (f)(2)).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individual accounting requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A separate account shall be maintained in the revolving fund under this section with respect to the programs described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees for services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Librarian may charge a fee for services under the FEDLINK program and the Federal Research program, and shall deposit any such fees charged into the account of the revolving fund under this section for such program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advances of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Participants in the FEDLINK program and the Federal Research program shall pay for products and services of the program by advance of funds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the Librarian determines that amounts in the Revolving Fund <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002013">1</ref> are otherwise insufficient to cover the costs of providing such products and services; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon agreement between participants and the Librarian.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each account of the revolving fund under this section shall consist of the following amounts:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Amounts deposited by the Librarian under subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any other amounts received by the Librarian which are attributable to the program covered by such account.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Amounts deposited by the Librarian under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Such other amounts as may be appropriated under law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of funds during transition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref>section 1535(d) of title 31</ref>, the Librarian shall transfer to the appropriate account of the revolving fund under this section the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any obligated, unexpended balances existing as of the date of the transfer which are attributable to the FEDLINK program or the Federal Research program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> An amount equal to the difference as of such date between—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the total value of the supplies, inventories, equipment, gift fund balances, and other assets attributable to such program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the total value of the liabilities attributable to such program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts in fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts in the accounts of the revolving fund under this section shall be available to the Librarian, in amounts specified in appropriations Acts and without fiscal year limitation, to carry out the program covered by each such account.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Programs described</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> FEDLINK</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this section, the “FEDLINK program” is the program of the Library of Congress under which the Librarian provides the following services on behalf of participating Federal libraries, Federal information centers, other entities of the Federal Government, tribal governments (as defined in <ref>40 U.S.C. 502(c)(2)(B)</ref>) and the District of Columbia:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The procurement of commercial information services, publications in any format, and library support services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Related accounting services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Related education, information, and support services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Research program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this section, the “Federal Research program” is the program of the Library of Congress under which the Librarian provides research reports, translations, and analytical studies for entities of the Federal Government and the District of Columbia (other than any program of the Congressional Research Service).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–481, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2189</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 151(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 784</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 182d.</num>
<heading> Audits by Comptroller General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each of the revolving funds established under sections 182a to 182d of this title shall be subject to audit by the Comptroller General at the Comptroller General’s discretion.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–481, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2190</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 182e.</num>
<heading> Library of Congress National Collection Stewardship Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States, as an account for the Librarian of Congress, the “Library of Congress National Collection Stewardship Fund” (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Fund”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of Fund</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Fund shall consist of the following amounts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002014">1</ref> Such amounts as may be transferred by the Librarian from available amounts appropriated for any fiscal year for the Library of Congress under the heading “Salaries and Expenses”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Amounts in the Fund may be used by the Librarian as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Librarian may use amounts directly for the purpose of preparing collection materials of the Library of Congress for long-term storage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Librarian may transfer amounts to the Architect of the Capitol for the purpose of designing, constructing, altering, upgrading, and equipping collections preservation and storage facilities for the Library of Congress, or for the purpose of acquiring real property by lease for the preservation and storage of Library of Congress collections in accordance with <ref>section 1823a of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amounts in the Fund shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Librarian shall submit a joint report on the Fund to the Joint Committee on the Library and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial 5–year plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, the Librarian shall submit to the Joint Committee on the Library and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate a report providing a plan for expenditures from the Fund for the first 5 fiscal years of the Fund’s operation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Prior to any transfer into the Fund, the Librarian shall notify the Joint Committee on the Library and the Committees on Appropriations of the House and the Senate of the amount and origin of funds to be transferred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2017 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–31, div. I, title I, § 1302</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 183.</num>
<heading> Written history of the House of Representatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to available funding and in accordance with the requirements of this section and <ref>section 183a of this title</ref>, the Librarian of Congress shall prepare, print, distribute, and arrange for the funding of, a new and complete written history of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the Committee on House Administration. In preparing this written history, the Librarian of Congress shall consult, commission, or engage the services or participation of, eminent historians, Members, and former Members of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), the Librarian of Congress shall take into account the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The history should be an illustrated, narrative history of the House of Representatives, organized chronologically.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The history’s intended audience is the general reader, as well as Members of Congress and their staffs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The history should include a discussion of the First and Second Continental Congresses and the Constitutional Convention, especially with regard to their roles in creating the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Printing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Librarian of Congress shall arrange for the printing of the history.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Printing arrangements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The printing may be performed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by the Director of the Government Publishing Office pursuant to the provisions of chapter 5 of title 44;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> under a cooperative arrangement among the Librarian of Congress, a private funding source obtained pursuant to subsection (e), and a publisher in the private sector; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> under subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Internet dissemination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any arrangement under paragraph (2) shall include terms for dissemination of excerpts of the history over the Internet via facilities maintained by the United States Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Member copies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent that the history is printed by the Director of the Government Publishing Office, copies of the history provided to the Congress under subsection (d) shall be charged to the Government Publishing Office’s congressional allotment for printing and binding.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress shall make the history available for sale to the public, and shall make available, free of charge, 5 copies to each Member of the House of Representatives and 250 copies to the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Private funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress shall solicit and accept funding for the preparation, publication, marketing, and public distribution of the history from private individuals, organizations, or entities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–99, § 2</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1330</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1305</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 379</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, (d), <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 183a.</num>
<heading> Oral history of the House of Representatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress shall accept for deposit, preserve, maintain, and make accessible an oral history of the House of Representatives, as told by its Members and former Members, compiled and updated (on a voluntary or contract basis) by the United States Association of Former Members of Congress or other private organization. In carrying out this section, the Librarian of Congress may enlist the voluntary aid or assistance of such organization, or may contract with it for such services as may be necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of oral history</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “oral history” means a story or history consisting of personal recollection as recorded by any one or more of the following means:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Interviews.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Transcripts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Audio recordings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Video recordings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other form or means as may be suitable for the recording and preservation of such information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–99, § 3</ref>, <date date="1999-11-12">Nov. 12, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1331</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 184.</num>
<heading> Incorporation of digital collections into educational curricula</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “Library of Congress Digital Collections and Educational Curricula Act of 2005”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress shall administer a program to teach educators and librarians how to incorporate the digital collections of the Library of Congress into educational curricula.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Educational consortium</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In administering the program under this section, the Librarian of Congress may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish an educational consortium to support the program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make funds appropriated for the program available to consortium members, educational institutions, and libraries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section for fiscal year 2006 and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–55, title I, § 1306</ref>, <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 583</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 185.</num>
<heading> Inspector General of the Library of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “Library of Congress Inspector General Act of 2005”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office of Inspector General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is an Office of Inspector General within the Library of Congress which is an independent objective office to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct and supervise audits and investigations (excluding incidents involving violence and personal property) relating to the Library of Congress, except that nothing in this paragraph may be construed to authorize the Inspector General to audit or investigate any operations or activities of the United States Capitol Police;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide leadership and coordination and recommend policies to promote economy, efficiency, and effectiveness; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide a means of keeping the Librarian of Congress and the Congress fully and currently informed about problems and deficiencies relating to the administration and operations of the Library of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment of Inspector General; supervision; removal; pay; limits on bonuses; counsel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and supervision</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">There shall be at the head of the Office of Inspector General, an Inspector General who shall be appointed by the Librarian of Congress without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations. The Inspector General shall report to, and be under the general supervision of, the Librarian of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audits, investigations, and reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Librarian of Congress shall have no authority to prevent or prohibit the Inspector General from—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> initiating, carrying out, or completing any audit or investigation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> issuing any subpoena during the course of any audit or investigation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> issuing any report.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal or transfer</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Inspector General may be removed from office, or transferred to another position within, or another location of, the Library of Congress, by the Librarian of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 30 days before the Librarian of Congress removes or transfers the Inspector General under subparagraph (A), the Librarian of Congress shall communicate in writing the reason for the removal or transfer to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on House Administration and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Rules and Administration and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph shall prohibit a personnel action (except for removal or transfer) that is otherwise authorized by law.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pay</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The position of Inspector General shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> be classified as a position above GS–15 in accordance with <ref>section 5108 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> have a rate of basic pay that is not less than the average rate of basic pay of all other employees in positions classified as above GS–15 of the Library of Congress calculated on an annual basis.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Librarian of Congress shall establish the amount of the annual adjustment in the rate of basic pay for the Inspector General in an amount equal to the average of the annual adjustments in the rate of basic pay provided to all other employees in positions classified as above GS–15 of the Library of Congress, in a manner consistent with <ref>section 5376 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No bonuses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Inspector General may not receive any cash award or cash bonus, including a cash award under chapter 45 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Inspector General shall, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations governing selections, appointments, and employment at the Library of Congress, obtain legal advice from a counsel reporting directly to the Inspector General or another Inspector General.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties, responsibilities, authority, and reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Sections 404, 405 (other than subsection (b)(13)), 406(a) (other than paragraphs (7) and (8) thereof),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002015">1</ref> and 407 of title 5 shall apply to the Inspector General of the Library of Congress and the Office of such Inspector General and such sections shall be applied to the Library of Congress and the Librarian of Congress by substituting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> “Library of Congress” for “establishment”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> “Librarian of Congress” for “head of the establishment”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employees</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Inspector General, in carrying out the provisions of this section, is authorized, without the supervision or approval of any other employee, office, or other entity within the Library of Congress, to select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees (including consultants) as may be necessary for carrying out the functions, powers, and duties of the Office of Inspector General subject to the provisions of law governing selections, appointments, and employment in the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Security and suitability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Appointments under the authority under subparagraph (A) shall be made consistent with personnel security and suitability requirements.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any appointment of a consultant under the authority under subparagraph (A) shall be made consistent with section 6(a)(8) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.).<sup>1</sup></p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement authority</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), any supervisory special agent under the Inspector General and any special agent supervised by such a supervisory special agent is authorized to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> make an arrest without a warrant while engaged in official duties as authorized under this section or any other statute for any offense against the United States committed in the presence of such supervisory special agent or special agent, or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if such supervisory special agent or special agent has reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such felony;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> seek and execute warrants for arrest, search of a premises, or seizure of evidence issued under the authority of the United States upon probable cause to believe that a violation has been committed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> carry a firearm while engaged in official duties as authorized under this section or any other statute.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements to exercise authority</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required certification</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">In order to exercise the authority under subparagraph (A), a supervisory special agent or a special agent supervised by such a supervisory special agent shall certify that he or she—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> is a citizen of the United States;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> has successfully completed a basic law enforcement training program or military or other equivalent; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> is not prohibited from receiving a firearm under Federal law, including under <ref>section 922(g)(9) of title 18</ref>, because of a conviction of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">After providing notice to the appropriate committees of Congress, the Inspector General may add requirements to the certification required under subclause (I), as determined appropriate by the Inspector General.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Inspector General shall maintain firearms-related requirements (including quarterly firearms qualifications) and use of force training requirements that, except to the extent the Inspector General determines necessary to effectively carry out the duties of the Office of the Inspector General, are in accordance with the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency use of force policies, which incorporate Department of Justice guidelines.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility determination</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">The Inspector General shall—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> determine whether an individual meets the requirements under this paragraph; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> revoke any authority granted to an individual under subparagraph (A) if the individual is not in compliance with the requirements of this paragraph.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reauthorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The Inspector General may reauthorize an individual to exercise the authority granted under subparagraph (A) if the Inspector General determines the individual has achieved compliance with the requirements under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on appeal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">A revocation of the authority granted under subparagraph (A) shall not be subject to administrative, judicial, or other review, unless the revocation results in an adverse action. Such an adverse action may, at the election of the applicable individual, be reviewed in accordance with the otherwise applicable procedures.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Semiannual certification of program</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Before the first grant of authority under subparagraph (A), and semiannually thereafter as part of the report under section 5 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.),<sup>1</sup> the Inspector General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a written certification that adequate internal safeguards and management procedures exist that, except to the extent the Inspector General determines necessary to effectively carry out the duties of the Office of the Inspector General, are in compliance with standards established by the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, which incorporate Department of Justice guidelines, to ensure proper exercise of the powers authorized under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The authority granted under this paragraph (including any grant of authority to an individual under subparagraph (A), without regard to whether the individual is in compliance with subparagraph (B)) may be suspended by the Inspector General if the Office of Inspector General fails to comply with the reporting and review requirements under clause (i) of this subparagraph or subparagraph (D). Any suspension of authority under this clause shall be reported to the appropriate committees of Congress.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Peer review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To ensure the proper exercise of the law enforcement powers authorized under this paragraph, the Office of Inspector General shall submit to and participate in the external review process established by the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency for ensuring that adequate internal safeguards and management procedures continue to exist. Under the review process, the exercise of the law enforcement powers by the Office of Inspector General shall be reviewed periodically by another Office of Inspector General or by a committee of Inspectors General. The results of each review shall be communicated in writing to the Inspector General, the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, and the appropriate committees of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alleged misconduct</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any allegation of misconduct by an individual granted authority under subparagraph (A) may be reviewed by the Integrity Committee of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate committees of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on Rules and Administration and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on House Administration and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Budget independence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Librarian of Congress shall include the annual budget request of the Inspector General in the budget of the Library of Congress without change.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All functions, personnel, and budget resources of the Office of Investigations of the Library of Congress are transferred to the Office of Inspector General.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incumbent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The individual who serves in the position of Inspector General of the Library of Congress on <date date="2005-08-02">August 2, 2005</date>, shall continue to serve in that position, subject to removal in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> References</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">References in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or relating to the Inspector General of the Library of Congress shall be deemed to refer to the Inspector General of the Library of Congress as set forth under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall be effective on <date date="2005-08-02">August 2, 2005</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–55, title I, § 1307</ref>, <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 583</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1004(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2234</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–178, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2552</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–145, § 6(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-04">Mar. 4, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 54</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1602(a), 1603(a), 1604(a)(1), 1605(a), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3209</ref>, 3212, 3218, 3219; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4342</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 186.</num>
<heading> Library of Congress orders under task and delivery order contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract modifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An order issued under a task order contract or a delivery order contract (as such terms are defined in <ref>section 4101 of title 41</ref>) entered into by the Librarian of Congress may not increase the scope, period, or maximum value of the contract under which the order is issued. The scope, period, or maximum value of the contract may be increased only by modification of the contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protests</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protest not authorized</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A protest to an order described in subsection (a) filed pursuant to the procedures in subchapter V of chapter 35 of title 31 is not authorized unless such protest—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is an objection on the basis that the order is in violation of subsection (a); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> concerns an order valued in excess of $10,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction over protests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref>section 3556 of title 31</ref>, the Comptroller General shall have exclusive jurisdiction of a protest authorized under paragraph (1)(B).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section and the amendment made by this section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2022 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. I, title I, § 142</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 519</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>