<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 49—</num>
<heading>CONGRESSIONAL PAGES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4901.</num>
<heading> Congressional pages</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A person shall not be appointed as a page of the Senate or House of Representatives—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> unless he agrees that, in the absence of unforeseen circumstances preventing his service as a page after his appointment, he will continue to serve as a page for the period specified in writing at the time of the appointment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> until complete information in writing is transmitted to his parent or parents, his legal guardian, or other appropriate person or persons acting as his parent or parents, with respect to the nature of the work of pages, their pay, their working conditions (including hours and scheduling of work), and the housing accommodations available to pages.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A person shall not serve as a page—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> of the Senate before he has attained the age of sixteen years; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> of the House of Representatives before he has attained the age of sixteen years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title IV, § 491(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1198</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–51</ref>, §§ 101(c), 123, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 959</ref>, 965; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(36)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 9</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3170</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4902.</num>
<heading> John W. McCormack Residential Page School</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction authorization for dormitory and classroom facilities complex</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be constructed, on a site jointly approved by the Senate Office Building Commission and the House Office Building Commission, in accordance with plans which shall be prepared by or under the direction of the Architect of the Capitol and which shall be submitted to and jointly approved by the Senate Office Building Commission and the House Office Building Commission, a fireproof building containing dormitory and classroom facilities, including necessary furnishings and equipment, for pages of the Senate, the House of Representatives, and the Supreme Court of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acquisition of property in District of Columbia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol, under the joint direction and supervision of the Senate Office Building Commission and the House Office Building Commission, is authorized to acquire on behalf of the United States, by purchase, condemnation, transfer, or otherwise, such publicly or privately owned real property in the District of Columbia (including all alleys, and parts of alleys, and streets within the curblines surrounding such real property) located in the vicinity of the United States Capitol Grounds, as may be approved jointly by the Senate Office Building Commission and the House Office Building Commission, for the purpose of constructing on such real property, in accordance with this section, a suitable dormitory and classroom facilities complex for pages of the Senate, the House of Representatives, and the Supreme Court of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Condemnation proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any proceeding for condemnation instituted under subsection (b) of this section shall be conducted in accordance with subchapter IV of chapter 13 of title 16 of the District of Columbia Code.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of United States owned property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any real property owned by the United States, and any alleys, or parts of alleys and streets, contained within the curblines surrounding the real property acquired on behalf of the United States under this section shall be transferred, upon the request of the Architect of the Capitol made with the joint approval of the Senate Office Building Commission and the House Office Building Commission, to the jurisdiction and control of the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alley and street closures by Mayor of the District of Columbia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any alleys, or parts of alleys and streets, contained within the curblines surrounding the real property acquired on behalf of the United States under this section shall be closed and vacated by the Mayor of the District of Columbia in accordance with any request therefor made by the Architect of the Capitol with the joint approval of the Senate Office Building Commission and the House Office Building Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States Capitol Grounds provisions applicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the acquisition on behalf of the United States of all real property under this section, such property shall be a part of the United States Capitol Grounds and shall be subject to the provisions of sections 1922, 1961, 1966, 1967, and 1969 of this title and sections 5101 to 5107 and 5109 of title 40.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation; employment of services under supervision and control of Architect of the Capitol: joint approval and direction of Speaker and President pro tempore; annual estimates to Congress; regulations governing Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The building constructed on the real property acquired under this section shall be designated the “John W. McCormack Residential Page School”. The employment of all services (other than that of the United States Capitol Police) necessary for its protection, care, maintenance, and use, for which appropriations are made by Congress, shall be under the control and supervision of the Architect of the Capitol. Such supervision and control shall be subject to the joint approval and direction of the Speaker and the President pro tempore. The Architect shall submit annually to the Congress estimates in detail for all services, other than those of the United States Capitol Police or those provided in connection with the conduct of school operations and the personal supervision of pages, and for all other expenses in connection with the protection, care, maintenance, and use of the John W. McCormack Residential Page School. The Speaker and the President pro tempore shall prescribe, from time to time, regulations governing the Architect in the provision of services and the protection, care, and maintenance, of the John W. McCormack Residential Page School.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint appointee for supervision and control over page activities; regulations; Residence Superintendent of Pages: appointment, compensation, and duties; additional personnel: appointment and compensation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate jointly shall designate an officer of the House and an officer of the Senate, other than a Member of the House or Senate, who shall jointly exercise supervision and control over the activities of the pages resident in the John W. McCormack Residential Page School. With the approval of the Speaker and the President pro tempore, such officers so designated shall prescribe regulations governing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the actual use and occupancy of the John W. McCormack Residential Page School including, if necessary, the imposition of a curfew for pages;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the conduct of pages generally; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> other matters pertaining to the supervision, direction, safety, and well-being of pages in off-duty hours.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such officers, subject to the approval of the Speaker and the President pro tempore, jointly shall appoint and fix the per annum gross rate of pay of a Residence Superintendent of Pages, who shall perform such duties with respect to the supervision of pages resident therein as those officials shall prescribe. In addition, such officers, subject to the approval of the Speaker and the President pro tempore, jointly shall appoint and fix the per annum gross rates of pay of such additional personnel as may be necessary to assist those officers and the Residence Superintendent of Pages in carrying out their functions under this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"><ref>Section 4903 of this title</ref> unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this part shall affect the operation of <ref>section 4903 of this title</ref>, relating to educational facilities of pages and other minors who are congressional employees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title IV, § 492</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1199</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–198, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="1973-12-24">Dec. 24, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 789</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(34)(C)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1734</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4903.</num>
<heading> Education of other minors who are Senate employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The facilities provided for the education of Congressional and Supreme Court pages shall be available from and after <date date="1947-01-02">January 2, 1947</date>, also for the education of such other minors who are Senate employees as may be certified by the Secretary of the Senate to receive such education.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 22, 1947, ch. 20</ref>, title I, <ref>61 Stat. 16</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(35)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1735</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4911.</num>
<heading> House of Representatives Page Board; establishment and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Until otherwise provided by law, there is hereby established a board to be known as the House of Representatives Page Board to ensure that the page program is conducted in a manner that is consistent with the efficient functioning of the House and the welfare of the pages.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Page Board shall meet regularly, in accordance with a schedule established jointly by the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–377, title I, § 127</ref>, <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1914</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–2, § 3</ref>, <date date="2007-02-02">Feb. 2, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 5</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4912.</num>
<heading> Membership of Page Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointed and designated members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Page Board shall consist of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> two Members of the House appointed by the Speaker and two Members of the House appointed by the minority leader;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> one individual who, at any time during the 5-year period which ends on the date of the individual’s appointment, is or was a parent of a page participating in the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> one individual who is a former page of the House who is not a Member of the House or an individual described in paragraph (2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Clerk and the Sergeant at Arms of the House.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules for members representing parents and former pages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of the members of the Page Board who are described in paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (a), the following shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each such member shall be appointed jointly by the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each such member shall serve for a term of one year and may be reappointed for additional terms if the member continues to meet the requirements for appointment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A vacancy in the position held by any such member shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. An individual appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve for the remainder of the original term and may be reappointed in accordance with paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Each such member may be paid travel or transportation expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, for attending meetings of the Page Board while away from the member’s home or place of business. There are authorized to be appropriated from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives such sums as may be necessary for payments under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Member of the House” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in sections 4911 to 4913 of this title, the term “Member of the House” means a Representative in, and a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–377, title I, § 127</ref>, <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1914</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(37)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–2, § 2</ref>, <date date="2007-02-02">Feb. 2, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 4</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4913.</num>
<heading> Regulations of Page Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Page Board shall have authority to prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out sections 4911 to 4913 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 97–377, title I, § 127</ref>, <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1914</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4914.</num>
<heading> Academic year and summer term for page program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The page program shall consist of the two semesters of the academic year, plus a non-academic summer term.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(40)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4915.</num>
<heading> Service of page during academic year and summer term; filling of vacancies; eligibility</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (b), a page serving during an academic year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be in the eleventh grade; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall serve for one full semester or two full semesters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (b), a page serving during the summer term—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall have completed the tenth grade; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall not have begun the twelfth grade.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An unforeseen vacancy occurring in a page position during an academic year may be filled, except that no appointment may be made under this paragraph for service to begin on or after October 1 with respect to the first semester or on or after March 1 with respect to the second semester.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An individual who has served as a congressional page at any time during each of any three semesters or terms, as the case may be, shall not be eligible to serve as a page.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(40)(C)</ref>–(E), <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4916.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in sections 4914 to 4916 of this title, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “academic year” means a regular school year, consisting of two semesters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “page” means a page of the House of Representatives, but such term does not include a full time, permanent employee of the House of Representatives with supervisory responsibility for pages; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “congressional page” means a page of the House of Representatives or the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 479</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(40)(F)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4917.</num>
<heading> Page residence hall and page meal plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revolving fund; establishment within House contingent fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective at the beginning of the Ninety-eighth Congress and until otherwise provided by law, there is established a revolving fund within the contingent fund of the House of Representatives for the page residence hall and the page meal plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits in revolving fund; disbursements by Chief Administrative Officer of House</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be deposited in the revolving fund such amounts as may be received by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives with respect to lodging, meals, and related services furnished for congressional pages. Amounts so deposited shall be available for disbursement by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, as determined by the Clerk of the House of Representatives, for expenses relating to the page residence hall and the page meal plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The House of Representatives Page Board shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–51, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="1983-07-14">July 14, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 269</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(38)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1735</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>SENATE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4931.</num>
<heading> Daniel Webster Senate Page Residence Revolving Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund within the contingent fund of the Senate to be known as the Daniel Webster Senate Page Residence Revolving Fund (hereafter referred to in this section as the “fund”). The fund shall consist of all rental payments and other moneys collected or received by the Sergeant at Arms with regard to the Daniel Webster Senate Page Residence. All moneys in the fund shall be available without fiscal year limitation for disbursement by the Secretary of the Senate in connection with operation and maintenance of the Daniel Webster Senate Page Residence not normally performed by the Architect of the Capitol. In addition, such moneys may be used by the Sergeant at Arms to purchase food and food related items and fund activities for the pages.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of moneys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All moneys received from rental payments and other moneys (including donated moneys) collected or received by the Sergeant at Arms with regard to the Daniel Webster Senate Page Residence shall be deposited in the fund and shall be available for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vouchers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Disbursements from the fund shall be made upon vouchers approved by the Sergeant at Arms, or the designee of the Sergeant at Arms.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms is authorized to prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section and to provide for the operations of the Daniel Webster Senate Page Residence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–283, title I, § 4</ref>, <date date="1994-07-22">July 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1427</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–53, title I, § 6</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 518</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>