<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 47—</num>
<heading>CONGRESSIONAL ETHICS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4701.</num>
<heading> Subletting duties of employees of Senate or House</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No employee of Congress, either in the Senate or House, shall sublet to, or hire, another to do or perform any part of the duties or work attached to the position to which he was appointed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1895, ch. 177, § 1</ref>, <ref>28 Stat. 771</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4702.</num>
<heading> Notification of post-employment restrictions for Members of Congress and employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of post-employment restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After a Member of Congress or an elected officer of either House of Congress leaves office, or after the termination of employment with the House of Representatives or the Senate of an employee who is covered under paragraph (2), (3), (4), or (5) of <ref>section 207(e) of title 18</ref>, the Clerk of the House of Representatives, after consultation with the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct, or the Secretary of the Senate, as the case may be, shall notify the Member, officer, or employee of the beginning and ending date of the prohibitions that apply to the Member, officer, or employee under section 207(e) of that title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Posting on Internet</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Clerk of the House of Representatives, with respect to notifications under subsection (a) relating to Members, officers, and employees of the House, and the Secretary of the Senate, with respect to such notifications relating to Members, officers, and employees of the Senate, shall post the information contained in such notifications on the public Internet site of the Office of the Clerk or the Secretary of the Senate, as the case may be, in a format that, to the extent technically practicable, is searchable, sortable, and downloadable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–81, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2007-09-14">Sept. 14, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 739</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4711.</num>
<heading> Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of House of Representatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Committee composition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The respective party caucus or conference of the House of Representatives shall each nominate to the House of Representatives at the beginning of each Congress 7 members to serve on the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigative subcommittees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Committee on Standards of Official Conduct shall adopt rules providing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the establishment of a 4 or 6-member investigative subcommittee (with equal representation from the majority and minority parties) whenever the committee votes to undertake any investigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that the senior majority and minority members on an investigative subcommittee shall serve as the chairman and ranking minority member of the subcommittee; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that the chairman and ranking minority member of the full committee may only serve as non-voting, ex officio members on an investigative subcommittee.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Clause 5(d) of rule XI <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002102">1</ref> of the Rules of the House of Representatives shall not apply to any investigative subcommittee.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjudicatory subcommittees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Committee on Standards of Official Conduct shall adopt rules providing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that upon the completion of an investigation, an investigative subcommittee shall report its findings and recommendations to the committee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that, if an investigative subcommittee by majority vote of its membership adopts a statement of alleged violation, the remaining members of the committee shall comprise an adjudicatory subcommittee to hold a disciplinary hearing on the violation alleged in the statement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that any statement of alleged violation and any written response thereto shall be made public at the first meeting or hearing on the matter which is open to the public after the respondent has been given full opportunity to respond to the statement in accordance with committee rules, but, if no public hearing or meeting is held on the matter, the statement of alleged violation and any written response thereto shall be included in the committee’s final report to the House of Representatives as required by clause 4(e)(1)(B) of rule X <sup>1</sup> of the Rules of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> that a quorum for an adjudicatory subcommittee for the purpose of taking testimony and conducting any business shall consist of a majority of the membership of the subcommittee plus one; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> that an adjudicatory subcommittee shall determine, after receiving evidence, whether the counts in the statement have been proved and shall report its findings to the committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Clause 5(d) of rule XI <sup>1</sup> of the Rules of the House of Representatives shall not apply to any adjudicatory subcommittee.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (h) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advice and education</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Committee on Standards of Official Conduct shall establish within the committee an Office on Advice and Education (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the “Office”) under the supervision of the chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Office shall be headed by a director who shall be appointed by the chairman, in consultation with the ranking minority member, and shall be comprised of such staff as the chairman determines is necessary to carry out the responsibilities of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The primary responsibilities of the Office shall include:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Providing information and guidance to Members, officers and employees of the House regarding any laws, rules, regulations, and other standards of conduct applicable to such individuals in their official capacities, and any interpretations and advisory opinions of the committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Submitting to the chairman and ranking minority member of the committee any written request from any such Member, officer or employee for an interpretation of applicable laws, rules, regulations, or other standards of conduct, together with any recommendations thereon.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Recommending to the committee for its consideration formal advisory opinions of general applicability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Developing and carrying out, subject to the approval of the chairman, periodic educational briefings for Members, officers and employees of the House on those laws, rules, regulations, or other standards of conduct applicable to them.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> No information provided to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct by a Member, officer or employee of the House of Representatives when seeking advice regarding prospective conduct of such Member, officer or employee may be used as the basis for initiating an investigation under clause 4(e)(1)(B) of rule X <sup>1</sup> of the Rules of the House of Representatives, if such Member, officer or employee acts in accordance with the written advice of the committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect immediately before noon <date date="1991-01-03">January 3, 1991</date>, except that subsections (g), (h), and (i) shall take effect on <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–194, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1774</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4712.</num>
<heading> Posting of travel and financial disclosure reports on public website of Clerk of the House of Representatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requiring posting on Internet</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Clerk of the House of Representatives shall post on the public Internet site of the Office of the Clerk, in a format that is searchable, sortable, and downloadable, to the extent technically practicable, each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The advance authorizations, certifications, and disclosures filed with respect to transportation, lodging, and related expenses for travel under clause 5(b) of rule XXV of the Rules of the House of Representatives by Members (including Delegates and Resident Commissioners to the Congress), officers, and employees of the House.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The reports filed under <ref>section 13105(h)(1) of title 5</ref> by Members of the House of Representatives (including Delegates and Resident Commissioners to the Congress).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability and timing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), subsection (a) shall apply with respect to information received by the Clerk of the House of Representatives on or after <date date="2007-09-14">September 14, 2007</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Clerk of the House of Representatives shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not later than <date date="2008-08-01">August 1, 2008</date>, post the information required by subsection (a) that the Clerk receives by <date date="2008-06-01">June 1, 2008</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not later than the end of each 45-day period occurring after information is required to be posted under subparagraph (A), post the information required by subsection (a) that the Clerk has received since the last posting under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omission of personally identifiable information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Members of the House of Representatives (including Delegates and Resident Commissioners to the Congress) shall be permitted to omit personally identifiable information not required to be disclosed on the reports posted on the public Internet site under this section (such as home address, Social Security numbers, personal bank account numbers, home telephone, and names of children) prior to the posting of such reports on such public Internet site.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance in protecting personal information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Clerk of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct, shall include in any informational materials concerning any disclosure that will be posted on the public Internet site under this section an explanation of the procedures for protecting personally identifiable information as described in this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retention</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Clerk shall maintain the information posted on the public Internet site of the Office of the Clerk under this section for a period of 6 years after receiving the information, or, in the case of reports filed under <ref>section 13105(h)(1) of title 5</ref>, until the expiration of the 6-year period which begins on the date the individual is no longer a Member of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–81, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2007-09-14">Sept. 14, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–105, § 19(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-04-04">Apr. 4, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 304</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4713.</num>
<heading> Reporting payments made to witnesses before Committee on Standards of Official Conduct</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law or any other rule or regulation, any information on payments made by the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of the House of Representatives to an individual for attendance as a witness before the Committee in executive session during a Congress shall be reported not later than the second semiannual report filed under <ref>section 5535 of this title</ref> in the following Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>SENATE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4721.</num>
<heading> Referral of ethics violations by Senate Ethics Committee to Government Accountability Office for investigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Committee on Ethics of the Senate determines that there is a reasonable basis to believe that a Member, officer, or employee of the Senate may have committed an ethics violation, the committee may request the Office of Special Investigations of the Government Accountability Office to conduct factfinding and an investigation into the matter. The Office of Special Investigations shall promptly investigate the matter as directed by the committee.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–194, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1753</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4722.</num>
<heading> Mandatory Senate ethics training for Members and staff</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Select Committee on Ethics shall conduct ongoing ethics training and awareness programs for Members of the Senate and Senate staff.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The ethics training program conducted by the Select Committee on Ethics shall be completed by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> new Senators or staff not later than 60 days after commencing service or employment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Senators and Senate staff serving or employed on <date date="2007-09-14">September 14, 2007</date>, not later than 165 days after <date date="2007-09-14">September 14, 2007</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–81, title V, § 553</ref>, <date date="2007-09-14">Sept. 14, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 773</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4723.</num>
<heading> Annual report by Select Committee on Ethics</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate shall issue an annual report due no later than January 31, describing the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The number of alleged violations of Senate rules received from any source, including the number raised by a Senator or staff of the committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A list of the number of alleged violations that were dismissed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for lack of subject matter jurisdiction or, in which, even if the allegations in the complaint are true, no violation of Senate rules would exist; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> because they failed to provide sufficient facts as to any material violation of the Senate rules beyond mere allegation or assertion.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The number of alleged violations in which the committee staff conducted a preliminary inquiry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The number of alleged violations that resulted in an adjudicatory review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The number of alleged violations that the committee dismissed for lack of substantial merit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The number of private letters of admonition or public letters of admonition issued.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The number of matters resulting in a disciplinary sanction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Any other information deemed by the committee to be appropriate to describe its activities in the preceding year.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–81, title V, § 554</ref>, <date date="2007-09-14">Sept. 14, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 773</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4724.</num>
<heading> Amendment to Senate conflict of interest rule</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided by subsection (b), any employee of the Senate who is required to file a report pursuant to Senate rules shall refrain from participating personally and substantially as an employee of the Senate in any contact with any agency of the executive or judicial branch of Government with respect to non-legislative matters affecting any non-governmental person in which the employee has a significant financial interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) shall not apply if an employee first advises his supervisor of his significant financial interest and obtains from such supervisor a written waiver stating that the participation of the employee is necessary. A copy of each such waiver shall be filed with the Select Committee.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–194, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1781</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4725.</num>
<heading> Gifts and travel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gifts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No Member, officer, or employee of the Senate, or the spouse or dependent thereof, shall knowingly accept, directly or indirectly, any gift or gifts in any calendar year aggregating more than the minimal value as established by <ref>section 7342(a)(5) of title 5</ref> or $250, whichever is greater <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002103">1</ref> from any person, organization, or corporation unless, in an unusual case, a waiver is granted by the Select Committee on Ethics.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The prohibitions of this subsection do not apply to gifts—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> from relatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with a value of $100 or less, as adjusted under <ref>section 13104(a)(2)(A) of title 5</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> of personal hospitality of an individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “gift” means a payment, subscription, advance, forbearance, rendering, or deposit of money, services, or anything of value, including food, lodging, transportation, or entertainment, and reimbursement for other than necessary expenses, unless consideration of equal or greater value is received, but does not include (1) a political contribution otherwise reported as required by law, (2) a loan made in a commercially reasonable manner (including requirements that the loan be repaid and that a reasonable rate of interest be paid), (3) a bequest, inheritance, or other transfer at death, (4) a bona fide award presented in recognition of public service and available to the general public, (5) a reception at which the Member, officer, or employee is to be honored, provided such individual receives no other gifts that exceed the restrictions in this rule, other than a suitable memento, (6) meals or beverages consumed or enjoyed, provided the meals or beverages are not consumed or enjoyed in connection with a gift of overnight lodging, or (7) anything of value given to a spouse or dependent of a reporting individual by the employer of such spouse or dependent in recognition of the service provided by such spouse or dependent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “relative” has the same meaning given to such term in <ref>section 13101(16) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If a Member, officer, or employee, after exercising reasonable diligence to obtain the information necessary to comply with this rule, unknowingly accepts a gift described in paragraph (1) such Member, officer, or employee shall, upon learning of the nature of the gift and its source, return the gift or, if it is not possible to return the gift, reimburse the donor for the value of the gift.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection, a Member, officer, or employee of the Senate may participate in a program, the principal objective of which is educational, sponsored by a foreign government or a foreign educational or charitable organization involving travel to a foreign country paid for by that foreign government or organization if such participation is not in violation of any law and if the select <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002104">2</ref> Committee on Ethics has determined that participation in such program by Members, officers, or employees of the Senate is in the interests of the Senate and the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any Member who accepts an invitation to participate in any such program shall notify the Select Committee in writing of his acceptance. A Member shall also notify the Select Committee in writing whenever he has permitted any officer or employee whom he supervises to participate in any such program. The chairman of the Select Committee shall place in the Congressional Record a list of all individuals,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002105">3</ref> participating, the supervisors of such individuals where applicable; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002106">4</ref> and the nature and itinerary of such program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> No Member, officer, or employee may accept funds in connection with participation in a program permitted under subparagraph (A) if such funds are not used for necessary food, lodging, transportation, and related expenses of the Member, officer, or employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limits on domestic and foreign travel by Members and staff of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term “necessary expenses”, with respect to limits on domestic and foreign travel by Members and staff of the Senate, means reasonable expenses for food, lodging, or transportation which are incurred by a Member, officer, or employee of the Senate in connection with services provided to (or participation in an event sponsored by) the organization which provides reimbursement for such expenses or which provides the food, lodging, or transportation directly. Necessary expenses do not include the provision of food, lodging, or transportation, or the payment for such expenses, for a continuous period in excess of 3 days exclusive of travel time within the United States or 7 days exclusive of travel time outside of the United States unless such travel is approved by the Committee on Ethics as necessary for participation in a conference, seminar, meeting or similar matter. Necessary expenses do not include the provision of food, lodging, or transportation, or the payment for such expenses, for anyone accompanying a Member, officer, or employee of the Senate, other than the spouse or child of such Member, officer, or employee of the Senate or one Senate employee acting as an aide to a Member.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–194, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–280, § 8</ref>, <date date="1990-05-04">May 4, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 162</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–90, title III, § 314(c)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 470</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(c)(5)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4726.</num>
<heading> Guidelines relating to restrictions on registered lobbyist participation in travel and disclosure</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in paragraph (4) and not later than 60 days after <date date="2007-09-14">September 14, 2007</date>, and at annual intervals thereafter, the Select Committee on Ethics shall develop and revise, as necessary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> guidelines, for purposes of implementing the amendments made by subsection (a),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002107">1</ref> on evaluating a trip proposal and judging the reasonableness of an expense or expenditure, including guidelines related to evaluating—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the stated mission of the organization sponsoring the trip;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the organization’s prior history of sponsoring congressional trips, if any;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> other educational activities performed by the organization besides sponsoring congressional trips;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> whether any trips previously sponsored by the organization led to an investigation by the Select Committee on Ethics;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> whether the length of the trip and the itinerary is consistent with the official purpose of the trip;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> whether there is an adequate connection between a trip and official duties;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the reasonableness of an amount spent by a sponsor of the trip;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> whether there is a direct and immediate relationship between a source of funding and an event; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> any other factor deemed relevant by the Select Committee on Ethics; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> regulations describing the information it will require individuals subject to the requirements of the amendments made by subsection (a) <sup>1</sup> to submit to the committee in order to obtain the prior approval of the committee for travel under paragraph 2 of rule XXXV of the Standing Rules of the Senate, including any required certifications.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In developing and revising guidelines under paragraph (1)(A), the committee shall take into account the maximum per diem rates for official Federal Government travel published annually by the General Services Administration, the Department of State, and the Department of Defense.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unreasonable expense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, travel on a flight described in paragraph 1(c)(1)(C)(ii) of rule XXXV of the Standing Rules of the Senate shall not be considered to be a reasonable expense.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The deadline for the initial guidelines required by paragraph (1) may be extended for 30 days by the Committee on Rules and Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–81, title V, § 544(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-09-14">Sept. 14, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 769</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4727.</num>
<heading> Senate privately paid travel public website</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel disclosure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2008-01-01">January 1, 2008</date>, the Secretary of the Senate shall establish a publicly available website without fee or without access charge, that contains information on travel that is subject to disclosure under paragraph 2 of rule XXXV of the Standing Rules of the Senate, that includes, with respect to travel occurring on or after <date date="2008-01-01">January 1, 2008</date>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a search engine;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> uniform categorization by Member, dates of travel, and any other common categories associated with congressional travel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> forms filed in the Senate relating to officially related travel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retention</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Senate shall maintain the information posted on the public Internet site of the Office of the Secretary under this section for a period not longer than 4 years after receiving the information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary of the Senate is unable to meet the deadline established under subsection (a), the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate may grant an extension of the Secretary of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002108">1</ref> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–81, title V, § 546</ref>, <date date="2007-09-14">Sept. 14, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 772</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4728.</num>
<heading> Notification of post-employment restrictions for Senators and employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After a Senator or an elected officer of the Senate leaves office or after the termination of employment with the Senate of an employee of the Senate, the Secretary of the Senate shall notify the Member, officer, or employee of the beginning and ending date of the prohibitions that apply to the Member, officer, or employee under rule XXXVII of the Standing Rules of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect 60 days after <date date="2007-09-14">September 14, 2007</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–81, title V, § 535</ref>, <date date="2007-09-14">Sept. 14, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 766</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>