<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 51—</num>
<heading>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES LEADERSHIP</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5101.</num>
<heading> Employment of administrative assistants for Speaker and House Majority and Minority Leaders; compensation; appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Speaker, the majority leader, and the minority leader of the House of Representatives are each authorized to employ an administrative assistant, who shall receive basic compensation at a rate not to exceed $8,000 a year. There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for the payment of such compensation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title II, § 201(c), <ref>60 Stat. 834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5102.</num>
<heading> Appointment of consultants by Speaker, Majority Leader, and Minority Leader of House; compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Speaker, Majority Leader, and Minority Leader of the House of Representatives are each authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of one consultant, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of the per diem equivalent of the highest gross rate of annual compensation which may be paid to employees of a standing committee of the House.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 1999 and each succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5103.</num>
<heading> Single per annum gross rates of allowances for personal services in offices of Speaker, Leaders, and Whips</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The allowance for additional office personnel in the office of each of the following officials of the House of Representatives shall be at a single per annum gross rate, as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Speaker, $110,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Majority Leader, $90,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Minority Leader, $55,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Majority Whip, $55,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Minority Whip, $55,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–510, title IV, § 473</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1194</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5104.</num>
<heading> Authority of Speaker and Minority Leader to allocate funds among certain House leadership offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Speaker</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including any provision of law that sets forth an allowance for official expenses), the amount appropriated or otherwise made available during a Congress for the salaries and expenses of any office or authority described in paragraph (2) shall be the amount allocated for such office or authority by the Speaker of the House of Representatives from the aggregate amount appropriated or otherwise made available for all such offices and authorities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offices and authorities described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The offices and authorities described in this paragraph are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Office of the Speaker.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Speaker’s Office for Legislative Floor Activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Republican Steering Committee (if the Speaker is a member of the Republican party) or the Democratic Steering and Policy Committee (if the Speaker is a member of the Democratic party).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Republican Policy Committee (if the Speaker is a member of the Republican party).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Training and program development—majority (as described under the heading “House leadership offices” in the most recent bill making appropriations for the legislative branch that was enacted prior to <date date="2011-12-23">December 23, 2011</date>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Cloakroom personnel—majority (as so described).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Minority Leader</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including any provision of law that sets forth an allowance for official expenses), the amount appropriated or otherwise made available during a Congress for the salaries and expenses of any office or authority described in paragraph (2) shall be the amount allocated for such office or authority by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives from the aggregate amount appropriated or otherwise made available for all such offices and authorities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offices and authorities described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The offices and authorities described in this paragraph are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Office of the Minority Leader.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Democratic Steering and Policy Committee (if the Minority Leader is a member of the Democratic party) or the Republican Steering Committee (if the Minority Leader is a member of the Republican party).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Republican Policy Committee (if the Minority Leader is a member of the Republican party).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Training and program development—minority (as described under the heading “House leadership offices” in the most recent bill making appropriations for the legislative branch that was enacted prior to <date date="2011-12-23">December 23, 2011</date>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Cloakroom personnel—minority (as so described).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Nine minority employees (as so described).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to any months occurring during the One Hundred Twelfth Congress that begin after <date date="2011-12-23">December 23, 2011</date>, and to any succeeding Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. G, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1121</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5105.</num>
<heading> Transfer of appropriations by House Leadership Offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each office described under the heading “HOUSE LEADERSHIP OFFICES” in the Act making appropriations for the legislative branch for a fiscal year may transfer any amounts appropriated for the office under such heading among the various categories of allowances and expenses for the office under such heading.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Official expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to any amounts appropriated for official expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 1999 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–31, title III, § 3009</ref>, <date date="1999-05-21">May 21, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 93</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5106.</num>
<heading> Allowance for compensation of interns in House leadership offices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established for the House of Representatives an allowance which shall be available for the compensation of interns who serve in House leadership offices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benefit exclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 5321(b) of this title</ref> shall apply with respect to an intern who is compensated under the allowance under this section in the same manner as such section applies with respect to an intern who is compensated under the Members’ Representational Allowance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “House leadership office” means, with respect to a fiscal year, any office for which the appropriation for salaries and expenses of the office for the fiscal year is provided under the heading “House Leadership Offices” in the Act making appropriations for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> term “intern”, with respect to a House leadership office, has the meaning given such term with respect to a Member of the House of Representatives in <ref>section 5321(c)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2020 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2020 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2759</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>THE SPEAKER</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5121.</num>
<heading> Expense allowance of Speaker of House of Representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be paid to the Speaker of the House of Representatives in equal monthly installments an expense allowance of $10,000 per annum to assist in defraying expenses relating to or resulting from the discharge of his official duties, for which no accounting, other than for income tax purposes, shall be made by him.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Jan. 19, 1949, ch. 2, § 1(e)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 4</ref>; <ref>Oct. 20, 1951, ch. 521</ref>, title VI, § 619(c), <ref>65 Stat. 570</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 203(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1725</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5122.</num>
<heading> Personal services in office of Speaker; payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be paid from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives until otherwise provided by law, for personal services in the office of the Speaker of the House, an additional basic sum of $10,000 per annum.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–730, § 103</ref>, <date date="1962-10-02">Oct. 2, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 693</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(14)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1732</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5123.</num>
<heading> Speaker’s Office for Legislative Floor Activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the House of Representatives an office to be known as the Speaker’s Office for Legislative Floor Activities. The Speaker shall appoint and set the annual rate of pay for employees of the Office. The Office shall have the responsibility of assisting the Speaker in the management of legislative floor activity.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–53, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 520</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5124.</num>
<heading> Lump sum allowance for Speaker</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The aggregate amount otherwise authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year for the lump-sum allowance for the Office of the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall be increased by $40,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2002 and each succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 573</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5125.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–244, div. B, title I, § 118(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2018-09-21">Sept. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2930</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 5126 to 5129.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–244, div. B, title I, § 118(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-09-21">Sept. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2930</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>MAJORITY AND MINORITY LEADERS AND WHIPS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5141.</num>
<heading> Additional employees in offices of House Minority Leader, Majority Whip, and Chief Deputy Majority Whip; authorization; compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisions of subsection (b), effective <date date="1977-03-01">March 1, 1977</date>, there shall be two additional employees in the office of the minority leader, and one additional employee each in the offices of the majority whip and the chief deputy majority whip.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The maximum annual rate of compensation for any individual employed under subsection (a) shall not exceed the greater of $173,900 or the applicable rate of pay in effect under an order issued by the Speaker of the House of Representatives pursuant to the authority of <ref>section 4532 of this title</ref>, and until otherwise provided by law such compensation as may be necessary shall be paid from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 668</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–53, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(15)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(b)(3)(E)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2778</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5142.</num>
<heading> Additional amounts for personnel and equipment for House Majority and Minority Leaders and Majority and Minority Whips</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Effective <date date="1977-03-01">March 1, 1977</date>, and until otherwise provided by law, there shall be paid out of the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives such additional amounts as may be necessary for office personnel, and rental or lease of necessary equipment, of each of the following officials of the House the following per annum amounts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The majority leader, $30,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The minority leader, $30,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The majority whip, $15,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The minority whip, $15,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 668</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(15)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1732</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5143.</num>
<heading> Compensation of certain House minority employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1977-01-03">January 3, 1977</date>, and until otherwise provided by law, the rate of pay for each of the six positions of minority employee authorized by the Legislative Pay Act of 1929 and referred to in House Resolution 441 of the Ninety-first Congress shall be a per annum gross rate equal to the annual rate of basic pay of level IV of the Executive Schedule of <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref>, unless a lower rate is established by the Minority Leader.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 668</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5144.</num>
<heading> Lump-sum allowances for House Minority Leader and Majority Whip</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The aggregate amount otherwise authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year for the lump-sum allowance for the Office of the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives and the aggregate amount otherwise authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year for the lump-sum allowance for the Office of the Majority Whip of the House of Representatives shall each be increased by $333,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2000 and each succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–31, title III, § 3008</ref>, <date date="1999-05-21">May 21, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 93</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5145.</num>
<heading> Lump-sum allowances for House Majority Floor Leader, Minority Floor Leader, Majority Whip, and Minority Whip</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Effective with respect to fiscal year 2008 and each succeeding fiscal year, the aggregate amount otherwise authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year for the lump-sum allowance for each of the following offices is increased as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The allowance for the office of the Majority Floor Leader is increased by $200,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The allowance for the office of the Minority Floor Leader is increased by $200,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Effective with respect to fiscal year 2009 and each succeeding fiscal year, the aggregate amount otherwise authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year for the lump-sum allowance for each of the following offices is increased as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The allowance for the office of the Majority Whip is increased by $72,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The allowance for the office of the Minority Whip is increased by $72,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. G, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 818</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5146.</num>
<heading> Lump-sum allowances for House Majority Whip and Minority Whip</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Effective with respect to fiscal year 2010 and each succeeding fiscal year, the aggregate amount otherwise authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year for the lump-sum allowance for each of the following offices is increased as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The allowance for the office of the Majority Whip is increased by $96,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The allowance for the office of the Minority Whip is increased by $96,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–68, div. A, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2029</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>POLICY COMMITTEES AND CONFERENCES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5161.</num>
<heading> Training and program development activities of Republican Conference and Democratic Steering and Policy Committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established an account in the House of Representatives for purposes of carrying out training and program development activities of the Republican Conference and the Democratic Steering and Policy Committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts, times, terms, and conditions of payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Funds in the account established under subsection (a) shall be paid—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for activities of the Republican Conference in such amounts, at such times, and under such terms and conditions as the Speaker of the House of Representatives may direct (or, if the Speaker is not a member of the Republican Party, under such terms and conditions as the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives may direct); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for activities of the Democratic Steering and Policy Committee in such amounts, at such times, and under such terms and conditions as the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives may direct (or, if the Speaker is a member of the Democratic Party, under such terms and conditions as the Speaker may direct).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the account under this section for fiscal year 1999 and each succeeding fiscal year such sums as may be necessary for training and program development activities of the Republican Conference and the Democratic Steering and Policy Committee during the fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. G, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1122</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5162.</num>
<heading> Republican Policy Committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the House of Representatives an office to be known as the Republican Policy Committee, which shall have such responsibilities as may be assigned by the Speaker of the House of Representatives (or, if the Speaker is not a member of the Republican Party, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Salaries and expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be a lump sum allowance for the salaries and expenses of the Republican Policy Committee, which shall be treated as a category of House leadership offices for purposes of <ref>section 5507(c) of this title</ref>, and which shall be obligated and expended as directed by the Speaker (or, if the Speaker is not a member of the Republican party, the Minority Leader).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2005 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3177</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. G, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1121</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>