<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 55—</num>
<heading>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES OFFICERS AND ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5501.</num>
<heading> Temporary appointments in case of vacancies or incapacity of House officers; compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary appointments in case of vacancy or incapacity in office of Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer, or Chaplain of House</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In case of a vacancy, from whatever cause, in the office of Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer or Chaplain, of the House of Representatives, or in case of the incapacity or inability of the incumbent of any such office to perform the duties thereof, the Speaker of the House of Representatives may appoint a person to act as, and to exercise temporarily the duties of, Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer or Chaplain, as the case may be, until a person is chosen by the House of Representatives and duly qualifies as Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer or Chaplain, as the case may be, or until the termination of the incapacity or inability of the incumbent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of temporary appointees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person appointed pursuant to this section shall exercise all the duties, shall have all the powers, and shall be subject to all the requirements and limitations applicable with respect to one chosen by the House of Representatives to fill the office involved.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation of temporary appointee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person appointed pursuant to this section shall be paid the compensation which he would receive if he were chosen by the House of Representatives to fill the office involved, unless such person is concurrently serving in any office or position the compensation for which is paid from the funds of the United States, in which case he shall receive no compensation for services rendered pursuant to his appointment under this section, and his compensation for performing the duties of such office other than the one to which he is appointed pursuant to this section shall be in full discharge for all services he performs for the United States while serving in such dual capacity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753, § 208</ref>, as added <ref>Aug. 5, 1953, ch. 330</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 387</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(20)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1733</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–289, div. B, title II, § 20702(b)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–5, § 2</ref>, <date date="2007-02-15">Feb. 15, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 38</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5502.</num>
<heading> House emergency operations positions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment in certain offices</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Effective with respect to fiscal year 2002 and each succeeding fiscal year, there are hereby established 2 additional positions in each of the following offices of the House of Representatives:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Office of the Clerk.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Office of the Chief Administrative Officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Office of the Sergeant at Arms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The duty of the personnel appointed to a position established under this section shall be to ensure the continuity of the operations of the House of Representatives during periods of emergency, in accordance with the direction of the head of the office in which the position is established.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rate of pay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The annual rate of pay provided for a position established under this section shall be determined by the head of the office in which the position is established.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the head of the office in which a position is established under this section shall have the exclusive authority to appoint personnel to such a position.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 118</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 573</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5503.</num>
<heading> Actions against officers for official acts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any action brought against any person for or on account of anything done by him while an officer of either House of Congress in the discharge of his official duty, in executing any order of such House, the United States attorney for the district within which the action is brought, on being thereto requested by the officer sued, shall enter an appearance in behalf of such officer; and all provisions of the eighth section of the Act of <date date="1866-07-28">July 28, 1866</date>, entitled “An Act to protect the revenue, and for other purposes”, and also all provisions of the sections of former Acts therein referred to, so far as the same relate to the removal of suits, the withholding of executions, and the paying of judgments against revenue or other officers of the United States, shall become applicable to such action and to all proceedings and matters whatsoever connected therewith, and the defense of such action shall thenceforth be conducted under the supervision and direction of the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1875, ch. 130, § 8</ref>, <ref>18 Stat. 401</ref>; <ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 1</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5504.</num>
<heading> Officers of Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 5503 of this title</ref> shall not apply to officers of the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–521, title VII, § 714(d)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-26">Oct. 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1884</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5505.</num>
<heading> Payments from applicable accounts of House of Representatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No payment may be made from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives (as determined by the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives), unless sanctioned by that Committee. Payments on vouchers approved in the manner directed by that Committee shall be deemed, held, and taken, and are declared to be conclusive upon all the departments and officers of the Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “applicable accounts of the House of Representatives” means accounts for salaries and expenses of committees (other than the Committee on Appropriations), the computer support organization of the House of Representatives, and allowances and expenses of Members of the House of Representatives, officers of the House of Representatives, and administrative and support offices of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Member of the House of Representatives” means a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1721</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5506.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for expenses of House; restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations made for expenses of the House of Representatives shall not be used for the payment of personal services except upon the express and specific authorization of the House in whose behalf such services are rendered. Nor shall such appropriations be used for any expenses not intimately and directly connected with the routine legislative business of the House of Representatives, and the Government Accountability Office shall apply the provisions of this section in the settlement of the accounts of expenditures from said appropriations incurred for services or materials.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 14, 1902, ch. 17, § 1</ref>, <ref>32 Stat. 26</ref>; <ref>June 10, 1921, ch. 18</ref>, title III, § 304, <ref>42 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(45)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5507.</num>
<heading> Transfers of amounts appropriated for House</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers among categories of allowances and expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated for any fiscal year for the House of Representatives under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">allowances and expenses</inline>” may be transferred among and merged with the various categories of allowances and expenses under such heading, effective upon the expiration of the 21-day period (or such alternative period that may be imposed by the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives) which begins on the date such Committee has been notified of the transfer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers among offices and activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated for any fiscal year for the House of Representatives under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">salaries, officers and employees</inline>” may be transferred among and merged with the various offices and activities under such heading, effective upon the expiration of the 21-day period (or such alternative period that may be imposed by the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives) which begins on the date such Committee has been notified of the transfer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers among various appropriations headings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Amounts appropriated for any fiscal year for the House of Representatives under the headings specified in paragraph (2) may be transferred among and merged with such headings, effective upon the expiration of the 21-day period (or such alternative period that may be imposed by the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives) which begins on the date such Committee has been notified of the transfer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The headings referred to in paragraph (1) are “House Leadership Offices”, “Members’ Representational Allowances”, “Committee Employees”, “Salaries, Officers and Employees”, “Allowances and Expenses”, the heading for any joint committee under the heading “Joint Items” (to the extent that amounts appropriated for the joint committee are disbursed by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives), “Office of the Attending Physician”, “Allowance for Compensation of Interns in Member Offices” <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002112">1</ref> “Allowance for Compensation of Interns in House Appropriations Committee Offices”, “Allowance for Compensation of Interns in House Standing, Special and Select Committee Offices”, “Allowance for Compensation of Interns in House Leadership Offices”, and “House of Representatives Modernization Initiatives Account”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers to Architect of the Capitol</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated for any fiscal year for the House of Representatives under the heading “Allowances and Expenses” may be transferred to the Architect of the Capitol and merged with and made available under the heading “House Office Buildings”, subject to the approval of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers to House Historic Buildings Revitalization Trust Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated for any fiscal year for the House of Representatives under any heading other than the heading “Members’ Representational Allowances” may be transferred to the Architect of the Capitol and merged with and made available under the heading “House Historic Buildings Revitalization Trust Fund”, subject to the approval of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfers among House Leadership Offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated for any fiscal year for the House of Representatives under the heading “House Leadership Offices” may be transferred among and merged with the various offices and activities under such heading, effective upon the expiration of the 21-day period (or such alternative period that may be imposed by the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives) which begins on the date such Committee has been notified of the transfer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–392, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1709</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 109(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 355</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. G, title I</ref>, §§ 103(a), 105(a), (b), <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 817</ref>, 818; <ref>Pub. L. 111–68, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 104(a), 1304(d), <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2029</ref>, 2035; <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. I, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 422</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–244, div. B, title I, § 119(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-09-21">Sept. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title I</ref>, §§ 112(b), 113(e), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2759</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. I, title I, § 115(d)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1637</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. I, title I, § 113(d)</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5508.</num>
<heading> Account in House of Representatives for Employees’ Compensation Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established an account in the House of Representatives for purposes of making payments of the House of Representatives to the Employees’ Compensation Fund under <ref>section 8147 of title 5</ref>, and for reimbursing the Secretary of Labor for any amounts paid with respect to unemployment compensation payments for former employees of the House.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments made from account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, payments may be made from the account established under subsection (a) at any time after <date date="1997-10-07">October 7, 1997</date>, without regard to the fiscal year for which the obligation to make such payments is incurred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Category of allowances and expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The account established under subsection (a) shall be treated as a category of allowances and expenses for purposes of <ref>section 5507(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1184</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. I, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5509.</num>
<heading> Incidental use of equipment and supplies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Committee on House Oversight may prescribe by regulation appropriate conditions for the incidental use, for other than official business, of equipment and supplies owned or leased by, or the cost of which is reimbursed by, the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The authority of the Committee on House Oversight to prescribe regulations pursuant to subsection (a) shall apply with respect to fiscal year 1999 and each succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5510.</num>
<heading> Providing assistance to House of Representatives in response to cybersecurity events</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Speaker of the House of Representatives (or the Speaker’s designee), with the concurrence of the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives (or the Minority Leader’s designee), determines that a cybersecurity event has occurred and that containing, mitigating, or resolving the event exceeds the resources of the House of Representatives, then notwithstanding any other provision of law or any rule, regulation, or executive order—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Speaker may request assistance in responding to the event from the head of any Executive department, military department, or independent establishment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not later than 24 hours after receiving the request, the head of the department or establishment shall begin to provide appropriate assistance in response to the incident, including (if necessary) restoring the information systems of the House to an operational state which allows for the continuation of the legislative process and for Members, officers, and employees of the House to continue to meet their official and representational duties; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such assistance shall be provided without reimbursement by the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The assistance provided to the Speaker by the head of a department or establishment under this section may consist only of a type that the head of the department or establishment is authorized under law to provide to the department or establishment, another Executive department, military department, or independent establishment, or a private entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Connections between department or establishment and House information systems</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In providing assistance under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> personnel of a department or establishment may not log onto the information systems of the House without the authorization of the Speaker (or the Speaker’s designee); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> personnel of a department or establishment may provide the House with access to technological support services of the department or establishment, including by authorizing personnel or systems of the House to connect with and operate services or programs of the department or establishment with guidance from subject matter experts of the department or establishment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination upon notice from Speaker</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After initiating assistance under this section, the head of the department or establishment shall continue providing assistance until the Speaker (or Speaker’s designee) notifies the head of the department or establishment that the cybersecurity incident has terminated and that it is no longer necessary for the department or establishment to provide post-incident assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of technological support services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon receiving notice from the Speaker under paragraph (1), the head of the department or establishment shall ensure that any technological support services or programs of the department or establishment are removed from the information systems of the House, and that personnel of the department or establishment are no longer monitoring such systems.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with existing standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In providing assistance under this section, the head of the Executive department, military department, or independent establishment shall meet the requirements of section 113 of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2017 (<ref>Public Law 115–31</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No effect on other authority to provide support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section may be construed to affect the authority of an Executive department, military department, or independent establishment to provide any support, including cybersecurity support, to the House of Representatives under any other law, rule, or regulation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, each of the terms “Executive department”, “military department”, and “independent establishment” has the meaning given such term in chapter 1 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1090</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1606</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5511.</num>
<heading> Transfer of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of unexpended appropriations for salaries and expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, upon completion of the second fiscal year which begins after the end of the period during which amounts appropriated under any of the items under the heading “House of Representatives, Salaries and Expenses” are available for obligation or expenditure, any such amounts which remain unobligated and unexpended shall be transferred to the heading “House of Representatives, Salaries and Expenses, Allowances and Expenses” and shall be available until expended for purposes of House of Representatives Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for Members’ Representational Allowances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) does not apply to amounts appropriated under the heading “House of Representatives, Salaries and Expenses, Members’ Representational Allowances”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives shall notify the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives prior to the obligation or expenditure of any amounts transferred under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2018 or any succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 119</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 777</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5512.</num>
<heading> Use of available balances of expired appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to <ref>section 5511 of this title</ref>, available balances of expired appropriations for the House of Representatives shall be available to the House of Representatives—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the payment of a death gratuity which is specifically appropriated by law and which is made in connection with the death of an employee of the House of Representatives, without regard to the fiscal year in which the payment is made; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for deposit into the account established under <ref>section 5508 of this title</ref> for making payments of the House of Representatives to the Employees’ Compensation Fund under <ref>section 8147 of title 5</ref> and for reimbursing the Secretary of Labor for any amounts paid with respect to unemployment compensation payments for former employees of the House.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section shall apply with respect to funds appropriated or otherwise made available in fiscal year 2020 and each succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2760</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5513.</num>
<heading> House of Representatives Modernization Initiatives Account</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States an account for the House of Representatives to be known as the “House of Representatives Modernization Initiatives Account” (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Account”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds in the Account shall be used by the House of Representatives to carry out initiatives to modernize the operations of the House, including initiatives to promote administrative efficiencies and expand the use of innovative technologies in offices of the House.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds in the Account are available without fiscal year limitation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2021 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. I, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1637</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5514.</num>
<heading> Green and Gold Congressional Aide Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the House of Representatives the Green and Gold Congressional Aide Program (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Program”) for veterans and Gold Star Families, under the direction of the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, under which an eligible individual may serve a 2-year fellowship in the office of a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) or House Officer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Placement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An individual may serve a fellowship under the Program at the Member’s office in the District of Columbia or the Member’s office in the congressional district the Member represents. Fellows assigned to House Officers may serve where assigned.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion of appointees for purposes of limit on number of employees in Member offices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any individual serving a fellowship under the Program in the office of a Member shall not be included in the determination of the number of employees employed by the Member under <ref>section 5321(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Program shall be carried out in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Committee on House Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2022 and each succeeding fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to carry out the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2022 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. I, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>CHAPLAIN</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5521.</num>
<heading> Compensation of Chaplain of House</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The maximum per year gross rate of compensation of the Chaplain of the House of Representatives shall not exceed the greater of $173,900 or the rate of pay in effect for such position under an order issued by the Speaker of the House of Representatives pursuant to the authority of <ref>section 4532 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. E, title II, § 212(b)(3)(D)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2777</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>CHIEF ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICER</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5531.</num>
<heading> Program to increase employment opportunities in House of Representatives for individuals with disabilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to promote an increase in opportunities for individuals with disabilities to provide services to the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enter into 1 or more contracts with nongovernmental entities to provide for the performance of services for offices of the House of Representatives by individuals with disabilities who are employees of, or under contract with, such entities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide reasonable accommodations, including assistive technology devices and assistive technology services, to enable such individuals to perform such services under such contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements of program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, in entering into any contract under subsection (a), shall seek to ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> traditional and nontraditional outreach efforts are used to attract individuals with disabilities for educational benefit and employment opportunities in the House;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the non-governmental entity provides adequate education and training for individuals with disabilities to enhance such employment opportunities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> efforts are made to educate employing offices in the House about opportunities to employ individuals with disabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives $500,000 to carry out this section for each of the fiscal years 2003 through 2007.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5532.</num>
<heading> Advance payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For fiscal year 1998 and each succeeding fiscal year, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives is authorized to make advance payments under a contract or other agreement to provide a service or deliver an article for the United States Government without regard to the provisions of <ref>section 3324 of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An advance payment authorized by subsection (a) shall be made in accordance with regulations issued by the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority granted by subsection (a) shall not take effect until regulations are issued pursuant to subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5533.</num>
<heading> House of Representatives Revolving Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is established in the House of Representatives a fund to be known as the “House of Representatives Revolving Fund”, consisting of the following amounts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Amounts appropriated to the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts donated to the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Interest on the balance of the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts in the Fund shall be expended at the direction of the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, upon notification provided by the Chief Administrative Officer to the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2004 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. H, § 156</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 450</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5534.</num>
<heading> House revolving fund for stationery allowances; disposition of moneys from stationery sales; availability of unexpended balances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a revolving fund for the purpose of administering the funds appropriated for stationery allowances to each Representative, Delegate, the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico; and stationery for use of the committees, departments, and officers of the House. All moneys hereafter received by the stationery room of the House of Representatives from the sale of stationery supplies and other equipment shall be deposited in the revolving fund and shall be available for disbursement from the fund in the same manner as other sums that may be appropriated by the Congress for this purpose. The unexpended balance of all moneys heretofore received by the stationery room of the House of Representatives from the sale of stationery supplies and equipment shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the fund: <i>Provided</i>, That the unexpended balances in the appropriations “Contingent expenses, House of Representatives, stationery, 1945–1946”; “Contingent expenses, House of Representatives, stationery, 1946”; “Contingent expenses, House of Representatives, stationery, 1947–48”, as of <date date="1947-06-30">June 30, 1947</date>, shall be transferred to and made available for expenditure out of the fund, together with appropriations herein or hereafter made therefor, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 17, 1947, ch. 262</ref>, <ref>61 Stat. 366</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5535.</num>
<heading> Report of disbursements for House of Representatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after the last day of each semiannual period, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives shall submit to the House of Representatives, with respect to that period, a detailed, itemized report of the disbursements for the operations of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the name of each person who receives a payment from the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the quantity and price of any item furnished to the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of any service rendered to the House of Representatives, together with a statement of the time required for the service, and the name, title, and amount paid to each person who renders the service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a statement of all amounts appropriated to, or received, or expended by the House of Representatives, and any unexpended balances of such amounts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the information submitted to the Comptroller General under <ref>section 3523(a) of title 31</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> such additional information as may be required by regulation of the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (b), if a voucher is for payment to an individual for attendance as a witness before a committee of the Congress in executive session, the report for the semiannual period in which the appearance occurs shall show only the date of payment, voucher number, and amount paid. Any information excluded from a report under the preceding sentence shall be included in the report for the next period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> House document</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each report under this section shall be printed as a House document.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conforming provision</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The provisions of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> sections 102, 103, and 104 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002113">1</ref> of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>section 4108 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">that require submission and printing of statements and reports are not applicable to the House of Representatives.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply to the semiannual periods of January 1 through June 30 and July 1 through December 31 of each year, beginning with the semiannual period in which this section is enacted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1722</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5536.</num>
<heading> Office equipment for House Members, officers, and committees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Chief Administrative Officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of any Member, officer, or committee of the House of Representatives, or the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico, and with the approval of the Committee on House Oversight, but subject to the limitations prescribed by this Act, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives shall furnish office equipment for use in the office of that Member, Resident Commissioner, officer, or committee. Office equipment so furnished is limited to equipment of those types and categories which the Committee on House Oversight shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registration and ownership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Office equipment furnished under this section shall be registered in the office of the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives and shall remain the property of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The cost of office equipment furnished under this section shall be paid from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee on House Oversight shall prescribe such regulations as it considers necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 91–139, § 1</ref>, <date date="1969-12-05">Dec. 5, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(59)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5537.</num>
<heading> Net Expenses of Equipment Revolving Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund for the House of Representatives to be known as the Net Expenses of Equipment Revolving Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Revolving Fund”), consisting of funds deposited by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives from amounts provided by offices of the House of Representatives to purchase, lease, obtain, and maintain the equipment located in such offices, and amounts provided by Members of the House of Representatives (including Delegates and Resident Commissioners to the Congress) to purchase, lease, obtain, and maintain furniture for their district offices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts in the Revolving Fund shall be used by the Chief Administrative Officer without fiscal year limitation to purchase, lease, obtain, and maintain equipment for offices of the House of Representatives and furniture for the district offices of Members of the House of Representatives (including Delegates and Resident Commissioners to the Congress).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Revolving Fund shall be treated as a category of allowances and expenses for purposes of <ref>section 5507(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability to fiscal years</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2003 and each succeeding fiscal year, except that for purposes of making deposits into the Revolving Fund under subsection (a), the Chief Administrative Officer may deposit amounts provided by offices of the House of Representatives during fiscal year 2002 or any succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability to telecommunications equipment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply with respect to any telecommunications equipment which is subject to coverage under section 5538 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002114">1</ref> of this title (relating to the Net Expenses of Telecommunications Revolving Fund).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 102(e)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3174</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5538.</num>
<heading> Net Expenses of Telecommunications Revolving Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund for the House of Representatives to be known as the Net Expenses of Telecommunications Revolving Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Revolving Fund”), consisting of funds deposited by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives from amounts provided by legislative branch offices to purchase, lease, obtain, and maintain the data and voice telecommunications services and equipment located in such offices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts in Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts in the Revolving Fund shall be used by the Chief Administrative Officer without fiscal year limitation to purchase, lease, obtain, and maintain the data and voice telecommunications services and equipment of legislative branch offices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Revolving Fund shall be treated as a category of allowances and expenses for purposes of <ref>section 5507(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold">, (e) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2005 and each succeeding fiscal year, except that for purposes of making deposits into the Revolving Fund under subsection (a), the Chief Administrative Officer may deposit amounts provided by legislative branch offices during fiscal year 2004 or any succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3174</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5539.</num>
<heading> Commissions and charges for public telephone or telecommunications services; deposit of receipts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Chief Administrative Officer to receive commissions for providing public telephone service in House occupied areas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective <date date="1988-10-01">October 1, 1988</date>, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives is authorized to receive commissions for providing public telephone service in space occupied by the United States House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of receipts; availability for expenditure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Receipts from the commissions and charges set forth in subsection (a) of this section shall be deposited in the United States Treasury for credit to the appropriation for “Salaries and Expenses of the United States House of Representatives”, and shall be available for expenditure upon the approval of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–458, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(64)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1739</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 102(d)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3174</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5540.</num>
<heading> Disposal of used or surplus furniture and equipment by Chief Administrative Officer of House; procedure; deposit of receipts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives may dispose of used equipment of the House of Representatives, by trade-in or sale, directly or through the General Services Administration. Any direct disposal under the preceding sentence shall be in accordance with normal business practice and shall be at fair market value. Receipts from disposals under the first sentence of this section (together with receipts from sale of transcripts, waste paper and other items provided by law, and receipts for missing or damaged equipment) shall be deposited in the Treasury for credit to the appropriate account of the House of Representatives, and shall be available for expenditure in accordance with applicable law. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of receipts from the sale or disposal of any audio or video transcripts prepared by the House Recording Studio, the “appropriate account of the House of Representatives” shall be the account of the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If disposal in accordance with paragraph (1) is not feasible because of age, location, condition, or any other relevant factor, the Chief Administrative Officer may donate the equipment to the government of a State, to a local government, or to an organization that is described in <ref>section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref> and exempt from tax under <ref>section 501(a) of title 26</ref>. Except as provided in paragraph (3), a donation under this paragraph—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be at no cost to the Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may be made only if the used equipment has no recoverable value because disposal in accordance with paragraph (1), under the most favorable terms available to the Government, would result in a loss to the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of computer-related equipment, during fiscal year 1998 the Chief Administrative Officer may donate directly the equipment to a public elementary or secondary school of the District of Columbia without regard to whether the donation meets the requirements of the second sentence of paragraph (2), except that the total number of workstations donated as a result of this paragraph may not exceed 1,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> In this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the term “computer-related equipment” includes desktops, laptops, printers, file servers, and peripherals which are appropriate for use in public school education;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the terms “public elementary school” and “public secondary school” have the meaning given the terms elementary school and secondary school in <ref>section 7801 of title 20</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the term “workstation” includes desktops and peripherals, file servers and peripherals, laptops and peripherals, printers and peripherals, and workstations and peripherals.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Committee on House Oversight shall have authority to issue regulations to carry out this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives shall have authority to prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and a territory or possession of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “used equipment” means such used or surplus equipment (including furniture and motor vehicles) as the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives may prescribe by regulation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(j)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1783–287</ref>, and <ref>Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(j)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3341–287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–71, title I</ref>, <date date="1987-07-11">July 11, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 425</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–163, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1049</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(63)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1739</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1184</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 114(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1076(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2091</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(xx)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5541.</num>
<heading> Fees for internal delivery in House of Representatives of nonpostage mail from outside sources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective with respect to fiscal years beginning with fiscal year 1995, in the case of mail from outside sources presented to the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives (other than mail through the Postal Service and mail with postage otherwise paid) for internal delivery in the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer is authorized to collect fees equal to the applicable postage. Amounts received by the Chief Administrative Officer as fees under the preceding sentence shall be deposited in the Treasury for credit to the account of the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–53, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2225</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5542.</num>
<heading> Regulations for safe handling of mail matter</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the approval of the Committee on House Administration, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives shall implement regulations under which the Chief Administrative Officer shall be authorized to handle any mail matter delivered by the United States Postal Service or any other carrier to the House of Representatives, or to any other entity with whom the Chief Administrative Officer has entered into an agreement to receive mail matter delivered to the entity, in such manner as the Chief Administrative Officer deems necessary to ensure the safety of any individuals who may come into contact with, or otherwise be exposed to, such mail matter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil or criminal liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No action taken under the regulations implemented pursuant to this section may serve as a basis for civil or criminal liability of any individual or entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “handle” includes but is not limited to collecting, isolating, testing, opening, disposing, and destroying.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2004 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3177</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5543.</num>
<heading> Rebates under Government Travel Charge Card Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective with respect to fiscal years beginning with fiscal year 1995, amounts received by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives from the Administrator of General Services for rebates under the Government Travel Charge Card Program shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–53, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 520</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5544.</num>
<heading> Deposit of House Information Resources reimbursements for services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective with respect to fiscal year 2003 and each succeeding fiscal year, any amount received by House Information Resources from any office of the House of Representatives as reimbursement for services provided shall be deposited in the Treasury for credit to the account of the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5545.</num>
<heading> House Services Revolving Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of House Services Revolving Fund</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund for the House of Representatives to be known as the “House Services Revolving Fund” (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Revolving Fund”), consisting of funds deposited by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives from all amounts received by the House of Representatives with respect to the following activities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The operation of the House Barber Shop.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The operation of the House Beauty Shop.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The operation of the House Restaurant System (including vending operations).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The provision of mail services to entities which are not part of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The payment of fees for the use of the exercise facility described in section 103(a).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002115">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The collection of promotional rebates and incentives on credit card purchases, balances, and payments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The collection of a service fee from vendors of the Master Web Services Agreement or the Technology Services Contract for failure to abide by and maintain House of Representatives security policies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The operation of the House Dry Cleaning and Laundry Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Other activities related to the operation of services offered by the House of Representatives, as approved by the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of amounts in Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts in the Revolving Funds <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002116">2</ref> shall be used for any purpose designated by the Chief Administrative Officer, including purposes relating to energy and water conservation and environmental activities carried out in buildings, facilities, and grounds under the Chief Administrative Officer’s jurisdiction, upon notification provided by the Chief Administrative Officer to the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Revolving Fund shall be treated as a category of allowances and expenses for purposes of <ref>section 5507(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination and transfer of existing funds and accounts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each fund and account specified in paragraph (2) is hereby terminated, and the balance of each such fund and account is hereby transferred to the Revolving Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funds and accounts specified</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The funds and accounts referred to in paragraph (1) are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The revolving fund for the House Barber Shop, established by the paragraph under the heading “HOUSE BARBER SHOPS REVOLVING FUND” in the matter relating to the House of Representatives in chapter III of title I of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1975 (<ref>Public Law 93–554</ref>; <ref>88 Stat. 1776</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The revolving funds for the House Beauty Shop, established by the matter under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">house beauty shop</inline>” in the matter relating to administrative provisions for the House of Representatives in the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1970 (<ref>Public Law 91–145</ref>; <ref>83 Stat. 347</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The special deposit account established for the House of Representatives Restaurant by section 208 of the First Supplemental Civil Functions Appropriation Act, 1941, or any successor fund or account established for the receipt of revenues of the House Restaurant System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect <date date="2004-10-01">October 1, 2004</date>, and shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2005 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–13, div. A, title III, § 3401(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. G, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 817</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 118(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. I, title I, § 115(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5546.</num>
<heading> Support services for House during emergency; memorandum of understanding with an executive agency</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subject to subsection (b), the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives and the head of an executive agency (as defined in <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref>) may enter into a memorandum of understanding under which the agency may provide facilities, equipment, supplies, personnel, and other support services for the use of the House of Representatives during an emergency situation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Chief Administrative Officer and the head of the agency may take any action necessary to carry out the terms of the memorandum of understanding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of Speaker required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives may not enter into a memorandum of understanding described in subsection (a)(1) without the approval of the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2002 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–117, div. B, § 904</ref>, <date date="2002-01-10">Jan. 10, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5547.</num>
<heading> Emergency expenditures for meals, refreshments, and other support and maintenance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> At any time on or after <date date="2003-02-20">February 20, 2003</date>, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives may incur obligations and make expenditures out of available appropriations for meals, refreshments, and other support and maintenance for Members, officers, and employees of the House of Representatives when, in the judgment of the Chief Administrative Officer, such obligations and expenditures are necessary to respond to emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section may be construed to affect any other authority of the Chief Administrative Officer to incur obligations and make expenditures for the items and services described in subsection (a) for Members, officers, and employees of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5548.</num>
<heading> Payments to ensure continuing availability of goods and services during the coronavirus emergency</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization to make payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to subsection (b), during an emergency situation, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives may make payments under contracts with vendors providing goods and services to the House in amounts and under terms and conditions other than those provided under the contract in order to ensure that those goods and services remain available to the House throughout the duration of the emergency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief Administrative Officer may not make payments under the authority of subsection (a) without the approval of the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The authority of the Chief Administrative Officer to make payments under the authority of subsection (a) is subject to the availability of appropriations to make such payments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2020 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–136, div. B, title IX, § 19003</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 578</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5549.</num>
<heading> House Intern Resource Office</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; Coordinator</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; Coordinator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established in the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives the House Intern Resource Office (hereinafter referred to as the “Office”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office shall be headed by the House Intern Resource Coordinator (hereinafter referred to as the “Coordinator”), who shall be employed by the Chief Administrative Officer in consultation with the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on House Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In consultation with the Office of Diversity and Inclusion and such other offices as the Coordinator considers appropriate, the Office shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide support services, such as accommodations, training, and professional development, to interns of offices of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> serve as a center for resources and best practices for the recruitment, hiring, training, and use of interns by offices of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> gather demographic and other data about interns of offices of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Addressing inequities in access to internships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out its duties, the Office shall consider inequities in access to internships in offices of the House of Representatives, and shall consider the viability of establishing an intern stipend program for interns from underrepresented backgrounds, including those who attend Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs), Tribal Colleges and Universities, Hispanic-Serving Institutions (HSIs), and other Minority Serving Institutions described in <ref>section 1067q(a) of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2023 and each succeeding fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2023 and each succeeding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. I, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4922</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>CLERK</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5561.</num>
<heading> Reporters for House of Representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person shall be employed as a reporter for the House of Representatives without the approval of the Speaker.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 54.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5562.</num>
<heading> Preservation of reports, statements, or documents filed with Clerk of House</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> If the Clerk of the House of Representatives is required under any law, rule, or regulation to make available for public inspection a report, statement, or other document filed with the Office of the Clerk, the Clerk shall preserve the report, statement, or document—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for a period of 6 years from the date on which the document is filed; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the law, rule, or regulation so provides, the period required under such law, rule, or regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) shall apply with respect to reports, statements, and documents filed before, on, or after <date date="2004-12-08">December 8, 2004</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5563.</num>
<heading> Index to House daily calendar</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The index to the daily calendar of business of the House of Representatives shall be printed only on Monday of each week.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 1, 1921, ch. 89, § 1</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 1181</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>GENERAL COUNSEL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5571.</num>
<heading> Office of General Counsel of House; administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with admission requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The General Counsel of the House of Representatives and any other counsel in the Office of the General Counsel of the House of Representatives, including any counsel specially retained by the Office of General Counsel, shall be entitled, for the purpose of performing the counsel’s functions, to enter an appearance in any proceeding before any court of the United States or of any State or political subdivision thereof without compliance with any requirements for admission to practice before such court, except that the authorization conferred by this subsection shall not apply with respect to the admission of any such person to practice before the United States Supreme Court.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification by Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall notify the General Counsel of the House of Representatives as required by <ref>section 530D of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General Counsel definition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “General Counsel of the House of Representatives” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the head of the Office of General Counsel established and operating under clause 8 of rule II of the Rules of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the head of any successor office to the Office of General Counsel which is established after <date date="1999-09-29">September 29, 1999</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other person authorized and directed in accordance with the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide legal assistance and representation to the House in connection with the matters described in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall become effective beginning with <date date="1999-09-29">September 29, 1999</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–57, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 414</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 202(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 110(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>INTERPARLIAMENTARY AFFAIRS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5581.</num>
<heading> Participation by House in interparliamentary institutions; reception of members of foreign legislative bodies and foreign officials; meetings with Government officials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> It is the purpose of this section to enable the House of Representatives more properly to discharge and coordinate its activities and responsibilities in connection with participation in various interparliamentary institutions, to facilitate the interchange and reception in the United States of members of foreign legislative bodies and permanent officials of foreign governments, and to enable the House of Representatives to host meetings with senior United States Government officials and other dignitaries in order to discuss matters relevant to United States relations with other countries.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For payment of expenses incurred in carrying out subsection (a) of this section, there shall be paid out of the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives, until otherwise provided by law, such sums as may be necessary but not to exceed $40,000 in any calendar year. Such payments shall be made on vouchers signed by the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Affairs and approved by the Committee on House Oversight.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–391, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4581</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(72)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 103(e)</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1017</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5582.</num>
<heading> Office of Interparliamentary Affairs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established in the House of Representatives an office to be known as the “Office of Interparliamentary Affairs” (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Office”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The duties of the Office are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To receive and respond to inquiries from foreign parliamentarians or foreign legislative bodies regarding official visits to the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To coordinate official visits to the House of Representatives by parliamentarians, officers, or employees of foreign legislative bodies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To coordinate with the Sergeant at Arms, the Clerk, and other officers of the House of Representatives in providing services for delegations of Members on official visits to foreign nations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> To carry out other activities to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> discharge and coordinate the activities and responsibilities of the House of Representatives in connection with participation in various interparliamentary exchanges and organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> facilitate the interchange and reception in the United States of members of foreign legislative bodies and permanent officials of foreign governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> enable the House to host meetings with senior government officials and other dignitaries in order to discuss matters relevant to United States relations with other nations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Office shall be headed by the Director of Interparliamentary Affairs of the House of Representatives (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Director”), who shall be appointed by the Speaker without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the position. Any person so appointed shall serve at the pleasure of the Speaker.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall be paid at an annual rate determined by the Speaker.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other staff</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With the approval of the Speaker, or in accordance with policies and procedures approved by the Speaker, the Director may appoint and set the pay of such other employees as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the Office. Any such appointment shall be made without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the position. Any person so appointed may be removed by the Director with the approval of the Speaker, or in accordance with policies and procedures approved by the Speaker.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any employee of the Office appointed under this subsection shall be paid at an annual rate determined by the Director with the approval of the Speaker or in accordance with policies approved by the Speaker.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2003 and each succeeding fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect on <date date="2003-09-30">September 30, 2003</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1016</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>MEDIA SERVICES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5591.</num>
<heading> Media support services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support services for presidential nominating conventions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The responsibilities of positions under the House Press Gallery, the House Periodical Press Gallery, and the House Radio and Television Correspondents’ Gallery shall include providing media support services with respect to the presidential nominating conventions of the national committees of political parties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements with national committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Standing Committee of Correspondents may enter into agreements with national committees of political parties under which the committees and persons authorized by the committees may reimburse employees for necessary expenses incurred in carrying out the responsibilities described in subsection (a) and employees may accept such reimbursement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The terms and conditions under which employees exercise responsibilities under subsection (a), and the terms and conditions of any agreement entered into under subsection (b), shall be subject to the approval of the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the terms “national committee” and “political party” have the meaning given such terms in <ref>section 30101 of title 52</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–289, div. B, title II, § 20702(b)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–5, § 2</ref>, <date date="2007-02-15">Feb. 15, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 38</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VIII—</num>
<heading>SERGEANT AT ARMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5601.</num>
<heading> Sergeant at Arms of House; additional compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives shall receive, directly or indirectly, no fees or other compensation or emolument whatever for performing the duties of the office, or in connection therewith, otherwise than the salary prescribed by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 20, 1874, ch. 328</ref>, <ref>18 Stat. 87</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5602.</num>
<heading> Tenure of office of Sergeant at Arms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person duly elected and qualified as Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives shall continue in said office until his successor is chosen and qualified, subject however, to removal by the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 1, 1890, ch. 1256, § 6</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 646</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5603.</num>
<heading> Symbol of office of Sergeant at Arms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The symbol of his office shall be the mace, which shall be borne by him while enforcing order on the floor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 1, 1890, ch. 1256, § 2</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5604.</num>
<heading> Duties of Sergeant at Arms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives to attend the House during its sittings, to maintain order under the direction of the Speaker, and, pending the election of a Speaker or Speaker pro tempore, under the direction of the Clerk, execute the commands of the House and all processes issued by authority thereof, directed to him by the Speaker.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Oct. 1, 1890, ch. 1256, § 1</ref>, <ref>26 Stat. 645</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(25)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1733</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5605.</num>
<heading> Law enforcement authority of Sergeant at Arms</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives shall have the same law enforcement authority, including the authority to carry firearms, as a member of the Capitol Police. The law enforcement authority under the preceding sentence shall be subject to the requirement that the Sergeant at Arms have the qualifications specified in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The qualifications referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A minimum of five years of experience as a law enforcement officer before beginning service as the Sergeant at Arms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Current certification in the use of firearms by the appropriate Federal law enforcement entity or an equivalent non-Federal entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any other firearms qualification required for members of the Capitol Police.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives shall have authority to prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–53, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5606.</num>
<heading> Arrangements for attendance at funeral of deceased House Members; payment of funeral expenses and expenses of attending funeral rites</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Sergeant at Arms of the House is authorized and directed on and after <date date="1962-10-02">October 2, 1962</date>, to make such arrangements as may be necessary for any committee of Members of the Senate and House of Representatives duly appointed to attend the funeral of a deceased Member of the House. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, there shall be paid out of the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives, under such rules and regulations as the Committee on House Oversight may prescribe, such sums as may be necessary to defray the funeral expenses of the deceased Member and to defray the expenses of such committee, the Sergeant at Arms of the House or a representative of his office, and the widow (or widower) or minor children, or both, of the deceased Member incurred in attending the funeral rites and burial of such Member.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–730, § 101</ref>, <date date="1962-10-02">Oct. 2, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 686</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(69)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1740</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IX—</num>
<heading>CORRECTIONS CALENDAR OFFICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5621.</num>
<heading> Corrections Calendar Office</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is established in the House of Representatives an office to be known as the Corrections Calendar Office, which shall have the responsibility of assisting the Speaker in the management of the Corrections Calendar under the Rules of the House of Representatives. The Office shall have not more than five employees—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who shall be appointed by the Speaker, in consultation with the minority leader; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whose annual rate of pay shall be established by the Speaker, but may not exceed 75 percent of the maximum annual rate under the general limitation specified by the order of the Speaker in effect under <ref>section 4532 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5622.</num>
<heading> Lump sum allowance for Corrections Calendar Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be a lump sum allowance of $300,000 per fiscal year for the salaries and expenses of the Corrections Calendar Office, established by <ref>section 5621 of this title</ref>. Such amount shall be allocated between the majority party and the minority party as determined by the Speaker, in consultation with the minority leader.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5623.</num>
<heading> Effective date</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The allowance under <ref>section 5622 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be available beginning with the month of May 1997;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> through the end of September 1997, shall be paid from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives on a pro rata basis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> beginning with fiscal year 1998, shall be paid as provided in appropriations Acts.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–55, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5624.</num>
<heading> Transfer of positions in Corrections Calendar Office</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Effective <date date="2003-10-01">October 1, 2003</date>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 3 of the positions in the Corrections Calendar Office, and the functions associated with such positions, shall be transferred to the Office of the Speaker; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 2 of the positions in the Corrections Calendar Office, and the functions associated with such positions, shall be transferred to the Office of the Minority Leader.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of any individual who is an incumbent of a position transferred under paragraph (1) at the time of the transfer, the total number of days of annual leave and the total number of days of sick leave which were provided by the Corrections Calendar Office to the individual and which remain unused as of the date of the transfer shall remain available for the individual to use after the transfer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Effective with respect to fiscal year 2004 and each succeeding fiscal year, the lump sum allowance for salaries and expenses of the Corrections Calendar Office provided under House Resolution 130, One Hundred Fifth Congress, agreed to <date date="1997-04-24">April 24, 1997</date>, as enacted into permanent law by section 101 of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1998 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 74d–1</ref> et seq.) [now <ref>2 U.S.C. 5622</ref> and 5623], is transferred as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 63.5 percent of such allowance shall be transferred to the Office of the Speaker.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 36.5 percent of such allowance shall be transferred to the Office of the Minority Leader.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>