<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 507—</num>
<heading>LAW ENFORCEMENT SUICIDE DATA COLLECTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50701.</num>
<heading> Information on suicide in law enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2020-06-16">June 16, 2020</date>, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall establish, for the purpose of preventing future law enforcement suicides and promoting understanding of suicide in law enforcement, the Law Enforcement Officers Suicide Data Collection Program, under which law enforcement agencies may submit to the Director information on suicides and attempted suicides within such law enforcement agencies, including information on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the circumstances and events that occurred before each suicide or attempted suicide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the general location of each suicide or attempted suicide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the demographic information of each law enforcement officer who commits or attempts suicide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the occupational category, including criminal investigator, corrections officer, line of duty officer, 911 dispatch operator, of each law enforcement officer who commits or attempts suicide; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the method used in each suicide or attempted suicide.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Bureau of Investigation shall work with the Confidentiality and Data Access Committee of the Federal Committee on Statistical Methodology to develop publication policies to manage the risk of identity disclosure based upon the best practices identified by other Federal statistical programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2020-06-16">June 16, 2020</date>, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall submit to Congress and publish on the website of the Federal Bureau of Investigation a report containing the information submitted to the Director pursuant to subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report described under subsection (c) may not include any personally identifiable information of a law enforcement officer who commits or attempts suicide.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “law enforcement agency” means a Federal, State, Tribal, or local agency engaged in the prevention, detection, or investigation, prosecution, or adjudication of any violation of the criminal laws of the United States, a State, Tribal, or a political subdivision of a State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “law enforcement officer” means any current or former officer (including a correctional officer), agent, or employee of the United States, a State, Indian Tribe, or a political subdivision of a State authorized by law to engage in or supervise the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of any violation of the criminal laws of the United States, a State, Indian Tribe, or a political subdivision of a State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–143, § 2</ref>, <date date="2020-06-16">June 16, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 644</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>