<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 407—</num>
<heading>DNA IDENTIFICATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>COLLECTION AND ANALYSIS OF SAMPLES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40701.</num>
<heading> The Debbie Smith DNA Backlog Grant Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General may make grants to eligible States or units of local government for use by the State or unit of local government for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To carry out, for inclusion in the Combined DNA Index System of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, DNA analyses of samples collected under applicable legal authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To carry out, for inclusion in such Combined DNA Index System, DNA analyses of samples from crime scenes, prioritizing, to the extent practicable consistent with public safety considerations <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002220">1</ref> samples from rape kits, samples from other sexual assault evidence, and samples taken in cases without an identified suspect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To increase the capacity of laboratories owned by the State or by units of local government to carry out DNA analyses of samples specified in paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To collect DNA samples specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To ensure that DNA testing and analysis of samples from crimes, including sexual assault and other serious violent crimes, are carried out in a timely manner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title X, § 1006</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 134</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> To conduct an audit consistent with subsection (n) of the samples of sexual assault evidence that are in the possession of the State or unit of local government and are awaiting testing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> To ensure that the collection and processing of DNA evidence by law enforcement agencies from crimes, in particular, sexual assault and other violent crimes against persons, is carried out in an appropriate and timely manner and in accordance with the protocols and practices developed under subsection (<i>o</i>)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> To increase the capacity of State and local prosecution offices to address the backlog of violent crime cases in which suspects have been identified through DNA evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For a State or unit of local government to be eligible to receive a grant under this section, the chief executive officer of the State or unit of local government shall submit to the Attorney General an application in such form and containing such information as the Attorney General may require. The application shall, as required by the Attorney General—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide assurances that the State or unit of local government has implemented, or will implement not later than 120 days after the date of such application, a comprehensive plan for the expeditious DNA analysis of samples in accordance with this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> include a certification that each DNA analysis carried out under the plan shall be maintained pursuant to the privacy requirements described in <ref>section 12592(b)(3) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> include a certification that the State or unit of local government has determined, by statute, rule, or regulation, those offenses under State law that shall be treated for purposes of this section as qualifying State offenses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> specify the allocation that the State or unit of local government shall make, in using grant amounts to carry out DNA analyses of samples, as between samples specified in subsection (a)(1) and samples specified in subsection (a)(2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> specify that portion of grant amounts that the State or unit of local government shall use for the purpose specified in subsection (a)(3);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> if submitted by a unit of local government, certify that the unit of local government has taken, or is taking, all necessary steps to ensure that it is eligible to include, directly or through a State law enforcement agency, all analyses of samples for which it has requested funding in the Combined DNA Index System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> specify that portion of grant amounts that the State or unit of local government shall use for the purpose specified in subsection (a)(4); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> provide assurances that the DNA section of the laboratory to be used to conduct DNA analyses has a written policy that prioritizes the analysis of, to the extent practicable consistent with public safety considerations, samples from homicides and sexual assaults.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Formula for distribution of grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Attorney General shall distribute grant amounts, and establish appropriate grant conditions under this section, in conformity with a formula or formulas that are designed to effectuate a distribution of funds among eligible States and units of local government that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> maximizes the effective utilization of DNA technology to solve crimes and protect public safety; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> allocates grants among eligible entities fairly and efficiently to address jurisdictions in which significant backlogs exist, by considering—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of offender and casework samples awaiting DNA analysis in a jurisdiction;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the population in the jurisdiction; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the number of part 1 violent crimes in the jurisdiction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall allocate to each State not less than 0.50 percent of the total amount appropriated in a fiscal year for grants under this section, except that the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands shall each be allocated 0.125 percent of the total appropriation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Grant amounts distributed under paragraph (1) shall be awarded to conduct DNA analyses of samples from casework or from victims of crime under subsection (a)(2) in accordance with the following limitations:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2009, not less than 40 percent of the grant amounts shall be awarded for purposes under subsection (a)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For each of the fiscal years 2019 through 2024, not less than 40 percent of the grant amounts shall be awarded for purposes under subsection (a)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> For each of fiscal years 2019 through 2024, not less than 75 percent of the total grant amounts shall be awarded for a combination of purposes under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of grant awards for audits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each of fiscal years 2014 through 2029, not less than 5 percent, but not more than 7 percent, of the grant amounts distributed under paragraph (1) shall, if sufficient applications to justify such amounts are received by the Attorney General, be awarded for purposes described in subsection (a)(7), provided that none of the funds required to be distributed under this paragraph shall decrease or otherwise limit the availability of funds required to be awarded to States or units of local government under paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of grant awards for prosecutors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each fiscal year, not less than 5 percent, but not more than 7 percent, of the grant amounts distributed under paragraph (1) shall, if sufficient applications to justify such amounts are received by the Attorney General, be awarded for purposes described in subsection (a)(9), provided that none of the funds required to be distributed under this paragraph shall decrease or otherwise limit the availability of funds required to be awarded to States or units of local government under paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Analysis of samples</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A plan pursuant to subsection (b)(1) shall require that, except as provided in paragraph (3), each DNA analysis be carried out in a laboratory that satisfies quality assurance standards and is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> operated by the State or a unit of local government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operated by a private entity pursuant to a contract with the State or a unit of local government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quality assurance standards</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall maintain and make available to States and units of local government a description of quality assurance protocols and practices that the Director considers adequate to assure the quality of a forensic laboratory.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, a laboratory satisfies quality assurance standards if the laboratory satisfies the quality control requirements described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of <ref>section 12592(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of vouchers or contracts for certain purposes</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A grant for the purposes specified in paragraph (1), (2), or (5) of subsection (a) may be made in the form of a voucher or contract for laboratory services, even if the laboratory makes a reasonable profit for the services.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A voucher or contract under subparagraph (A) may be redeemed at a laboratory operated on a nonprofit or for-profit basis, by a private entity that satisfies quality assurance standards and has been approved by the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Attorney General may use amounts authorized under subsection (j) to make payments to a laboratory described under subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on use of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonsupplanting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds made available pursuant to this section shall not be used to supplant State or local government funds, but shall be used to increase the amount of funds that would, in the absence of Federal funds, be made available from State or local government sources for the purposes of this Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A State or unit of local government may not use more than 3 percent of the funds it receives from this section for administrative expenses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to the Attorney General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each State or unit of local government which receives a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General, for each year in which funds from a grant received under this section is expended, a report at such time and in such manner as the Attorney General may reasonably require, which contains—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a summary of the activities carried out under the grant and an assessment of whether such activities are meeting the needs identified in the application; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such other information as the Attorney General may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year for which grants are made under this section, the Attorney General shall submit to the Congress a report that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the aggregate amount of grants made under this section to each State or unit of local government for such fiscal year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a summary of the information provided by States or units of local government receiving grants under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of the priorities and plan for awarding grants among eligible States and units of local government, and how such plan will ensure the effective use of DNA technology to solve crimes and protect public safety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditure records</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State or unit of local government which receives a grant under this section shall keep records as the Attorney General may require to facilitate an effective audit of the receipt and use of grant funds received under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State or unit of local government which receives a grant under this section shall make available, for the purpose of audit and examination, such records as are related to the receipt or use of any such grant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General for grants under subsection (a) $151,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2029.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds for accreditation and audits</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General may distribute not more than 1 percent of the grant amounts under subsection (j)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to States or units of local government to defray the costs incurred by laboratories operated by each such State or unit of local government in preparing for accreditation or reaccreditation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in the form of additional grants to States, units of local government, or nonprofit professional organizations of persons actively involved in forensic science and nationally recognized within the forensic science community—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to defray the costs of external audits of laboratories operated by such State or unit of local government, which participates in the National DNA Index System, to determine whether the laboratory is in compliance with quality assurance standards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to assess compliance with any plans submitted to the National Institute of Justice, which detail the use of funds received by States or units of local government under this Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to support future capacity building efforts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the form of additional grants to nonprofit professional associations actively involved in forensic science and nationally recognized within the forensic science community to defray the costs of training persons who conduct external audits of laboratories operated by States and units of local government and which participate in the National DNA Index System.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds for other forensic sciences</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General may award a grant under this section to a State or unit of local government to alleviate a backlog of cases with respect to a forensic science other than DNA analysis if the State or unit of local government—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> certifies to the Attorney General that in such State or unit—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all of the purposes set forth in subsection (a) have been met;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a significant backlog of casework is not waiting for DNA analysis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> there is no need for significant laboratory equipment, supplies, or additional personnel for timely DNA processing of casework or offender samples; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> demonstrates to the Attorney General that such State or unit requires assistance in alleviating a backlog of cases involving a forensic science other than DNA analysis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> External audits and remedial efforts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the event that a laboratory operated by a State or unit of local government which has received funds under this Act has undergone an external audit conducted to determine whether the laboratory is in compliance with standards established by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and, as a result of such audit, identifies measures to remedy deficiencies with respect to the compliance by the laboratory with such standards, the State or unit of local government shall implement any such remediation as soon as practicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title X, § 1006</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 134</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(o)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of protocols, technical assistance, and definitions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protocols and practices</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 18 months after <date date="2013-03-07">March 7, 2013</date>, the Director, in consultation with Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and government laboratories, shall develop and publish a description of protocols and practices the Director considers appropriate for the accurate, timely, and effective collection and processing of DNA evidence, including protocols and practices specific to sexual assault cases, which shall address appropriate steps in the investigation of cases that might involve DNA evidence, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> how to determine—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> which evidence is to be collected by law enforcement personnel and forwarded for testing;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the preferred order in which evidence from the same case is to be tested; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> what information to take into account when establishing the order in which evidence from different cases is to be tested;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the establishment of a reasonable period of time in which evidence is to be forwarded by emergency response providers, law enforcement personnel, and prosecutors to a laboratory for testing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the establishment of reasonable periods of time in which each stage of analytical laboratory testing is to be completed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> systems to encourage communication within a State or unit of local government among emergency response providers, law enforcement personnel, prosecutors, courts, defense counsel, crime laboratory personnel, and crime victims regarding the status of crime scene evidence to be tested; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> standards for conducting the audit of the backlog for DNA case work in sexual assault cases required under subsection (n).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance and training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall make available technical assistance and training to support States and units of local government in adopting and implementing the protocols and practices developed under paragraph (1) on and after the date on which the protocols and practices are published.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the terms “awaiting testing” and “possession” have the meanings given those terms in subsection (n).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–546, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-12-19">Dec. 19, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2726</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title II</ref>, §§ 202, 206, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2266</ref>, 2272; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title X, § 1003</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3085</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–360, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-10-08">Oct. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4008</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–253, § 6</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2409</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title X</ref>, §§ 1002, 1004, 1006, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 127</ref>, 131, 134; <ref>Pub. L. 113–182, § 2</ref>, <date date="2014-09-29">Sept. 29, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–107, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-01-08">Jan. 8, 2018</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2266</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–257, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-09">Oct. 9, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3660</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–104, § 2</ref>, <date date="2019-12-30">Dec. 30, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–72</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <date date="2024-07-30">July 30, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1503</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40702.</num>
<heading> Collection and use of DNA identification information from certain Federal offenders</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection of DNA samples</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> From individuals in custody</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may, as prescribed by the Attorney General in regulation, collect DNA samples from individuals who are arrested, facing charges, or convicted or from non-United States persons who are detained under the authority of the United States. The Attorney General may delegate this function within the Department of Justice as provided in <ref>section 510 of title 28</ref> and may also authorize and direct any other agency of the United States that arrests or detains individuals or supervises individuals facing charges to carry out any function and exercise any power of the Attorney General under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall collect a DNA sample from each individual in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons who is, or has been, convicted of a qualifying Federal offense (as determined under subsection (d)) or a qualifying military offense, as determined under <ref>section 1565 of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> From individuals on release, parole, or probation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The probation office responsible for the supervision under Federal law of an individual on probation, parole, or supervised release shall collect a DNA sample from each such individual who is, or has been, convicted of a qualifying Federal offense (as determined under subsection (d)) or a qualifying military offense, as determined under <ref>section 1565 of title 10</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individuals already in CODIS</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each individual described in paragraph (1) or (2), if the Combined DNA Index System (in this section referred to as “CODIS”) of the Federal Bureau of Investigation contains a DNA analysis with respect to that individual, or if a DNA sample has been collected from that individual under <ref>section 1565 of title 10</ref>, the Attorney General, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, or the probation office responsible (as applicable) may (but need not) collect a DNA sample from that individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection procedures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Attorney General, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, or the probation office responsible (as applicable) may use or authorize the use of such means as are reasonably necessary to detain, restrain, and collect a DNA sample from an individual who refuses to cooperate in the collection of the sample.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Attorney General, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, or the probation office, as appropriate, may enter into agreements with units of State or local government or with private entities to provide for the collection of the samples described in paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal penalty</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An individual from whom the collection of a DNA sample is authorized under this subsection who fails to cooperate in the collection of that sample shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> guilty of a class A misdemeanor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> punished in accordance with title 18.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Analysis and use of samples</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, or the probation office responsible (as applicable) shall furnish each DNA sample collected under subsection (a) to the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, who shall carry out a DNA analysis on each such DNA sample and include the results in CODIS. The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation may waive the requirements under this subsection if DNA samples are analyzed by means of Rapid DNA instruments and the results are included in CODIS.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “DNA sample” means a tissue, fluid, or other bodily sample of an individual on which a DNA analysis can be carried out.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “DNA analysis” means analysis of the deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) identification information in a bodily sample.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Rapid DNA instruments” means instrumentation that carries out a fully automated process to derive a DNA analysis from a DNA sample.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifying Federal offenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The offenses that shall be treated for purposes of this section as qualifying Federal offenses are the following offenses, as determined by the Attorney General:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any felony.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any offense under chapter 109A of title 18.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any crime of violence (as that term is defined in <ref>section 16 of title 18</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any attempt or conspiracy to commit any of the offenses in paragraphs (1) through (3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), this section shall be carried out under regulations prescribed by the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Probation officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall make available model procedures for the activities of probation officers in carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commencement of collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Collection of DNA samples under subsection (a) shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, commence not later than the date that is 180 days after <date date="2000-12-19">December 19, 2000</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–546, § 3</ref>, <date date="2000-12-19">Dec. 19, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title II, § 203(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title X, § 1004(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3085</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–248, title I, § 155</ref>, <date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–50, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-18">Aug. 18, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1001</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40703.</num>
<heading> Collection and use of DNA identification information from certain District of Columbia offenders</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection of DNA samples</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> From individuals in custody</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall collect a DNA sample from each individual in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons who is, or has been, convicted of a qualifying District of Columbia offense (as determined under subsection (d)).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> From individuals on release, parole, or probation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia shall collect a DNA sample from each individual under the supervision of the Agency who is on supervised release, parole, or probation who is, or has been, convicted of a qualifying District of Columbia offense (as determined under subsection (d)).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individuals already in CODIS</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each individual described in paragraph (1) or (2), if the Combined DNA Index System (in this section referred to as “CODIS”) of the Federal Bureau of Investigation contains a DNA analysis with respect to that individual, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons or Agency (as applicable) may (but need not) collect a DNA sample from that individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection procedures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Director of the Bureau of Prisons or Agency (as applicable) may use or authorize the use of such means as are reasonably necessary to detain, restrain, and collect a DNA sample from an individual who refuses to cooperate in the collection of the sample.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Director of the Bureau of Prisons or Agency, as appropriate, may enter into agreements with units of State or local government or with private entities to provide for the collection of the samples described in paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal penalty</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An individual from whom the collection of a DNA sample is authorized under this subsection who fails to cooperate in the collection of that sample shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> guilty of a class A misdemeanor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> punished in accordance with title 18.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Analysis and use of samples</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Bureau of Prisons or Agency (as applicable) shall furnish each DNA sample collected under subsection (a) to the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, who shall carry out a DNA analysis on each such DNA sample and include the results in CODIS. The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation may waive the requirements under this subsection if DNA samples are analyzed by means of Rapid DNA instruments and the results are included in CODIS.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “DNA sample” means a tissue, fluid, or other bodily sample of an individual on which a DNA analysis can be carried out.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “DNA analysis” means analysis of the deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) identification information in a bodily sample.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Rapid DNA instruments” means instrumentation that carries out a fully automated process to derive a DNA analysis from a DNA sample.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifying District of Columbia offenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The government of the District of Columbia may determine those offenses under the District of Columbia Code that shall be treated for purposes of this section as qualifying District of Columbia offenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commencement of collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Collection of DNA samples under subsection (a) shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, commence not later than the date that is 180 days after <date date="2000-12-19">December 19, 2000</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2001 through 2005.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–546, § 4</ref>, <date date="2000-12-19">Dec. 19, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2730</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–50, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-18">Aug. 18, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1002</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40704.</num>
<heading> Conditions of release generally</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the collection of a DNA sample from an individual on probation, parole, or supervised release is authorized pursuant to section 40702 or 40703 of this title or <ref>section 1565 of title 10</ref>, the individual shall cooperate in the collection of a DNA sample as a condition of that probation, parole, or supervised release.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–546, § 7(d)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-19">Dec. 19, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2734</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40705.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General to carry out this Act (including to reimburse the Federal judiciary for any reasonable costs incurred in implementing such Act, as determined by the Attorney General) such sums as may be necessary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–546, § 9</ref>, <date date="2000-12-19">Dec. 19, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2735</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40706.</num>
<heading> Privacy protection standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), any sample collected under, or any result of any analysis carried out under, section 40701, 40702, or 40703 of this title may be used only for a purpose specified in such section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permissive uses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A sample or result described in subsection (a) may be disclosed under the circumstances under which disclosure of information included in the Combined DNA Index System is allowed, as specified in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of <ref>section 12592(b)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person who knowingly discloses a sample or result described in subsection (a) in any manner to any person not authorized to receive it, or obtains or uses, without authorization, such sample or result, shall be fined not more than $250,000, or imprisoned for a period of not more than one year. Each instance of disclosure, obtaining, or use shall constitute a separate offense under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–546, § 10</ref>, <date date="2000-12-19">Dec. 19, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title II, § 203(e)(2)</ref>, title III, § 309, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2271</ref>, 2275.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>TRAINING, TECHNOLOGY, RESEARCH, AND EXPANDED USE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40721.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress on plans to modify CODIS system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Department of Justice plans to modify or supplement the core genetic markers needed for compatibility with the CODIS system, it shall notify the Judiciary Committee of the Senate and the Judiciary Committee of the House of Representatives in writing not later than 180 days before any change is made and explain the reasons for such change.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title II, § 203(f)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40722.</num>
<heading> DNA training and education for law enforcement, correctional personnel, and court officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall make grants to provide training, technical assistance, education, and information relating to the identification, collection, preservation, analysis, and use of DNA samples and DNA evidence by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> law enforcement personnel, including police officers and other first responders, evidence technicians, investigators, and others who collect or examine evidence of crime;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> court officers, including State and local prosecutors, defense lawyers, and judges;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> forensic science professionals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> corrections personnel, including prison and jail personnel, and probation, parole, and other officers involved in supervision.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $12,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2024 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–360, § 3</ref>, <date date="2008-10-08">Oct. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4008</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–182, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-09-29">Sept. 29, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–104, § 3</ref>, <date date="2019-12-30">Dec. 30, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3272</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40723.</num>
<heading> Sexual assault forensic exam program grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible entity” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State, Tribal, or local government or hospital;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a sexual assault examination program, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a SANE program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a SAFE program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a SART program;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> medical personnel, including a doctor or nurse, involved in treating victims of sexual assault; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a victim service provider involved in treating victims of sexual assault;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a State sexual assault coalition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a health care facility, including a hospital that provides sexual assault forensic examinations by a qualified or certified SANE or SAFE;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a sexual assault examination program that provides SANE or SAFE training; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a community-based program that provides sexual assault forensic examinations, including pediatric forensic exams in a multidisciplinary setting, by a qualified or certified SANE or SAFE outside of a traditional health care setting.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Health care facility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “health care facility” means any State, local, Tribal, community, free, nonprofit, academic, or private medical facility, including a hospital, that provides emergency medical care to patients.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Medical forensic examination; MFE</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “medical forensic examination” or “MFE” means an examination of a sexual assault patient by a health care provider, who has specialized education and clinical experience in the collection of forensic evidence and treatment of these patients, which includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> gathering information from the patient for the medical forensic history;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an examination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> coordinating treatment of injuries, documentation of biological and physical findings, and collection of evidence from the patient;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> documentation of findings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> providing information, treatment, and referrals for sexually transmitted infections, pregnancy, suicidal ideation, alcohol and substance abuse, and other non-acute medical concerns; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> providing follow-up as needed to provide additional healing, treatment, or collection of evidence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pediatric SANE and SAFE</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “pediatric SANE and SAFE” means a SANE or SAFE who is trained to conduct sexual assault forensic examinations on children and youth between the ages of 0 and 18.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “qualified personnel” includes a registered or advanced practice nurse, physician, doctor of osteopathy, or physician assistant who has specialized training conducting medical forensic examinations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified SANE and SAFE training program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “qualified SANE and SAFE training program” means a program that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is qualified to prepare current and future sexual assault nurse examiners to be profession-ready and meet the applicable State and National certification and licensure requirements, through didactic, clinical, preceptor, or capstone programs that include longer-term training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides that preparation under a health care model that uses trauma-informed techniques; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is approved as meeting the most recent National Training Standards for Sexual Assault Medical Forensic Examiners.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rural area</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “rural area” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 12291 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexual assault</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “sexual assault” means any nonconsensual sexual act or sexual contact proscribed by Federal, Tribal, or State law, including when the individual lacks capacity to consent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexual assault forensic examiner; SAFE</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “sexual assault forensic examiner” or “SAFE” means an individual who has specialized forensic training in treating sexual assault survivors and conducting medical forensic examinations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexual assault forensic examination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “sexual assault forensic examination” means an examination of a sexual assault patient by a health care provider, who has specialized education and clinical experience in the collection of forensic evidence and treatment of these patients, which includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> gathering information from the patient for the medical forensic history;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an examination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> coordinating treatment of injuries, documentation of biological and physical findings, and collection of evidence from the patient;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> documentation of findings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> providing information, treatment, and referrals for sexually transmitted infections, pregnancy, suicidal ideation, alcohol and substance abuse, and other non-acute medical concerns; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> providing follow-up as needed to provide additional healing, treatment, or collection of evidence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexual assault nurse examiner; SANE</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “sexual assault nurse examiner” or “SANE” means a registered or advanced practice nurse who has specialized training conducting medical forensic examinations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexual assault response team; SART</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “sexual assault response team” or “SART” means a multidisciplinary team that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provides a specialized and immediate response to survivors of sexual assault; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may include health care personnel, law enforcement representatives, community-based survivor advocates, prosecutors, and forensic scientists.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any territory or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trauma-informed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “trauma-informed” means, with respect to services or training, services or training that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> use a patient-centered approach to providing services or care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promote the dignity, strength, and empowerment of patients who have experienced trauma; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> incorporate evidence-based practices based on knowledge about the impact of trauma on patients’ lives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Underserved populations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “underserved populations” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 12291 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexual assault nurse examiner training program grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization for grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary, shall make grants to eligible entities for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> To establish qualified regional SANE training programs—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to provide clinical education for SANE students;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to provide salaries for full and part-time SANE instructors, including those specializing in pediatrics and working in a multidisciplinary team setting, to help with the clinical training of SANEs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to provide access to simulation laboratories and other resources necessary for clinical education.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To provide full and part time salaries for SANEs and SAFEs, including pediatric SANEs and SAFEs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To increase access to SANEs and SAFEs by otherwise providing training, education, or technical assistance relating to the collection, preservation, analysis, and use of DNA samples and DNA evidence by SANEs, SAFEs, and other qualified personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preference for grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In reviewing applications for grants under this section, the Attorney General shall give preference to any eligible entity that certifies in the grant application that the entity will coordinate with a rape crisis center or the State sexual assault coalition to facilitate sexual assault advocacy to support sexual assault survivors and use the grant funds to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish qualified SANE training programs in localities with a high volume of forensic trauma cases, including adult and child sexual assault, domestic violence, elder abuse, sex trafficking, and strangulation cases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increase the local and regional availability of full and part time sexual assault nurse examiners in a rural area, Tribal area, an area with a health professional shortage, or for an underserved population, including efforts to provide culturally competent services; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> establish or sustain sexual assault mobile teams or units or otherwise enhance SANE and SAFE access through telehealth.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Directive to the Attorney General</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than the beginning of fiscal year 2022, the Attorney General shall coordinate with the Secretary to inform health care facilities, including Federally qualified health centers and hospitals, colleges and universities, and other appropriate health-related entities about—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the availability of grant funding under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the role of sexual assault nurse examiners, both adult and pediatric, and available resources of the Department of Justice and the Department of Health and Human Services to train or employ sexual assault nurses examiners to address the needs of communities dealing with sexual assault, domestic violence, sex trafficking, elder abuse, strangulation, and, in particular, the need for pediatric SANEs, including such nurse examiners working in the multidisciplinary setting, in responding to abuse of both children and adolescents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall collaborate with nongovernmental organizations representing SANEs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public information on access to sexual assault forensic examinations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2022-03-15">March 15, 2022</date>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary, shall establish, and update annually, a public website on the access to forensic nurse examiners.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The website required under paragraph (1) shall with specificity describe, by State—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> funding opportunities for SANE training and continuing education; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the availability of sexual assault advocates at locations providing sexual assault forensic exams.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 4 years after <date date="2022-03-15">March 15, 2022</date>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary, shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the availability of, and patient access to, trained SANEs and other providers who perform MFEs or sexual assault forensic examinations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the health care facilities, including hospitals or clinics, that offer SANEs and sexual assault forensic examinations and whether each health care facility, including a hospital or clinic, has full-time, part-time, or on-call coverage;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> regional, provider, or other barriers to access for SANE care and services, including MFEs and sexual assault forensic examinations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> State requirements, minimum standards, and protocols for training SANEs, including trauma-informed and culturally competent training standards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> State requirements, minimum standards, and protocols for training emergency services personnel involved in MFEs and sexual assault forensic examinations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the availability of sexual assault nurse examiner training, frequency of when training is convened, the providers of such training, the State’s role in such training, and what process or procedures are in place for continuing education of such examiners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the dedicated Federal and State funding to support SANE training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> funding opportunities for SANE training and continuing education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the availability of sexual assault advocates at locations providing MFEs and sexual assault forensic exams; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the total annual cost of conducting sexual assault forensic exams described in <ref>section 10449(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–360, § 4</ref>, <date date="2008-10-08">Oct. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4009</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–182, § 4</ref>, <date date="2014-09-29">Sept. 29, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–324, § 4</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1950</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–107, § 2</ref>, <date date="2018-01-08">Jan. 8, 2018</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2266</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–104, § 4</ref>, <date date="2019-12-30">Dec. 30, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title XIII, § 1318(b)</ref>–(e), <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 940–945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40724.</num>
<heading> DNA research and development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Improving DNA technology</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall make grants for research and development to improve forensic DNA technology, including increasing the identification accuracy and efficiency of DNA analysis, decreasing time and expense, and increasing portability.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demonstration projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall make grants to appropriate entities under which research is carried out through demonstration projects involving coordinated training and commitment of resources to law enforcement agencies and key criminal justice participants to demonstrate and evaluate the use of forensic DNA technology in conjunction with other forensic tools. The demonstration projects shall include scientific evaluation of the public safety benefits, improvements to law enforcement operations, and cost-effectiveness of increased collection and use of DNA evidence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–324, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1954</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40725.</num>
<heading> National Forensic Science Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall appoint a National Forensic Science Commission (in this section referred to as the “Commission”), composed of persons experienced in criminal justice issues, including persons from the forensic science and criminal justice communities, to carry out the responsibilities under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assess the present and future resource needs of the forensic science community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make recommendations to the Attorney General for maximizing the use of forensic technologies and techniques to solve crimes and protect the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify potential scientific advances that may assist law enforcement in using forensic technologies and techniques to protect the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> make recommendations to the Attorney General for programs that will increase the number of qualified forensic scientists available to work in public crime laboratories;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> disseminate, through the National Institute of Justice, best practices concerning the collection and analyses of forensic evidence to help ensure quality and consistency in the use of forensic technologies and techniques to solve crimes and protect the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> examine additional issues pertaining to forensic science as requested by the Attorney General;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> examine Federal, State, and local privacy protection statutes, regulations, and practices relating to access to, or use of, stored DNA samples or DNA analyses, to determine whether such protections are sufficient;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> make specific recommendations to the Attorney General, as necessary, to enhance the protections described in paragraph (7) to ensure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the appropriate use and dissemination of DNA information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the accuracy, security, and confidentiality of DNA information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the timely removal and destruction of obsolete, expunged, or inaccurate DNA information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> that any other necessary measures are taken to protect privacy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> provide a forum for the exchange and dissemination of ideas and information in furtherance of the objectives described in paragraphs (1) through (8).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel; procedures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> designate the Chair of the Commission from among its members;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> designate any necessary staff to assist in carrying out the functions of the Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establish procedures and guidelines for the operations of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $500,000 for each of fiscal years 2005 through 2009 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40726.</num>
<heading> DNA identification of missing persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall make grants to promote the use of forensic DNA technology to identify missing persons and unidentified human remains.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each State or unit of local government that receives funding under this section shall be required to submit the DNA profiles of such missing persons and unidentified human remains to the National Missing Persons DNA Database of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–324, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1954</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40727.</num>
<heading> Kirk Bloodsworth Post-Conviction DNA Testing Grant Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall establish the Kirk Bloodsworth Post-Conviction DNA Testing Grant Program to award grants to States to help defray the costs of post-conviction DNA testing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–324, § 12(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1957</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40728.</num>
<heading> Establishment of best practices for evidence retention</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the National Institute of Justice, in consultation with Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and government laboratories, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish best practices for evidence retention to focus on the preservation of forensic evidence; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assist State, local, and tribal governments in adopting and implementing the best practices established under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, the Director of the National Institute of Justice shall publish the best practices established under subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to require or obligate compliance with the best practices established under subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title IV, § 414</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–324, § 13(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1958</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>DNA ARRESTEE COLLECTION PROCESSES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40741.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> DNA arrestee collection process</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “DNA arrestee collection process” means, with respect to a State, a process under which the State provides for the collection, for purposes of inclusion in the index described in <ref>section 12592(a) of this title</ref> (in this subchapter referred to as the “National DNA Index System”), of DNA profiles or DNA data from the following individuals who are at least 18 years of age:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Individuals who are arrested for or charged with a criminal offense under State law that consists of a homicide.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Individuals who are arrested for or charged with a criminal offense under State law that has an element involving a sexual act or sexual contact with another and that is punishable by imprisonment for more than 1 year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Individuals who are arrested for or charged with a criminal offense under State law that has an element of kidnaping or abduction and that is punishable by imprisonment for more than 1 year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Individuals who are arrested for or charged with a criminal offense under State law that consists of burglary punishable by imprisonment for more than 1 year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Individuals who are arrested for or charged with a criminal offense under State law that consists of aggravated assault punishable by imprisonment for more than 1 year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–253, § 2</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2407</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40742.</num>
<heading> Grants to States to implement DNA arrestee collection processes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall, subject to amounts made available pursuant to <ref>section 40744 of this title</ref>, carry out a grant program for the purpose of assisting States with the costs associated with the implementation of DNA arrestee collection processes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applications</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, in addition to any other requirements specified by the Attorney General, a State shall submit to the Attorney General an application that demonstrates that it has statutory authorization for the implementation of a DNA arrestee collection process.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-supplanting funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An application submitted under paragraph (1) by a State shall include assurances that the amounts received under the grant under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, State funds that would otherwise be available for the purpose described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall require a State seeking a grant under this section to document how such State will use the grant to meet expenses associated with a State’s implementation or planned implementation of a DNA arrestee collection process.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant allocation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount available to a State under this section shall be based on the projected costs that will be incurred by the State to implement a DNA arrestee collection process. Subject to paragraph (2), the Attorney General shall retain discretion to determine the amount of each such grant awarded to an eligible State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum grant allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a State seeking a grant under this section with respect to the implementation of a DNA arrestee collection process, such State shall be eligible for a grant under this section that is equal to no more than 100 percent of the first year costs to the State of implementing such process.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As a condition of receiving a grant under this section, a State shall have a procedure in place to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide written notification of expungement provisions and instructions for requesting expungement to all persons who submit a DNA profile or DNA data for inclusion in the index;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide the eligibility criteria for expungement and instructions for requesting expungement on an appropriate public Web site; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make a determination on all expungement requests not later than 90 days after receipt and provide a written response of the determination to the requesting party.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–253, § 3</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2408</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40743.</num>
<heading> Expungement of profiles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The expungement requirements under <ref>section 12592(d) of this title</ref> shall apply to any DNA profile or DNA data collected pursuant to this subchapter for purposes of inclusion in the National DNA Index System.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–253, § 4</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2408</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40744.</num>
<heading> Offset of funds appropriated</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any funds appropriated to carry out this subchapter, not to exceed $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2013 through 2015, shall be derived from amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (j) of <ref>section 40701 of this title</ref> in each such fiscal year for grants under such section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–253, § 5</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2409</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>