<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 301—</num>
<heading>COMPUTER CRIMES AND INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY CRIMES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 30101.</num>
<heading> State grant program for training and prosecution of computer crimes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of amounts provided in advance in appropriations Acts, the Office of Justice Programs shall make a grant to each State, which shall be used by the State, in conjunction with units of local government, State and local courts, other States, or combinations thereof in accordance with subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of grant amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Grants under this section may be used to establish and develop programs to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assist State and local law enforcement agencies in enforcing State and local criminal laws relating to computer crime, including infringement of copyrighted works over the Internet;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assist State and local law enforcement agencies in educating the public to prevent and identify computer crime, including infringement of copyrighted works over the Internet;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> educate and train State and local law enforcement officers and prosecutors to conduct investigations and forensic analyses of evidence and prosecutions of computer crime, including infringement of copyrighted works over the Internet;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> assist State and local law enforcement officers and prosecutors in acquiring computer and other equipment to conduct investigations and forensic analysis of evidence of computer crimes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> facilitate and promote the sharing of Federal law enforcement expertise and information about the investigation, analysis, and prosecution of computer crimes with State and local law enforcement officers and prosecutors, including the use of multijurisdictional task forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assurances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State shall provide assurances to the Attorney General that the State—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> has in effect laws that penalize computer crime, such as criminal laws prohibiting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> fraudulent schemes executed by means of a computer system or network;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the unlawful damaging, destroying, altering, deleting, removing of computer software, or data contained in a computer, computer system, computer program, or computer network; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the unlawful interference with the operation of or denial of access to a computer, computer program, computer system, or computer network;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assessment of the State and local resource needs, including criminal justice resources being devoted to the investigation and enforcement of computer crime laws; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a plan for coordinating the programs funded under this section with other federally funded technical assistant and training programs, including directly funded local programs such as the Local Law Enforcement Block Grant program (described under the heading “Violent Crime Reduction Programs, State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance” of the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998 (<ref>Public Law 105–119</ref>)).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal share of a grant received under this section may not exceed 90 percent of the costs of a program or proposal funded under this section unless the Attorney General waives, wholly or in part, the requirements of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2013.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amount made available to carry out this section in any fiscal year not more than 3 percent may be used by the Attorney General for salaries and administrative expenses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Unless all eligible applications submitted by any State or unit of local government within such State for a grant under this section have been funded, such State, together with grantees within the State (other than Indian tribes), shall be allocated in each fiscal year under this section not less than 0.75 percent of the total amount appropriated in the fiscal year for grants pursuant to this section, except that the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands each shall be allocated 0.25 percent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants to Indian tribes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Attorney General may use amounts made available under this section to make grants to Indian tribes for use in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–572, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-12-28">Dec. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 3058</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–403, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30102.</num>
<heading> Development and support of cybersecurity forensic capabilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall establish such regional computer forensic laboratories as the Attorney General considers appropriate, and provide support to existing computer forensic laboratories, in order that all such computer forensic laboratories have the capability—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide forensic examinations with respect to seized or intercepted computer evidence relating to criminal activity (including cyberterrorism);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide training and education for Federal, State, and local law enforcement personnel and prosecutors regarding investigations, forensic analyses, and prosecutions of computer-related crime (including cyberterrorism);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to assist Federal, State, and local law enforcement in enforcing Federal, State, and local criminal laws relating to computer-related crime;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to facilitate and promote the sharing of Federal law enforcement expertise and information about the investigation, analysis, and prosecution of computer-related crime with State and local law enforcement personnel and prosecutors, including the use of multijurisdictional task forces; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to carry out such other activities as the Attorney General considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated in each fiscal year $50,000,000 for purposes of carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VIII, § 816</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 385</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30103.</num>
<heading> Local law enforcement grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice may make grants to eligible State or local law enforcement entities, including law enforcement agencies of municipal governments and public educational institutions, for training, prevention, enforcement, and prosecution of intellectual property theft and infringement crimes (in this subsection referred to as “IP–TIC grants”), in accordance with the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of IP–TIC grant amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">IP–TIC grants may be used to establish and develop programs to do the following with respect to the enforcement of State and local true name and address laws and State and local criminal laws on anti-infringement, anti-counterfeiting, and unlawful acts with respect to goods by reason of their protection by a patent, trademark, service mark, trade secret, or other intellectual property right under State or Federal law:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Assist State and local law enforcement agencies in enforcing those laws, including by reimbursing State and local entities for expenses incurred in performing enforcement operations, such as overtime payments and storage fees for seized evidence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Assist State and local law enforcement agencies in educating the public to prevent, deter, and identify violations of those laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Educate and train State and local law enforcement officers and prosecutors to conduct investigations and forensic analyses of evidence and prosecutions in matters involving those laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Establish task forces that include personnel from State or local law enforcement entities, or both, exclusively to conduct investigations and forensic analyses of evidence and prosecutions in matters involving those laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Assist State and local law enforcement officers and prosecutors in acquiring computer and other equipment to conduct investigations and forensic analyses of evidence in matters involving those laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Facilitate and promote the sharing, with State and local law enforcement officers and prosecutors, of the expertise and information of Federal law enforcement agencies about the investigation, analysis, and prosecution of matters involving those laws and criminal infringement of copyrighted works, including the use of multijurisdictional task forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To be eligible to receive an IP–TIC grant, a State or local government entity shall provide to the Attorney General, in addition to the information regularly required to be provided under the Financial Guide issued by the Office of Justice Programs and any other information required of Department of Justice’s grantees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assurances that the State in which the government entity is located has in effect laws described in paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment of the resource needs of the State or local government entity applying for the grant, including information on the need for reimbursements of base salaries and overtime costs, storage fees, and other expenditures to improve the investigation, prevention, or enforcement of laws described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a plan for coordinating the programs funded under this section with other federally funded technical assistance and training programs, including directly funded local programs such as the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program authorized by subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 3750</ref> et seq.).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002209">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Federal share of an IP–TIC grant may not exceed 50 percent of the costs of the program or proposal funded by the IP–TIC grant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection the sum of $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2013.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the amount made available to carry out this subsection in any fiscal year, not more than 3 percent may be used by the Attorney General for salaries and administrative expenses.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–403, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30104.</num>
<heading> Improved investigative and forensic resources for enforcement of laws related to intellectual property crimes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations to carry out this subsection, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall, with respect to crimes related to the theft of intellectual property—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that there are at least 10 additional operational agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation designated to support the Computer Crime and Intellectual Property Section of the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice in the investigation and coordination of intellectual property crimes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that any Computer Hacking and Intellectual Property Crime Unit in the Department of Justice is supported by at least 1 agent of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (in addition to any agent supporting such unit as of <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>) to support such unit for the purpose of investigating or prosecuting intellectual property crimes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensure that all Computer Hacking and Intellectual Property Crime Units located at an office of a United States Attorney are assigned at least 2 Assistant United States Attorneys responsible for investigating and prosecuting computer hacking or intellectual property crimes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> ensure the implementation of a regular and comprehensive training program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the purpose of which is to train agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation in the investigation and prosecution of such crimes and the enforcement of laws related to intellectual property crimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that includes relevant forensic training related to investigating and prosecuting intellectual property crimes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Organized crime plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations to carry out this subsection, and not later than 180 days after <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>, the Attorney General, through the United States Attorneys’ Offices, the Computer Crime and Intellectual Property section, and the Organized Crime and Racketeering section of the Department of Justice, and in consultation with the Federal Bureau of Investigation and other Federal law enforcement agencies, such as the Department of Homeland Security, shall create and implement a comprehensive, long-range plan to investigate and prosecute international organized crime syndicates engaging in or supporting crimes relating to the theft of intellectual property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2013.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–403, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4272</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30105.</num>
<heading> Additional funding for resources to investigate and prosecute intellectual property crimes and other criminal activity involving computers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional funding for resources</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to amounts otherwise authorized for resources to investigate and prosecute intellectual property crimes and other criminal activity involving computers, there are authorized to be appropriated for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2013—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 to the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $10,000,000 to the Attorney General for the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of additional funding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Funds made available under subsection (a) shall be used by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Attorney General, for the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice, respectively, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> hire and train law enforcement officers to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> investigate intellectual property crimes and other crimes committed through the use of computers and other information technology, including through the use of the Internet; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assist in the prosecution of such crimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enable relevant units of the Department of Justice, including units responsible for investigating computer hacking or intellectual property crimes, to procure advanced tools of forensic science and expert computer forensic assistance, including from non-governmental entities, to investigate, prosecute, and study such crimes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–403, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4273</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30106.</num>
<heading> Annual reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report of the Attorney General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a report to Congress on actions taken to carry out sections 30103 to 30106 of this title. The initial report required under this subsection shall be submitted by <date date="2009-05-01">May 1, 2009</date>. All subsequent annual reports shall be submitted by May 1st of each fiscal year thereafter. The report required under this subsection may be submitted as part of the annual performance report of the Department of Justice, and shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> With respect to grants issued under <ref>section 30103 of this title</ref>, the number and identity of State and local law enforcement grant applicants, the number of grants issued, the dollar value of each grant, including a break down of such value showing how the recipient used the funds, the specific purpose of each grant, and the reports from recipients of the grants on the efficacy of the program supported by the grant. The Department of Justice shall use the information provided by the grant recipients to produce a statement for each individual grant. Such statement shall state whether each grantee has accomplished the purposes of the grant as established in <ref>section 30103(b) of this title</ref>. Those grantees not in compliance with the requirements of sections 30103 to 30106 of this title shall be subject, but not limited to, sanctions as described in the Financial Guide issued by the Office of Justice Programs at the Department of Justice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> With respect to the additional agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation authorized under paragraphs (1) and (2) of <ref>section 30104(a) of this title</ref>, the number of investigations and actions in which such agents were engaged, the type of each action, the resolution of each action, and any penalties imposed in each action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> With respect to the training program authorized under <ref>section 30104(a)(4) of this title</ref>, the number of agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation participating in such program, the elements of the training program, and the subject matters covered by the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> With respect to the organized crime plan authorized under <ref>section 30104(b) of this title</ref>, the number of organized crime investigations and prosecutions resulting from such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> With respect to the authorizations under <ref>section 30105 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of law enforcement officers hired and the number trained;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number and type of investigations and prosecutions resulting from the hiring and training of such law enforcement officers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the defendants involved in any such prosecutions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any penalties imposed in each such successful prosecution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the advanced tools of forensic science procured to investigate, prosecute, and study computer hacking or intellectual property crimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the number and type of investigations and prosecutions in such tools were used.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Any other information that the Attorney General may consider relevant to inform Congress on the effective use of the resources authorized under sections 30103, 30104, and 30105 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> A summary of the efforts, activities, and resources the Department of Justice has allocated to the enforcement, investigation, and prosecution of intellectual property crimes, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a review of the policies and efforts of the Department of Justice related to the prevention and investigation of intellectual property crimes, including efforts at the Office of Justice Programs, the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice, the Executive Office of United States Attorneys, the Office of the Attorney General, the Office of the Deputy Attorney General, the Office of Legal Policy, and any other agency or bureau of the Department of Justice whose activities relate to intellectual property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a summary of the overall successes and failures of such policies and efforts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> a review of the investigative and prosecution activity of the Department of Justice with respect to intellectual property crimes, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of investigations initiated related to such crimes;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of arrests related to such crimes; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> the number of prosecutions for such crimes, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the number of defendants involved in such prosecutions;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> whether the prosecution resulted in a conviction; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the sentence and the statutory maximum for such crime, as well as the average sentence imposed for such crime; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a Department-wide assessment of the staff, financial resources, and other resources (such as time, technology, and training) devoted to the enforcement, investigation, and prosecution of intellectual property crimes, including the number of investigators, prosecutors, and forensic specialists dedicated to investigating and prosecuting intellectual property crimes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> A summary of the efforts, activities, and resources that the Department of Justice has taken to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> minimize duplicating the efforts, materials, facilities, and procedures of any other Federal agency responsible for the enforcement, investigation, or prosecution of intellectual property crimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enhance the efficiency and consistency with which Federal funds and resources are expended to enforce, investigate, or prosecute intellectual property crimes, including the extent to which the Department has utilized existing personnel, materials, technologies, and facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report of the Attorney General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The first report required to be submitted by the Attorney General under subsection (a) shall include a summary of the efforts, activities, and resources the Department of Justice has allocated in the 5 years prior to <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>, as well as the 1-year period following such date, to the enforcement, investigation, and prosecution of intellectual property crimes, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a review of the policies and efforts of the Department of Justice related to the prevention and investigation of intellectual property crimes, including efforts at the Office of Justice Programs, the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice, the Executive Office of United States Attorneys, the Office of the Attorney General, the Office of the Deputy Attorney General, the Office of Legal Policy, and any other agency or bureau of the Department of Justice whose activities relate to intellectual property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a summary of the overall successes and failures of such policies and efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> a review of the investigative and prosecution activity of the Department of Justice with respect to intellectual property crimes, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of investigations initiated related to such crimes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of arrests related to such crimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the number of prosecutions for such crimes, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of defendants involved in such prosecutions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> whether the prosecution resulted in a conviction; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the sentence and the statutory maximum for such crime, as well as the average sentence imposed for such crime; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a Department-wide assessment of the staff, financial resources, and other resources (such as time, technology, and training) devoted to the enforcement, investigation, and prosecution of intellectual property crimes, including the number of investigators, prosecutors, and forensic specialists dedicated to investigating and prosecuting intellectual property crimes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report of the FBI</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>, and annually thereafter, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit a report to Congress on actions taken to carry out sections 30103 to 30106 of this title. The initial report required under this subsection shall be submitted by <date date="2009-05-01">May 1, 2009</date>. All subsequent annual reports shall be submitted by May 1st of each fiscal year thereafter. The report required under this subsection may be submitted as part of the annual performance report of the Department of Justice, and shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a review of the policies and efforts of the Bureau related to the prevention and investigation of intellectual property crimes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a summary of the overall successes and failures of such policies and efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> a review of the investigative and prosecution activity of the Bureau with respect to intellectual property crimes, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of investigations initiated related to such crimes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of arrests related to such crimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the number of prosecutions for such crimes, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of defendants involved in such prosecutions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> whether the prosecution resulted in a conviction; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the sentence and the statutory maximum for such crime, as well as the average sentence imposed for such crime; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a Bureau-wide assessment of the staff, financial resources, and other resources (such as time, technology, and training) devoted to the enforcement, investigation, and prosecution of intellectual property crimes, including the number of investigators, prosecutors, and forensic specialists dedicated to investigating and prosecuting intellectual property crimes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report of the FBI</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The first report required to be submitted by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation under subsection (c) shall include a summary of the efforts, activities, and resources the Federal Bureau of Investigation has allocated in the 5 years prior to <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>, as well as the 1-year period following such date to the enforcement, investigation, and prosecution of intellectual property crimes, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a review of the policies and efforts of the Bureau related to the prevention and investigation of intellectual property crimes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a summary of the overall successes and failures of such policies and efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> a review of the investigative and prosecution activity of the Bureau with respect to intellectual property crimes, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of investigations initiated related to such crimes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of arrests related to such crimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the number of prosecutions for such crimes, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of defendants involved in such prosecutions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> whether the prosecution resulted in a conviction; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the sentence and the statutory maximum for such crime, as well as the average sentence imposed for such crime; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a Bureau-wide assessment of the staff, financial resources, and other resources (such as time, technology, and training) devoted to the enforcement, investigation, and prosecution of intellectual property crimes, including the number of investigators, prosecutors, and forensic specialists dedicated to investigating and prosecuting intellectual property crimes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–403, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30107.</num>
<heading> Local law enforcement grants for enforcement of cybercrimes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Computer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “computer” includes a computer network and an interactive electronic device.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cybercrime against individuals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “cybercrime against individuals”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a criminal offense applicable in the area under the jurisdiction of the relevant State, Indian Tribe, or unit of local government that involves the use of a computer to harass, threaten, stalk, extort, coerce, cause fear to, or intimidate an individual, or without consent distribute intimate images of an adult, except that use of a computer need not be an element of such an offense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include the use of a computer to cause harm to a commercial entity, government agency, or non-natural person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indian tribe; State; Tribal government; unit of local government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “Indian Tribe”, “State”, “Tribal government”, and “unit of local government” have the meanings given such terms in <ref>section 12291(a) of this title</ref>, as amended by this Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of grant program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Attorney General shall award grants under this section to States, Indian Tribes, and units of local government for the prevention, enforcement, and prosecution of cybercrimes against individuals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To request a grant under this section, the chief executive officer of a State, Tribal government, or unit of local government shall submit an application to the Attorney General not later than 90 days after the date on which funds to carry out this section are appropriated for a fiscal year, in such form as the Attorney General may require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A certification that Federal funds made available under this section will not be used to supplant State, Tribal, or local funds, but will be used to increase the amounts of such funds that would, in the absence of Federal funds, be made available for law enforcement activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> An assurance that, not later than 30 days before the application (or any amendment to the application) was submitted to the Attorney General, the application (or amendment) was submitted for review to the governing body of the State, Tribe, or unit of local government (or to an organization designated by that governing body).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> An assurance that, before the application (or any amendment to the application) was submitted to the Attorney General—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the application (or amendment) was made public; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an opportunity to comment on the application (or amendment) was provided to citizens, to neighborhood or community-based organizations, and to victim service providers, to the extent applicable law or established procedure makes such an opportunity available;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> An assurance that, for each fiscal year covered by an application, the applicant shall maintain and report such data, records, and information (programmatic and financial) as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> A certification, made in a form acceptable to the Attorney General and executed by the chief executive officer of the applicant (or by another officer of the applicant, if qualified under regulations promulgated by the Attorney General), that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the programs to be funded by the grant meet all the requirements of this section;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all the information contained in the application is correct;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> there has been appropriate coordination with affected agencies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the applicant will comply with all provisions of this section and all other applicable Federal laws.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> A certification that the State, Tribe, or in the case of a unit of local government, the State in which the unit of local government is located, has in effect criminal laws which prohibit cybercrimes against individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> A certification that any equipment described in subsection (d)(8) purchased using grant funds awarded under this section will be used primarily for investigations and forensic analysis of evidence in matters involving cybercrimes against individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Grants awarded under this section may be used only for programs that provide—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> training for State, Tribal, or local law enforcement personnel relating to cybercrimes against individuals, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> training such personnel to identify and protect victims of cybercrimes against individuals, provided that the training is developed in collaboration with victim service providers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> training such personnel to utilize Federal, State, Tribal, local, and other resources to assist victims of cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> training such personnel to identify and investigate cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> training such personnel to enforce and utilize the laws that prohibit cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> training such personnel to utilize technology to assist in the investigation of cybercrimes against individuals and enforcement of laws that prohibit such crimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the payment of overtime incurred as a result of such training;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> training for State, Tribal, or local prosecutors, judges, and judicial personnel relating to cybercrimes against individuals, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> training such personnel to identify, investigate, prosecute, or adjudicate cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> training such personnel to utilize laws that prohibit cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> training such personnel to utilize Federal, State, Tribal, local, and other resources to assist victims of cybercrimes against individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> training such personnel to utilize technology to assist in the prosecution or adjudication of acts of cybercrimes against individuals, including the use of technology to protect victims of such crimes;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> training for State, Tribal, or local emergency dispatch personnel relating to cybercrimes against individuals, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> training such personnel to identify and protect victims of cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> training such personnel to utilize Federal, State, Tribal, local, and other resources to assist victims of cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> training such personnel to utilize technology to assist in the identification of and response to cybercrimes against individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the payment of overtime incurred as a result of such training;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> assistance to State, Tribal, or local law enforcement agencies in enforcing laws that prohibit cybercrimes against individuals, including expenses incurred in performing enforcement operations, such as overtime payments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> assistance to State, Tribal, or local law enforcement agencies in educating the public in order to prevent, deter, and identify violations of laws that prohibit cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> assistance to State, Tribal, or local law enforcement agencies to support the placement of victim assistants to serve as liaisons between victims of cybercrimes against individuals and personnel of law enforcement agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> assistance to State, Tribal, or local law enforcement agencies to establish task forces that operate solely to conduct investigations, forensic analyses of evidence, and prosecutions in matters involving cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> assistance to State, Tribal, or local law enforcement agencies and prosecutors in acquiring computers, computer equipment, and other equipment necessary to conduct investigations and forensic analysis of evidence in matters involving cybercrimes against individuals, including expenses incurred in the training, maintenance, or acquisition of technical updates necessary for the use of such equipment for the duration of a reasonable period of use of such equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> assistance in the facilitation and promotion of sharing, with State, Tribal, and local law enforcement agencies and prosecutors, of the expertise and information of Federal law enforcement agencies about the investigation, analysis, and prosecution of matters involving laws that prohibit cybercrimes against individuals, including the use of multijurisdictional task forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> assistance to State, Tribal, and local law enforcement and prosecutors in processing interstate extradition requests for violations of laws involving cybercrimes against individuals, including expenses incurred in the extradition of an offender from one State to another.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to the Attorney General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On the date that is 1 year after the date on which a State, Indian Tribe, or unit of local government receives a grant under this section, and annually thereafter, the chief executive officer of the State, Tribal government, or unit of local government shall submit to the Attorney General a report which contains—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a summary of the activities carried out during the previous year with any grant received under this section by such State, Indian Tribe, or unit of local government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the results of such activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such other information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than November 1 of each even-numbered fiscal year, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report that contains a compilation of the information contained in the reports submitted under subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amount made available under paragraph (1) in any fiscal year, not more than 5 percent may be used for evaluation, monitoring, technical assistance, salaries, and administrative expenses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title XIV, § 1401</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30108.</num>
<heading> National Resource Center grant</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cybercrime against individuals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “cybercrime against individuals” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 30107 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible entity” means a nonprofit private organization that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> focuses on cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides documentation to the Attorney General demonstrating experience working directly on issues of cybercrimes against individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> includes on the organization’s advisory board representatives who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> have a documented history of working directly on issues of cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> have a history of working directly with victims of cybercrimes against individuals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> are geographically and culturally diverse.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of grant program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Attorney General shall award a grant under this section to an eligible entity for the purpose of the establishment and maintenance of a National Resource Center on Cybercrimes Against Individuals to provide resource information, training, and technical assistance to improve the capacity of individuals, organizations, governmental entities, and communities to prevent, enforce, and prosecute cybercrimes against individuals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To request a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Attorney General not later than 90 days after the date on which funds to carry out this section are appropriated for fiscal year 2022 in such form as the Attorney General may require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An assurance that, for each fiscal year covered by the application, the applicant will maintain and report such data, records, and information (programmatic and financial) as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A certification, made in a form acceptable to the Attorney General, that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the programs funded by the grant meet all the requirements of this section;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all the information contained in the application is correct; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the applicant will comply with all provisions of this section and all other applicable Federal laws.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The eligible entity awarded a grant under this section shall use such amounts for the establishment and maintenance of a National Resource Center on Cybercrimes Against Individuals, which shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> offer a comprehensive array of technical assistance and training resources to Federal, State, and local governmental agencies, community-based organizations, and other professionals and interested parties related to cybercrimes against individuals, including programs and research related to victims;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> maintain a resource library which shall collect, prepare, analyze, and disseminate information and statistics related to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the incidence of cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the enforcement and prosecution of laws relating to cybercrimes against individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the provision of supportive services and resources for victims, including victims from underserved populations, of cybercrimes against individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> conduct research related to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the causes of cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the effect of cybercrimes against individuals on victims of such crimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> model solutions to prevent or deter cybercrimes against individuals or to enforce the laws relating to cybercrimes against individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of grant</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A grant awarded under this section shall be awarded for a period of 5 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Renewal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A grant under this section may be renewed for additional 5-year periods if the Attorney General determines that the funds made available to the recipient were used in a manner described in subsection (d), and if the recipient resubmits an application described in subsection (c) in such form, and at such time, as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subgrants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The eligible entity awarded a grant under this section may make subgrants to other nonprofit private organizations with relevant subject matter expertise in order to establish and maintain the National Resource Center on Cybercrimes Against Individuals in accordance with subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to the Attorney General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On the date that is 1 year after the date on which an eligible entity receives a grant under this section, and annually thereafter for the duration of the grant period, the entity shall submit to the Attorney General a report which contains—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a summary of the activities carried out under the grant program during the previous year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the results of such activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such other information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than November 1 of each even-numbered fiscal year, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report that contains a compilation of the information contained in the reports submitted under subsection (g).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title XIV, § 1402</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 948</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30109.</num>
<heading> National strategy, classification, and reporting on cybercrime</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Computer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “computer” includes a computer network and any interactive electronic device.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cybercrime against individuals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “cybercrime against individuals” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 30107 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall develop a national strategy to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reduce the incidence of cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate investigations of cybercrimes against individuals by Federal law enforcement agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> increase the number of Federal prosecutions of cybercrimes against individuals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop an evaluation process that measures rates of cybercrime victimization and prosecutorial rates among Tribal and culturally specific communities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Classification of cybercrimes against individuals for purposes of crime reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In accordance with the authority of the Attorney General under <ref>section 534 of title 28</ref>, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> design and create within the Uniform Crime Reports a category for offenses that constitute cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the extent feasible, within the category established under paragraph (1), establish subcategories for each type of cybercrime against individuals that is an offense under Federal or State law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> classify the category established under paragraph (1) as a Part I crime in the Uniform Crime Reports; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> classify each type of cybercrime against individuals that is an offense under Federal or State law as a Group A offense for the purpose of the National Incident-Based Reporting System.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual summary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall publish an annual summary of the information reported in the Uniform Crime Reports and the National Incident-Based Reporting System relating to cybercrimes against individuals, including an evaluation of the implementation process for the national strategy developed under subsection (b) and outcome measurements on its impact on Tribal and culturally specific communities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title XIV, § 1403</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 950</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30110.</num>
<heading> Improved investigative and forensic resources for enforcement of laws related to cybercrimes against individuals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations to carry out this section, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Secretary of Homeland Security, including the Executive Associate Director of Homeland Security Investigations, shall, with respect to cybercrimes against individuals—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that there are not fewer than 10 additional operational agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation designated to support the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice in the investigation and coordination of cybercrimes against individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that each office of a United States Attorney designates at least 1 Assistant United States Attorney as responsible for investigating and prosecuting cybercrimes against individuals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> ensure the implementation of a regular and comprehensive training program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the purpose of which is to train agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation in the investigation and prosecution of such crimes and the enforcement of laws related to cybercrimes against individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that includes relevant forensic training related to investigating and prosecuting cybercrimes against individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30111.</num>
<heading> Training and technical assistance for States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the United States Secret Service, the Executive Associate Director of Homeland Security Investigations, and nongovernmental and survivor stakeholders, shall create, compile, evaluate, and disseminate materials and information, and provide the necessary training and technical assistance, to assist States and units of local government in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> investigating, prosecuting, pursuing, preventing, understanding, and mitigating the impact of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> physical, sexual, and psychological abuse of cybercrime victims, including victims of human trafficking that is facilitated by interactive computer services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> exploitation of cybercrime victims; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> deprioritization of cybercrime; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assessing, addressing, and mitigating the physical and psychological trauma to victims of cybercrime.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title III, § 324</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>