<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 503—</num>
<heading>LAW ENFORCEMENT CONGRESSIONAL BADGE OF BRAVERY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal agency head</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal agency head” means the head of any executive, legislative, or judicial branch Government entity that employs Federal law enforcement officers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal Board” means the Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board established under <ref>section 50313(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Board members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal Board members” means the members of the Federal Board appointed under <ref>section 50313(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal Law Enforcement Badge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Federal Law Enforcement Badge” means the Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery described in <ref>section 50311 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal law enforcement officer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Federal law enforcement officer”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> means a Federal employee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who has statutory authority to make arrests or apprehensions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who is authorized by the agency of the employee to carry firearms; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> whose duties are primarily—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> engagement in or supervision of the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of, or the incarceration of any person for, any violation of law; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the protection of Federal, State, local, or foreign government officials against threats to personal safety; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes a law enforcement officer employed by the Amtrak Police Department or Federal Reserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Office” means the Congressional Badge of Bravery Office established under <ref>section 50331(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and Local Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State and Local Board” means the State and Local Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board established under <ref>section 50323(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and Local Board members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State and Local Board members” means the members of the State and Local Board appointed under <ref>section 50323(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and Local Law Enforcement Badge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State and Local Law Enforcement Badge” means the State and Local Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery described in <ref>section 50321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State or local agency head</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State or local agency head” means the head of any executive, legislative, or judicial branch entity of a State or local government that employs State or local law enforcement officers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State or local law enforcement officer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “State or local law enforcement officer” means an employee of a State or local government—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> who has statutory authority to make arrests or apprehensions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> who is authorized by the agency of the employee to carry firearms; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> whose duties are primarily—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> engagement in or supervision of the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of, or the incarceration of any person for, any violation of law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the protection of Federal, State, local, or foreign government officials against threats to personal safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–298, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-07-31">July 31, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2985</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL LAW ENFORCEMENT CONGRESSIONAL BADGE OF BRAVERY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50311.</num>
<heading> Authorization of a Badge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may award, and a Member of Congress or the Attorney General may present, in the name of Congress a Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery to a Federal law enforcement officer who is cited by the Attorney General, upon the recommendation of the Federal Board, for performing an act of bravery while in the line of duty.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–298, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2008-07-31">July 31, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50312.</num>
<heading> Nominations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A Federal agency head may nominate for a Federal Law Enforcement Badge an individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who is a Federal law enforcement officer working within the agency of the Federal agency head making the nomination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> sustained a physical injury while—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> engaged in the lawful duties of the individual; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> performing an act characterized as bravery by the Federal agency head making the nomination; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> put the individual at personal risk when the injury described in clause (i) occurred; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> while not injured, performed an act characterized as bravery by the Federal agency head making the nomination that placed the individual at risk of serious physical injury or death.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A nomination under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a written narrative, of not more than 2 pages, describing the circumstances under which the nominee performed the act of bravery described in subsection (a) and how the circumstances meet the criteria described in such subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the full name of the nominee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the home mailing address of the nominee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the agency in which the nominee served on the date when such nominee performed the act of bravery described in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the occupational title and grade or rank of the nominee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the field office address of the nominee on the date when such nominee performed the act of bravery described in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the number of years of Government service by the nominee as of the date when such nominee performed the act of bravery described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Federal agency head shall submit each nomination under subsection (a) to the Office not later than February 15 of the year following the date on which the nominee performed the act of bravery described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–298, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2008-07-31">July 31, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2986</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50313.</num>
<heading> Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Department of Justice a Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Federal Board shall do the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Design the Federal Law Enforcement Badge with appropriate ribbons and appurtenances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Select an engraver to produce each Federal Law Enforcement Badge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Recommend recipients of the Federal Law Enforcement Badge from among those nominations timely submitted to the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Annually present to the Attorney General the names of Federal law enforcement officers who the Federal Board recommends as Federal Law Enforcement Badge recipients in accordance with the criteria described in <ref>section 50312(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> After approval by the Attorney General—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> procure the Federal Law Enforcement Badges from the engraver selected under paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> send a letter announcing the award of each Federal Law Enforcement Badge to the Federal agency head who nominated the recipient of such Federal Law Enforcement Badge;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> send a letter to each Member of Congress representing the congressional district where the recipient of each Federal Law Enforcement Badge resides to offer such Member an opportunity to present such Federal Law Enforcement Badge; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> make or facilitate arrangements for presenting each Federal Law Enforcement Badge in accordance with <ref>section 50314 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Set an annual timetable for fulfilling the duties described in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Number and appointment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Federal Board shall be composed of 7 members appointed as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> One member jointly appointed by the majority leader and minority leader of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> One member jointly appointed by the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> One member from the Department of Justice appointed by the Attorney General.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Two members of the Federal Law Enforcement Officers Association appointed by the Executive Board of the Federal Law Enforcement Officers Association.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Two members of the Fraternal Order of Police appointed by the Executive Board of the Fraternal Order of Police.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not more than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 2 Federal Board members may be members of the Federal Law Enforcement Officers Association; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 2 Federal Board members may be members of the Fraternal Order of Police.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Federal Board members shall be individuals with knowledge or expertise, whether by experience or training, in the field of Federal law enforcement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each Federal Board member shall be appointed for 2 years and may be reappointed. A vacancy in the Federal Board shall not affect the powers of the Federal Board and shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chairperson of the Federal Board shall be a Federal Board member elected by a majority of the Federal Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Federal Board shall conduct its first meeting not later than 90 days after the appointment of a majority of Federal Board members. Thereafter, the Federal Board shall meet at the call of the Chairperson, or in the case of a vacancy of the position of Chairperson, at the call of the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting and rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A majority of Federal Board members shall constitute a quorum to conduct business, but the Federal Board may establish a lesser quorum for conducting hearings scheduled by the Federal Board. The Federal Board may establish by majority vote any other rules for the conduct of the business of the Federal Board, if such rules are not inconsistent with this subchapter or other applicable law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Federal Board may hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Federal Board considers appropriate to carry out the duties of the Federal Board under this subchapter. The Federal Board may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before it.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Witness expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Witnesses requested to appear before the Federal Board may be paid the same fees as are paid to witnesses under <ref>section 1821 of title 28</ref>. The per diem and mileage allowances for witnesses shall be paid from funds appropriated to the Federal Board.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information from Federal agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to sections 552, 552a, and 552b of title 5—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Federal Board may secure directly from any Federal department or agency information necessary to enable it to carry out this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon request of the Federal Board, the head of that department or agency shall furnish the information to the Federal Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information to be kept confidential</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Federal Board shall not disclose any information which may compromise an ongoing law enforcement investigation or is otherwise required by law to be kept confidential.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), each Federal Board member shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref> for each day (including travel time) during which such Federal Board member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the Federal Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of compensation for government employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Federal Board members who serve as officers or employees of the Federal Government or a State or a local government may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Federal Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each Federal Board member shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–298, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2008-07-31">July 31, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50314.</num>
<heading> Presentation of Federal Law Enforcement Badges</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presentation by Member of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Member of Congress may present a Federal Law Enforcement Badge to any Federal Law Enforcement Badge recipient who resides in such Member’s congressional district. If both a Senator and Representative choose to present a Federal Law Enforcement Badge, such Senator and Representative shall make a joint presentation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presentation by Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If no Member of Congress chooses to present the Federal Law Enforcement Badge as described in subsection (a), the Attorney General, or a designee of the Attorney General, shall present such Federal Law Enforcement Badge.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presentation arrangements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The office of the Member of Congress presenting each Federal Law Enforcement Badge may make arrangements for the presentation of such Federal Law Enforcement Badge, and if a Senator and Representative choose to participate jointly as described in subsection (a), the Members shall make joint arrangements. The Federal Board shall facilitate any such presentation arrangements as requested by the congressional office presenting the Federal Law Enforcement Badge and shall make arrangements in cases not undertaken by Members of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–298, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2008-07-31">July 31, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2989</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>STATE AND LOCAL LAW ENFORCEMENT CONGRESSIONAL BADGE OF BRAVERY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50321.</num>
<heading> Authorization of a Badge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may award, and a Member of Congress or the Attorney General may present, in the name of Congress a State and Local Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery to a State or local law enforcement officer who is cited by the Attorney General, upon the recommendation of the State and Local Board, for performing an act of bravery while in the line of duty.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–298, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2008-07-31">July 31, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50322.</num>
<heading> Nominations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A State or local agency head may nominate for a State and Local Law Enforcement Badge an individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who is a State or local law enforcement officer working within the agency of the State or local agency head making the nomination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> sustained a physical injury while—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> engaged in the lawful duties of the individual; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> performing an act characterized as bravery by the State or local agency head making the nomination; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> put the individual at personal risk when the injury described in clause (i) occurred; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> while not injured, performed an act characterized as bravery by the State or local agency head making the nomination that placed the individual at risk of serious physical injury or death.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A nomination under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a written narrative, of not more than 2 pages, describing the circumstances under which the nominee performed the act of bravery described in subsection (a) and how the circumstances meet the criteria described in such subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the full name of the nominee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the home mailing address of the nominee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the agency in which the nominee served on the date when such nominee performed the act of bravery described in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the occupational title and grade or rank of the nominee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the field office address of the nominee on the date when such nominee performed the act of bravery described in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the number of years of government service by the nominee as of the date when such nominee performed the act of bravery described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A State or local agency head shall submit each nomination under subsection (a) to the Office not later than February 15 of the year following the date on which the nominee performed the act of bravery described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–298, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2008-07-31">July 31, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50323.</num>
<heading> State and Local Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Department of Justice a State and Local Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The State and Local Board shall do the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Design the State and Local Law Enforcement Badge with appropriate ribbons and appurtenances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Select an engraver to produce each State and Local Law Enforcement Badge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Recommend recipients of the State and Local Law Enforcement Badge from among those nominations timely submitted to the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Annually present to the Attorney General the names of State or local law enforcement officers who the State and Local Board recommends as State and Local Law Enforcement Badge recipients in accordance with the criteria described in <ref>section 50322(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> After approval by the Attorney General—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> procure the State and Local Law Enforcement Badges from the engraver selected under paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> send a letter announcing the award of each State and Local Law Enforcement Badge to the State or local agency head who nominated the recipient of such State and Local Law Enforcement Badge;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> send a letter to each Member of Congress representing the congressional district where the recipient of each State and Local Law Enforcement Badge resides to offer such Member an opportunity to present such State and Local Law Enforcement Badge; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> make or facilitate arrangements for presenting each State and Local Law Enforcement Badge in accordance with <ref>section 50324 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Set an annual timetable for fulfilling the duties described in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Number and appointment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The State and Local Board shall be composed of 9 members appointed as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> One member jointly appointed by the majority leader and minority leader of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> One member jointly appointed by the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> One member from the Department of Justice appointed by the Attorney General.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Two members of the Fraternal Order of Police appointed by the Executive Board of the Fraternal Order of Police.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> One member of the National Association of Police Organizations appointed by the Executive Board of the National Association of Police Organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> One member of the National Organization of Black Law Enforcement Executives appointed by the Executive Board of the National Organization of Black Law Enforcement Executives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> One member of the International Association of Chiefs of Police appointed by the Board of Officers of the International Association of Chiefs of Police.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> One member of the National Sheriffs’ Association appointed by the Executive Committee of the National Sheriffs’ Association.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not more than 5 State and Local Board members may be members of the Fraternal Order of Police.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">State and Local Board members shall be individuals with knowledge or expertise, whether by experience or training, in the field of State and local law enforcement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms and vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State and Local Board member shall be appointed for 2 years and may be reappointed. A vacancy in the State and Local Board shall not affect the powers of the State and Local Board and shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chairperson of the State and Local Board shall be a State and Local Board member elected by a majority of the State and Local Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State and Local Board shall conduct its first meeting not later than 90 days after the appointment of a majority of State and Local Board members. Thereafter, the State and Local Board shall meet at the call of the Chairperson, or in the case of a vacancy of the position of Chairperson, at the call of the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting and rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A majority of State and Local Board members shall constitute a quorum to conduct business, but the State and Local Board may establish a lesser quorum for conducting hearings scheduled by the State and Local Board. The State and Local Board may establish by majority vote any other rules for the conduct of the business of the State and Local Board, if such rules are not inconsistent with this subchapter or other applicable law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The State and Local Board may hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the State and Local Board considers appropriate to carry out the duties of the State and Local Board under this subchapter. The State and Local Board may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before it.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Witness expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Witnesses requested to appear before the State and Local Board may be paid the same fees as are paid to witnesses under <ref>section 1821 of title 28</ref>. The per diem and mileage allowances for witnesses shall be paid from funds appropriated to the State and Local Board.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information from Federal agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to sections 552, 552a, and 552b of title 5—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the State and Local Board may secure directly from any Federal department or agency information necessary to enable it to carry out this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon request of the State and Local Board, the head of that department or agency shall furnish the information to the State and Local Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information to be kept confidential</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State and Local Board shall not disclose any information which may compromise an ongoing law enforcement investigation or is otherwise required by law to be kept confidential.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), each State and Local Board member shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref> for each day (including travel time) during which such State and Local Board member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the State and Local Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of compensation for government employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">State and Local Board members who serve as officers or employees of the Federal Government or a State or a local government may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the State and Local Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State and Local Board member shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–298, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2008-07-31">July 31, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50324.</num>
<heading> Presentation of State and Local Law Enforcement Badges</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presentation by Member of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Member of Congress may present a State and Local Law Enforcement Badge to any State and Local Law Enforcement Badge recipient who resides in such Member’s congressional district. If both a Senator and Representative choose to present a State and Local Law Enforcement Badge, such Senator and Representative shall make a joint presentation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presentation by Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If no Member of Congress chooses to present the State and Local Law Enforcement Badge as described in subsection (a), the Attorney General, or a designee of the Attorney General, shall present such State and Local Law Enforcement Badge.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presentation arrangements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The office of the Member of Congress presenting each State and Local Law Enforcement Badge may make arrangements for the presentation of such State and Local Law Enforcement Badge, and if a Senator and Representative choose to participate jointly as described in subsection (a), the Members shall make joint arrangements. The State and Local Board shall facilitate any such presentation arrangements as requested by the congressional office presenting the State and Local Law Enforcement Badge and shall make arrangements in cases not undertaken by Members of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–298, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2008-07-31">July 31, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>CONGRESSIONAL BADGE OF BRAVERY OFFICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50331.</num>
<heading> Congressional Badge of Bravery Office</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Department of Justice a Congressional Badge of Bravery Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> receive nominations from Federal agency heads on behalf of the Federal Board and deliver such nominations to the Federal Board at Federal Board meetings described in <ref>section 50313(d)(2) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> receive nominations from State or local agency heads on behalf of the State and Local Board and deliver such nominations to the State and Local Board at State and Local Board meetings described in <ref>section 50323(d)(2) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide staff support to the Federal Board and the State and Local Board to carry out the duties described in section 50313(b) and <ref>section 50323(b) of this title</ref>, respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–298, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2008-07-31">July 31, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2994</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>