<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 413—</num>
<heading>CRIME REPORTS AND STATISTICS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 41301.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress on sexual exploitation of children</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning one hundred and twenty days after <date date="1984-05-21">May 21, 1984</date>, and every year thereafter, the Attorney General shall report to the Congress on prosecutions, convictions, and forfeitures under chapter 110 of title 18.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–292, § 9</ref>, <date date="1984-05-21">May 21, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 206</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41302.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of statistical data on child abuse</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data acquisition for 1987 and 1988</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall acquire from criminal justice agencies statistical data, for the calendar years 1987 and 1988, about the incidence of child abuse, including child sexual abuse, and shall publish annually a summary of such data.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of uniform crime reporting program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As soon as practicable, but in no case later than <date date="1989-01-01">January 1, 1989</date>, the Attorney General shall modify the uniform crime reporting program in the Federal Bureau of Investigation to include data on the age of the victim of the offense and the relationship, if any, of the victim to the offender, for types of offenses that may involve child abuse, including child sexual abuse.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The modification, once made, shall remain in effect until the later of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 10 years after the date it is made; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such ending date as may be set by the Attorney General.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–401, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 906</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41303.</num>
<heading> Uniform Federal Crime Reporting Act of 1988</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “Uniform Federal Crime Reporting Act of 1988”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “Uniform Crime Reports” means the reports authorized under <ref>section 534 of title 28</ref> and administered by the Federal Bureau of Investigation which compiles nationwide criminal statistics for use in law enforcement administration, operation, and management and to assess the nature and type of crime in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of system</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall acquire, collect, classify, and preserve national data on Federal criminal offenses as part of the Uniform Crime Reports.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting by Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">All departments and agencies within the Federal government (including the Department of Defense) which routinely investigate complaints of criminal activity, shall report details about crime within their respective jurisdiction to the Attorney General in a uniform manner and on a form prescribed by the Attorney General. The reporting required by this subsection shall be limited to the reporting of those crimes comprising the Uniform Crime Reports.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall distribute data received pursuant to paragraph (2), not less frequently than annually, to the President, Members of the Congress, State governments, and officials of localities and penal and other institutions participating in the Uniform Crime Reports program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency coordination</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2018-12-21">December 21, 2018</date>, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall coordinate with the head of each department or agency within the Federal Government that is subject to the mandatory reporting requirements under paragraph (2) for the purpose of ensuring successful implementation of paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> For report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 6 months after <date date="2018-12-21">December 21, 2018</date>, the head of each department or agency within the Federal Government that is subject to the mandatory reporting requirements under paragraph (2) shall provide the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation such information as the Director determines is necessary to complete the first report required under paragraph (5).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report by Federal Bureau of Investigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-12-21">December 21, 2018</date>, and annually thereafter, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall prepare and submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report detailing the efforts of the departments and agencies within the Federal Government to come into compliance with paragraph (2). The report shall contain a list of all departments and agencies within the Federal Government subject to paragraph (2) and whether each department or agency is in compliance with paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Role of Federal Bureau of Investigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may designate the Federal Bureau of Investigation as the lead agency for purposes of performing the functions authorized by this section and may appoint or establish such advisory and oversight boards as may be necessary to assist the Bureau in ensuring uniformity, quality, and maximum use of the data collected.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of offenses involving illegal drugs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation is authorized to classify offenses involving illegal drugs and drug trafficking as a part I crime in the Uniform Crime Reports.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $350,000 for fiscal year 1989 and such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section after fiscal year 1989.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall be effective on <date date="1989-01-01">January 1, 1989</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7332</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4468</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–393, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5274</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41304.</num>
<heading> Family and domestic violence: data collection and reporting</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Family violence reporting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under the authority of <ref>section 534 of title 28</ref>, the Attorney General shall require, and include in uniform crime reports, data that indicate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the age of the victim; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the relationship of the victim to the offender, for crimes of murder, aggravated assault, simple assault, rape, sexual offenses, and offenses against children.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Crime Survey</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics, through the annual National Crime Survey, shall collect and publish data that more accurately measures the extent of domestic violence in America, especially the physical and sexual abuse of children and the elderly.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated in fiscal years 1989, 1990, 1991, and 1992, such sums as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7609</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4517</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41305.</num>
<heading> Hate crime statistics</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> This Act may be cited as the “Hate Crime Statistics Act”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under the authority of <ref>section 534 of title 28</ref>, the Attorney General shall acquire data, for each calendar year, about crimes that manifest evidence of prejudice based on race, gender and gender identity, religion, disability, sexual orientation, or ethnicity, including where appropriate the crimes of murder, non-negligent manslaughter; forcible rape; aggravated assault, simple assault, intimidation; arson; and destruction, damage or vandalism of property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall establish guidelines for the collection of such data including the necessary evidence and criteria that must be present for a finding of manifest prejudice and procedures for carrying out the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section creates a cause of action or a right to bring an action, including an action based on discrimination due to sexual orientation. As used in this section, the term “sexual orientation” means consensual homosexuality or heterosexuality. This subsection does not limit any existing cause of action or right to bring an action, including any action under the Administrative Procedure Act [<ref>5 U.S.C. 551</ref> et seq., 701 et seq.] or the All Writs Act [<ref>28 U.S.C. 1651</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Data acquired under this section shall be used only for research or statistical purposes and may not contain any information that may reveal the identity of an individual victim of a crime.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall publish an annual summary of the data acquired under this section, including data about crimes committed by, and crimes directed against, juveniles.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section through fiscal year 2002.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–275, § 1</ref>, <date date="1990-04-23">Apr. 23, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 140</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320926</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2131</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–155, § 7</ref>, <date date="1996-07-03">July 3, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1394</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. E, § 4708</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41306.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress on banking law offenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data collection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Attorney General shall compile and collect data concerning—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the nature and number of civil and criminal investigations, prosecutions, and related proceedings, and civil enforcement and recovery proceedings, in progress with respect to banking law offenses under sections 981, 1008, 1032, and 3322(d) of title 18 and <ref>section 1833a of title 12</ref> and conspiracies to commit any such offense, including inactive investigations of such offenses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the number of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> investigations, prosecutions, and related proceedings described in subparagraph (A) which are inactive as of the close of the reporting period but have not been closed or declined; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> unaddressed referrals which allege criminal misconduct involving offenses described in subparagraph (A),</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">and the reasons such matters are inactive and the referrals unaddressed;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the nature and number of such matters closed, settled, or litigated to conclusion; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the results achieved, including convictions and pretrial diversions, fines and penalties levied, restitution assessed and collected, and damages recovered, in such matters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Analysis and report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall analyze and report to the Congress on the data described in paragraph (1) and its coordination and other related activities named in section 41501(c)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002222">1</ref> of this title and shall provide such report on the data monthly through <date date="1991-12-31">December 31, 1991</date>, and quarterly after such date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specifics of report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The report required by subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> categorize data as to various types of financial institutions and appropriate dollar loss categories;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> disclose data for each Federal judicial district;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> describe the activities of the Financial Institution Fraud Unit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> list—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of institutions, categorized by failed and open institutions, in which evidence of significant fraud, unlawful activity, insider abuse or serious misconduct has been alleged or detected;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> civil, criminal, and administrative enforcement actions, including those of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, brought against offenders;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any settlements or judgments obtained against offenders;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> indictments, guilty pleas, or verdicts obtained against offenders; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the resources allocated in pursuit of investigations, prosecutions, and sentencings (including indictments, guilty pleas, or verdicts obtained against offenders) and related proceedings.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXV, § 2546</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4885</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41307.</num>
<heading> Reporting requirement for missing children</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each Federal, State, and local law enforcement agency shall report each case of a missing child under the age of 21 reported to such agency to the National Crime Information Center of the Department of Justice and, consistent with section 40507 (including rules promulgated pursuant to section 40507(c)) of this title, shall also report such case, either directly or through authorization described in such section to transmit, enter, or share information on such case, to the NamUs databases.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may establish guidelines for the collection of such reports including procedures for carrying out the purposes of this section and <ref>section 41308 of this title</ref>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002223">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual summary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall publish an annual statistical summary of the reports received under this section and <ref>section 41308 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXVII, § 3701</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4966</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–21, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2003-04-30">Apr. 30, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 660</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–327, § 2(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4455</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41308.</num>
<heading> State requirements for reporting missing children</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each State reporting under the provisions of this section and <ref>section 41307 of this title</ref> shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure that no law enforcement agency within the State establishes or maintains any policy that requires the observance of any waiting period before accepting a missing child or unidentified person report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that no law enforcement agency within the State establishes or maintains any policy that requires the removal of a missing person entry from its State law enforcement system, the National Crime Information Center computer database, or the NamUs databases based solely on the age of the person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> provide that each such report and all necessary and available information, which, with respect to each missing child report, shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name, date of birth, sex, race, height, weight, and eye and hair color of the child;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a recent photograph of the child, if available;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the date and location of the last known contact with the child; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the category under which the child is reported missing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">is entered within 2 hours of receipt into the State law enforcement system, the National Crime Information Center computer networks, and the NamUs databases and made available to the Missing Children Information Clearinghouse within the State or other agency designated within the State to receive such reports; and</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> provide that after receiving reports as provided in paragraph (3), the law enforcement agency that entered the report into the National Crime Information Center or the NamUs databases shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> no later than 30 days after the original entry of the record into the State law enforcement system, National Crime Information Center computer networks, and the NamUs databases, verify and update such record with any additional information, including, where available, medical and dental records and a photograph taken during the previous 180 days;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> institute or assist with appropriate search and investigative procedures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> notify the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children of each report received relating to a child reported missing from a foster care family home or childcare institution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> maintain close liaison with State and local child welfare systems and the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children for the exchange of information and technical assistance in the missing children cases; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> grant permission to the National Crime Information Center Terminal Contractor for the State to update the missing person record in the National Crime Information Center computer networks with additional information learned during the investigation relating to the missing person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXVII, § 3702</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4967</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–248, title I, § 154(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title I, § 116(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 244</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–327, § 2(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4455</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41309.</num>
<heading> Reporting on human trafficking</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trafficking offense classification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> classify the offense of human trafficking as a Part I crime in the Uniform Crime Reports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to the extent feasible, establish subcategories for State sex crimes that involve—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a person who is younger than 18 years of age;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use of force, fraud or coercion; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> neither of the elements described in subparagraphs (A) and (B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> classify the offense of human trafficking as a Group A offense for purpose of the National Incident-Based Reporting System.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall revise the Uniform Crime Reporting System <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002224">1</ref> and the National Incident-Based Reporting System to distinguish between reports of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> incidents of assisting or promoting prostitution, which shall include crimes committed by persons who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> do not directly engage in commercial sex acts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> direct, manage, or profit from such acts, such as State pimping and pandering crimes;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> incidents of purchasing prostitution, which shall include crimes committed by persons who purchase or attempt to purchase or trade anything of value for commercial sex acts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> incidents of prostitution, which shall include crimes committed by persons providing or attempting to provide commercial sex acts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> incidents of assisting or promoting prostitution, child labor that is a violation of law, or forced labor of an individual under the age of 18 as described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> incidents of purchasing or soliciting commercial sex acts, child labor that is a violation of law, or forced labor with an individual under the age of 18 as described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title II, § 237(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5083</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–392, § 17</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41310.</num>
<heading> Report on theft of trade secrets occurring abroad</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Director” means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign instrumentality, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “foreign instrumentality”, “foreign agent”, and “trade secret” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 1839 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” includes the District of Columbia and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States company</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States company” means an organization organized under the laws of the United States or a State or political subdivision thereof.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2016-05-11">May 11, 2016</date>, and biannually thereafter, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Intellectual Property Enforcement Coordinator, the Director, and the heads of other appropriate agencies, shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and make publicly available on the Web site of the Department of Justice and disseminate to the public through such other means as the Attorney General may identify, a report on the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The scope and breadth of the theft of the trade secrets of United States companies occurring outside of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The extent to which theft of trade secrets occurring outside of the United States is sponsored by foreign governments, foreign instrumentalities, or foreign agents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The threat posed by theft of trade secrets occurring outside of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The ability and limitations of trade secret owners to prevent the misappropriation of trade secrets outside of the United States, to enforce any judgment against foreign entities for theft of trade secrets, and to prevent imports based on theft of trade secrets overseas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A breakdown of the trade secret protections afforded United States companies by each country that is a trading partner of the United States and enforcement efforts available and undertaken in each such country, including a list identifying specific countries where trade secret theft, laws, or enforcement is a significant problem for United States companies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Instances of the Federal Government working with foreign countries to investigate, arrest, and prosecute entities and individuals involved in the theft of trade secrets outside of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Specific progress made under trade agreements and treaties, including any new remedies enacted by foreign countries, to protect against theft of trade secrets of United States companies outside of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> Recommendations of legislative and executive branch actions that may be undertaken to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduce the threat of and economic impact caused by the theft of the trade secrets of United States companies occurring outside of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> educate United States companies regarding the threats to their trade secrets when taken outside of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide assistance to United States companies to reduce the risk of loss of their trade secrets when taken outside of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide a mechanism for United States companies to confidentially or anonymously report the theft of trade secrets occurring outside of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–153, § 4</ref>, <date date="2016-05-11">May 11, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 382</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41311.</num>
<heading> Improving Department of Justice data collection on mental illness involved in crime</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, on or after the date that is 90 days after the date on which the Attorney General promulgates regulations under subsection (b), any data prepared by, or submitted to, the Attorney General or the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation with respect to the incidences of homicides, law enforcement officers killed, seriously injured, and assaulted, or individuals killed or seriously injured by law enforcement officers shall include data with respect to the involvement of mental illness in such incidences, if any.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2016-12-13">December 13, 2016</date>, the Attorney General shall promulgate or revise regulations as necessary to carry out subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–255, div. B, title XIV, § 14015</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41312.</num>
<heading> Report on female genital mutilation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than one year after <date date="2021-01-05">January 5, 2021</date>, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Secretary of Education, shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an estimate of the number of women and girls in the United States at risk of or who have been subjected to female genital mutilation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the protections available and actions taken, if any, by Federal, State, and local agencies to protect such women and girls; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the actions taken by Federal agencies to educate and assist communities and key stakeholders about female genital mutilation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–309, § 4</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4924</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 41313.</num>
<heading> GAO study on incidence of fatal and non-fatal physical and sexual assault of passengers, TNC drivers, and drivers of other for-hire vehicles</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> GAO report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2023-01-05">January 5, 2023</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that includes the results of a study regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the incidence of fatal and non-fatal physical assault and sexual assault perpetrated in the preceding 2 calendar years (starting with calendar years 2019 and 2020 for the first study)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> against TNC drivers and drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs) by passengers and riders of for-hire vehicles; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> against passengers and riders by other passengers and TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs), including the incidences that are committed by individuals who are not TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles but who pose as TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the nature and specifics of any background checks conducted on prospective TNC drivers and drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs), including any State and local laws requiring those background checks; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the safety steps taken by transportation network companies and other for-hire vehicle services (including taxicab companies) related to rider and driver safety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexual assault defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “sexual assault” means the occurrence of an act that constitutes any nonconsensual sexual act proscribed by Federal, Tribal, or State law, including when the victim lacks capacity to consent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–330, § 2</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6114</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>