<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 211—</num>
<heading>COMBATING CHILD EXPLOITATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21101.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Child exploitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “child exploitation” means any conduct, attempted conduct, or conspiracy to engage in conduct involving a minor that violates section 1591, chapter 109A, chapter 110, and chapter 117 of title 18 or any sexual activity involving a minor for which any person can be charged with a criminal offense.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Child obscenity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “child obscenity” means any visual depiction proscribed by <ref>section 1466A of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “minor” means any person under the age of 18 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexually explicit conduct</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “sexually explicit conduct” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 2256 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–401, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4229</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL STRATEGY FOR CHILD EXPLOITATION PREVENTION AND INTERDICTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21111.</num>
<heading> Establishment of National Strategy for Child Exploitation Prevention and Interdiction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General of the United States shall create and implement a National Strategy for Child Exploitation Prevention and Interdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>, and on February 1 of every second year thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress the National Strategy established under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required contents of National Strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The National Strategy established under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Comprehensive long-range,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002194">1</ref> goals for reducing child exploitation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Annual measurable objectives and specific targets to accomplish long-term, quantifiable goals that the Attorney General determines may be achieved during each year beginning on the date when the National Strategy is submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Annual budget priorities and Federal efforts dedicated to combating child exploitation, including resources dedicated to Internet Crimes Against Children task forces, Project Safe Childhood, FBI Innocent Images Initiative, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, regional forensic computer labs, Internet Safety <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002195">2</ref> programs, and all other entities whose goal or mission is to combat the exploitation of children that receive Federal support.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A 5-year projection for program and budget goals and priorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A review of the policies and work of the Department of Justice related to the prevention and investigation of child exploitation crimes, including efforts at the Office of Justice Programs, the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice, the Executive Office of United States Attorneys, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Office of the Attorney General, the Office of the Deputy Attorney General, the Office of Legal Policy, and any other agency or bureau of the Department of Justice whose activities relate to child exploitation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A description of the Department’s efforts to coordinate with international, State, local, tribal law enforcement, and private sector entities on child exploitation prevention and interdiction efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> Plans for interagency coordination regarding the prevention, investigation, and apprehension of individuals exploiting children, including cooperation and collaboration with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the United States Postal Inspection Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Department of State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Department of Commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Department of Education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Department of Health and Human Services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> other appropriate Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> A review of the Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force Program, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of ICAC task forces and location of each ICAC task force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of trained personnel at each ICAC task force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the amount of Federal grants awarded to each ICAC task force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> an assessment of the Federal, State, and local cooperation in each task force, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of arrests made by each task force;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of criminal referrals to United States attorneys for prosecution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the number of prosecutions and convictions from the referrals made under clause (ii);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the number, if available, of local prosecutions and convictions based on ICAC task force investigations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any other information demonstrating the level of Federal, State, and local coordination and cooperation, as such information is to be determined by the Attorney General;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an assessment of the training opportunities and technical assistance available to support ICAC task force grantees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an assessment of the success of the Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force Program at leveraging State and local resources and matching funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> An assessment of the technical assistance and support available for Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies, in the prevention, investigation, and prosecution of child exploitation crimes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> A review of the backlog of forensic analysis for child exploitation cases at each FBI Regional Forensic lab and an estimate of the backlog at State and local labs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Plans for reducing the forensic backlog described in paragraph (10), if any, at Federal, State and local forensic labs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> A review of the Federal programs related to child exploitation prevention and education, including those related to Internet safety, including efforts by the private sector and nonprofit entities, or any other initiatives, that have proven successful in promoting child safety and Internet safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> An assessment of the future trends, challenges, and opportunities, including new technologies, that will impact Federal, State, local, and tribal efforts to combat child exploitation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Plans for liaisons with the judicial branches of the Federal and State governments on matters relating to child exploitation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<chapeau> An assessment of Federal investigative and prosecution activity relating to reported incidents of child exploitation crimes, which shall include a number of factors, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of high-priority suspects (identified because of the volume of suspected criminal activity or because of the danger to the community or a potential victim) who were investigated and prosecuted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of investigations, arrests, prosecutions and convictions for a crime of child exploitation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the average sentence imposed and statutory maximum for each crime of child exploitation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<chapeau> A review of all available statistical data indicating the overall magnitude of child pornography trafficking in the United States and internationally, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of computers or computer users, foreign and domestic, observed engaging in, or suspected by law enforcement agencies and other sources of engaging in, peer-to-peer file sharing of child pornography;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of computers or computer users, foreign and domestic, observed engaging in, or suspected by law enforcement agencies and other reporting sources of engaging in, buying and selling, or other commercial activity related to child pornography;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number of computers or computer users, foreign and domestic, observed engaging in, or suspected by law enforcement agencies and other sources of engaging in, all other forms of activity related to child pornography;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the number of tips or other statistical data from the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children’s CyberTipline and other data indicating the magnitude of child pornography trafficking; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any other statistical data indicating the type, nature, and extent of child exploitation crime in the United States and abroad.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<chapeau> Copies of recent relevant research and studies related to child exploitation, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> studies related to the link between possession or trafficking of child pornography and actual abuse of a child;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> studies related to establishing a link between the types of files being viewed or shared and the type of illegal activity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other research, studies, and available information related to child exploitation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> A review of the extent of cooperation, coordination, and mutual support between private sector and other entities and organizations and Federal agencies, including the involvement of States, local and tribal government agencies to the extent Federal programs are involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> The results of the Project Safe Childhood Conference or other conferences or meetings convened by the Department of Justice related to combating child exploitation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment of high-level official</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall designate a senior official at the Department of Justice with experience in investigating or prosecuting child exploitation cases as the National Coordinator for Child Exploitation Prevention and Interdiction who shall be responsible for coordinating the development of the National Strategy established under subsection (a). The National Coordinator for Child Exploitation Prevention and Interdiction shall be a position in the Senior Executive Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The duties of the official designated under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> acting as a liaison with all Federal agencies regarding the development of the National Strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> working to ensure that there is proper coordination among agencies in developing the National Strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> being knowledgeable about budget priorities and familiar with all efforts within the Department of Justice and the FBI related to child exploitation prevention and interdiction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> communicating the National Strategy to Congress and being available to answer questions related to the strategy at congressional hearings, if requested by committees of appropriate jurisdictions, on the contents of the National Strategy and progress of the Department of Justice in implementing the National Strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–401, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4230</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–206, § 6</ref>, <date date="2012-12-07">Dec. 7, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21112.</num>
<heading> Establishment of National ICAC Task Force Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established within the Department of Justice, under the general authority of the Attorney General, a National Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force Program (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “ICAC Task Force Program”), which shall consist of a national program of State and local law enforcement task forces dedicated to developing effective responses to online enticement of children by sexual predators, child exploitation, and child obscenity and pornography cases.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intent of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It is the purpose and intent of Congress that the ICAC Task Force Program established under paragraph (1) is intended to continue the ICAC Task Force Program authorized under title I of the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998, and funded under title IV of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 [<ref>34 U.S.C. 11291</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State representation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The ICAC Task Force Program established under subsection (a) shall include at least 1 ICAC task force in each State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capacity and continuity of investigations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In order to maintain established capacity and continuity of investigations and prosecutions of child exploitation cases, the Attorney General, shall, in establishing the ICAC Task Force Program under subsection (a) consult with and consider all 59 task forces in existence on <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>. The Attorney General shall include all existing ICAC task forces in the ICAC Task Force Program, unless the Attorney General makes a determination that an existing ICAC <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002196">1</ref> does not have a proven track record of success.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ongoing review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Attorney General shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct periodic reviews of the effectiveness of each ICAC task force established under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have the discretion to establish a new task force if the Attorney General determines that such decision will enhance the effectiveness of combating child exploitation provided that the Attorney General notifies Congress in advance of any such decision and that each state <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002197">2</ref> maintains at least 1 ICAC task force at all times.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Attorney General may establish national training programs to support the mission of the ICAC task forces, including the effective use of the National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In establishing training courses under this paragraph, the Attorney General may not award any one entity other than a law enforcement agency more than $4,000,000 annually to establish and conduct training courses for ICAC task force members and other law enforcement officials.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Attorney General shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> conduct periodic reviews of the effectiveness of each training session authorized by this paragraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> consider outside reports related to the effective use of Federal funding in making future grant awards for training.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–401, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–206, § 5</ref>, <date date="2012-12-07">Dec. 7, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21113.</num>
<heading> Purpose of ICAC task forces</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The ICAC Task Force Program, and each State or local ICAC task force that is part of the national program of task forces, shall be dedicated toward—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> increasing the investigative capabilities of State and local law enforcement officers in the detection, investigation, and apprehension of Internet crimes against children offenses or offenders, including technology-facilitated child exploitation offenses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conducting proactive and reactive Internet crimes against children investigations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> providing training and technical assistance to ICAC task forces and other Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies in the areas of investigations, forensics, prosecution, community outreach, and capacity-building, using recognized experts to assist in the development and delivery of training programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> increasing the number of Internet crimes against children offenses being investigated and prosecuted in both Federal and State courts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> creating a multiagency task force response to Internet crimes against children offenses within each State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> participating in the Department of Justice’s Project Safe Childhood initiative, the purpose of which is to combat technology-facilitated sexual exploitation crimes against children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> enhancing nationwide responses to Internet crimes against children offenses, including assisting other ICAC task forces, as well as other Federal, State, and local agencies with Internet crimes against children investigations and prosecutions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> developing and delivering Internet crimes against children public awareness and prevention programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> participating in such other activities, both proactive and reactive, that will enhance investigations and prosecutions of Internet crimes against children.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–401, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21114.</num>
<heading> Duties and functions of task forces</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each State or local ICAC task force that is part of the national program of task forces shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consist of State and local investigators, prosecutors, forensic specialists, and education specialists who are dedicated to addressing the goals of such task force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> work consistently toward achieving the purposes described in <ref>section 21113 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> engage in proactive investigations, forensic examinations, and effective prosecutions of Internet crimes against children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide forensic, preventive, and investigative assistance to parents, educators, prosecutors, law enforcement, and others concerned with Internet crimes against children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> develop multijurisdictional, multiagency responses and partnerships to Internet crimes against children offenses through ongoing informational, administrative, and technological support to other State and local law enforcement agencies, as a means for such agencies to acquire the necessary knowledge, personnel, and specialized equipment to investigate and prosecute such offenses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> participate in nationally coordinated investigations in any case in which the Attorney General determines such participation to be necessary, as permitted by the available resources of such task force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> establish or adopt investigative and prosecution standards, consistent with established norms, to which such task force shall comply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> investigate, and seek prosecution on, tips related to Internet crimes against children, including tips from Operation Fairplay, the National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established in <ref>section 21115 of this title</ref>, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children’s CyberTipline, ICAC task forces, and other Federal, State, and local agencies, with priority being given to investigative leads that indicate the possibility of identifying or rescuing child victims, including investigative leads that indicate a likelihood of seriousness of offense or dangerousness to the community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> develop procedures for handling seized evidence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> maintain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such reports and records as are required under this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such other reports and records as determined by the Attorney General; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> seek to comply with national standards regarding the investigation and prosecution of Internet crimes against children, as set forth by the Attorney General, to the extent such standards are consistent with the law of the State where the task force is located.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–401, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21115.</num>
<heading> National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall establish, consistent with all existing Federal laws relating to the protection of privacy, a National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System. The system shall not be used to search for or obtain any information that does not involve the use of the Internet to facilitate child exploitation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intent of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the purpose and intent of Congress that the National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established in subsection (a) is intended to continue and build upon Operation Fairplay developed by the Wyoming Attorney General’s office, which has established a secure, dynamic undercover infrastructure that has facilitated online law enforcement investigations of child exploitation, information sharing, and the capacity to collect and aggregate data on the extent of the problems of child exploitation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of system</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established under subsection (a) shall be dedicated to assisting and supporting credentialed law enforcement agencies authorized to investigate child exploitation in accordance with Federal, State, local, and tribal laws, including by providing assistance and support to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Federal agencies investigating and prosecuting child exploitation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the ICAC Task Force Program established under <ref>section 21112 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> State, local, and tribal agencies investigating and prosecuting child exploitation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> foreign or international law enforcement agencies, subject to approval by the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cyber safe deconfliction and information sharing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be housed and maintained within the Department of Justice or a credentialed law enforcement agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be made available for a nominal charge to support credentialed law enforcement agencies in accordance with subsection (c); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> allow Federal, State, local, and tribal agencies and ICAC task forces investigating and prosecuting child exploitation to contribute and access data for use in resolving case conflicts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide, directly or in partnership with a credentialed law enforcement agency, a dynamic undercover infrastructure to facilitate online law enforcement investigations of child exploitation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> facilitate the development of essential software and network capability for law enforcement participants; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide software or direct hosting and support for online investigations of child exploitation activities, or, in the alternative, provide users with a secure connection to an alternative system that provides such capabilities, provided that the system is hosted within a governmental agency or a credentialed law enforcement agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection and reporting of data</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established under subsection (a) shall ensure the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real-time reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">All child exploitation cases involving local child victims that are reasonably detectable using available software and data are, immediately upon their detection, made available to participating law enforcement agencies.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High-priority suspects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Every 30 days, at minimum, the National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identify high-priority suspects, as such suspects are determined by indicators of seriousness of offense or dangerousness to the community or a potential local victim; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> report all such identified high-priority suspects to participating law enforcement agencies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any statistical data indicating the overall magnitude of child pornography trafficking and child exploitation in the United States and internationally is made available and included in the National Strategy, as is required under <ref>section 21111(c)(16) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the ability of participating law enforcement agencies to disseminate investigative leads or statistical information in accordance with State and local laws.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory requirements of network</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established under subsection (a) shall develop, deploy, and maintain an integrated technology and training program that provides—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a secure, online system for Federal law enforcement agencies, ICAC task forces, and other State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies for use in resolving case conflicts, as provided in subsection (d);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a secure system enabling online communication and collaboration by Federal law enforcement agencies, ICAC task forces, and other State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies regarding ongoing investigations, investigatory techniques, best practices, and any other relevant news and professional information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a secure online data storage and analysis system for use by Federal law enforcement agencies, ICAC task forces, and other State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> secure connections or interaction with State and local law enforcement computer networks, consistent with reasonable and established security protocols and guidelines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> guidelines for use of the National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System by Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies and ICAC task forces; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> training and technical assistance on the use of the National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System by Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies and ICAC task forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System Steering Committee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall establish a National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System Steering Committee to provide guidance to the Network relating to the program under subsection (f), and to assist in the development of strategic plans for the System. The Steering Committee shall consist of 10 members with expertise in child exploitation prevention and interdiction prosecution, investigation, or prevention, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 3 representatives elected by the local directors of the ICAC task forces, such representatives shall represent different geographic regions of the country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 1 representative of the Department of Justice Office of Information Services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> 1 representative from Operation Fairplay, currently hosted at the Wyoming Office of the Attorney General;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> 1 representative from the law enforcement agency having primary responsibility for hosting and maintaining the National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> 1 representative of the Federal Bureau of Investigation’s Innocent Images National Initiative or Regional Computer Forensic Lab program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> 1 representative of the Immigration and Customs Enforcement’s Cyber Crimes Center;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> 1 representative of the United States Postal Inspection Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> 1 representative of the Department of Justice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2016, $2,000,000 to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–401, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4236</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–206, § 8</ref>, <date date="2012-12-07">Dec. 7, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1493</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21116.</num>
<heading> ICAC grant program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General is authorized to award grants to State and local ICAC task forces to assist in carrying out the duties and functions described under <ref>section 21114 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Formula grants</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of formula</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">At least 75 percent of the total funds appropriated to carry out this section shall be available to award or otherwise distribute grants pursuant to a funding formula established by the Attorney General in accordance with the requirements in subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Formula requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any formula established by the Attorney General under subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> ensure that each State or local ICAC task force shall, at a minimum, receive an amount equal to 0.5 percent of the funds available to award or otherwise distribute grants under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> take into consideration the following factors:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The population of each State, as determined by the most recent decennial census performed by the Bureau of the Census.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> The number of investigative leads within the applicant’s jurisdiction generated by Operation Fairplay, the ICAC Data Network, the CyberTipline, and other sources.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> The number of criminal cases related to Internet crimes against children referred to a task force for Federal, State, or local prosecution.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> The number of successful prosecutions of child exploitation cases by a task force.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> The amount of training, technical assistance, and public education or outreach by a task force related to the prevention, investigation, or prosecution of child exploitation offenses.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> Such other criteria as the Attorney General determines demonstrate the level of need for additional resources by a task force.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution of remaining funds based on need</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any funds remaining from the total funds appropriated to carry out this section after funds have been made available to award or otherwise distribute formula grants under paragraph (2)(A) shall be distributed to State and local ICAC task forces based upon need, as set forth by criteria established by the Attorney General. Such criteria shall include the factors under paragraph (2)(B)(ii).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A State or local ICAC task force shall contribute matching non-Federal funds in an amount equal to not less than 25 percent of the amount of funds received by the State or local ICAC task force under subparagraph (A). A State or local ICAC task force that is not able or willing to contribute matching funds in accordance with this subparagraph shall not be eligible for funds under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Attorney General may waive, in whole or in part, the matching requirement under subparagraph (B) if the State or local ICAC task force demonstrates good cause or financial hardship.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State or local ICAC task force seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each application submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> describe the activities for which assistance under this section is sought; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide such additional assurances as the Attorney General determines to be essential to ensure compliance with the requirements of this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allowable uses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Grants awarded under this section may be used to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> hire personnel, investigators, prosecutors, education specialists, and forensic specialists;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish and support forensic laboratories utilized in Internet crimes against children investigations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> support investigations and prosecutions of Internet crimes against children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conduct and assist with education programs to help children and parents protect themselves from Internet predators;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> conduct and attend training sessions related to successful investigations and prosecutions of Internet crimes against children; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> fund any other activities directly related to preventing, investigating, or prosecuting Internet crimes against children.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> ICAC reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To measure the results of the activities funded by grants under this section, and to assist the Attorney General in complying with the Government Performance and Results Act (<ref>Public Law 103–62</ref>; <ref>107 Stat. 285</ref>), each State or local ICAC task force receiving a grant under this section shall, on an annual basis, submit a report to the Attorney General that sets forth the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Staffing levels of the task force, including the number of investigators, prosecutors, education specialists, and forensic specialists dedicated to investigating and prosecuting Internet crimes against children.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Investigation and prosecution performance measures of the task force, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of investigations initiated related to Internet crimes against children;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of arrests related to Internet crimes against children; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> the number of prosecutions for Internet crimes against children, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> whether the prosecution resulted in a conviction for such crime; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the sentence and the statutory maximum for such crime under State law.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The number of referrals made by the task force to the United States Attorneys office, including whether the referral was accepted by the United States Attorney.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Statistics that account for the disposition of investigations that do not result in arrests or prosecutions, such as referrals to other law enforcement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The number of investigative technical assistance sessions that the task force provided to nonmember law enforcement agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The number of computer forensic examinations that the task force completed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The number of law enforcement agencies participating in Internet crimes against children program standards established by the task force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>, the Attorney General shall submit a report to Congress on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the progress of the development of the ICAC Task Force Program established under <ref>section 21112 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of Federal and State investigations, prosecutions, and convictions in the prior 12-month period related to child exploitation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–401, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21117.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2009;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2010;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2011;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2012;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2013 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002198">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2014;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2015;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2016;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2017; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> $60,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2024.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds appropriated under subsection (a) shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–401, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–206, § 7</ref>, <date date="2012-12-07">Dec. 7, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1493</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–82, § 2</ref>, <date date="2017-11-02">Nov. 2, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1266</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–262, § 2</ref>, <date date="2022-12-21">Dec. 21, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ADDITIONAL MEASURES TO COMBAT CHILD EXPLOITATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21131.</num>
<heading> Additional regional computer forensic labs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall establish additional computer forensic capacity to address the current backlog for computer forensics, including for child exploitation investigations. The Attorney General may utilize funds under this subchapter to increase capacity at existing regional forensic laboratories or to add laboratories under the Regional Computer Forensic Laboratories Program operated by the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of new resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The additional forensic capacity established by resources provided under this section shall be dedicated to assist Federal agencies, State and local Internet Crimes Against Children task forces, and other Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies in preventing, investigating, and prosecuting Internet crimes against children.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> New computer forensic labs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Attorney General determines that new regional computer forensic laboratories are required under subsection (a) to best address existing backlogs, such new laboratories shall be established pursuant to subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location of new labs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The location of any new regional computer forensic laboratories under this section shall be determined by the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Regional Computer Forensic Laboratory National Steering Committee, and other relevant stakeholders.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-10-13">October 13, 2008</date>, and every year thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a report to the Congress on how the funds appropriated under this section were utilized.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for fiscal years 2009 through 2013, $2,000,000 to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–401, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>