<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 213—</num>
<heading>RAPE SURVIVOR CHILD CUSTODY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered formula grant</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “covered formula grant” means a grant under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> part T of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 3796gg</ref> et seq.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002199">1</ref> (commonly referred to as the “STOP Violence Against Women Formula Grant Program”); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 12511 of this title</ref> (commonly referred to as the “Sexual Assault Services Program”).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “termination” means, when used with respect to parental rights, a complete and final termination of the parent’s right to custody of, guardianship of, visitation with, access to, and inheritance from a child.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to require a State, in order to receive an increase in the amount provided to the State under the covered formula grants under this chapter, to have in place a law that terminates any obligation of a person who fathered a child through rape to support the child.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21302.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Men who father children through rape should be prohibited from visiting or having custody of those children.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Thousands of rape-related pregnancies occur annually in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A substantial number of women choose to raise their child conceived through rape and, as a result, may face custody battles with their rapists.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Rape is one of the most under-prosecuted serious crimes, with estimates of criminal conviction occurring in less than 5 percent of rapes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The clear and convincing evidence standard is the most common standard for termination of parental rights among the 50 States, territories, and the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Supreme Court established that the clear and convincing evidence standard satisfies due process for allegations to terminate or restrict parental rights in Santosky v. Kramer (455 U.S. 745 (1982)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Currently only 10 States have statutes allowing rape survivors to petition for the termination of parental rights of the rapist based on clear and convincing evidence that the child was conceived through rape.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> A rapist pursuing parental or custody rights causes the survivor to have continued interaction with the rapist, which can have traumatic psychological effects on the survivor, and can make it more difficult for her to recover.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> These traumatic effects on the mother can severely negatively impact her ability to raise a healthy child.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Rapists may use the threat of pursuing custody or parental rights to coerce survivors into not prosecuting rape, or otherwise harass, intimidate, or manipulate them.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21303.</num>
<heading> Increased funding for formula grants authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall increase the amount provided to a State under the covered formula grants in accordance with this chapter if the State has in place a law that allows the mother of any child that was conceived through rape to seek court-ordered termination of the parental rights of her rapist with regard to that child, which the court is authorized to grant upon clear and convincing evidence of rape.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21304.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A State seeking an increase in the amount provided to the State under the covered formula grants shall include in the application of the State for each covered formula grant such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require, including information about the law described in <ref>section 21303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21305.</num>
<heading> Grant increase</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount of the increase provided to a State under the covered formula grants under this chapter shall be equal to not more than 10 percent of the average of the total amount of funding provided to the State under the covered formula grants under the 3 most recent awards to the State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21306.</num>
<heading> Period of increase</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall provide an increase in the amount provided to a State under the covered formula grants under this chapter for a 2-year period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may not provide an increase in the amount provided to a State under the covered formula grants under this chapter more than 4 times.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21307.</num>
<heading> Allocation of increased formula grant funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall allocate an increase in the amount provided to a State under the covered formula grants under this chapter such that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 25 percent <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002200">1</ref> the amount of the increase is provided under the program described in <ref>section 21301(1)(A) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 75 percent <sup>1</sup> the amount of the increase is provided under the program described in <ref>section 21301(1)(B) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 258</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21308.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this chapter $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title IV, § 409</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 258</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>