<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 607—</num>
<heading>PROJECT SAFE NEIGHBORHOODS BLOCK GRANT PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 60701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “firearms offenses” means an offense under section 922 or 924 of title 18;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Program” means the Project Safe Neighborhoods Block Grant Program established under <ref>section 60702 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “transnational organized crime group” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 2708(k)(6) of title 22</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–185, § 2</ref>, <date date="2018-06-18">June 18, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1485</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 60702.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General of the United States is authorized to establish and carry out a program, to be known as the “Project Safe Neighborhoods Block Grant Program” within the Office of Justice Programs at the Department of Justice.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–185, § 3</ref>, <date date="2018-06-18">June 18, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1485</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 60703.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Project Safe Neighborhoods Block Grant Program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of the Program is to foster and improve existing partnerships between Federal, State, and local agencies, including the United States Attorney in each Federal judicial district, entities representing members of the community affected by increased violence, victims’ advocates, and researchers to create safer neighborhoods through sustained reductions in violent crimes by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> developing and executing comprehensive strategic plans to reduce violent crimes, including the enforcement of gun laws, and prioritizing efforts focused on identified subsets of individuals or organizations responsible for increasing violence in a particular geographic area;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> developing evidence-based and data-driven intervention and prevention initiatives, including juvenile justice projects and activities which may include street-level outreach, conflict mediation, provision of treatment and social services, and the changing of community norms, in order to reduce violence; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> collecting data on outcomes achieved through the Program, including the effect on the violent crime rate, incarceration rate, and recidivism rate of the jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional purpose areas</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to the purpose described in subsection (a), the Attorney General may use funds authorized under this chapter for any of the following purposes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> competitive and evidence-based programs to reduce gun crime and gang violence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Edward Byrne criminal justice innovation program; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002236">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> community-based violence prevention initiatives; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> gang and youth violence education, prevention and intervention, and related activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–185, § 4</ref>, <date date="2018-06-18">June 18, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1485</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 60704.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall issue guidance to create, carry out, and administer the Program in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funds to be directed to local control</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts made available as grants under the Program shall be, to the greatest extent practicable, locally controlled to address problems that are identified locally.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Task Forces</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Thirty percent of the amounts made available as grants under the Program each fiscal year shall be granted to Gang Task Forces in regions experiencing a significant or increased presence of criminal or transnational organizations engaging in high levels of violent crime, firearms offenses, human trafficking, and drug trafficking.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts made available as grants under the Program shall be used to prioritize the investigation and prosecution of individuals who have an aggravating or leadership role in a criminal or transnational organization described in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–185, § 5</ref>, <date date="2018-06-18">June 18, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1486</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 60705.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General to carry out the Program $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2021.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–185, § 6</ref>, <date date="2018-06-18">June 18, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1486</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>