<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 201—</num>
<heading>VICTIM RIGHTS, COMPENSATION, AND ASSISTANCE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>CRIME VICTIMS FUND</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20101.</num>
<heading> Crime Victims Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is created in the Treasury a separate account to be known as the Crime Victims Fund (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Fund”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fines deposited in Fund; penalties; forfeited appearance bonds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as limited by subsection (c), there shall be deposited in the Fund—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> all fines that are collected from persons convicted of offenses against the United States except—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> fines available for use by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> section 11(d) of the Endangered Species Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1540(d)</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> section 6(d) of the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3375(d)</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> fines to be paid into—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the railroad unemployment insurance account pursuant to the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act (<ref>45 U.S.C. 351</ref> et seq.);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Postal Service Fund pursuant to sections 2601(a)(2) and 2003 of title 39 and for the purposes set forth in <ref>section 404(a)(7) of title 39</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the navigable waters revolving fund pursuant to section 311 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1321</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> county public school funds pursuant to <ref>section 3613 of title 18</ref>;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> penalty assessments collected under <ref>section 3013 of title 18</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002148">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the proceeds of forfeited appearance bonds, bail bonds, and collateral collected under <ref>section 3146 of title 18</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any money ordered to be paid into the Fund under <ref>section 3671(c)(2) of title 18</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> any gifts, bequests, or donations to the Fund from private entities or individuals, which the Director is hereby authorized to accept for deposit into the Fund, except that the Director is not hereby authorized to accept any such gift, bequest, or donation that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> attaches conditions inconsistent with applicable laws or regulations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is conditioned upon or would require the expenditure of appropriated funds that are not available to the Office for Victims of Crime; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> any funds that would otherwise be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury collected pursuant to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a deferred prosecution agreement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a non-prosecution agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retention of sums in Fund; availability for expenditure without fiscal year limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Sums deposited in the Fund shall remain in the Fund and be available for expenditure under this subchapter for grants under this subchapter without fiscal year limitation. Notwithstanding subsection (d)(5), all sums deposited in the Fund in any fiscal year that are not made available for obligation by Congress in the subsequent fiscal year shall remain in the Fund for obligation in future fiscal years, without fiscal year limitation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability for judicial branch administrative costs; grant program percentages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Fund shall be available as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–119, title I, § 109(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2457</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the first $10,000,000 deposited in the Fund shall be available for grants under <ref>section 20104 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> For any fiscal year for which the amount deposited in the Fund is greater than the amount deposited in the Fund for fiscal year 1998, the $10,000,000 referred to in subparagraph (A) plus an amount equal to 50 percent of the increase in the amount from fiscal year 1998 shall be available for grants under <ref>section 20104 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Amounts available under this subparagraph for any fiscal year shall not exceed $20,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Of the sums remaining in the Fund in any particular fiscal year after compliance with paragraph (2), such sums as may be necessary shall be available only for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the United States Attorneys Offices and the Federal Bureau of Investigation to provide and improve services for the benefit of crime victims in the Federal criminal justice system (as described in section 3771 or section 3772, as it relates to direct services, of title 18 and <ref>section 20141 of this title</ref>) through victim coordinators, victims’ specialists, and advocates, including for the administrative support of victim coordinators and advocates providing such services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a Victim Notification System.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Amounts made available under subparagraph (A) may not be used for any purpose that is not specified in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Of the remaining amount to be distributed from the Fund in a particular fiscal year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 47.5 percent shall be available for grants under <ref>section 20102 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 47.5 percent shall be available for grants under <ref>section 20103(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 5 percent shall be available for grants under <ref>section 20103(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In addition to the amounts distributed under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), the Director may set aside up to $50,000,000 from the amounts transferred to the Fund in response to the airplane hijackings and terrorist acts that occurred on <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, as an antiterrorism emergency reserve. The Director may replenish any amounts obligated from such reserve in subsequent fiscal years by setting aside up to 5 percent of the amounts remaining in the Fund in any fiscal year after distributing amounts under paragraphs (2), (3) and (4). Such reserve shall not exceed $50,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The antiterrorism emergency reserve referred to in subparagraph (A) may be used for supplemental grants under <ref>section 20105 of this title</ref> and to provide compensation to victims of international terrorism under <ref>section 20106 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Amounts in the antiterrorism emergency reserve established pursuant to subparagraph (A) may be carried over from fiscal year to fiscal year. Notwithstanding subsection (c) and section 619 of the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001 (and any similar limitation on Fund obligations in any future Act, unless the same should expressly refer to this section), any such amounts carried over shall not be subject to any limitation on obligations from amounts deposited to or available in the Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Director may set aside up to $10,000,000 of the amounts remaining in the Fund in any fiscal year after distributing the amounts under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), in a Child Pornography Victims Reserve, which may be used by the Attorney General for payments under <ref>section 2259(d) of title 18</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Amounts in the reserve may be carried over from fiscal year to fiscal year, but the total amount of the reserve shall not exceed $10,000,000. Notwithstanding subsection (c) and any limitation on Fund obligations in any future Act, unless the same should expressly refer to this section, any such amounts carried over shall not be subject to any limitation on obligations from amounts deposited to or available in the Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts awarded and unspent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amount awarded as part of a grant under this subchapter that remains unspent at the end of a fiscal year in which the grant is made may be expended for the purpose for which the grant is made at any time during the 3 succeeding fiscal years, at the end of which period, any remaining unobligated sums shall be available for deposit into the emergency reserve fund referred to in subsection (d)(5) at the discretion of the Director, except that renewals and extensions beyond that period may be granted at the discretion of the Attorney General. Any remaining unobligated sums shall be returned to the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Offenses against the United States” as excluding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “offenses against the United States” does not include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a criminal violation of the Uniform Code of Military Justice (<ref>10 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an offense against the laws of the District of Columbia; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an offense triable by an Indian tribal court or Court of Indian Offenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants for Indian tribes; child abuse cases</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General shall use 15 percent of the funds available under subsection (d)(2) to make grants for the purpose of assisting Native American Indian tribes in developing, establishing, and operating programs designed to improve—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the handling of child abuse cases, particularly cases of child sexual abuse, in a manner which limits additional trauma to the child victim; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the investigation and prosecution of cases of child abuse, particularly child sexual abuse.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may use 5 percent of the funds available under subsection (d)(2) (prior to distribution) for grants to Indian tribes to establish child victim assistance programs, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> As used in this subsection, the term “tribe” <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002149">2</ref> has the meaning given that term in section 5304(b) <sup>1</sup> of title 25.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1402</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–401, title I, § 102(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 904</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 82</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3619</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7121, 7124, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4419</ref>, 4422; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title X, § 1001</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–121, title I, § 110(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-27">Oct. 27, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXIII, § 230201</ref>, title XXXIII, § 330025(a), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2079</ref>, 2151; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title II</ref>, §§ 232(b), (c)(1), 236, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1243</ref>, 1244, 1247; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(a) [title I, § 112]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009</ref>, 3009–21; <ref>Pub. L. 105–119, title I, § 109(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2457</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(1) [title I, § 119]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–22; <ref>Pub. L. 106–177, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-03-10">Mar. 10, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 36</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. C, § 2003(b)</ref>, (c)(2), (d), <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1544</ref>, 1546; <ref>Pub. L. 106–553, § 1(a)(2) [title I, § 113, formerly § 114]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2762</ref>, 2762A–68, renumbered <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(4) [div. A, § 213(a)(2)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–179; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VI, § 621(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 370</ref>, 371; <ref>Pub. L. 107–77, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="2001-11-28">Nov. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1132</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3107</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–163, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1866</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–236, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-10-07">Oct. 7, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 967</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–299, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-07">Dec. 7, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4387</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–27, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-07-22">July 22, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 301</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20102.</num>
<heading> Crime victim compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Director; grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Director shall make an annual grant from the Fund to an eligible crime victim compensation program of 75 percent of the amounts awarded during the preceding fiscal year, other than amounts awarded for property damage. Except as provided in paragraph (4), a grant under this section shall be used by such program only for awards of compensation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the sums available in the Fund for grants under this section are insufficient to provide grants as provided in paragraph (1), the Director shall make, from the sums available, a grant to each eligible crime victim compensation program so that all such programs receive the same percentage of the amounts awarded by such program during the preceding fiscal year, other than amounts awarded for property damage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the purposes of calculating amounts awarded in the previous fiscal year under this subsection, the Director shall not require eligible crime victim compensation programs to deduct recovery costs or collections from restitution or from subrogation for payment under a civil lawsuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Not more than 5 percent of a grant made under this section may be used for training purposes and the administration of the State crime victim compensation program receiving the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible crime victim compensation programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A crime victim compensation program is an eligible crime victim compensation program for the purposes of this section if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> such program is operated by a State and offers compensation to victims and survivors of victims of criminal violence, including drunk driving and domestic violence for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> medical expenses attributable to a physical injury resulting from compensable crime, including expenses for mental health counseling and care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> loss of wages attributable to a physical injury resulting from a compensable crime; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> funeral expenses attributable to a death resulting from a compensable crime;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such program promotes victim cooperation with the reasonable requests of law enforcement authorities, except if a program determines such cooperation may be impacted due to a victim’s age, physical condition, psychological state, cultural or linguistic barriers, or any other health or safety concern that jeopardizes the victim’s wellbeing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> such State certifies that grants received under this section will not be used to supplant State funds otherwise available to provide crime victim compensation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> such program, as to compensable crimes occurring within the State, makes compensation awards to victims who are nonresidents of the State on the basis of the same criteria used to make awards to victims who are residents of such State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> such program provides compensation to victims of Federal crimes occurring within the State on the same basis that such program provides compensation to victims of State crimes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> such program provides compensation to residents of the State who are victims of crimes occurring outside the State if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the crimes would be compensable crimes had they occurred inside that State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the places the crimes occurred in are States not having eligible crime victim compensation programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> such program does not, except pursuant to rules issued by the program to prevent unjust enrichment of the offender, deny compensation to any victim because of that victim’s familial relationship to the offender, or because of the sharing of a residence by the victim and the offender;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> such program does not provide compensation to any person who has been convicted of an offense under Federal law with respect to any time period during which the person is delinquent in paying a fine, other monetary penalty, or restitution imposed for the offense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> beginning not later than 3 years after <date date="2022-03-15">March 15, 2022</date>, such program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> provides a waiver for any application filing deadline imposed by the program for a crime victim if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the crime victim is otherwise eligible for compensation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the delay in filing the application was a result of a delay in the testing of, or a delay in the DNA profile matching from, a sexual assault forensic examination kit or biological material collected as evidence related to a sexual offense; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not require the crime victim to undergo an appeals process to have the application of the crime victim considered for a filing deadline waiver under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> such program provides such other information and assurances related to the purposes of this section as the Director may reasonably require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion from income, resources, and assets for purposes of means tests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law (other than title IV of <ref>Public Law 107–42</ref>), for the purpose of any maximum allowed income, resource, or asset eligibility requirement in any Federal, State, or local government program using Federal funds that provides medical or other assistance (or payment or reimbursement of the cost of such assistance), any amount of crime victim compensation that the applicant receives through a crime victim compensation program under this section shall not be included in the income, resources, or assets of the applicant, nor shall that amount reduce the amount of the assistance available to the applicant from Federal, State, or local government programs using Federal funds, unless the total amount of assistance that the applicant receives from all such programs is sufficient to fully compensate the applicant for losses suffered as a result of the crime.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “property damage” does not include damage to prosthetic devices, eyeglasses or other corrective lenses, or dental devices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “medical expenses” includes, to the extent provided under the eligible crime victim compensation program, expenses for eyeglasses or other corrective lenses, for dental services and devices and prosthetic devices, and for services rendered in accordance with a method of healing recognized by the law of the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “compensable crime” means a crime the victims of which are eligible for compensation under the eligible crime victim compensation program, and includes crimes, whose victims suffer death or personal injury, that are described in <ref>section 247 of title 18</ref>, driving while intoxicated, and domestic violence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, and any other possession or territory of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “recovery costs” means expenses for personnel directly involved in the recovery efforts to obtain collections from restitution or from subrogation for payment under a civil law suit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to certain Federal programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law, if the compensation paid by an eligible crime victim compensation program would cover costs that a Federal program, including the program established under title IV of <ref>Public Law 107–42</ref>, or a federally financed State or local program, would otherwise pay,— <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002150">1</ref></chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such crime victim compensation program shall not pay that compensation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the other program shall make its payments without regard to the existence of the crime victim compensation program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1403</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2171</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7123(b)(1)–(3), 7125, 7126, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4421–4423</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXIII</ref>, §§ 230202, 230203, title XXXIII, § 330025(b), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2079</ref>, 2151; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title II</ref>, §§ 233(a), (b), 234(a)(1), (b), <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1244</ref>, 1245; <ref>Pub. L. 104–155, § 5</ref>, <date date="1996-07-03">July 3, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1394</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VI, § 622(a)</ref>–(e)(1), <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 371</ref>, 372; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1133(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3108</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–27, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-07-22">July 22, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title XIII</ref>, §§ 1311, 1316(b), <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 935</ref>, 939.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20103.</num>
<heading> Crime victim assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant authority of Director; chief executive of States; amount; insufficient funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to the availability of money in the Fund, the Director shall make an annual grant from any portion of the Fund made available by section 20101(d)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002151">1</ref> of this title for the purpose of grants under this subsection, or for the purpose of grants under <ref>section 20102 of this title</ref> but not used for that purpose, to the chief executive of each State for the financial support of eligible crime victim assistance programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such chief executive shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> certify that priority shall be given to eligible crime victim assistance programs providing assistance to victims of sexual assault, spousal abuse, or child abuse;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> certify that funds shall be made available for grants to programs which serve previously underserved populations of victims of violent crime. The Director, after consultation with State and local officials and representatives from private organizations, shall issue guidelines to implement this section that provide flexibility to the States in determining the populations of victims of violent crimes that may be underserved in their respective States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> certify that funds awarded to eligible crime victim assistance programs will not be used to supplant State and local funds otherwise available for crime victim assistance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide such other information and assurances related to the purposes of this section as the Director may reasonably require.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The amounts of grants under paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the base amount to each State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that portion of the then remaining available money to each State that results from a distribution among the States on the basis of each State’s population in relation to the population of all States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If the amount available for grants under paragraph (1) is insufficient to provide the base amount to each State, the funds available shall be distributed equally among the States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this subsection, the term “base amount” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> except as provided in subparagraph (B), $500,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for the territories of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Republic of Palau, $200,000, with the Republic of Palau’s share governed by the Compact of Free Association between the United States and the Republic of Palau.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> An agency of the Federal Government performing local law enforcement functions in and on behalf of the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any other territory or possession of the United States may qualify as an eligible crime victim assistance program for the purpose of grants under this subsection, or for the purpose of grants under subsection (c)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Each chief executive may waive a matching requirement imposed by the Director, in accordance with subparagraph (B), as a condition for the receipt of funds under any program to provide assistance to victims of crimes authorized under this subchapter. The chief executive shall report to the Director the approval of any waiver of the matching requirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Each chief executive shall establish and make public, a policy including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the manner in which an eligible crime victim assistance program can request a match waiver;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the criteria used to determine eligibility of the match waiver; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the process for decision making and notifying the eligible crime victim assistance program of the decision.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Beginning on the date a national emergency is declared under the National Emergencies Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.) with respect to a pandemic and ending on the date that is one year after the date of the end of such national emergency, each chief executive shall issue waivers for any matching requirement, in its entirety, for all eligible crime victim assistance programs contracted to provide services at that time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility of program; factors; limitation on expending of sums</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A victim assistance program is an eligible crime victim assistance program for the purposes of this section if such program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is operated by a public agency or a nonprofit organization, or a combination of such agencies or organizations or of both such agencies and organizations, and provides services to victims of crime;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> demonstrates—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a record of providing effective services to victims of crime and financial support from sources other than the Fund; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> substantial financial support from sources other than the Fund;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> utilizes volunteers in providing such services, unless and to the extent the chief executive determines that compelling reasons exist to waive this requirement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> promotes within the community served coordinated public and private efforts to aid crime victims;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> assists potential recipients in seeking crime victim compensation benefits; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> does not discriminate against victims because they disagree with the way the State is prosecuting the criminal case.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (3), an eligible crime victim assistance program shall expend sums received under subsection (a) only for providing services to victims of crime.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Not more than 5 percent of sums received under subsection (a) may be used for training purposes and the administration of the State crime victim assistance program receiving such sums.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants: purposes; distribution; duties of Director; reimbursement by Director</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Director shall make grants—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for victim services, demonstration projects, program evaluation, compliance efforts, and training and technical assistance services to eligible crime victim assistance programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for the financial support of services to victims of Federal crime by eligible crime victim assistance programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for nonprofit neighborhood and community-based victim service organizations and coalitions to improve outreach and services to victims of crime.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Of the amount available for grants under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less than 50 percent shall be used for grants under paragraphs (1)(A) and (1)(C);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not more than 50 percent shall be used for grants under paragraph (1)(B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not more than $10,000 shall be used for any single grant under paragraph (1)(C).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Director shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be responsible for monitoring compliance with guidelines for fair treatment of crime victims and witnesses issued under section 6 of the Victim and Witness Protection Act of 1982 (<ref>Public Law 97–291</ref>) [<ref>18 U.S.C. 1512</ref> note];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consult with the heads of Federal law enforcement agencies that have responsibilities affecting victims of Federal crimes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> coordinate victim services provided by the Federal Government with victim services offered by other public agencies and nonprofit organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> perform such other functions related to the purposes of this title <sup>1</sup> as the Director deems appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> use funds made available to the Director under this subsection—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for fellowships and clinical internships and for grants under subparagraphs (1)(A) and (B), pursuant to rules or guidelines that generally establish a publicly-announced, competitive process; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to carry out programs of training and special workshops for the presentation and dissemination of information resulting from demonstrations, surveys, and special projects.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Director may reimburse other instrumentalities of the Federal Government and contract for the performance of functions authorized under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “services to victims of crime” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> crises intervention services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing, in an emergency, transportation to court, short-term child care services, and temporary housing and security measures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assistance in participating in criminal justice proceedings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> payment of all reasonable costs for a forensic medical examination of a crime victim, to the extent that such costs are otherwise not reimbursed or paid;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “services to victims of Federal crime” means services to victims of crime with respect to Federal crime, and includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> training of law enforcement personnel in the delivery of services to victims of Federal crime;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> preparation, publication, and distribution of informational materials—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> setting forth services offered to victims of crime; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> concerning services to victims of Federal crime for use by Federal law enforcement personnel; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> salaries of personnel who provide services to victims of crime, to the extent that such personnel provide such services;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “crises intervention services” means counseling to provide emotional support in crises arising from the occurrence of crime; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “chief executive” includes a person designated by a chief executive to perform the functions of the chief executive under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1404</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2172</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–401, title I, § 102(b)(4)</ref>, (5), <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 905</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 71</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7122, 7123(b)(4)–(9), 7127, 7128, title IX, § 9306(a), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4420</ref>, 4421, 4423, 4537; <ref>Pub. L. 103–317, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1994-08-26">Aug. 26, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1736</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXIII</ref>, §§ 230204, 230205, 230208, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title II, § 232(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1244</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VI, § 623</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 372</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI</ref>, §§ 1131, 1133(b), <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3107</ref>, 3108; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. B, title II</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 579</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–324, § 17(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1962</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–27, § 3</ref>, <date date="2021-07-22">July 22, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 302</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20104.</num>
<heading> Child abuse prevention and treatment grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts made available by <ref>section 20101(d)(2) of this title</ref> for the purposes of this section shall be obligated and expended by the Secretary of Health and Human Services for grants under section 5106c <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002152">1</ref> of title 42. Any portion of an amount which is not obligated by the Secretary by the end of the fiscal year in which funds are made available for allocation, shall be reallocated for award under <ref>section 20103(a) of this title</ref>, except that with respect to funds deposited during fiscal year 1986 and made available for obligation during fiscal year 1987, any unobligated portion of such amount shall remain available for obligation until <date date="1988-09-30">September 30, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1404A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–401, title I, § 102(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 905</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–121, title I, § 110(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-27">Oct. 27, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–235, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-03">Oct. 3, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20105.</num>
<heading> Compensation and assistance to victims of terrorism or mass violence</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victims of acts of terrorism outside the United States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director may make supplemental grants as provided in 20101(d)(5) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002153">1</ref> of this title to States, victim service organizations, and public agencies (including Federal, State, or local governments) and nongovernmental organizations that provide assistance to victims of crime, which shall be used to provide emergency relief, including crisis response efforts, assistance, training, and technical assistance, and ongoing assistance, including during any investigation or prosecution, to victims of terrorist acts or mass violence occurring outside the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victim defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “victim”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a person who is a national of the United States or an officer or employee of the United States Government who is injured or killed as a result of a terrorist act or mass violence occurring outside the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a person described in subparagraph (A) who is less than 18 years of age, incompetent, incapacitated, or deceased, includes a family member or legal guardian of that person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to allow the Director to make grants to any foreign power (as defined by <ref>section 1801(a) of title 50</ref>) or to any domestic or foreign organization operated for the purpose of engaging in any significant political or lobbying activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victims of terrorism within the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may make supplemental grants as provided in <ref>section 20101(d)(5) of this title</ref> to States for eligible crime victim compensation and assistance programs, and to victim service organizations, public agencies (including Federal, State, or local governments) and nongovernmental organizations that provide assistance to victims of crime, which shall be used to provide emergency relief, including crisis response efforts, assistance, compensation, training and technical assistance, and ongoing assistance, including during any investigation or prosecution, to victims of terrorist acts or mass violence occurring within the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1404B</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title II, § 232(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1243</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. C, § 2003(a)(1)</ref>, (4), <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1543</ref>, 1544; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VI, § 624(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20106.</num>
<heading> Compensation to victims of international terrorism</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International terrorism</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “international terrorism” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 2331 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National of the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “national of the United States” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1101(a) of title 8</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victim</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “victim” means a person who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> suffered direct physical or emotional injury or death as a result of international terrorism occurring on or after <date date="1983-10-23">October 23, 1983</date>, with respect to which an investigation or civil or criminal prosecution was ongoing after <date date="1996-04-24">April 24, 1996</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> as of the date on which the international terrorism occurred, was a national of the United States or an officer or employee of the United States Government.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incompetent, incapacitated, or deceased victims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a victim who is less than 18 years of age, incompetent, incapacitated, or deceased, a family member or legal guardian of the victim may receive the compensation under this section on behalf of the victim.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, in no event shall an individual who is criminally culpable for the terrorist act or mass violence receive any compensation under this section, either directly or on behalf of a victim.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Award of compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may use the emergency reserve referred to in <ref>section 20101(d)(5)(A) of this title</ref> to carry out a program to compensate victims of acts of international terrorism that occur outside the United States for expenses associated with that victimization. The amount of compensation awarded to a victim under this subsection shall be reduced by any amount that the victim received in connection with the same act of international terrorism under title VIII of the Omnibus Diplomatic Security and Antiterrorism Act of 1986.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director shall annually submit to Congress a report on the status and activities of the program under this section, which report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an explanation of the procedures for filing and processing of applications for compensation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the procedures and policies instituted to promote public awareness about the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> a complete statistical analysis of the victims assisted under the program, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of applications for compensation submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of applications approved and the amount of each award;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number of applications denied and the reasons for the denial;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the average length of time to process an application for compensation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the number of applications for compensation pending and the estimated future liability of the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an analysis of future program needs and suggested program improvements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1404C</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. C, § 2003(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1544</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VI, § 624(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 373</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1083(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 342</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20107.</num>
<heading> Crime victims legal assistance grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may make grants as provided in <ref>section 20103(c)(1)(A) of this title</ref> to State, tribal, and local prosecutors’ offices, law enforcement agencies, courts, jails, and correctional institutions, and to qualified public and private entities, to develop, establish, and maintain programs for the enforcement of crime victims’ rights as provided in law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Grant amounts under this section may not be used to bring a cause of action for damages.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> False Claims Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts collected pursuant to sections 3729 through 3731 of title 31 (commonly known as the “False Claims Act”) may be used for grants under this section, subject to appropriation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1404D</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2264</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20108.</num>
<heading> Crime victims notification grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may make grants as provided in <ref>section 20103(c)(1)(A) of this title</ref> to State, tribal, and local prosecutors’ offices, law enforcement agencies, courts, jails, and correctional institutions, and to qualified public or private entities, to develop and implement state-of-the-art systems for notifying victims of crime of important dates and developments relating to the criminal proceedings at issue in a timely and efficient manner, provided that the jurisdiction has laws substantially equivalent to the provisions of chapter 237 of title 18.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integration of systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Systems developed and implemented under this section may be integrated with existing case management systems operated by the recipient of the grant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to funds made available under <ref>section 20101(d) of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2005; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2006, 2007, 2008, and 2009.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> False Claims Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts collected pursuant to sections 3729 through 3731 of title 31 (commonly known as the “False Claims Act”) may be used for grants under this section, subject to appropriation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1404E</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title I, § 103(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20109.</num>
<heading> Sexual assault survivors’ notification grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may make grants as provided in <ref>section 20103(c)(1)(A) of this title</ref> to States to develop and disseminate to entities described in subsection (c)(1) of this section written notice of applicable rights and policies for sexual assault survivors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each recipient of a grant awarded under subsection (a) shall make its best effort to ensure that each entity described in subsection (c)(1) provides individuals who identify as a survivor of a sexual assault, and who consent to receiving such information, with written notice of applicable rights and policies regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the right not to be charged fees for or otherwise prevented from pursuing a sexual assault evidence collection kit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the right to have a sexual assault medical forensic examination regardless of whether the survivor reports to or cooperates with law enforcement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the availability of a sexual assault advocate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the availability of protective orders and policies related to their enforcement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> policies regarding the storage, preservation, and disposal of sexual assault evidence collection kits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the process, if any, to request preservation of sexual assault evidence collection kits or the probative evidence from such kits; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the availability of victim compensation and restitution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dissemination of written notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each recipient of a grant awarded under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide the written notice described in subsection (b) to medical centers, hospitals, forensic examiners, sexual assault service providers, State and local law enforcement agencies, and any other State agency or department reasonably likely to serve sexual assault survivors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make the written notice described in subsection (b) publicly available on the Internet website of the attorney general of the State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision to promote compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may provide such technical assistance and guidance as necessary to help recipients meet the requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Integration of systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any system developed and implemented under this section may be integrated with an existing case management system operated by the recipient of the grant if the system meets the requirements listed in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1404F</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–236, § 3</ref>, <date date="2016-10-07">Oct. 7, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 967</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20110.</num>
<heading> Administrative provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Director to establish rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may establish such rules, regulations, guidelines, and procedures as are necessary to carry out any function of the Director under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recordkeeping</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each recipient of sums under this subchapter shall keep such records as the Director shall prescribe, including records that fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of such sums, the total cost of the undertaking for which such sums are used, and that portion of the cost of the undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access of Director to books and records for purpose of audit and examination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall have access, for purpose of audit and examination, to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipient of sums under this subchapter that, in the opinion of the Director, may be related to the expenditure of funds received under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revealing research or statistical information; prohibition; immunity from legal proceedings; permission; admission of information as evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided by Federal law, no officer or employee of the Federal Government, and no recipient of sums under this subchapter, shall use or reveal any research or statistical information furnished under this subchapter by any person and identifiable to any specific private person for any purpose other than the purpose for which such information was obtained in accordance with this subchapter. Such information, and any copy of such information, shall be immune from legal process and shall not, without the consent of the person furnishing such information, be admitted as evidence or used for any purpose in any action, suit, or other judicial, legislative, or administrative proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discrimination prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person shall on the ground of race, color, religion, national origin, handicap, or sex be excluded from participation in, denied the benefits of, subjected to discrimination under, or denied employment in connection with, any undertaking funded in whole or in part with sums made available under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to comply with provisions; notice and hearing; power of Director</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If, after reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing on the record, the Director finds that a State has failed to comply substantially with any provision of this subchapter or a rule, regulation, guideline, or procedure issued under this subchapter, or an application submitted in accordance with this subchapter or the provisions of any other applicable law, the Director shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> terminate payments to such State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> suspend payments to such State until the Director is satisfied that such noncompliance has ended; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> take such other action as the Director deems appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall, on <date date="1990-12-31">December 31, 1990</date>, and on June 30 every two years thereafter, report to the President and to the Congress on the revenue derived from each source described in <ref>section 20101 of this title</ref> and on the effectiveness of the activities supported under this subchapter. The Director may include in such report recommendations for legislation to improve this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maintenance of effort</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each entity receiving sums made available under this subchapter for administrative purposes shall certify that such sums will not be used to supplant State or local funds, but will be used to increase the amount of such funds that would, in the absence of Federal funds, be made available for these purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1407</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2176</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 48</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3605</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7123(b)(10)</ref>–(14), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4421</ref>, 4422; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXIII</ref>, §§ 230206, 230207, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2080</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20111.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Office for Victims of Crime</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office established within Department of Justice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Department of Justice an Office for Victims of Crime (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Office”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment of Director; authority; restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office shall be headed by a Director (referred to in this subchapter as the “Director”), who shall be appointed by the President. The Director shall report to the Attorney General through the Assistant Attorney General for the Office of Justice Programs and shall have final authority for all grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts awarded by the Office. The Director shall not engage in any employment other than that of serving as the Director, nor shall the Director hold any office in, or act in any capacity for, any organization, agency, or institution with which the Office makes any contract or other agreement under this subchapter.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002154">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Director</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director shall have the following duties:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Administering funds made available by <ref>section 20101 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Providing funds to eligible States pursuant to sections 20102 and 20103 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Establishing programs in accordance with <ref>section 20103(c) of this title</ref> on terms and conditions determined by the Director to be consistent with that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Cooperating with and providing technical assistance to States, units of local government, and other public and private organizations or international agencies involved in activities related to crime victims.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other functions as the Attorney General may delegate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1411</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7123(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4420</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(h)(5)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>VICTIMS OF DOMESTIC VIOLENCE, DATING VIOLENCE, SEXUAL ASSAULT, AND STALKING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20121.</num>
<heading> Legal assistance for victims</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to enable the Attorney General to award grants to increase the availability of civil and criminal legal assistance necessary to provide effective aid to adult and youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or sexual assault who are seeking relief in legal matters relating to or arising out of that abuse or violence, at minimal or no cost to the victims. When legal assistance to a dependent is necessary for the safety of a victim, such assistance may be provided. Criminal legal assistance provided for under this section shall be limited to criminal matters relating to or arising out of domestic violence, sexual assault, dating violence, and stalking.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and grant conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the definitions and grant conditions provided in <ref>section 12291 of this title</ref> shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Legal assistance for victims grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General may award grants under this subsection to private nonprofit entities, Indian tribal governments and tribal organizations, territorial organizations, and publicly funded organizations not acting in a governmental capacity such as law schools, and which shall be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to implement, expand, and establish cooperative efforts and projects between domestic violence, dating violence, and sexual assault victim service providers and legal assistance providers to provide legal assistance for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and sexual assault;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to implement, expand, and establish efforts and projects to provide legal assistance for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and sexual assault by organizations with a demonstrated history of providing direct legal or advocacy services on behalf of these victims; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to implement, expand, and establish efforts and projects to provide competent, supervised pro bono legal assistance for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, except that not more than 10 percent of the funds awarded under this section may be used for the purpose described in this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible for a grant under subsection (c), applicants shall certify in writing that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> any person providing legal assistance through a program funded under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is a licensed attorney or is working under the direct supervision of a licensed attorney;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in immigration proceedings, is a Board of Immigration Appeals accredited representative;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in Veterans’ Administration claims, is an accredited representative; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> is any person who functions as an attorney or lay advocate in Tribal court; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has demonstrated expertise in providing legal assistance to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking in the targeted population; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is partnered with an entity or person that has demonstrated expertise described in clause (i); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> has completed, or will complete, training in connection with domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or sexual assault and related legal issues, including training on evidence-based risk factors for domestic and dating violence homicide;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any training program conducted in satisfaction of the requirement of paragraph (1) has been or will be developed with input from and in collaboration with a tribal, State, territorial, local, or culturally specific domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault or stalking victim service provider or coalition, as well as appropriate tribal, State, territorial, and local law enforcement officials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any person or organization providing legal assistance through a program funded under subsection (c) has informed and will continue to inform State, local, or tribal domestic violence, dating violence, or sexual assault programs and coalitions, as well as appropriate State and local law enforcement officials of their work; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the grantee’s organizational policies do not require mediation or counseling involving offenders and victims physically together, in cases where sexual assault, domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or child sexual abuse is an issue.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may evaluate the grants funded under this section through contracts or other arrangements with entities expert on domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and sexual assault, and on evaluation research.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $60,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the amount made available under this subsection in each fiscal year, not less than 3 percent shall be used for grants for programs that assist adult and youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and sexual assault on lands within the jurisdiction of an Indian tribe.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tribal government program</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not less than 7 percent of the total amount available under this section for each fiscal year shall be available for grants under the program authorized by <ref>section 10452 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of part <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002155">1</ref></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The requirements of this section shall not apply to funds allocated for the program described in clause (i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victims of sexual assault</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the amount made available under this subsection in each fiscal year, not less than 25 percent shall be used for direct services, training, and technical assistance to support projects focused solely or primarily on providing legal assistance to victims of sexual assault.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonsupplantation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts made available under this section shall be used to supplement and not supplant other Federal, State, and local funds expended to further the purpose of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. B, title II, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–405, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title I, § 103</ref>, title IX, § 906(f), formerly § 906(g), <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2978</ref>, 3082, renumbered § 906(f), <ref>Pub. L. 109–271, § 7(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–271, § 7(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 73</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 850</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20122.</num>
<heading> Education, training, and enhanced services to end violence against and abuse of individuals with disabilities and Deaf people</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, may award grants to eligible entities—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide training, consultation, and information on domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, sexual assault, and abuse by caregivers against individuals with disabilities (as defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12102</ref>)) and Deaf people; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to enhance direct services to such individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Grants awarded under this section shall be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide personnel, training, technical assistance, advocacy, intervention, risk reduction (including using evidence-based indicators to assess the risk of domestic and dating violence homicide) and prevention of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and sexual assault against individuals with disabilities and Deaf people;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to conduct outreach activities to ensure that individuals with disabilities and Deaf people who are victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or sexual assault receive appropriate assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to conduct cross-training for victim service organizations, governmental agencies, courts, law enforcement and other first responders, and nonprofit, nongovernmental organizations serving individuals with disabilities about risk reduction, intervention, prevention and the nature of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and sexual assault for individuals with disabilities and Deaf people;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to provide technical assistance to assist with modifications to existing policies, protocols, and procedures to ensure equal access to the services, programs, and activities of victim service providers for individuals with disabilities and Deaf people;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> to provide training and technical assistance on the requirements of shelters and victim service providers under Federal antidiscrimination laws, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 12101</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 794 of title 29</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to modify facilities, purchase equipment, and provide personnel so that shelters and victim service organizations can accommodate the needs of individuals with disabilities and Deaf people;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to provide advocacy and intervention services for individuals with disabilities and Deaf people who are victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or sexual assault; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to develop model programs to enhance the capacity of organizations serving individuals with disabilities and Deaf people who are victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An entity shall be eligible to receive a grant under this section if the entity is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a unit of local government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an Indian tribal government or tribal organization; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a victim service provider, such as a State or tribal domestic violence or sexual assault coalition or a nonprofit, nongovernmental organization serving individuals with disabilities and Deaf people.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A grant awarded for the purpose described in subsection (b)(8) shall only be awarded to an eligible agency (as defined in section 796f–5 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002156">1</ref> of title 29).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Underserved populations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In awarding grants under this section, the Director shall ensure that the needs of underserved populations are being addressed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. B, title IV, § 1402</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1513</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3000</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 82</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 857</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20123.</num>
<heading> Grants for outreach and services to underserved populations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants authorized</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amounts appropriated under the grant programs identified in paragraph (2), the Attorney General shall take 2 percent of such appropriated amounts and combine them to award grants to eligible entities described in subsection (b) of this section to develop and implement outreach strategies targeted at adult or youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking in underserved populations and to provide victim services to meet the needs of adult and youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking in underserved populations. The requirements of the grant programs identified in paragraph (2) shall not apply to this grant program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Programs covered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The programs covered by paragraph (1) are the programs carried out under the following provisions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>Section 10441 of this title</ref> (Grants to Combat Violent Crimes Against Women).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>Section 10461 of this title</ref> (Grants to Encourage Arrest Policies and Enforcement of Protection Orders Program).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Eligible entities under this section are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> population specific organizations that have demonstrated experience and expertise in providing population specific services in the relevant underserved communities, or population specific organizations working in partnership with a victim service provider or domestic violence or sexual assault coalition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> victim service providers offering population specific services for a specific underserved population; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> victim service providers working in partnership with a national, State, tribal, Native Hawaiian, or local organization that has demonstrated experience and expertise in providing population specific services in the relevant underserved population.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Planning grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General may use up to 25 percent of funds available under this section to make one-time planning grants to eligible entities to support the planning and development of specially designed and targeted programs for adult and youth victims in one or more underserved populations, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identifying, building and strengthening partnerships with potential collaborators within underserved populations, Federal, State, tribal, territorial or local government entities, and public and private organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conducting a needs assessment of the community and the targeted underserved population or populations to determine what the barriers are to service access and what factors contribute to those barriers, using input from the targeted underserved population or populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identifying promising prevention, outreach and intervention strategies for victims from a targeted underserved population or populations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> developing a plan, with the input of the targeted underserved population or populations, for implementing prevention, outreach and intervention strategies to address the barriers to accessing services, promoting community engagement in the prevention of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking within the targeted underserved populations, and evaluating the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of providing or enhancing population specific outreach and services to adult and youth victims in one or more underserved populations, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> working with Federal, State, tribal, territorial and local governments, agencies, and organizations to develop or enhance population specific services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> strengthening the capacity of underserved populations to provide population specific services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> strengthening the capacity of traditional victim service providers to provide population specific services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> strengthening the response of criminal and civil justice interventions by providing population-specific training for law enforcement, prosecutors, judges and other court personnel on domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking in underserved populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> working in cooperation with an underserved population to develop and implement outreach, education, prevention, and intervention strategies that highlight available resources and the specific issues faced by victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking from underserved populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> developing, enlarging, or strengthening culturally specific programs and projects to provide culturally specific services regarding responses to, and prevention of, female genital mutilation and cutting; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> strengthening the response of social and human services by providing population-specific training for service providers on domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking in underserved populations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women at such time, in such form, and in such manner as the Director may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall submit to the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women a report that describes the activities carried out with grant funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the funds identified in subsection (a)(1), there are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and grant conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section the definitions and grant conditions in <ref>section 12291 of this title</ref> shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title I, § 120</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–271</ref>, §§ 1(c)(2), 2(h), <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 750</ref>, 752; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 78</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 851</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20124.</num>
<heading> Enhancing culturally specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amounts appropriated under certain grant programs identified in paragraph (2), the Attorney General, through the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women (referred to in this section as the “Director”), shall take 15 percent of such appropriated amounts for the program under paragraph (2)(A) and 5 percent of such appropriated amounts for the programs under subparagraphs (B) through (E) of paragraph (2) and combine them to establish a new grant program to enhance culturally specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. Grants made under this new program shall be administered by the Director. The requirements of the grant programs identified in paragraph (2) shall not apply to this new grant program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Programs covered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The programs covered by paragraph (1) are the programs carried out under the following provisions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>Section 10461 of this title</ref> (Grants to Encourage Arrest Policies and Enforcement of Protection Orders).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>Section 20121 of this title</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002157">1</ref> (Legal Assistance for Victims).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>Section 12341 of this title</ref> (Rural Domestic Violence, Dating Violence, Sexual Assault, Stalking, and Child Abuse Enforcement Assistance).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content><ref>Section 14041a of title 42</ref> (Enhanced Training and Services to End Violence Against Women Later in Life).<sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content><ref>Section 20122 of this title</ref> (Education, Training, and Enhanced Services to End Violence Against and Abuse of Women with Disabilities).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the amounts made available under paragraph (1), there are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the total amount available for grants under this section, not less than 40 percent of such funds shall be allocated for programs or projects that meaningfully address non-intimate partner relationship sexual assault.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternative allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding 12291(b)(11) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002158">2</ref> of this title, the Director may allocate a portion of funds described in subparagraph (A) to enhanced technical assistance relating to non-intimate partner sexual assault if the Office on Violence Against Women does not receive sufficient qualified applications proposing to address non-intimate partner relationship sexual assault.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of program and grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General program purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The purpose of the program required by this section is to promote:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The maintenance and replication of existing successful services in domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking community-based programs providing culturally specific services and other resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The development of innovative culturally specific strategies and projects to enhance access to services and resources for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes for which grants may be used</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall make grants to community-based programs for the purpose of enhancing culturally specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. Grants under the program shall support community-based efforts to address distinctive cultural responses to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> working with State and local governments and social service agencies to develop and enhance effective strategies to provide culturally specific services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increasing communities’ capacity to provide culturally specific resources and support for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking crimes and their families;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> strengthening criminal justice interventions, by providing training for law enforcement, prosecution, courts, probation, and correctional facilities on culturally specific responses to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> enhancing traditional services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking through the leadership of culturally specific programs offering services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> working in cooperation with the community to develop education and prevention strategies highlighting culturally specific issues and resources regarding victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> providing culturally specific programs for children exposed to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> providing culturally specific resources and services that address the safety, economic, housing, and workplace needs of victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, including emergency assistance; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> examining the dynamics of culture and its impact on victimization and healing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance and training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall provide technical assistance and training to grantees of this and other programs under this Act regarding the development and provision of effective culturally specific community-based services by entering into cooperative agreements or contracts with an organization or organizations having a demonstrated expertise in and whose primary purpose is addressing the development and provision of culturally specific community-based services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. Not less than 1 such organization shall have demonstrated expertise primarily in domestic violence services, and not less than 1 such organization shall have demonstrated expertise primarily in non-intimate partner sexual assault services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Eligible entities for grants under this Section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002159">3</ref> include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> community-based programs whose primary purpose is providing culturally specific services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> community-based programs whose primary purpose is providing culturally specific services who can partner with a program having demonstrated expertise in serving victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall issue a biennial report on the distribution of funding under this section, the progress made in replicating and supporting increased services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources, and the types of culturally accessible programs, strategies, technical assistance, and training developed or enhanced through this program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall award a contract or cooperative agreement to evaluate programs under this section to an entity with the demonstrated expertise in and primary goal of providing enhanced cultural access to services and resources for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-exclusivity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this Section <sup>3</sup> shall be interpreted to exclude culturally specific community-based programs from applying to other grant programs authorized under this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and grant conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section the definitions and grant conditions in <ref>section 12291 of this title</ref> shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2991</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–271</ref>, §§ 1(c)(3), 2(k), <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 751</ref>, 753; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 80</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title I, § 108</ref>, title IX, § 901(e), <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 852</ref>, 911.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20125.</num>
<heading> Grants to combat violent crimes on campuses</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants authorized</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General is authorized to make grants to institutions of higher education, for use by such institutions or consortia consisting of campus personnel, student organizations, campus administrators, security personnel, and regional crisis centers affiliated with the institution, to develop and strengthen effective security and investigation strategies to combat domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking on campuses, to develop and strengthen victim services in cases involving such crimes on campuses, which may include partnerships with local criminal justice authorities and community-based victim services agencies, and to develop and strengthen prevention education and awareness programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equitable participation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Attorney General shall make every effort to ensure—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the equitable participation of private and public institutions of higher education in the activities assisted under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the equitable geographic distribution of grants under this section among the various regions of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the equitable distribution of grants under this section to tribal colleges and universities and traditionally black colleges and universities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of grant funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Grant funds awarded under this section may be used for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To provide personnel, training, technical assistance, data collection, and other equipment with respect to the increased apprehension, investigation, and adjudication of persons committing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking on campus.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To develop, strengthen, and implement campus policies, protocols, and services that more effectively identify and respond to the crimes of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, including the use of technology to commit these crimes, and to train campus administrators, campus security personnel, and all participants in the resolution process, including personnel from the Title IX coordinator’s office, student conduct office, and campus disciplinary or judicial boards on such policies, protocols, and services that promote a prompt, fair, and impartial investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To provide prevention and education programming about domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, including technological abuse and reproductive and sexual coercion, that is age-appropriate, culturally relevant, ongoing, delivered in multiple venues on campus, accessible, promotes respectful nonviolent behavior as a social norm, and engages men and boys. Such programming should be developed in partnership or collaboratively with experts in intimate partner and sexual violence prevention and intervention.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To develop, enlarge, or strengthen victim services programs and population specific services on the campuses of the institutions involved, including programs providing legal, medical, or psychological counseling, for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, and to improve delivery of victim assistance on campus. To the extent practicable, such an institution shall collaborate with any victim service providers in the community in which the institution is located. If appropriate victim services programs are not available in the community or are not accessible to students, the institution shall, to the extent practicable, provide a victim services program on campus or create a victim services program in collaboration with a community-based organization. The institution shall use not less than 20 percent of the funds made available through the grant for a victim services program provided in accordance with this paragraph, regardless of whether the services are provided by the institution or in coordination with community victim service providers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To create, disseminate, or otherwise provide assistance and information about victims’ options on and off campus to bring disciplinary or other legal action, including assistance to victims in immigration matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> To develop, install, or expand data collection and communication systems, including computerized systems, linking campus security to the local law enforcement for the purpose of identifying and tracking arrests, protection orders, violations of protection orders, prosecutions, and convictions with respect to the crimes of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking on campus.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> To provide capital improvements (including improved lighting and communications facilities but not including the construction of buildings) on campuses to address the crimes of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> To support improved coordination among campus administrators, campus security personnel, and local law enforcement to reduce domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking on campus.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> To develop or adapt, provide, and disseminate developmental, culturally appropriate, and linguistically accessible print or electronic materials to address both prevention and intervention in domestic violence, dating violence, sexual violence, and stalking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> To develop or adapt and disseminate population specific strategies and projects for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking from underserved populations on campus.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> To train campus health centers and appropriate campus faculty, such as academic advisors or professionals who deal with students on a daily basis, on how to recognize and respond to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, including training health providers on how to provide universal education to all members of the campus community on the impacts of violence on health and unhealthy relationships and how providers can support ongoing outreach efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> To train campus personnel in how to use a victim-centered, trauma-informed interview technique, which means asking questions of a student or a campus employee who is reported to be a victim of sexual assault, domestic violence, dating violence, or stalking, in a manner that is focused on the experience of the reported victim, that does not judge or blame the reported victim for the alleged crime, and that is informed by evidence-based research on trauma response. To the extent practicable, campus personnel shall allow the reported victim to participate in a recorded interview and to receive a copy of the recorded interview.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> To develop and implement restorative practices (as defined in <ref>section 12291(a) of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applications</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In order to be eligible to be awarded a grant under this section for any fiscal year, an institution of higher education shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time and in such manner as the Attorney General shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each application submitted under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> describe the need for grant funds and the plan for implementation for any of the purposes described in subsection (b);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> include proof that the institution of higher education collaborated with victim service providers, including domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking victim services programs in the community in which the institution is located;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> describe the characteristics of the population being served, including type of campus, demographics of the population, and number of students;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> describe how underserved populations in the campus community will be adequately served, including the provision of relevant population specific services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> provide measurable goals and expected results from the use of the grant funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> provide assurances that the Federal funds made available under this section shall be used to supplement and, to the extent practical, increase the level of funds that would, in the absence of Federal funds, be made available by the institution for the purposes described in subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> include such other information and assurances as the Attorney General reasonably determines to be necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with campus crime reporting required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No institution of higher education shall be eligible for a grant under this section unless such institution is in compliance with the requirements of <ref>section 1092(f) of title 20</ref>. Up to $200,000 of the total amount of grant funds appropriated under this section for fiscal years 2023 through 2027 may be used to provide technical assistance in complying with the mandatory reporting requirements of <ref>section 1092(f) of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General terms and conditions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonmonetary assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the assistance provided under this section, the Attorney General may request any Federal agency to use the agency’s authorities and the resources granted to the agency under Federal law (including personnel, equipment, supplies, facilities, and managerial, technical, and advisory services) in support of campus security, and investigation and victim service efforts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grantee reporting</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each institution of higher education receiving a grant under this section shall submit a performance report to the Attorney General. The Attorney General shall suspend funding under this section for an institution of higher education if the institution fails to submit such a report.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Upon completion of the grant period under this section, the institution shall file a performance report with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Education explaining the activities carried out under this section together with an assessment of the effectiveness of those activities in achieving the purposes described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grantee minimum requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each grantee shall comply with the following minimum requirements during the grant period:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The grantee shall create a coordinated community response including both organizations external to the institution and relevant divisions of the institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The grantee shall establish a mandatory prevention and education program on domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking for all students.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The grantee shall train all campus law enforcement to respond effectively to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The grantee shall train all participants in the resolution process, including the campus disciplinary board, the title IX coordinator’s office, and the student conduct office, to respond effectively to situations involving domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after the end of the fiscal year for which grants are awarded under this section, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of grants, and the amount of funds, distributed under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a summary of the purposes for which the grants were provided and an evaluation of the progress made under the grant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a statistical summary of the persons served, detailing the nature of victimization, and providing data on age, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, race, ethnicity, language, disability, relationship to offender, geographic distribution, and type of campus; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the effectiveness of programs funded under this part.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002160">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, of which not less than 10 percent shall be made available for grants to historically Black colleges and universities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and grant conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section the definitions and grant conditions in <ref>section 12291 of this title</ref> shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3013</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–271</ref>, §§ 1(c)(1), 4(b), (d), <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 750</ref>, 758; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 87</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 866</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20126.</num>
<heading> Consultation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall conduct annual consultations with Indian tribal governments concerning the Federal administration of tribal funds and programs established under this Act, the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (title IV of <ref>Public Law 103–322</ref>; <ref>108 Stat. 1902</ref>), the Violence Against Women Act of 2000 (division B of <ref>Public Law 106–386</ref>; <ref>114 Stat. 1491</ref>), and the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">During consultations under subsection (a), the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Attorney General shall solicit recommendations from Indian tribes concerning—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> administering tribal funds and programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enhancing the safety of Indian women from domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, homicide, stalking, and sex trafficking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> strengthening the Federal response to such violent crimes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> improving access to local, regional, State, and Federal crime information databases and criminal justice information systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall submit to Congress an annual report on the annual consultations required under subsection (a) that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> contains the recommendations made under subsection (b) by Indian tribes during the year covered by the report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> describes actions taken during the year covered by the report to respond to recommendations made under subsection (b) during the year or a previous year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> describes how the Attorney General will work in coordination and collaboration with Indian tribes, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Secretary of the Interior to address the recommendations made under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 120 days before the date of a consultation under subsection (a), the Attorney General shall notify tribal leaders of the date, time, and location of the consultation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3078</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–165, § 4(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2020-10-10">Oct. 10, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 761</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20127.</num>
<heading> Emergency and transitional pet shelter and housing assistance grant program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant program</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary, acting in consultation with the Office of the Violence Against Women <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002161">1</ref> of the Department of Justice, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall award grants under this section to eligible entities to carry out programs to provide the assistance described in paragraph (3) with respect to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking and the pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses of such victims.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Memorandum of understanding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may enter into a memorandum of understanding with the head of another Department or agency, as appropriate, to carry out any of the authorities provided to the Secretary under this section.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002162">2</ref></p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of the activities for which a grant under this section is sought;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such assurances as the Secretary determines to be necessary to ensure compliance by the entity with the requirements of this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a certification that the entity, before engaging with any individual domestic violence victim, will disclose to the victim any mandatory duty of the entity to report instances of abuse and neglect (including instances of abuse and neglect of pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to the requirements of subparagraph (A), each application submitted by an eligible entity under that subparagraph shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> not include proposals for any activities that may compromise the safety of a domestic violence victim, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> background checks of domestic violence victims; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> clinical evaluations to determine the eligibility of such a victim for support services;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not include proposals that would require mandatory services for victims or that a victim obtain a protective order in order to receive proposed services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> reflect the eligible entity’s understanding of the dynamics of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules of construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to require—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> domestic violence victims to participate in the criminal justice system in order to receive services; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> eligible entities receiving a grant under this section to breach client confidentiality.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Grants awarded under this section may only be used for programs that provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> emergency and transitional shelter and housing assistance for domestic violence victims with pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses, including assistance with respect to any construction or operating expenses of newly developed or existing emergency and transitional pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse shelter and housing (regardless of whether such shelter and housing is co-located at a victim service provider or within the community);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> short-term shelter and housing assistance for domestic violence victims with pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses, including assistance with respect to expenses incurred for the temporary shelter, housing, boarding, or fostering of the pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses of domestic violence victims and other expenses that are incidental to securing the safety of such a pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse during the sheltering, housing, or relocation of such victims;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> support services designed to enable a domestic violence victim who is fleeing a situation of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> locate and secure—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> safe housing with the victim’s pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> safe accommodations for the victim’s pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide the victim with pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse related services, such as transportation, care services, and other assistance; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> for the training of relevant stakeholders on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the link between domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking and the abuse and neglect of pets, service animals, emotional support animals, and horses;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the needs of domestic violence victims;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> best practices for providing support services to such victims;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> best practices for providing such victims with referrals to victims’ services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the importance of confidentiality.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall, as a condition of such receipt, agree—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to be bound by the nondisclosure of confidential information requirements of <ref>section 12291(b)(2) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that the entity shall not condition the receipt of support, housing, or other benefits provided pursuant to this section on the participation of domestic violence victims in any or all of the support services offered to such victims through a program carried out by the entity using grant funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of assistance provided to victims</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to subparagraph (B), assistance provided with respect to a pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse of a domestic violence victim using grant funds awarded under this section shall be provided for a period of not more than 24 months.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may extend the 24-month period referred to in subparagraph (A) for a period of not more than 6 months in the case of a domestic violence victim who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has made a good faith effort to acquire permanent housing for the victim and the victim’s pet, service animal, emotional support animal, or horse during that 24-month period; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has been unable to acquire such permanent housing within that period.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to the Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after the date on which an eligible entity receives a grant under this section and each year thereafter in which the grant funds are used, the entity shall submit to the Secretary a report that contains, with respect to assistance provided by the entity to domestic violence victims with pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses using grant funds received under this section, information on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of domestic violence victims with pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses provided such assistance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the purpose, amount, type of, and duration of such assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than November 1 of each even-numbered fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report that contains a compilation of the information contained in the reports submitted under paragraph (6).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall transmit a copy of the report submitted under subparagraph (A) to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Office on Violence Against Women of the Department of Justice;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Office of Community Planning and Development of the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Administration for Children and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amount made available under subparagraph (A) in any fiscal year, not more than 5 percent may be used for evaluation, monitoring, salaries, and administrative expenses.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestic violence victim defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “domestic violence victim” means a victim of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “eligible entity” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a State;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a unit of local government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> any other organization that has a documented history of effective work concerning domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking (as determined by the Secretary), including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a domestic violence and sexual assault victim service provider;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a domestic violence and sexual assault coalition;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a community-based and culturally specific organization;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> any other nonprofit, nongovernmental organization; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(V)</num>
<chapeau> any organization that works directly with pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses and collaborates with any organization referred to in clauses (i) through (iv), including—</chapeau>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> an animal shelter; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> an animal welfare organization.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emotional support animal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “emotional support animal” means an animal that is covered by the exclusion specified in section 5.303 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), and that is not a service animal.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pet</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “pet” means a domesticated animal, such as a dog, cat, bird, rodent, fish, turtle, or other animal that is kept for pleasure rather than for commercial purposes.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service animal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “service animal” has the meaning given the term in section 36.104 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided in this section, terms used in this section <sup>2</sup> shall have the meaning given such terms in <ref>section 12291(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12502(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4983</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20128.</num>
<heading> Agency and department coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each head of an Executive department (as defined in <ref>section 101 of title 5</ref>) responsible for carrying out a program under this Act, the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (title IV of <ref>Public Law 103–322</ref>; <ref>108 Stat. 1902</ref>), the Violence Against Women Act of 2000 (division B of <ref>Public Law 106–386</ref>; <ref>114 Stat. 1491</ref>), the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005 (title IX of <ref>Public Law 109–162</ref>; <ref>119 Stat. 3080</ref>) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002163">1</ref>, or the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 (<ref>Public Law 113–4</ref>; <ref>127 Stat. 54</ref>) may coordinate and collaborate on the prevention of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, including sharing best practices and efficient use of resources and technology for victims and those seeking assistance from the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, § 3</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 846</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20129.</num>
<heading> LGBT specific services program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Violence Against Women Office <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002164">1</ref> (referred to in this section as the “Director”), shall make grants to eligible entities to enhance lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (referred to in this section as “LGBT”) specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault and stalking.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of program and grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General program purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The purpose of the program required by this section is to promote the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The maintenance and replication of existing successful LGBT specific domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking community-based programs providing services and resources for LGBT victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The development of innovative LGBT specific strategies and projects to enhance access to services and resources for LGBT victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes for which grants may be used</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall make grants to community-based programs for the purpose of enhancing LGBT specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. Grants under the program shall support community-based efforts to address distinctive LGBT specific responses to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing or enhancing services for LGBT victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, including services that address the safety, emotional well-being, economic, housing, legal and workplace needs of LGBT victims;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> supporting programs that specifically address underserved LGBT communities, including culturally specific communities, to provide specific resources and support for LGBT underserved victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> working in cooperation with the community to develop education and prevention strategies highlighting LGBT specific issues and resources regarding victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> conducting outreach activities to ensure that LGBT people who are victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or sexual assault receive appropriate assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> providing training for victim service providers, governmental agencies, courts, law enforcement and other first responders, and nonprofit, nongovernmental organizations serving the LGBT community about risk reduction, intervention, prevention, and the nature of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and sexual assault;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> developing and implementing LGBT specific programming that focuses on victim autonomy, agency, and safety in order to provide resolution and restitution for the victim; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> providing LGBT specific programs for the non-offending LGBT parents of children exposed to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance and training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director shall provide technical assistance and training to grantees of this and other programs under this Act regarding the development and provision of effective LGBT specific community-based services by entering into cooperative agreements or contracts with an organization or organizations having a demonstrated expertise in and whose primary purpose is addressing the development and provision of LGBT specific community-based services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Eligible entities for grants under this section include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> community-based organizations, the primary purpose of which is providing LGBT specific services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> community-based organizations, the primary purpose of which is providing LGBT specific services that can partner with a program having demonstrated expertise in serving victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, and that agrees to receive technical assistance from a program with LGBT specific expertise.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall issue a biennial report on the distribution of funding under this section, the progress made in replicating and supporting increased services to LGBT victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking and the types of LGBT specific programs, strategies, technical assistance, and training developed or enhanced through this program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall award a contract or cooperative agreement to evaluate programs under this section to an entity with the demonstrated expertise in and primary goal of providing enhanced access to services and resources for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-exclusivity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to exclude LGBT community-based organizations from applying to other grant programs authorized under this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $8,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 861</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20130.</num>
<heading> Study and reports on barriers to survivors’ economic security access</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall conduct a study on the barriers that survivors of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking throughout the United States experience in maintaining economic security, including the impact of the COVID–19 pandemic on such victims’ ability to maintain economic security, as a result of issues related to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-03-15">March 15, 2022</date>, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall submit a report to Congress on the study conducted under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The study and reports under this section shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> identification of geographic areas in which State laws, regulations, and practices have a strong impact on the ability of survivors of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking to exercise—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any rights under this title (including any amendments made by this title) without compromising personal safety or the safety of others, including family members and excluding the abuser; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other components of economic security, including financial empowerment, affordable housing, transportation, health care access, credit history, and quality education and training opportunities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> identification of geographic areas with shortages in resources for such survivors, with an accompanying analysis of the extent and impact of such shortage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> analysis of the unique barriers faced by such survivors living in rural communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> analysis of factors related to industries, workplace settings, employer practices, trends, and other elements that impact the ability of such survivors to exercise any rights under this Act (including any amendments made by this Act) without compromising personal safety or the safety of others, including family members;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the recommendations of the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Labor with respect to resources, oversight, and enforcement tools to ensure successful implementation of the provisions of this Act in order to support the economic security and safety of survivors of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> best practices for States, employers, health carriers, insurers, and other private entities in addressing issues related to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> barriers that impede victims’ ability to pursue legal action, including legal costs and filing fees, and complexities of the jurisdiction of law enforcement agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20131.</num>
<heading> Media campaign</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Director” means the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National media campaign</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “national media campaign” means the national “Choose Respect” media campaign described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Media campaign</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall, to the extent feasible and appropriate, conduct a national “Choose Respect” media campaign in accordance with this section for the purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> preventing and discouraging violence against women, including domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking by targeting the attitudes, perceptions, and beliefs of individuals who have or are likely to commit such crimes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> encouraging victims of the crimes described in subparagraph (A) to seek help through the means determined to be most effective by the most current evidence available, including seeking legal representation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> informing the public about the help available to victims of the crimes described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Amounts made available to carry out this section for the national media campaign may only be used for the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The purchase of media time and space, including the strategic planning for, tracking, and accounting of, such purchases.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Creative and talent costs, consistent with subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Advertising production costs, which may include television, radio, internet, social media, and other commercial marketing venues.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Testing and evaluation of advertising.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Evaluation of the effectiveness of the national media campaign.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Costs of contracts to carry out activities authorized by this subsection.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> Partnerships with professional and civic groups, community-based organizations, including faith-based organizations and culturally specific organizations, and government organizations related to the national media campaign.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> Entertainment industry outreach, interactive outreach, media projects and activities, public information, news media outreach, corporate sponsorship and participation, and professional sports associations and military branch participation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> Operational and management expenses.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific requirements</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Creative services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In using amounts for creative and talent costs under subparagraph (A), the Director shall use creative services donated at no cost to the Government wherever feasible and may only procure creative services for advertising—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> responding to high-priority or emergent campaign needs that cannot timely be obtained at no cost; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> intended to reach a minority, ethnic, or other special audience that cannot reasonably be obtained at no cost.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Testing and evaluation of advertising</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In using amounts for testing and evaluation of advertising under subparagraph (A)(iv), the Director shall test all advertisements prior to use in the national media campaign to ensure that the advertisements are effective with the target audience and meet industry-accepted standards. The Director may waive this requirement for advertisements using not more than 10 percent of the purchase of advertising time purchased under this section in a fiscal year and not more than 10 percent of the advertising space purchased under this section in a fiscal year, if the advertisements respond to emergent and time-sensitive campaign needs or the advertisements will not be widely utilized in the national media campaign.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For the planning of the campaign under paragraph (2), the Director may consult with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Office for Victims of Crime, the Administration on Children, Youth and Families, and other related Federal Government entities;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> State, local, and Indian Tribal governments;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the prevention of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, including national and local non-profits; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> communications professionals.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation of effectiveness of national media campaign</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In using amounts for the evaluation of the effectiveness of the national media campaign under subparagraph (A)(v), the Attorney General shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> designate an independent entity to evaluate by April 20 of each year the effectiveness of the national media campaign based on data from any relevant studies or publications, as determined by the Attorney General, including tracking and evaluation data collected according to marketing and advertising industry standards; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> ensure that the effectiveness of the national media campaign is evaluated in a manner that enables consideration of whether the national media campaign has contributed to changes in attitude or behaviors among the target audience with respect to violence against women and such other measures of evaluation as the Attorney General determines are appropriate.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advertising</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out this subsection, the Director shall ensure that sufficient funds are allocated to meet the stated goals of the national media campaign.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities and functions under the program</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director shall determine the overall purposes and strategy of the national media campaign.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Director shall approve—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the strategy of the national media campaign;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> all advertising and promotional material used in the national media campaign; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the plan for the purchase of advertising time and space for the national media campaign.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Director shall be responsible for implementing a focused national media campaign to meet the purposes described in paragraph (2) and shall ensure—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> information disseminated through the campaign is accurate and scientifically valid; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> the campaign is designed using strategies demonstrated to be the most effective at achieving the goals and requirements of paragraph (2), which may include—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> a media campaign, as described in paragraph (3);</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> local, regional, or population specific messaging;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(cc)</num>
<content> the development of websites to publicize and disseminate information;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(dd)</num>
<content> conducting outreach and providing educational resources for women;</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(ee)</num>
<content> collaborating with law enforcement agencies; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(ff)</num>
<content> providing support for school-based public health education classes to improve teen knowledge about the effects of violence against women.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">None of the amounts made available under paragraph (3) may be obligated or expended for any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To supplant current antiviolence against women campaigns by community-based coalitions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To supplant pro bono public service time donated by national and local broadcasting networks for other public service campaigns.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> For partisan political purposes, or to express advocacy in support of or to defeat any clearly identified candidate, clearly identified ballot initiative, or clearly identified legislative or regulatory proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> To fund advertising that features any elected officials, persons seeking elected office, cabinet level officials, or other Federal officials employed pursuant to schedule C of subpart C of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> To fund advertising that does not contain a primary message intended to reduce or prevent violence against women.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> To fund advertising containing a primary message intended to promote support for the national media campaign or private sector contributions to the national media campaign.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial and performance accountability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall cause to be performed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> audits and reviews of costs of the national media campaign pursuant to <ref>section 4706 of title 41</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an audit to determine whether the costs of the national media campaign are allowable under chapter 43 of title 41.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall submit on an annual basis a report to Congress that describes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the strategy of the national media campaign and whether specific objectives of the national media campaign were accomplished;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> steps taken to ensure that the national media campaign operates in an effective and efficient manner consistent with the overall strategy and focus of the national media campaign;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> plans to purchase advertising time and space;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> policies and practices implemented to ensure that Federal funds are used responsibly to purchase advertising time and space and eliminate the potential for waste, fraud, and abuse;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> all contracts entered into with a corporation, partnership, or individual working on behalf of the national media campaign;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the results of any financial audit of the national media campaign;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a description of any evidence used to develop the national media campaign;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> specific policies and steps implemented to ensure compliance with this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a detailed accounting of the amount of funds obligated during the previous fiscal year for carrying out the national media campaign, including each recipient of funds, the purpose of each expenditure, the amount of each expenditure, any available outcome information, and any other information necessary to provide a complete accounting of the funds expended; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> a review and evaluation of the effectiveness of the national media campaign strategy for the previous year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title XIII, § 1310(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 931</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>ADDITIONAL VICTIM COMPENSATION AND SERVICES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20141.</num>
<heading> Services to victims</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of responsible officials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of each department and agency of the United States engaged in the detection, investigation, or prosecution of crime shall designate by names and office titles the persons who will be responsible for identifying the victims of crime and performing the services described in subsection (c) at each stage of a criminal case.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of victims</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">At the earliest opportunity after the detection of a crime at which it may be done without interfering with an investigation, a responsible official shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify the victim or victims of a crime;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> inform the victims of their right to receive, on request, the services described in subsection (c); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> inform each victim of the name, title, and business address and telephone number of the responsible official to whom the victim should address a request for each of the services described in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description of services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A responsible official shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> inform a victim of the place where the victim may receive emergency medical and social services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> inform a victim of any restitution or other relief to which the victim may be entitled under this or any other law and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002165">1</ref> manner in which such relief may be obtained;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> inform a victim of public and private programs that are available to provide counseling, treatment, and other support to the victim; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> assist a victim in contacting the persons who are responsible for providing the services and relief described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A responsible official shall arrange for a victim to receive reasonable protection from a suspected offender and persons acting in concert with or at the behest of the suspected offender.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> During the investigation and prosecution of a crime, a responsible official shall provide a victim the earliest possible notice of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the status of the investigation of the crime, to the extent it is appropriate to inform the victim and to the extent that it will not interfere with the investigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the arrest of a suspected offender;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the filing of charges against a suspected offender;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the scheduling of each court proceeding that the witness is either required to attend or, under section 10606(b)(4) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002166">2</ref> of title 42, is entitled to attend;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the release or detention status of an offender or suspected offender;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the acceptance of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere or the rendering of a verdict after trial; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the sentence imposed on an offender, including the date on which the offender will be eligible for parole.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> During court proceedings, a responsible official shall ensure that a victim is provided a waiting area removed from and out of the sight and hearing of the defendant and defense witnesses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> After trial, a responsible official shall provide a victim the earliest possible notice of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the scheduling of a parole hearing for the offender;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the escape, work release, furlough, or any other form of release from custody of the offender; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the death of the offender, if the offender dies while in custody.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> At all times, a responsible official shall ensure that any property of a victim that is being held for evidentiary purposes be maintained in good condition and returned to the victim as soon as it is no longer needed for evidentiary purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Attorney General or the head of another department or agency that conducts an investigation of a sexual assault shall pay, either directly or by reimbursement of payment by the victim, the cost of a physical examination of the victim which an investigating officer determines was necessary or useful for evidentiary purposes. The Attorney General shall provide for the payment of the cost of up to 2 anonymous and confidential tests of the victim for sexually transmitted diseases, including HIV, gonorrhea, herpes, chlamydia, and syphilis, during the 12 months following sexual assaults that pose a risk of transmission, and the cost of a counseling session by a medically trained professional on the accuracy of such tests and the risk of transmission of sexually transmitted diseases to the victim as the result of the assault. A victim may waive anonymity and confidentiality of any tests paid for under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> A responsible official shall provide the victim with general information regarding the corrections process, including information about work release, furlough, probation, and eligibility for each.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No cause of action or defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section does not create a cause of action or defense in favor of any person arising out of the failure of a responsible person to provide information as required by subsection (b) or (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “responsible official” means a person designated pursuant to subsection (a) to perform the functions of a responsible official under that section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “victim” means a person that has suffered direct physical, emotional, or pecuniary harm as a result of the commission of a crime, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a victim that is an institutional entity, an authorized representative of the entity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a victim who is under 18 years of age, incompetent, incapacitated, or deceased, one of the following (in order of preference):</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a spouse;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a legal guardian;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a parent;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a child;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a sibling;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> another family member; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> another person designated by the court.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4820</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40503(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1946</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20142.</num>
<heading> Closed circuit televised court proceedings for victims of crime</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any provision of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure to the contrary, in order to permit victims of crime to watch criminal trial proceedings in cases where the venue of the trial is changed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> out of the State in which the case was initially brought; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> more than 350 miles from the location in which those proceedings originally would have taken place;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the trial court shall order closed circuit televising of the proceedings to that location, for viewing by such persons the court determines have a compelling interest in doing so and are otherwise unable to do so by reason of the inconvenience and expense caused by the change of venue.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited access</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Generally</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No other person, other than official court and security personnel, or other persons specifically designated by the court, shall be permitted to view the closed circuit televising of the proceedings.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The court shall not designate a person under paragraph (1) if the presiding judge at the trial determines that testimony by that person would be materially affected if that person heard other testimony at the trial.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The signal transmitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall be under the control of the court at all times and shall only be transmitted subject to the terms and conditions imposed by the court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No public broadcast or dissemination shall be made of the signal transmitted pursuant to subsection (a). In the event any tapes are produced in carrying out subsection (a), such tapes shall be the property of the court and kept under seal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any violations of this subsection, or any rule or order made pursuant to this section, shall be punishable as contempt of court as described in <ref>section 402 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Donations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrative Office of the United States Courts may accept donations to enable the courts to carry out subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002167">1</ref> Nothing in this section shall be construed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to create in favor of any person a cause of action against the United States or any officer or employees thereof, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to provide any person with a defense in any action in which application of this section is made.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “State” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “State” means any State, the District of Columbia, or any possession or territory of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Judicial Conference of the United States, pursuant to its rule making authority under <ref>section 331 of title 28</ref>, may promulgate and issue rules, or amend existing rules, to effectuate the policy addressed by this section. Upon the implementation of such rules, this section shall cease to be effective.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall only apply to cases filed after <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title II, § 235</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1246</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20143.</num>
<heading> Grants for young witness assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance of the Office of Justice Programs may make grants to State and local prosecutors and law enforcement agencies in support of juvenile and young adult witness assistance programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Grants made available under this section may be used—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to assess the needs of juvenile and young adult witnesses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to develop appropriate program goals and objectives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to develop and administer a variety of witness assistance services, which includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> counseling services to young witnesses dealing with trauma associated in witnessing a violent crime;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> pre- and post-trial assistance for the youth and their family;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> providing education services if the child is removed from or changes their school for safety concerns;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> protective services for young witnesses and their families when a serious threat of harm from the perpetrators or their associates is made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> community outreach and school-based initiatives that stimulate and maintain public awareness and support.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “juvenile” means an individual who is age 17 or younger.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “young adult” means an individual who is age 21 or younger but not a juvenile.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2006 through 2009.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1136</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3109</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–271, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 766</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20144.</num>
<heading> Justice for United States victims of state sponsored terrorism</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “Justice for United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration of the United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration of the Fund</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment and terms of Special Master</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2015-12-18">December 18, 2015</date>, the Attorney General shall appoint a Special Master. The initial term for the Special Master shall be 18 months.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Thereafter, each time there exists funds in excess of $100,000,000 in the Fund, the Attorney General shall appoint or reappoint a Special Master for such period as is appropriate, not to exceed 1 year. In addition, if there exists in the Fund funds that are less than $100,000,000, the Attorney General may appoint or reappoint a Special Master each time the Attorney General determines there are sufficient funds available in the Fund to compensate eligible claimants, for such period as is appropriate, not to exceed 1 year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special Master to administer compensation from the Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Special Master shall administer the compensation program described in this section for United States persons who are victims of state sponsored terrorism.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative costs and use of Department of Justice personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Special Master may utilize, as necessary, no more than 5 full-time equivalent Department of Justice personnel to assist in carrying out the duties of the Special Master under this section, except that, during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2019-11-21">November 21, 2019</date>, the Special Master may utilize an additional 5 full-time equivalent Department of Justice personnel and during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>, the Special Master may utilize an additional 5 full-time equivalent Department of Justice personnel. Any costs associated with the use of such personnel, and any other administrative costs of carrying out this section, shall be paid from the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation of Special Master</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Special Master shall be compensated from the Fund at a rate not to exceed the annual rate of basic pay for level IV of the Executive Schedule, as prescribed by <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of regulations and procedures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 60 days after the date of the initial appointment of the Special Master, the Special Master shall publish in the Federal Register and on a website maintained by the Department of Justice a notice specifying the procedures necessary for United States persons to apply and establish eligibility for payment, including procedures by which eligible United States persons may apply by and through their attorney. Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of the United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Fund Clarification Act, the Special Master shall update, as necessary as a result of the enactment of such Act, such procedures and other guidance previously issued by the Special Master. Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of the Fairness for 9/11 Families Act, the Special Master shall update, as necessary as a result of the enactment of such Act, such procedures and other guidance previously issued by the Special Master. Such notice and any updates to that notice or other guidance are not subject to the requirements of <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information regarding other sources of compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As part of the procedures for United States persons to apply and establish eligibility for payment, the Special Master shall require applicants to provide the Special Master with information regarding compensation from any source other than this Fund that the claimant (or, in the case of a personal representative, the victim’s beneficiaries) has received or is entitled or scheduled to receive as a result of the act of international terrorism that gave rise to a claimant’s final judgment, including information identifying the amount, nature, and source of such compensation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decisions of the Special Master</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">All decisions made by the Special Master with regard to compensation from the Fund shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in writing and provided to the Attorney General, each claimant and, if applicable, the attorney for each claimant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> final and, except as provided in paragraph (4), not subject to administrative or judicial review.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review hearing</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after receipt of a written decision by the Special Master, a claimant whose claim is denied in whole or in part by the Special Master may request a hearing before the Special Master pursuant to procedures established by the Special Master.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Not later than 90 days after any such hearing, the Special Master shall issue a final written decision affirming or amending the original decision. The written decision is final and nonreviewable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible claims</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For the purposes of this section, a claim is an eligible claim if the Special Master determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the judgment holder, or claimant, is a United States person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the claim is described in paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the requirements of paragraph (3) are met.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain claims</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The claims referred to in paragraph (1) are claims for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> compensatory damages awarded to a United States person in a final judgment—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> issued by a United States district court under State or Federal law against a foreign state that was designated as a state sponsor of terrorism at the time the acts described in clause (ii) occurred or was so designated as a result of such acts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> arising from acts of international terrorism, for which the foreign state was determined not to be immune from the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States under section 1605A, or section 1605(a)(7) (as such section was in effect on <date date="2008-01-27">January 27, 2008</date>), of title 28;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the sum total of $10,000 per day for each day that a United States person was taken and held hostage from the United States embassy in Tehran, Iran, during the period beginning <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, and ending <date date="1981-01-20">January 20, 1981</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> damages for the spouses and children of the former hostages described in subparagraph (B), if such spouse or child is identified as a member of the proposed class in case number 1:00-CV-03110 (EGS) of the United States Court for the District of Columbia, in the following amounts:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> For each spouse of a former hostage identified as a member of the proposed class described in this subparagraph, a $600,000 lump sum.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> For each child of a former hostage identified as a member of the proposed class described in this subparagraph, a $600,000 lump sum.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline for application submission</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The deadline for submitting an application for a payment under this subsection is as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 90 days after the date of the publication required under subsection (b)(2)(A), with regard to an application based on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a final judgment described in paragraph (2)(A) obtained before that date of publication; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a claim described in paragraph (2)(B) or (2)(C), except that any United States person with an eligible claim described in paragraph (2)(B) who did not have an eligible claim before <date date="2019-11-21">November 21, 2019</date>, shall have 90 days from <date date="2019-11-21">November 21, 2019</date>, to submit an application for payment.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 90 days after the date of obtaining a final judgment, with regard to a final judgment obtained on or after the date of that publication, unless—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the final judgment was awarded to a 9/11 victim, 9/11 spouse, or 9/11 dependent before <date date="2019-11-21">November 21, 2019</date>, in which case such United States person shall have 90 days from the date of enactment of such Act to submit an application for payment; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the final judgment was awarded to a 1983 Beirut barracks bombing victim or a 1996 Khobar Towers bombing victim before <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>, in which case such United States person shall have 180 days from <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>, to submit an application for payment.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Good cause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For good cause shown, the Special Master may grant a claimant a reasonable extension of a deadline under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> To whom made</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Special Master shall order payment from the Fund for each eligible claim of a United States person to that person or, if that person is deceased, to the personal representative of the estate of that person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing of initial payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Special Master shall authorize all initial payments to satisfy eligible claims under this section not later than 1 year after <date date="2015-12-18">December 18, 2015</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments to be made pro rata</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pro rata basis</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Except as provided in subparagraph (B) and subject to the limitations described in clause (ii), the Special Master shall carry out paragraph (1), by—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> dividing all available funds in half and allocating 50 percent of the available funds to non-9/11 related victims of state sponsored terrorism and the remaining 50 percent of the available funds to 9/11 related victims of state sponsored terrorism;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> further dividing the funds allocated to non-9/11 related victims of state sponsored terrorism on a pro rata basis, based on the amounts outstanding and unpaid on eligible claims, until such amounts have been paid in full or the Fund is closed; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> further dividing the funds allocated to 9/11 related victims of state sponsored terrorism on a pro rata basis, based on the amounts outstanding and unpaid on eligible claims, until such amounts have been paid in full or the Fund is closed.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The limitations described in this clause are as follows:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> In the event that a United States person has an eligible claim that exceeds $20,000,000, the Special Master shall treat that claim as if it were for $20,000,000 for purposes of this section.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> In the event that a non-9/11 related victim of state sponsored terrorism and the immediate family members of such person have claims that if aggregated would exceed $35,000,000, the Special Master shall, for purposes of this section, reduce such claims on a pro rata basis such that in the aggregate such claims do not exceed $35,000,000.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> In the event that a 9/11 victim, 9/11 spouse, or 9/11 dependent and the immediate family members of such person (who are also 9/11 victims, 9/11 spouses, or 9/11 dependents) have claims that if aggregated would exceed $35,000,000, the Special Master shall, for purposes of this section, reduce such claims on a pro rata basis such that in the aggregate such claims do not exceed $35,000,000.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> In the event that a 9/11 family member and the family members of such person (who are also 9/11 family members) have claims that if aggregated would exceed $20,000,000, the Special Master shall, for purposes of this section, reduce such claims on a pro rata basis such that in the aggregate such claims do not exceed $20,000,000.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum payments</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Any applicant with an eligible claim described in subsection (c)(2) who has received, or is entitled or scheduled to receive, any payment that is equal to, or in excess of, 30 percent of the total compensatory damages owed to such applicant on the applicant’s claim from any source other than this Fund shall not receive any payment from the Fund until such time as all other eligible applicants have received from the Fund an amount equal to 30 percent of the compensatory damages awarded to those applicants pursuant to their final judgments or to claims under subsection (c)(2)(B) or (c)(2)(C). For purposes of calculating the pro rata amounts for these payments, the Special Master shall not include the total compensatory damages for applicants excluded from payment by this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> To the extent that an applicant with an eligible claim has received less than 30 percent of the compensatory damages owed that applicant under a final judgment or claim described in subsection (c)(2) from any source other than this Fund, such applicant may apply to the Special Master for the difference between the percentage of compensatory damages the applicant has received from other sources and the percentage of compensatory damages to be awarded other eligible applicants from the Fund.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> For the purposes of clause (i), the calculation of the total compensatory damages received or entitled or scheduled to be received by an applicant who is a 1983 Beirut barracks bombing victim or a 1996 Khobar Towers bombing victim from any source other than the Fund shall include the total amount received by the applicant as a result of or in connection with the proceedings captioned Peterson v. Islamic Republic of Iran, No. 10 Vic. 4518 (S.D.N.Y.), or the proceedings captioned In Re 650 Fifth Avenue &amp; Related Properties, No. 08 Civ. 10934 (S.D.N.Y. filed <date date="2008-12-17">Dec. 17, 2008</date>), such that any such applicant who has received or is entitled or scheduled to receive 30 percent or more of such applicant’s compensatory damages judgment as a result of or in connection with such proceedings shall not receive any payment from the Fund, except in accordance with the requirements of clause (i), or as part of a lump-sum catch-up payment in accordance with paragraph (4)(D).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional payments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D), on January 1 of the second calendar year that begins after the date of the initial payments described in paragraph (1) if funds are available in the Fund, the Special Master shall authorize additional payments on a pro rata basis to those claimants with eligible claims under subsection (c)(2) and shall authorize additional payments for eligible claims annually thereafter if funds are available in the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Third round payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Special Master shall authorize third-round payments to satisfy eligible claims under this section not earlier than 90 days, and not later than 180 days, after <date date="2019-11-21">November 21, 2019</date>. The Special Master shall accept applications from eligible applicants (consistent with the deadlines for application submission prescribed in subsection (c)(3)) until the date that is 90 days after <date date="2019-11-21">November 21, 2019</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lump sum catch-up payments for 9/11 victims, 9/11 spouses, and 9/11 dependents</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, and in accordance with clauses (i) and (ii) of subsection (d)(3)(A), the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an audit and publish in the Federal Register a notice of proposed lump sum catch-up payments to 9/11 victims, 9/11 spouses, and 9/11 dependents who have submitted applications in accordance with subparagraph (B) in amounts that, after receiving the lump sum catch-up payments, would result in the percentage of the claims of 9/11 victims, 9/11 spouses, and 9/11 dependents received from the Fund being equal to the percentage of the claims of 9/11 family members received from the Fund, as of <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Comptroller General shall provide an opportunity for public comment for a 30-day period beginning on the date on which the notice is published under clause (i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Not later than 30 days after the expiration comment period in clause (ii), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and the Special Master a report that includes the determination of the Comptroller General on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the amount of the lump sum catch-up payment for each 9/11 victim;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the amount of the lump sum catch-up payment for each 9/11 spouse;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the amount of the lump sum catch-up payment for each 9/11 dependent; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the total amount of lump sum catch-up payments described in subclauses (I) through (III).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The Special Master shall authorize lump sum catch-up payments in amounts equal to the amounts described in subclauses (I), (II), and (III) of clause (iii).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriations</heading>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(aa)</num>
<heading> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">There are authorized to be appropriated and there are appropriated to the Fund such sums as are necessary to carry out this clause, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</item>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(bb)</num>
<heading> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">Amounts appropriated pursuant to item (aa) may not be used for a purpose other than to make lump sum catch-up payments under this clause.</p>
</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lump sum catch-up payments for 1983 Beirut barracks bombing victims and 1996 Khobar Towers bombing victims</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>, and in accordance with clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (3)(A), the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an audit and publish in the Federal Register a notice of proposed lump sum catch-up payments to the 1983 Beirut barracks bombing victims and the 1996 Khobar Towers bombing victims who have submitted applications in accordance with subsection (c)(3)(A)(ii)(II) on or after such date of enactment, in amounts that, after receiving the lump sum catch-up payments, would result in the percentage of the claims of such victims received from the Fund being equal to the percentage of the claims of non-9/11 victims of state sponsored terrorism received from the Fund, as of <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Comptroller General shall provide an opportunity for public comment for a 30-day period beginning on the date on which the notice is published under clause (i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Not later than 30 days after the expiration of the comment period in clause (ii), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and the Special Master a report that includes the determination of the Comptroller General on—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the amount of the proposed lump sum catch-up payment for each 1983 Beirut barracks bombing victim;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the amount of the proposed lump sum catch-up payment for each 1996 Khobar Towers bombing victim; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> amount of lump sum catch-up payments described in subclauses (I) and (II).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lump sum catch-up payment reserve fund</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">There is established within the Fund a lump sum catch-up payment reserve fund, to remain in reserve except in accordance with this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Not earlier than 90 days after the date on which the Comptroller General submits the report required under clause (iii), and not later than 1 year after such date, the Special Master shall authorize lump sum catch-up payments from the reserve fund established under subclause (I) in amounts equal to the amounts described in subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (iii).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriations</heading>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(aa)</num>
<heading> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">There are authorized to be appropriated and there are appropriated to the lump sum catch-up payment reserve fund $3,000,000,000 to carry out this clause, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</item>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(bb)</num>
<heading> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">Except as provided in subclause (IV), amounts appropriated pursuant to item (aa) may not be used for a purpose other than to make lump sum catch-up payments under this clause.</p>
</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(IV)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expiration</heading>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(aa)</num>
<heading> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">The lump sum catch-up payment reserve fund established by this clause shall be terminated not later than 1 year after the Special Master disperses all lump sum catch-up payments pursuant to subclause (II).</p>
</content>
</item>
<item class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold">
<num>(bb)</num>
<heading> Remaining amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent5">All amounts remaining in the lump sum catch-up payment reserve fund in excess of the amounts described in subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (iii) shall be deposited into the Fund under this section.</p>
</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subrogation and retention of rights</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States subrogated to creditor rights to the extent of payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The United States shall be subrogated to the rights of any person who applies for and receives payments under this section, but only to the extent and in the amount of such payments made under this section. The President shall pursue these subrogated rights as claims or offsets of the United States in appropriate ways, including any negotiation process that precedes the normalization of relations between the foreign state designated as a state sponsor of terrorism and the United States or the lifting of sanctions against such foreign state.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights retained</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the extent amounts of damages remain unpaid and outstanding following any payments made under this subsection, each applicant shall retain that applicant’s creditor rights in any unpaid and outstanding amounts of the judgment, including any prejudgment or post-judgment interest, or punitive damages, awarded by the United States district court pursuant to a judgment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established in the Treasury a fund, to be designated as the United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit and transfer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Beginning on <date date="2015-12-18">December 18, 2015</date>, the following shall be deposited or transferred into the Fund for distribution under this section:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forfeited funds and property</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal funds and property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">All funds, and the net proceeds from the sale of property, forfeited or paid to the United States after <date date="2015-12-18">December 18, 2015</date>, as a criminal penalty or fine arising from a violation of any license, order, regulation, or prohibition issued under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.) or the Trading with the Enemy Act (50 U.S.C. App. 1 et seq.),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002168">1</ref> or any related criminal conspiracy, scheme, or other Federal offense arising from the actions of, or doing business with or acting on behalf of, a state sponsor of terrorism.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil funds and property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Seventy-five percent of all funds, and seventy-five percent of the net proceeds from the sale of property, forfeited or paid to the United States after <date date="2015-12-18">December 18, 2015</date>, as a civil penalty or fine arising from a violation of any license, order, regulation, or prohibition issued under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.) or the Trading with the Enemy Act (50 U.S.C. App. 1 et seq.),<sup>1</sup> or any related conspiracy, scheme, or other Federal offense arising from the actions of, or doing business with or acting on behalf of, a state sponsor of terrorism.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer into Fund of certain assigned assets of Iran and election to participate in Fund</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit into Fund of assigned proceeds from sale of properties and related assets identified in In Re 650 Fifth Avenue &amp; Related Properties</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Except as provided in subclause (II), if the United States receives a final judgment forfeiting the properties and related assets identified in the proceedings captioned as In Re 650 Fifth Avenue &amp; Related Properties, No. 08 Civ. 10934 (S.D.N.Y. filed <date date="2008-12-17">Dec. 17, 2008</date>), the net proceeds (not including the litigation expenses and sales costs incurred by the United States) resulting from the sale of such properties and related assets by the United States shall be deposited into the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent4">The following proceeds resulting from any sale of the properties and related assets identified in subclause (I) shall not be transferred into the Fund:</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> The percentage of proceeds attributable to any party identified as a Settling Judgment Creditor in the order dated <date date="2014-04-16">April 16, 2014</date>, in such proceedings, who does not make an election (described in clause (iii)) to participate in the Fund.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> The percentage of proceeds attributable to the parties identified as the Hegna Judgment Creditors in such proceedings, unless and until a final judgment is entered denying the claims of such creditors.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit into Fund of assigned assets identified in Peterson v. Islamic Republic of Iran</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If a final judgment is entered in Peterson v. Islamic Republic of Iran, No. 10 Civ. 4518 (S.D.N.Y.), awarding the assets at issue in that case to the judgment creditors identified in the order dated <date date="2013-07-09">July 9, 2013</date>, those assets shall be deposited into the Fund, but only to the extent, and in such percentage, that the rights, title, and interest to such assets were assigned through elections made pursuant to clause (iii).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election to participate in the Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Upon written notice to the Attorney General, the Special Master, and the chief judge of the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York within 60 days after the date of the publication required under subsection (b)(2)(A) a United States person, who is a judgment creditor in the proceedings captioned Peterson v. Islamic Republic of Iran, No. 10 Civ. 4518 (S.D.N.Y.), or a Settling Judgment Creditor as identified in the order dated <date date="2014-05-27">May 27, 2014</date>, in the proceedings captioned In Re 650 Fifth Avenue &amp; Related Properties, No. 08 Civ. 10934 (S.D.N.Y. filed <date date="2008-12-17">Dec. 17, 2008</date>), shall have the right to elect to participate in the Fund and, to the extent any such person exercises such right, shall irrevocably assign to the Fund all rights, title, and interest to such person’s claims to the assets at issue in such proceedings. To the extent that a United States person is both a judgment creditor in the proceedings captioned Peterson v. Islamic Republic of Iran, No. 10 Civ. 4518 (S.D.N.Y.) and a Settling Judgment Creditor in In Re 650 Fifth Avenue &amp; Related Properties, No. 08 Civ. 10934 (S.D.N.Y. filed <date date="2008-12-17">Dec. 17, 2008</date>), any election by such person to participate in the Fund pursuant to this paragraph shall operate as an election to assign any and all rights, title, and interest in the assets in both actions for the purposes of participating in the Fund. The Attorney General is authorized to pursue any such assigned rights, title, and interest in those claims for the benefit of the Fund.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application for conditional payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">A United States person who is a judgment creditor or a Settling Judgment Creditor in the proceedings identified in clause (iii) and who does not elect to participate in the Fund may, notwithstanding such failure to elect, submit an application for conditional payment from the Fund, subject to the following limitations:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Notwithstanding any such claimant’s eligibility for payment and the initial deadline for initial payments set forth in subsection (d)(2), the Special Master shall allocate but withhold payment to an eligible claimant who applies for a conditional payment under this paragraph until such time as an adverse final judgment is entered in both of the proceedings identified in clause (iii).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> In the event that an adverse final judgment is entered in the proceedings captioned Peterson v. Islamic Republic of Iran, No. 10 Civ. 4518 (S.D.N.Y), prior to a final judgment being entered in the proceedings captioned In Re 650 Fifth Avenue &amp; Related Properties, No. 08 Civ. 10934 (S.D.N.Y. filed <date date="2008-12-17">Dec. 17, 2008</date>), the Special Master shall release a portion of an eligible claimant’s conditional payment to such eligible claimant if the Special Master anticipates that such claimant will receive less than the amount of the conditional payment from any proceeds from a final judgment that is entered in favor of the plaintiffs in In Re 650 Fifth Avenue &amp; Related Properties. Such portion shall not exceed the difference between the amount of the conditional payment and the amount the Special Master anticipates such claimant will receive from the proceeds of In Re 650 Fifth Avenue &amp; Related Properties.</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> In the event that a final judgment is entered in favor of the plaintiffs in the proceedings captioned Peterson v. Islamic Republic of Iran, No. 10 Civ. 4518 (S.D.N.Y) and funds are distributed, the payments allocated to claimants who applied for a conditional payment under this subparagraph shall be considered void, and any funds previously allocated to such conditional payments shall be made available and distributed to all other eligible claimants pursuant to subsection (d).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for 1983 Beirut barracks bombing victims and 1996 Khobar Towers bombing victims</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Nothing in this subparagraph shall apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a 1983 Beirut barracks bombing victim or a 1996 Khobar Towers bombing victim who submits an application under subsection (c)(3)(A)(ii)(II) on or after <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the assets, or the net proceeds of the sale of properties or related assets, attributable to a person described in subclause (I).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures from Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts in the Fund shall be available, without further appropriation, for the payment of eligible claims and compensation of the Special Master in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Management of Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Fund shall be managed and invested in the same manner as a trust fund is managed and invested under <ref>section 9602 of title 26</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is appropriated to the Fund, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $1,025,000,000 for fiscal year 2017, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Amounts in the Fund may not be obligated on or after <date date="2039-01-02">January 2, 2039</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Closing of Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Effective on the day after all amounts authorized to be paid from the Fund under this section that were obligated before <date date="2039-01-02">January 2, 2039</date> are expended, any unobligated balances in the Fund shall be transferred, as appropriate, to either the Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund established under <ref>section 9705 of title 31</ref> or to the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund established under <ref>section 524(c)(1) of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorneys’ fees and costs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No attorney representing a non-9/11 related victim of state sponsored terrorism shall charge, receive, or collect, and the Special Master shall not approve, any payment of fees and costs that in the aggregate exceeds 25 percent of any payment made under this section. After <date date="2019-11-21">November 21, 2019</date>, no attorney representing a 9/11 related victim of state sponsored terrorism shall charge, receive, or collect, and the Special Master shall not approve, any payment of fees and costs that in the aggregate exceeds 15 percent of any payment made under this section after <date date="2019-11-21">November 21, 2019</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any attorney who violates paragraph (1) shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Award of compensation to informers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any United States person who holds a final judgment described in subsection (c)(2)(A) or a claim under subsection (c)(2)(B) or (c)(2)(C) and who meets the requirements set forth in paragraph (2) is entitled to receive an award of 10 percent of the funds deposited in the Fund under subsection (e)(2) attributable to information such person furnished to the Attorney General that leads to a forfeiture described in subsection (e)(2)(A), which is made after <date date="2015-12-18">December 18, 2015</date>, pursuant to a proceeding resulting in forfeiture that was initiated after <date date="2015-12-18">December 18, 2015</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A person meets the requirements of this paragraph if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the person identifies and notifies the Attorney General of funds or property—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of a state sponsor of terrorism, or held by a third party on behalf of or subject to the control of that state sponsor of terrorism;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that were not previously identified or known by the United States Government; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> that are subsequently forfeited directly or in the form of substitute assets to the United States; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Attorney General finds that the identification and notification under subparagraph (A) by that person substantially contributed to the forfeiture to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special exclusion from compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In no event shall an individual who is criminally culpable for an act of international terrorism receive any compensation under this section, either directly or on behalf of a victim.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Within 30 days after authorizing the payment of compensation of eligible claims pursuant to subsection (d), the Special Master shall submit to the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report on the payment of eligible claims, which shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an explanation of the procedures for filing and processing of applications for compensation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> an analysis of the payments made to United States persons from the Fund and the amount of outstanding eligible claims, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of applications for compensation submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of applications approved and the amount of each award;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number of applications denied and the reasons for the denial;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the number of applications for compensation that are pending for which compensatory damages have not been paid in full; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the total amount of compensatory damages from eligible claims that have been paid and that remain unpaid.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Act of international terrorism</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “act of international terrorism” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an act of torture, extrajudicial killing, aircraft sabotage, or hostage taking as those terms are defined in <ref>section 1605A(h) of title 28</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing material support or resources, as defined in <ref>section 2339A of title 18</ref>, for an act described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adverse final judgment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “adverse final judgment” means a final judgment in favor of the defendant, or defendants, in the proceedings identified in subsection (e)(2)(B)(iii), or which does not order any payment from, or award any interest in, the assets at issue in such proceedings to the plaintiffs, judgment creditors, or Settling Judgment Creditors in such proceedings.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensatory damages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “compensatory damages” does not include pre-judgment or post-judgment interest or punitive damages.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final judgment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “final judgment” means an enforceable final judgment, decree or order on liability and damages entered by a United States district court that is not subject to further appellate review, but does not include a judgment, decree, or order that has been waived, relinquished, satisfied, espoused by the United States, or subject to a bilateral claims settlement agreement between the United States and a foreign state. In the case of a default judgment, such judgment shall not be considered a final judgment until such time as service of process has been completed pursuant to <ref>section 1608(e) of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Fund” means the United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Fund established by this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Source other than this Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “source other than this Fund” means all collateral sources, including life insurance, pension funds, death benefit programs, payments by Federal, State, or local governments, and court awarded compensation related to the act of international terrorism that gave rise to a claimant’s final judgment, except that the term does not include payments received in connection with an international claims agreement to which the United States is a state party or any other settlement of terrorism-related claims against Sudan. The term “entitled or scheduled to receive” in subsection (d)(3)(B)(i) includes any potential recovery where that person or their representative is a party to any civil or administrative action pending in any court or agency of competent jurisdiction in which the party seeks to enforce the judgment giving rise to the application to the Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State sponsor of terrorism</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “state sponsor of terrorism” means a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined, for purposes of section 4605(j) <sup>1</sup> of title 50, <ref>section 2371 of title 22</ref>, <ref>section 2780 of title 22</ref>, or any other provision of law, is a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States person” means a natural person who has suffered an injury arising from the actions of a foreign state for which the foreign state has been determined not to be immune from the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States under section 1605A or section 1605(a)(7) (as such section was in effect on <date date="2008-01-27">January 27, 2008</date>) of title 28 or is eligible to make a claim under subsection (c)(2)(B) or subsection (c)(2)(C).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-9/11 related victim of state sponsored terrorism</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “non-9/11 victim of state sponsored terrorism” means a United States person who has an eligible claim under subsection (c) that is unrelated to the acts of international terrorism carried out on <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 9/11 related victim of state sponsored terrorism</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “9/11 related victim of state sponsored terrorism” means a 9/11 victim, 9/11 spouse, 9/11 dependent, or 9/11 family member.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 9/11 dependent</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “9/11 dependent” means a United States person who has an eligible claim under subsection (c) who at the time of a 9/11 victim’s death was—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a dependent, as defined in section 104.3 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto, of the 9/11 victim; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the child of the 9/11 victim who has not, before <date date="2019-11-21">November 21, 2019</date>, received payment from the Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 9/11 family member</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “9/11 family member” means the immediate family member of an individual described in section 405(c) of the Air Transportation Safety and System Stabilization Act (<ref>49 U.S.C. 40101</ref> note) who is not a 9/11 dependent or a 9/11 spouse.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 9/11 spouse</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “9/11 spouse” means a United States person who has an eligible claim under subsection (c) who is a spouse, as defined in section 104.3 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto, of an individual described in section 405(c) of the Air Transportation Safety and System Stabilization Act (<ref>49 U.S.C. 40101</ref> note).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 9/11 victim</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “9/11 victim” means a United States person who has an eligible claim under subsection (c) who is an individual described in section 405(c)(2) of the Air Transportation Safety and System Stabilization Act (<ref>49 U.S.C. 40101</ref> note).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 1983 Beirut barracks bombing victim</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “1983 Beirut barracks bombing victim”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a plaintiff, or estate or successor in interest thereof, who has an eligible claim under subsection (c) that arises out of the <date date="1983-10-23">October 23, 1983</date>, bombing of the United States Marine Corps barracks in Beirut, Lebanon; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes a plaintiff, estate, or successor in interest described in subparagraph (A) who is a judgment creditor in the proceedings captioned Peterson v. Islamic Republic of Iran, No. 10 Vic.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002169">2</ref> 4518 (S.D.N.Y.), or a Settling Judgment Creditor as identified in the order dated <date date="2014-05-27">May 27, 2014</date>, in the proceedings captioned In Re 650 Fifth Avenue &amp; Related Properties, No. 08 Vic.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002169">2</ref> 10934 (S.D.N.Y. filed <date date="2008-12-17">Dec. 17, 2008</date>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 1996 Khobar Towers bombing victim</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “1996 Khobar Towers bombing victim”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a plaintiff, or estate or successor in interest thereof, who has an eligible claim under subsection (c) that arises out of the <date date="1996-06-25">June 25, 1996</date> bombing of the Khobar Tower housing complex in Saudi Arabia; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes a plaintiff, estate, or successor in interest described in subparagraph (A) who is a judgment creditor in the proceedings captioned Peterson v. Islamic Republic of Iran, No. 10 Vic.<sup>2</sup> 4518 (S.D.N.Y.), or a Settling Judgment Creditor as identified in the order dated <date date="2014-05-27">May 27, 2014</date>, in the proceedings captioned In Re 650 Fifth Avenue &amp; Related Properties, No. 08 Vic.<sup>2</sup> 10934 (S.D.N.Y. filed <date date="2008-12-17">Dec. 17, 2008</date>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Severability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this section are severable. If any provision of this section, or any application thereof, is found unconstitutional, that finding shall not affect any provision or application of this section not so adjudicated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3007</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–69, div. B, title VII, § 1701(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-11-21">Nov. 21, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1140</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title XVII, § 1705</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3293</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. MM, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20145.</num>
<heading> Elimination of barriers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Federal agency may not require a survivor of human trafficking who is less than 18 years of age or a homeless youth to obtain the consent or signature of the parent or guardian of the survivor or homeless youth to receive a copy of a Government-issued identity card issued to the survivor or homeless youth.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Federal agency may not charge a survivor of human trafficking or a homeless youth a fee to obtain a copy of a Government-issued identity card issued to the survivor or homeless youth.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>