<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 405—</num>
<heading>REPORTING OF UNIDENTIFIED AND MISSING PERSONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40501.</num>
<heading> Program authorized</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General may award grants to eligible entities described in paragraph (2) to enable the eligible entities to improve the transportation, processing, identification, and reporting of missing persons and unidentified remains, including migrants.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Eligible entities described in this paragraph are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> States and units of local government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Accredited, publicly funded, Combined DNA Index System (commonly known as “CODIS”) forensic laboratories, which demonstrate the grant funds will be used for DNA typing and uploading biological family DNA reference samples, including samples from foreign nationals, into CODIS, subject to the protocols for inclusion of such forensic DNA profiles into CODIS, and the privacy protections required under <ref>section 40502(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Medical examiners offices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Accredited, publicly funded toxicology laboratories.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Accredited, publicly funded crime laboratories.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Publicly funded university forensic anthropology laboratories.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Nonprofit organizations that have working collaborative agreements with State and county forensic offices, including medical examiners, coroners, and justices of the peace, for entry of data into CODIS or the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System (commonly known as “NamUs”), or both.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–177, title II, § 202</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–277, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-31">Dec. 31, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3368</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40502.</num>
<heading> Eligibility</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant award under this chapter, an entity described in <ref>section 40501 of this title</ref> shall submit an application at such time and in such form as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each such application shall include assurances that the applicant shall, to the greatest extent possible—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> report to the National Crime Information Center and, when possible, to law enforcement authorities throughout the applicant’s jurisdiction regarding every deceased unidentified person, regardless of age, found in the applicant’s jurisdiction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enter a complete profile of such unidentified person in compliance with the guidelines established by the Department of Justice for the National Crime Information Center Missing and Unidentified Persons File, including dental records, DNA records, x-rays, and fingerprints, if available;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enter the National Crime Information Center number or other appropriate number assigned to the unidentified person on the death certificate of each such unidentified person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> retain all such records pertaining to unidentified persons until a person is identified; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> collect and report information to the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System (NamUs) regarding missing persons and unidentified remains.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Privacy protections for biological family reference samples</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any suspected biological family DNA reference samples received from citizens of the United States or foreign nationals and uploaded into the Combined DNA Index System (commonly referred to as “CODIS”) by an accredited, publicly funded CODIS forensic laboratory awarded a grant under this section may be used only for identifying missing persons and unidentified remains.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any biological family DNA reference samples from citizens of the United States or foreign nationals entered into CODIS for purposes of identifying missing persons and unidentified remains may not be disclosed to a Federal or State law enforcement agency for law enforcement purposes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–177, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2000-03-10">Mar. 10, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 36</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–277, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-31">Dec. 31, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3369</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40503.</num>
<heading> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An applicant receiving a grant award under this chapter may use such funds to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pay for the costs incurred during or after fiscal year 2017 for the transportation, processing, identification, and reporting of missing persons and unidentified remains, including migrants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish and expand programs developed to improve the reporting of unidentified persons in accordance with the assurances provided in the application submitted pursuant to <ref>section 40502(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> hire and maintain additional DNA case analysts and technicians, fingerprint examiners, forensic odontologists, and forensic anthropologists, needed to support such identification programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> procure and maintain state of the art multi-modal, multi-purpose forensic and DNA-typing and analytical equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–177, title II, § 205</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–277, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-31">Dec. 31, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3369</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40504.</num>
<heading> Grants for the assistance of organizations to find missing adults</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General may make grants to public agencies or nonprofit private organizations, or combinations thereof, for programs—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to assist law enforcement and families in locating missing adults;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to maintain a national, interconnected database for the purpose of tracking missing adults who are determined by law enforcement to be endangered due to age, diminished mental capacity, or the circumstances of disappearance, when foul play is suspected or circumstances are unknown;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to maintain statistical information of adults reported as missing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to provide informational resources and referrals to families of missing adults;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to assist in public notification and victim advocacy related to missing adults; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to establish and maintain a national clearinghouse for missing adults.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out this title.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002218">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–468, title I, § 101</ref>, formerly § 2, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2027</ref>; renumbered title I, § 101, and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–401, § 2(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5336</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40505.</num>
<heading> Reporting on National Missing and Unidentified Persons System (NamUs) Program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 18 months after <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>, and every year thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a report to the appropriate committees of Congress regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of unidentified person cases processed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> CODIS associations and identifications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the number of anthropology cases processed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the number of suspected border crossing cases and associations made;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the number of trials supported with expert testimony;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the number of students trained and professions of those students; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the turnaround time and backlog.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–277, § 4</ref>, <date date="2020-12-31">Dec. 31, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40506.</num>
<heading> Authorization of the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002219">1</ref> shall maintain the “National Missing and Unidentified Persons System” or “NamUs”, consistent with the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The NamUs shall be a national information clearinghouse and resource center for missing, unidentified, and unclaimed person cases across the United States administered by the National Institute of Justice and managed through an agreement with an eligible entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The NamUs shall coordinate or provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> online database technology which serves as a national information clearinghouse to help expedite case associations and resolutions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> various free-of-charge forensic services to aid in the identification of missing persons and unidentified remains;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> investigative support for criminal justice efforts to help missing and unidentified person case resolutions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> technical assistance for family members of missing persons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> assistance and training by coordinating State and local service providers in order to support individuals and families impacted by the loss or disappearance of a loved one; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> training and outreach from NamUs subject matter experts, including assistance with planning and facilitating Missing Person Day events across the country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permissible use of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The permissible use of funds awarded under this section for the implementation and maintenance of the agreement created in subparagraph (a)(1) include the use of funds—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to hire additional personnel to provide case support and perform other core NamUs functions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to develop new technologies to facilitate timely data entry into the relevant data bases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to conduct contracting activities relevant to core NamUs services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to provide forensic analyses to support the identification of missing and unidentified persons, to include, but not limited to DNA typing, forensic odontology, fingerprint examination, and forensic anthropology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to train State, local, and Tribal law enforcement personnel and forensic medicine service providers to use NamUs resources and best practices for the investigation of missing and unidentified person cases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> to assist States in providing information to the NCIC database, the NamUs database, or any future database system for missing, unidentified, and unclaimed person cases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> to report to law enforcement authorities in the jurisdiction in which the remains were found information on every deceased, unidentified person, regardless of age;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> to participate in Missing Person Days and other events to directly support family members of the missing with NamUs case entries and DNA collections;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> to provide assistance and training by coordinating State and local service providers in order to support individuals and families;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> to conduct data analytics and research projects for the purpose of enhancing knowledge, best practices, and training related to missing and unidentified person cases, as well as developing NamUs system enhancements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> to create and maintain a secure, online, nationwide critical incident response tool for professionals that will connect law enforcement, medico-legal and emergency management professionals, as well as victims and families during a critical incident; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> for other purposes consistent with the goals of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amendments to the Crime Control Act of 1990 to require reports of missing children to NamUs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold">, (2) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amendments made by this subsection shall apply with respect to reports made before, on, or after <date date="2022-12-27">December 27, 2022</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–327, § 2</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4454</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40507.</num>
<heading> Information sharing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to NCIC</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-27">December 27, 2022</date>, the Attorney General shall, in accordance with this section, provide access to the NCIC Missing Person and Unidentified Person Files to the National Institute of Justice or its designee administering the NamUs program as a grantee or contractor, for the purpose of reviewing missing and unidentified person records in NCIC for case validation and NamUs data reconciliation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Electronic data sharing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after <date date="2022-12-27">December 27, 2022</date>, the Attorney General shall, in accordance with this section, have completed an assessment of the NCIC and NamUs system architectures and governing statutes, policies, and procedures and provide a proposed plan for the secure and automatic data transmission of missing and unidentified person records that are reported to and entered into the NCIC database, with the following criteria, to be electronically transmitted to the NamUs system.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Missing Person cases with an MNP (Missing Person) code of CA (Child Abduction) or AA (Amber Alert) within 72 hours of entry into NCIC;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Missing Person cases with an MNP code EME (Endangered) or EMI (Involuntary) within 30 days of entry into NCIC;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> All other Missing Person cases that have been active (non-cancelled) in NCIC for 180 days;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Unidentified person cases that have been active (non-cancelled) in NCIC for 60 days;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Once case data are transmitted to NamUs, cases are marked as such within NCIC, and any updates to such cases will be transmitted to NamUs within 24 hours.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules on confidentiality</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-27">December 27, 2022</date>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the FBI, shall promulgate rules pursuant to notice and comment that specify the information the Attorney General may allow NamUs to access from the NCIC Missing Person and Unidentified Person files or be transmitted from the NCIC database to the NamUs databases for purposes of this Act. Such rules shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide for the protection of confidential, private, and law enforcement sensitive information contained in the NCIC Missing Person and Unidentified Person files; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> specify the circumstances in which access to portions of information in the Missing Person and Unidentified Person files may be withheld from the NamUs databases.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–327, § 3</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4456</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40508.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-27">December 27, 2022</date>, and biennially thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report describing the status of the NCIC database and NamUs databases.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report required by subsection (a) shall describe, to the extent available, information on the process of information sharing between the NCIC database and NamUs databases.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–327, § 5</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4457</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>