<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 409—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL INSTANT CRIMINAL BACKGROUND CHECK SYSTEM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40901.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of timetables</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after <date date="1993-11-30">November 30, 1993</date>, the Attorney General shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> determine the type of computer hardware and software that will be used to operate the national instant criminal background check system and the means by which State criminal records systems and the telephone or electronic device of licensees will communicate with the national system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> investigate the criminal records system of each State and determine for each State a timetable by which the State should be able to provide criminal records on an on-line capacity basis to the national system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> notify each State of the determinations made pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of system</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 60 months after <date date="1993-11-30">November 30, 1993</date>, the Attorney General shall establish a national instant criminal background check system that any licensee may contact, by telephone or by other electronic means in addition to the telephone, for information, to be supplied immediately, on whether receipt of a firearm by a prospective transferee would violate <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref> or State law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voluntary background checks</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2022-06-25">June 25, 2022</date>, the Attorney General shall promulgate regulations allowing licensees to use the national instant criminal background check system established under this section for purposes of voluntarily conducting an employment background check relating to a current or prospective employee. The Attorney General may not collect a fee for an employment background check under this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Before conducting an employment background check relating to a current or prospective employee under subparagraph (A), a licensee shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provide written notice to the current or prospective employee that the licensee intends to conduct the background check; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> obtain consent to conduct the background check from the current or prospective employee in writing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An employment background check conducted by a licensee under subparagraph (A) shall not be governed by the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1681</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appeal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any individual who is the subject of an employment background check conducted by a licensee under subparagraph (A) the result of which indicates that the individual is prohibited from possessing a firearm or ammunition pursuant to subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref> may appeal the results of the background check in the same manner and to the same extent as if the individual had been the subject of a background check relating to the transfer of a firearm.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expedited action by the Attorney General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall expedite—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the upgrading and indexing of State criminal history records in the Federal criminal records system maintained by the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the development of hardware and software systems to link State criminal history check systems into the national instant criminal background check system established by the Attorney General pursuant to this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the current revitalization initiatives by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for technologically advanced fingerprint and criminal records identification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of licensees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On establishment of the system under this section, the Attorney General shall notify each licensee and the chief law enforcement officer of each State of the existence and purpose of the system and the means to be used to contact the system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative provisions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to obtain official information</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other law, the Attorney General may secure directly from any department or agency of the United States such information on persons for whom receipt of a firearm would violate subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref> or State law, as is necessary to enable the system to operate in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request of attorney general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On request of the Attorney General, the head of such department or agency shall furnish electronic versions of the information described under subparagraph (A) to the system.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quarterly submission to Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a Federal department or agency under subparagraph (A) has any record of any person demonstrating that the person falls within one of the categories described in subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref>, the head of such department or agency shall, not less frequently than quarterly, provide the pertinent information contained in such record to the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information updates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Federal department or agency, on being made aware that the basis under which a record was made available under subparagraph (A) does not apply, or no longer applies, shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> update, correct, modify, or remove the record from any database that the agency maintains and makes available to the Attorney General, in accordance with the rules pertaining to that database; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> notify the Attorney General that such basis no longer applies so that the National Instant Criminal Background Check System is kept up to date.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">The Attorney General upon receiving notice pursuant to clause (ii) shall ensure that the record in the National Instant Criminal Background Check System is updated, corrected, modified, or removed within 30 days of receipt.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Attorney General shall submit an annual report to Congress that describes the compliance of each department or agency with the provisions of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Semiannual certification and reporting</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The head of each Federal department or agency shall submit a semiannual written certification to the Attorney General indicating whether the department or agency is in compliance with the record submission requirements under subparagraph (C).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission dates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The head of a Federal department or agency shall submit a certification to the Attorney General under clause (i)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> not later than July 31 of each year, which shall address all relevant records, including those that have not been transmitted to the Attorney General, in possession of the department or agency during the period beginning on January 1 of the year and ending on June 30 of the year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> not later than January 31 of each year, which shall address all relevant records, including those that have not been transmitted to the Attorney General, in possession of the department or agency during the period beginning on July 1 of the previous year and ending on December 31 of the previous year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">A certification required under clause (i) shall state, for the applicable period—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the total number of records of the Federal department or agency demonstrating that a person falls within one of the categories described in subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> for each category of records described in subclause (I), the total number of records of the Federal department or agency that have been provided to the Attorney General; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the efforts of the Federal department or agency to ensure complete and accurate reporting of relevant records, including efforts to monitor compliance and correct any reporting failures or inaccuracies.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation plan</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-03-23">March 23, 2018</date>, the head of each Federal department or agency, in coordination with the Attorney General, shall establish a plan to ensure maximum coordination and automated reporting or making available of records to the Attorney General as required under subparagraph (C), and the verification of the accuracy of those records, including the pre-validation of those records, where appropriate, during a 4-year period specified in the plan. The records shall be limited to those of an individual described in subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benchmark requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Each plan established under clause (i) shall include annual benchmarks to enable the Attorney General to assess implementation of the plan, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> qualitative goals and quantitative measures;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> measures to monitor internal compliance, including any reporting failures and inaccuracies;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a needs assessment, including estimated compliance costs; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> an estimated date by which the Federal department or agency will fully comply with record submission requirements under subparagraph (C).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Not later than the end of each fiscal year beginning after the date of the establishment of a plan under clause (i), the Attorney General shall determine whether the applicable Federal department or agency has achieved substantial compliance with the benchmarks included in the plan.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(H)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accountability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Attorney General shall publish, including on the website of the Department of Justice, and submit to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a semiannual report that discloses—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the name of each Federal department or agency that has failed to submit a required certification under subparagraph (F);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the name of each Federal department or agency that has submitted a required certification under subparagraph (F), but failed to certify compliance with the record submission requirements under subparagraph (C);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the name of each Federal department or agency that has failed to submit an implementation plan under subparagraph (G);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the name of each Federal department or agency that is not in substantial compliance with an implementation plan under subparagraph (G);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a detailed summary of the data, broken down by department or agency, contained in the certifications submitted under subparagraph (F);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a detailed summary of the contents and status, broken down by department or agency, of the implementation plans established under subparagraph (G); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the reasons for which the Attorney General has determined that a Federal department or agency is not in substantial compliance with an implementation plan established under subparagraph (G).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Noncompliance penalties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For each of fiscal years 2019 through 2022, each political appointee of a Federal department or agency that has failed to certify compliance with the record submission requirements under subparagraph (C), and is not in substantial compliance with an implementation plan established under subparagraph (G), shall not be eligible for the receipt of bonus pay, excluding overtime pay, until the department or agency—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> certifies compliance with the record submission requirements under subparagraph (C); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> achieves substantial compliance with an implementation plan established under subparagraph (G).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(J)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Attorney General may use funds made available for the national instant criminal background check system established under subsection (b) to provide technical assistance to a Federal department or agency, at the request of the department or agency, in order to help the department or agency comply with the record submission requirements under subparagraph (C).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(K)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application to Federal courts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the terms “department or agency of the United States” and “Federal department or agency” include a Federal court; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall perform, for a Federal court, the functions assigned to the head of a department or agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall develop such computer software, design and obtain such telecommunications and computer hardware, and employ such personnel, as are necessary to establish and operate the system in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Written reasons provided on request</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the national instant criminal background check system determines that an individual is ineligible to receive a firearm and the individual requests the system to provide the reasons for the determination, the system shall provide such reasons to the individual, in writing, within 5 business days after the date of the request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correction of erroneous system information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the system established under this section informs an individual contacting the system that receipt of a firearm by a prospective transferee would violate subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref> or State law, the prospective transferee may request the Attorney General to provide the prospective transferee with the reasons therefor. Upon receipt of such a request, the Attorney General shall immediately comply with the request. The prospective transferee may submit to the Attorney General information to correct, clarify, or supplement records of the system with respect to the prospective transferee. After receipt of such information, the Attorney General shall immediately consider the information, investigate the matter further, and correct all erroneous Federal records relating to the prospective transferee and give notice of the error to any Federal department or agency or any State that was the source of such erroneous records. For purposes of the preceding sentence, not later than 60 days after the date on which the Attorney General receives such information, the Attorney General shall determine whether or not the prospective transferee is the subject of an erroneous record and remove any records that are determined to be erroneous. In addition to any funds made available under subsection (k), the Attorney General may use such sums as are necessary and otherwise available for the salaries and expenses of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to comply with this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After 90 days’ notice to the public and an opportunity for hearing by interested parties, the Attorney General shall prescribe regulations to ensure the privacy and security of the information of the system established under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition relating To establishment of registration systems with respect to firearms</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No department, agency, officer, or employee of the United States may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> require that any record or portion thereof generated by the system established under this section be recorded at or transferred to a facility owned, managed, or controlled by the United States or any State or political subdivision thereof; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use the system established under this section to establish any system for the registration of firearms, firearm owners, or firearm transactions or dispositions, except with respect to persons, prohibited by section 922(g) or (n) of title 18 or State law, from receiving a firearm.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Licensee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “licensee” means a licensed importer (as defined in <ref>section 921(a)(9) of title 18</ref>), a licensed manufacturer (as defined in section 921(a)(10) of that title), or a licensed dealer (as defined in section 921(a)(11) of that title).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “firearm”, “handgun”, “licensed importer”, “licensed manufacturer”, and “licensed dealer” have the meanings stated in <ref>section 921(a) of title 18</ref>, as amended by subsection (a)(2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to enable the Attorney General to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements relating to background checks for persons under age 21</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If a licensee contacts the system established under this section regarding a proposed transfer of a firearm to a person less than 21 years of age in accordance with subsection (t) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref>, the system shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> immediately contact—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the criminal history repository or juvenile justice information system, as appropriate, of the State in which the person resides for the purpose of determining whether the person has a possibly disqualifying juvenile record under subsection (d) of such section 922;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the appropriate State custodian of mental health adjudication records in the State in which the person resides to determine whether the person has a possibly disqualifying juvenile record under subsection (d) of such section 922; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a local law enforcement agency of the jurisdiction in which the person resides for the purpose of determining whether the person has a possibly disqualifying juvenile record under subsection (d) of such section 922;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as soon as possible, but in no case more than 3 business days, after the licensee contacts the system, notify the licensee whether cause exists to further investigate a possibly disqualifying juvenile record under subsection (d) of such section 922; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> if there is cause for further investigation, as soon as possible, but in no case more than 10 business days, after the licensee contacts the system, notify the licensee whether—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> transfer of a firearm to the person would violate subsection (d) of such section 922; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> receipt of a firearm by the person would violate subsection (g) or (n) of such section 922, or State, local, or Tribal law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–159, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1541</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXI, § 210603(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2074</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 603(h)</ref>, (i)(1), <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–180, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2561</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. S, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1132</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–159, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 12001(a)(2), (3), 12004(h)(1), <date date="2022-06-25">June 25, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1323</ref>, 1324, 1330.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40902.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Approximately 916,000 individuals were prohibited from purchasing a firearm for failing a background check between <date date="1998-11-30">November 30, 1998</date>, (the date the National Instant Criminal Background Check System (NICS) began operating) and <date date="2004-12-31">December 31, 2004</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> From <date date="1998-11-30">November 30, 1998</date>, through <date date="2004-12-31">December 31, 2004</date>, nearly 49,000,000 Brady background checks were processed through NICS.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Although most Brady background checks are processed through NICS in seconds, many background checks are delayed if the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) does not have automated access to complete information from the States concerning persons prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm under Federal or State law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Nearly 21,000,000 criminal records are not accessible by NICS and millions of criminal records are missing critical data, such as arrest dispositions, due to data backlogs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The primary cause of delay in NICS background checks is the lack of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> updates and available State criminal disposition records; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> automated access to information concerning persons prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm because of mental illness, restraining orders, or misdemeanor convictions for domestic violence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Automated access to this information can be improved by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> computerizing information relating to criminal history, criminal dispositions, mental illness, restraining orders, and misdemeanor convictions for domestic violence; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> making such information available to NICS in a usable format.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Helping States to automate these records will reduce delays for law-abiding gun purchasers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> On <date date="2002-03-12">March 12, 2002</date>, the senseless shooting, which took the lives of a priest and a parishioner at the Our Lady of Peace Church in Lynbrook, New York, brought attention to the need to improve information-sharing that would enable Federal and State law enforcement agencies to conduct a complete background check on a potential firearm purchaser. The man who committed this double murder had a prior disqualifying mental health commitment and a restraining order against him, but passed a Brady background check because NICS did not have the necessary information to determine that he was ineligible to purchase a firearm under Federal or State law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> On <date date="2007-04-16">April 16, 2007</date>, a student with a history of mental illness at the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University shot to death 32 students and faculty members, wounded 17 more, and then took his own life. The shooting, the deadliest campus shooting in United States history, renewed the need to improve information-sharing that would enable Federal and State law enforcement agencies to conduct complete background checks on potential firearms purchasers. In spite of a proven history of mental illness, the shooter was able to purchase the two firearms used in the shooting. Improved coordination between State and Federal authorities could have ensured that the shooter’s disqualifying mental health information was available to NICS.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–180, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2559</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40903.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Court order</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “court order” includes a court order (as described in <ref>section 922(g)(8) of title 18</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mental health terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “adjudicated as a mental defective” and “committed to a mental institution” have the same meanings as in <ref>section 922(g)(4) of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Misdemeanor crime of domestic violence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “misdemeanor crime of domestic violence” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 921(a)(33) of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–180, § 3</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>TRANSMITTAL OF RECORDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40911.</num>
<heading> Enhancement of requirement that Federal departments and agencies provide relevant information to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision and maintenance of NICS records</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of Homeland Security</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall make available to the Attorney General—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> records, updated not less than quarterly, which are relevant to a determination of whether a person is disqualified from possessing or receiving a firearm under subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref> for use in background checks performed by the National Instant Criminal Background Check System; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information regarding all the persons described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph who have changed their status to a category not identified under <ref>section 922(g)(5) of title 18</ref> for removal, when applicable, from the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of Defense</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 3 business days after the final disposition of a judicial proceeding conducted within the Department of Defense, the Secretary of Defense shall make available to the Attorney General records which are relevant to a determination of whether a member of the Armed Forces involved in such proceeding is disqualified from possessing or receiving a firearm under subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref> for use in background checks performed by the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial proceeding defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “judicial proceeding” means a hearing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of which the person received actual notice; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> at which the person had an opportunity to participate with counsel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of Justice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Attorney General shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure that any information submitted to, or maintained by, the Attorney General under this section is kept accurate and confidential, as required by the laws, regulations, policies, or procedures governing the applicable record system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for the timely removal and destruction of obsolete and erroneous names and information from the National Instant Criminal Background Check System; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> work with States to encourage the development of computer systems, which would permit electronic notification to the Attorney General when—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a court order has been issued, lifted, or otherwise removed by order of the court; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a person has been adjudicated as a mental defective or committed to a mental institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standard for adjudications and commitments related to mental health</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No department or agency of the Federal Government may provide to the Attorney General any record of an adjudication related to the mental health of a person or any commitment of a person to a mental institution if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the adjudication or commitment, respectively, has been set aside or expunged, or the person has otherwise been fully released or discharged from all mandatory treatment, supervision, or monitoring;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the person has been found by a court, board, commission, or other lawful authority to no longer suffer from the mental health condition that was the basis of the adjudication or commitment, respectively, or has otherwise been found to be rehabilitated through any procedure available under law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the adjudication or commitment, respectively, is based solely on a medical finding of disability, without an opportunity for a hearing by a court, board, commission, or other lawful authority, and the person has not been adjudicated as a mental defective consistent with <ref>section 922(g)(4) of title 18</ref>, except that nothing in this section or any other provision of law shall prevent a Federal department or agency from providing to the Attorney General any record demonstrating that a person was adjudicated to be not guilty by reason of insanity, or based on lack of mental responsibility, or found incompetent to stand trial, in any criminal case or under the Uniform Code of Military Justice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain adjudications and commitments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program for relief from disabilities</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each department or agency of the United States that makes any adjudication related to the mental health of a person or imposes any commitment to a mental institution, as described in subsection (d)(4) and (g)(4) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref> shall establish, not later than 120 days after <date date="2008-01-08">January 8, 2008</date>, a program that permits such a person to apply for relief from the disabilities imposed by such subsections.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each application for relief submitted under the program required by this subparagraph shall be processed not later than 365 days after the receipt of the application. If a Federal department or agency fails to resolve an application for relief within 365 days for any reason, including a lack of appropriated funds, the department or agency shall be deemed for all purposes to have denied such request for relief without cause. Judicial review of any petitions brought under this clause shall be de novo.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Relief and judicial review with respect to the program required by this subparagraph shall be available according to the standards prescribed in <ref>section 925(c) of title 18</ref>. If the denial of a petition for relief has been reversed after such judicial review, the court shall award the prevailing party, other than the United States, a reasonable attorney’s fee for any and all proceedings in relation to attaining such relief, and the United States shall be liable for such fee. Such fee shall be based upon the prevailing rates awarded to public interest legal aid organizations in the relevant community.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relief from disabilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of an adjudication related to the mental health of a person or a commitment of a person to a mental institution, a record of which may not be provided to the Attorney General under paragraph (1), including because of the absence of a finding described in subparagraph (C) of such paragraph, or from which a person has been granted relief under a program established under subparagraph (A) or (B), or because of a removal of a record under <ref>section 40901(e)(1)(D) of this title</ref>, the adjudication or commitment, respectively, shall be deemed not to have occurred for purposes of subsections (d)(4) and (g)(4) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref>. Any Federal agency that grants a person relief from disabilities under this subparagraph shall notify such person that the person is no longer prohibited under 922(d)(4) or 922(g)(4) of title 18 on account of the relieved disability for which relief was granted pursuant to a proceeding conducted under this subparagraph, with respect to the acquisition, receipt, transfer, shipment, transportation, or possession of firearms.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Effective 30 days after <date date="2008-01-08">January 8, 2008</date>, any Federal department or agency that conducts proceedings to adjudicate a person as a mental defective under 922(d)(4) or 922(g)(4) of title 18 shall provide both oral and written notice to the individual at the commencement of the adjudication process including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> notice that should the agency adjudicate the person as a mental defective, or should the person be committed to a mental institution, such adjudication, when final, or such commitment, will prohibit the individual from purchasing, possessing, receiving, shipping or transporting a firearm or ammunition under section 922(d)(4) or <ref>section 922(g)(4) of title 18</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information about the penalties imposed for unlawful possession, receipt, shipment or transportation of a firearm under <ref>section 924(a)(2) of title 18</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> information about the availability of relief from the disabilities imposed by Federal laws with respect to the acquisition, receipt, transfer, shipment, transportation, or possession of firearms.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except for paragraph (3), this subsection shall apply to names and other information provided before, on, or after <date date="2008-01-08">January 8, 2008</date>. Any name or information provided in violation of this subsection (other than in violation of paragraph (3)) before, on, or after such date shall be removed from the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–180, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2561</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 544</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40912.</num>
<heading> Requirements to obtain waiver</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning 3 years after <date date="2008-01-08">January 8, 2008</date>, a State shall be eligible to receive a waiver of the 10 percent matching requirement for National Criminal History Improvement Grants under <ref>section 40301 of this title</ref> if the State is in compliance with an implementation plan established under subsection (b) or provides at least 90 percent of the information described in subsection (c). The length of such a waiver shall not exceed 2 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State estimates</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial state estimate</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To assist the Attorney General in making a determination under subsection (a) of this section, and under <ref>section 40914 of this title</ref>, concerning the compliance of the States in providing information to the Attorney General for the purpose of receiving a waiver under subsection (a) of this section, or facing a loss of funds under <ref>section 40914 of this title</ref>, by a date not later than 180 days after <date date="2008-01-08">January 8, 2008</date>, each State shall provide the Attorney General with a reasonable estimate, as calculated by a method determined by the Attorney General and in accordance with <ref>section 40914(d) of this title</ref>, of the number of the records described in subparagraph (C) applicable to such State that concern persons who are prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm under subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to provide initial estimate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A State that fails to provide an estimate described in subparagraph (A) by the date required under such subparagraph shall be ineligible to receive any funds under <ref>section 40913 of this title</ref>, until such date as it provides such estimate to the Attorney General or has established an implementation plan under <ref>section 40917 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Record defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), a record is the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A record that identifies a person who has been convicted in any court of a crime punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A record that identifies a person for whom an indictment has been returned for a crime punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year that is valid under the laws of the State involved or who is a fugitive from justice, as of the date of the estimate, and for which a record of final disposition is not available.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A record that identifies a person who is an unlawful user of, or addicted to a controlled substance (as such terms “unlawful user” and “addicted” are respectively defined in regulations implementing <ref>section 922(g)(3) of title 18</ref> as in effect on <date date="2008-01-08">January 8, 2008</date>) as demonstrated by arrests, convictions, and adjudications, and whose record is not protected from disclosure to the Attorney General under any provision of State or Federal law.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> A record that identifies a person who has been adjudicated as a mental defective or committed to a mental institution, consistent with <ref>section 922(g)(4) of title 18</ref> and whose record is not protected from disclosure to the Attorney General under any provision of State or Federal law.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> A record that is electronically available and that identifies a person who, as of the date of such estimate, is subject to a court order described in <ref>section 922(g)(8) of title 18</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> A record that is electronically available and that identifies a person convicted in any court of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence, as defined in <ref>section 921(a)(33) of title 18</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General, in determining the compliance of a State under this section or <ref>section 40914 of this title</ref> for the purpose of granting a waiver or imposing a loss of Federal funds, shall assess the total percentage of records provided by the State concerning any event occurring within the prior 20 years, which would disqualify a person from possessing a firearm under subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Clarification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (2), States shall endeavor to provide the National Instant Criminal Background Check System with all records concerning persons who are prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm under subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref>, regardless of the elapsed time since the disqualifying event.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility of State records for submission to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for eligibility</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">From the information collected by a State, the State shall make electronically available to the Attorney General records relevant to a determination of whether a person is disqualified from possessing or receiving a firearm under subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref> or applicable State law.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> NICS updates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The State, on being made aware that the basis under which a record was made available under subparagraph (A) does not apply, or no longer applies, shall, as soon as practicable—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> update, correct, modify, or remove the record from any database that the Federal or State government maintains and makes available to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, consistent with the rules pertaining to that database; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> notify the Attorney General that such basis no longer applies so that the record system in which the record is maintained is kept up to date.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">The Attorney General upon receiving notice pursuant to clause (ii) shall ensure that the record in the National Instant Criminal Background Check System is updated, corrected, modified, or removed within 30 days of receipt.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To remain eligible for a waiver under subsection (a), a State shall certify to the Attorney General, not less than once during each 2-year period, that at least 90 percent of all records described in subparagraph (A) has been made electronically available to the Attorney General in accordance with subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of all records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, a State shall identify and include all of the records described under subparagraph (A) without regard to the age of the record.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application to persons convicted of misdemeanor crimes of domestic violence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State shall make available to the Attorney General, for use by the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, records relevant to a determination of whether a person has been convicted in any court of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence. With respect to records relating to such crimes, the State shall provide information specifically describing the offense and the specific section or subsection of the offense for which the defendant has been convicted and the relationship of the defendant to the victim in each case.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application to persons who have been adjudicated as a mental defective or committed to a mental institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The State shall make available to the Attorney General, for use by the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, the name and other relevant identifying information of persons adjudicated as a mental defective or those committed to mental institutions to assist the Attorney General in enforcing <ref>section 922(g)(4) of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Privacy protections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For any information provided to the Attorney General for use by the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, relating to persons prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm under <ref>section 922(g)(4) of title 18</ref>, the Attorney General shall work with States and local law enforcement and the mental health community to establish regulations and protocols for protecting the privacy of information provided to the system. The Attorney General shall make every effort to meet with any mental health group seeking to express its views concerning these regulations and protocols and shall seek to develop regulations as expeditiously as practicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorney General report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than January 31 of each year, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on the progress of States in automating the databases containing the information described in subsection (b) and in making that information electronically available to the Attorney General pursuant to the requirements of subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–180, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. S, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40913.</num>
<heading> Implementation assistance to States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">From amounts made available to carry out this section and subject to <ref>section 40912(b)(1)(B) of this title</ref>, the Attorney General shall make grants to States and Indian tribal governments, in a manner consistent with the National Criminal History Improvement Program, which shall be used by the States and Indian tribal governments, in conjunction with units of local government and State and local courts, to establish or upgrade information and identification technologies for firearms eligibility determinations. Not less than 3 percent, and no more than 10 percent of each grant under this paragraph shall be used to maintain the relief from disabilities program in accordance with <ref>section 40915 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants to Indian tribes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Up to 5 percent of the grant funding available under this section may be reserved for Indian tribal governments, including tribal judicial systems.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of grant amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Grants awarded to States or Indian tribes under this section may only be used to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> create electronic systems, which provide accurate and up-to-date information which is directly related to checks under the National Instant Criminal Background Check System (referred to in this section as “NICS”), including court disposition and corrections records;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assist States in establishing or enhancing their own capacities to perform NICS background checks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> supply accurate and timely information to the Attorney General concerning final dispositions of criminal records to databases accessed by NICS, including through increased efforts to pre-validate the contents of those records to expedite eligibility determinations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> supply accurate and timely information to the Attorney General concerning the identity of persons who are prohibited from obtaining a firearm under <ref>section 922(g)(4) of title 18</ref> to be used by the Federal Bureau of Investigation solely to conduct NICS background checks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> supply accurate and timely court orders and records of misdemeanor crimes of domestic violence for inclusion in Federal and State law enforcement databases used to conduct NICS background checks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> collect and analyze data needed to demonstrate levels of State compliance with this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> maintain the relief from disabilities program in accordance with <ref>section 40915 of this title</ref>, but not less than 3 percent, and no more than 10 percent of each grant shall be used for this purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To be eligible for a grant under this section, a State shall certify, to the satisfaction of the Attorney General, that the State has implemented a relief from disabilities program in accordance with <ref>section 40915 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Condition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As a condition of receiving a grant under this section, a State shall specify the projects for which grant amounts will be used, and shall use such amounts only as specified. A State that violates this subsection shall be liable to the Attorney General for the full amount of the grant received under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $125,000,000 for fiscal year 2009, $250,000,000 for fiscal year 2010, $250,000,000 for fiscal year 2011, $125,000,000 for fiscal year 2012, $125,000,000 for fiscal year 2013, and $125,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestic Abuse and Violence Prevention Initiative</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, the Attorney General shall create a priority area under the NICS Act Record Improvement Program (commonly known as “NARIP”) for a Domestic Abuse and Violence Prevention Initiative that emphasizes the need for grantees to identify and upload all felony conviction records and domestic violence records.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Attorney General—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> may use not more than 50 percent of the amounts made available under this subsection for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out the initiative described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> shall give a funding preference under NARIP to States that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> have established an implementation plan under <ref>section 40917 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> will use amounts made available under this subparagraph to improve efforts to identify and upload all felony conviction records and domestic violence records described in clauses (i), (v), and (vi) of <ref>section 40912(b)(1)(C) of this title</ref> by not later than <date date="2022-09-30">September 30, 2022</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> User fee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Bureau of Investigation shall not charge a user fee for background checks pursuant to <ref>section 922(t) of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall direct the Office of Justice Programs, the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, and the Federal Bureau of Investigation to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> assist States that are not currently eligible for grants under this section to achieve compliance with all eligibility requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide technical assistance and training services to grantees under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–180, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2567</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. S, title VI, § 603(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40914.</num>
<heading> Penalties for noncompliance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorney General report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than January 31 of each year, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on the progress of the States in automating the databases containing information described under sections 40912 and 40913 of this title, and in providing that information pursuant to the requirements of sections 40912 and 40913 of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Justice, such funds as may be necessary to carry out paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretionary reduction</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> During the 2-year period beginning 3 years after <date date="2008-01-08">January 8, 2008</date>, the Attorney General may withhold not more than 3 percent of the amount that would otherwise be allocated to a State under <ref>section 10156 of this title</ref> if the State provides less than 50 percent of the records required to be provided under sections 40912 and 40913 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> During the 5-year period after the expiration of the period referred to in subparagraph (A), the Attorney General may withhold not more than 4 percent of the amount that would otherwise be allocated to a State under <ref>section 10156 of this title</ref> if the State provides less than 70 percent of the records required to be provided under sections 40912 and 40913 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory reduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After the expiration of the periods referred to in paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall withhold 5 percent of the amount that would otherwise be allocated to a State under <ref>section 10156 of this title</ref>, if the State provides less than 90 percent of the records required to be provided under sections 40912 and 40913 of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver by Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General may waive the applicability of paragraph (2) to a State if the State provides substantial evidence, as determined by the Attorney General, that the State is making a reasonable effort to comply with the requirements of sections 40912 and 40913 of this title, including an inability to comply due to court order or other legal restriction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reallocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any funds that are not allocated to a State because of the failure of the State to comply with the requirements of this chapter shall be reallocated to States that meet such requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methodology</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The method established to calculate the number of records to be reported, as set forth in <ref>section 40912(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, and State compliance with the required level of reporting under sections 40912 and 40913 of this title shall be determined by the Attorney General. The Attorney General shall calculate the methodology based on the total number of records to be reported from all subcategories of records, as described in <ref>section 40912(b)(1)(C) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–180, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40915.</num>
<heading> Relief from disabilities program required as condition for participation in grant programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A relief from disabilities program is implemented by a State in accordance with this section if the program—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> permits a person who, pursuant to State law, has been adjudicated as described in subsection (g)(4) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref> or has been committed to a mental institution, to apply to the State for relief from the disabilities imposed by subsections (d)(4) and (g)(4) of such section by reason of the adjudication or commitment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provides that a State court, board, commission, or other lawful authority shall grant the relief, pursuant to State law and in accordance with the principles of due process, if the circumstances regarding the disabilities referred to in paragraph (1), and the person’s record and reputation, are such that the person will not be likely to act in a manner dangerous to public safety and that the granting of the relief would not be contrary to the public interest; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> permits a person whose application for the relief is denied to file a petition with the State court of appropriate jurisdiction for a de novo judicial review of the denial.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to provide relief from certain disabilities with respect to firearms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, under a State relief from disabilities program implemented in accordance with this section, an application for relief referred to in subsection (a)(1) of this section is granted with respect to an adjudication or a commitment to a mental institution or based upon a removal of a record under <ref>section 40912(c)(1)(B) of this title</ref>, the adjudication or commitment, as the case may be, is deemed not to have occurred for purposes of subsections (d)(4) and (g)(4) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–180, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2569</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40916.</num>
<heading> Illegal immigrant gun purchase notification</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law or of this chapter, all records obtained by the National Instant Criminal Background Check system relevant to whether an individual is prohibited from possessing a firearm because such person is an alien illegally or unlawfully in the United States shall be made available to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General, at his or her discretion, shall promulgate guidelines relevant to what records relevant to illegal aliens shall be provided pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–180, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2570</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 40917.</num>
<heading> Implementation plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2018-03-23">March 23, 2018</date>, the Attorney General, in coordination with the States and Indian tribal governments, shall establish, for each State or Indian tribal government, a plan to ensure maximum coordination and automation of the reporting or making available of appropriate records to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System established under <ref>section 40901 of this title</ref> and the verification of the accuracy of those records during a 4-year period specified in the plan. The records shall be limited to those of an individual described in subsection (g) or (n) of <ref>section 922 of title 18</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002221">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benchmark requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each plan established under this section shall include annual benchmarks to enable the Attorney General to assess the implementation of the plan, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> qualitative goals and quantitative measures; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a needs assessment, including estimated compliance costs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than the end of each fiscal year beginning after the date of the establishment of an implementation plan under this section, the Attorney General shall determine whether each State or Indian tribal government has achieved substantial compliance with the benchmarks included in the plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accountability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> shall disclose and publish, including on the website of the Department of Justice—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of each State or Indian tribal government that received a determination of failure to achieve substantial compliance with an implementation plan under subsection (c) for the preceding fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the reasons for which the Attorney General has determined that the State or Indian tribal government is not in substantial compliance with the implementation plan, including, to the greatest extent possible, a description of the types and amounts of records that have not been submitted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> if a State or Indian tribal government described in paragraph (1) subsequently receives a determination of substantial compliance, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> immediately correct the applicable record; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not later than 3 days after the determination, remove the record from the website of the Department of Justice and any other location where the record was published.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incentives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, the Attorney General shall give affirmative preference to all Bureau of Justice Assistance discretionary grant applications of a State or Indian tribal government that received a determination of substantial compliance under subsection (c) for the fiscal year in which the grant was solicited.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–180, title I, § 107</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. S, title VI, § 605(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1137</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>FOCUSING FEDERAL ASSISTANCE ON THE IMPROVEMENT OF RELEVANT RECORDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40931.</num>
<heading> Continuing evaluations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics (referred to in this section as the “Director”) shall study and evaluate the operations of the National Instant Criminal Background Check System. Such study and evaluation shall include compilations and analyses of the operations and record systems of the agencies and organizations necessary to support such System.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than January 31 of each year, the Director shall submit to Congress a report containing the estimates submitted by the States under <ref>section 40912(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on best practices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than January 31 of each year, the Director shall submit to Congress, and to each State participating in the National Criminal History Improvement Program, a report of the practices of the States regarding the collection, maintenance, automation, and transmittal of information relevant to determining whether a person is prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm by Federal or State law, by the State or any other agency, or any other records relevant to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, that the Director considers to be best practices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2013 to complete the studies, evaluations, and reports required under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–180, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2570</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>GRANTS TO STATE COURT SYSTEMS FOR THE IMPROVEMENT IN AUTOMATION AND TRANSMITTAL OF DISPOSITION RECORDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 40941.</num>
<heading> Disposition records automation and transmittal improvement grants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From amounts made available to carry out this section, the Attorney General shall make grants to each State, consistent with State plans for the integration, automation, and accessibility of criminal history records, for use by the State court system to improve the automation and transmittal of criminal history dispositions, records relevant to determining whether a person has been convicted of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence, court orders, and mental health adjudications or commitments, to Federal and State record repositories in accordance with sections 40912 and 40913 of this title and the National Criminal History Improvement Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants to Indian tribes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Up to 5 percent of the grant funding available under this section may be reserved for Indian tribal governments for use by Indian tribal judicial systems.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Amounts granted under this section shall be used by the State court system only—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to carry out, as necessary, assessments of the capabilities of the courts of the State for the automation and transmission of arrest and conviction records, court orders, and mental health adjudications or commitments to Federal and State record repositories; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to implement policies, systems, and procedures for the automation and transmission of arrest and conviction records, court orders, and mental health adjudications or commitments to Federal and State record repositories.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State shall certify, to the satisfaction of the Attorney General, that the State has implemented a relief from disabilities program in accordance with <ref>section 40915 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General to carry out this section $62,500,000 for fiscal year 2009, $125,000,000 for fiscal year 2010, $125,000,000 for fiscal year 2011, $62,500,000 for fiscal year 2012, and $62,500,000 for fiscal year 2013.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–180, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2571</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>