<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 303—</num>
<heading>PRISON RAPE ELIMINATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 30301.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 2,100,146 persons were incarcerated in the United States at the end of 2001: 1,324,465 in Federal and State prisons and 631,240 in county and local jails. In 1999, there were more than 10,000,000 separate admissions to and discharges from prisons and jails.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Insufficient research has been conducted and insufficient data reported on the extent of prison rape. However, experts have conservatively estimated that at least 13 percent of the inmates in the United States have been sexually assaulted in prison. Many inmates have suffered repeated assaults. Under this estimate, nearly 200,000 inmates now incarcerated have been or will be the victims of prison rape. The total number of inmates who have been sexually assaulted in the past 20 years likely exceeds 1,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Inmates with mental illness are at increased risk of sexual victimization. America’s jails and prisons house more mentally ill individuals than all of the Nation’s psychiatric hospitals combined. As many as 16 percent of inmates in State prisons and jails, and 7 percent of Federal inmates, suffer from mental illness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Young first-time offenders are at increased risk of sexual victimization. Juveniles are 5 times more likely to be sexually assaulted in adult rather than juvenile facilities—often within the first 48 hours of incarceration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Most prison staff are not adequately trained or prepared to prevent, report, or treat inmate sexual assaults.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Prison rape often goes unreported, and inmate victims often receive inadequate treatment for the severe physical and psychological effects of sexual assault—if they receive treatment at all.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> HIV and AIDS are major public health problems within America’s correctional facilities. In 2000, 25,088 inmates in Federal and State prisons were known to be infected with HIV/AIDS. In 2000, HIV/AIDS accounted for more than 6 percent of all deaths in Federal and State prisons. Infection rates for other sexually transmitted diseases, tuberculosis, and hepatitis B and C are also far greater for prisoners than for the American population as a whole. Prison rape undermines the public health by contributing to the spread of these diseases, and often giving a potential death sentence to its victims.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Prison rape endangers the public safety by making brutalized inmates more likely to commit crimes when they are released—as 600,000 inmates are each year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The frequently interracial character of prison sexual assaults significantly exacerbates interracial tensions, both within prison and, upon release of perpetrators and victims from prison, in the community at large.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Prison rape increases the level of homicides and other violence against inmates and staff, and the risk of insurrections and riots.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Victims of prison rape suffer severe physical and psychological effects that hinder their ability to integrate into the community and maintain stable employment upon their release from prison. They are thus more likely to become homeless and/or require government assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Members of the public and government officials are largely unaware of the epidemic character of prison rape and the day-to-day horror experienced by victimized inmates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> The high incidence of sexual assault within prisons involves actual and potential violations of the United States Constitution. In Farmer v. Brennan, 511 U.S. 825 (1994), the Supreme Court ruled that deliberate indifference to the substantial risk of sexual assault violates prisoners’ rights under the Cruel and Unusual Punishments Clause of the Eighth Amendment. The Eighth Amendment rights of State and local prisoners are protected through the Due Process Clause of the Fourteenth Amendment. Pursuant to the power of Congress under Section Five of the Fourteenth Amendment, Congress may take action to enforce those rights in States where officials have demonstrated such indifference. States that do not take basic steps to abate prison rape by adopting standards that do not generate significant additional expenditures demonstrate such indifference. Therefore, such States are not entitled to the same level of Federal benefits as other States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<chapeau> The high incidence of prison rape undermines the effectiveness and efficiency of United States Government expenditures through grant programs such as those dealing with health care; mental health care; disease prevention; crime prevention, investigation, and prosecution; prison construction, maintenance, and operation; race relations; poverty; unemployment and homelessness. The effectiveness and efficiency of these federally funded grant programs are compromised by the failure of State officials to adopt policies and procedures that reduce the incidence of prison rape in that the high incidence of prison rape—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> increases the costs incurred by Federal, State, and local jurisdictions to administer their prison systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increases the levels of violence, directed at inmates and at staff, within prisons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> increases health care expenditures, both inside and outside of prison systems, and reduces the effectiveness of disease prevention programs by substantially increasing the incidence and spread of HIV, AIDS, tuberculosis, hepatitis B and C, and other diseases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> increases mental health care expenditures, both inside and outside of prison systems, by substantially increasing the rate of post-traumatic stress disorder, depression, suicide, and the exacerbation of existing mental illnesses among current and former inmates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> increases the risks of recidivism, civil strife, and violent crime by individuals who have been brutalized by prison rape; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> increases the level of interracial tensions and strife within prisons and, upon release of perpetrators and victims, in the community at large.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<chapeau> The high incidence of prison rape has a significant effect on interstate commerce because it increases substantially—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the costs incurred by Federal, State, and local jurisdictions to administer their prison systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the incidence and spread of HIV, AIDS, tuberculosis, hepatitis B and C, and other diseases, contributing to increased health and medical expenditures throughout the Nation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the rate of post-traumatic stress disorder, depression, suicide, and the exacerbation of existing mental illnesses among current and former inmates, contributing to increased health and medical expenditures throughout the Nation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the risk of recidivism, civil strife, and violent crime by individuals who have been brutalized by prison rape.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–79, § 2</ref>, <date date="2003-09-04">Sept. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30302.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish a zero-tolerance standard for the incidence of prison rape in prisons in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make the prevention of prison rape a top priority in each prison system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develop and implement national standards for the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of prison rape;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> increase the available data and information on the incidence of prison rape, consequently improving the management and administration of correctional facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> standardize the definitions used for collecting data on the incidence of prison rape;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> increase the accountability of prison officials who fail to detect, prevent, reduce, and punish prison rape;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> protect the Eighth Amendment rights of Federal, State, and local prisoners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> increase the efficiency and effectiveness of Federal expenditures through grant programs such as those dealing with health care; mental health care; disease prevention; crime prevention, investigation, and prosecution; prison construction, maintenance, and operation; race relations; poverty; unemployment; and homelessness; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> reduce the costs that prison rape imposes on interstate commerce.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–79, § 3</ref>, <date date="2003-09-04">Sept. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30303.</num>
<heading> National prison rape statistics, data, and research</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual comprehensive statistical review</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Bureau of Justice Statistics of the Department of Justice (in this section referred to as the “Bureau”) shall carry out, for each calendar year, a comprehensive statistical review and analysis of the incidence and effects of prison rape. The statistical review and analysis shall include, but not be limited to the identification of the common characteristics of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> both victims and perpetrators of prison rape; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prisons and prison systems with a high incidence of prison rape.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Bureau shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> how rape should be defined for the purposes of the statistical review and analysis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> how the Bureau should collect information about staff-on-inmate sexual assault;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> how the Bureau should collect information beyond inmate self-reports of prison rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> how the Bureau should adjust the data in order to account for differences among prisons as required by subsection (c)(3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the categorization of prisons as required by subsection (c)(4); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> whether a preliminary study of prison rape should be conducted to inform the methodology of the comprehensive statistical review.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Solicitation of views</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Bureau of Justice Statistics shall solicit views from representatives of the following: State departments of correction; county and municipal jails; juvenile correctional facilities; former inmates; victim advocates; researchers; and other experts in the area of sexual assault.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sampling techniques</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The review and analysis under paragraph (1) shall be based on a random sample, or other scientifically appropriate sample, of not less than 10 percent of all Federal, State, and county prisons, and a representative sample of municipal prisons. The selection shall include at least one prison from each State. The selection of facilities for sampling shall be made at the latest practicable date prior to conducting the surveys and shall not be disclosed to any facility or prison system official prior to the time period studied in the survey. Selection of a facility for sampling during any year shall not preclude its selection for sampling in any subsequent year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surveys</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out the review and analysis under paragraph (1), the Bureau shall, in addition to such other methods as the Bureau considers appropriate, use surveys and other statistical studies of current and former inmates from a sample of Federal, State, county, and municipal prisons. The Bureau shall ensure the confidentiality of each survey participant, except as authorized in paragraph (7).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation in survey</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Federal, State, or local officials or facility administrators that receive a request from the Bureau under subsection (a)(4) or (5) will be required to participate in the national survey and provide access to any inmates under their legal custody.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting on child abuse and neglect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in section 10134 or 10231 of this title or any other provision of law, including paragraph (5), shall prevent the Bureau (including its agents), in carrying out the review and analysis under paragraph (1), from reporting to the designated public officials such information (and only such information) regarding child abuse or child neglect with respect to which the statutes or regulations of a State (or a political subdivision thereof) require prompt reporting.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review Panel on Prison Rape</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To assist the Bureau in carrying out the review and analysis under subsection (a), there is established, within the Department of Justice, the Review Panel on Prison Rape (in this section referred to as the “Panel”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Panel shall be composed of 3 members, each of whom shall be appointed by the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Members of the Panel shall be selected from among individuals with knowledge or expertise in matters to be studied by the Panel.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public hearings</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The duty of the Panel shall be to carry out, for each calendar year, public hearings concerning the operation of the three prisons with the highest incidence of prison rape and the two prisons with the lowest incidence of prison rape in each category of facilities identified under subsection (c)(4). The Panel shall hold a separate hearing regarding the three Federal or State prisons with the highest incidence of prison rape. The purpose of these hearings shall be to collect evidence to aid in the identification of common characteristics of both victims and perpetrators of prison rape, and the identification of common characteristics of prisons and prison systems with a high incidence of prison rape, and the identification of common characteristics of prisons and prison systems that appear to have been successful in deterring prison rape.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Testimony at hearings</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public officials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In carrying out the hearings required under subparagraph (A), the Panel shall request the public testimony of Federal, State, and local officials (and organizations that represent such officials), including the warden or director of each prison, who bears responsibility for the prevention, detection, and punishment of prison rape at each entity, and the head of the prison system encompassing such prison.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Panel may request the testimony of prison rape victims, organizations representing such victims, and other appropriate individuals and organizations.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subpoenas</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Panel may issue subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses and the production of written or other matter.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In the case of contumacy or refusal to obey a subpoena, the Attorney General may in a Federal court of appropriate jurisdiction obtain an appropriate order to enforce the subpoena.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than June 30 of each year, the Attorney General shall submit a report on the activities of the Bureau and the Review Panel, with respect to prison rape, for the preceding calendar year to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to the effects of prison rape, statistical, sociological, and psychological data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to the incidence of prison rape—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> statistical data aggregated at the Federal, State, prison system, and prison levels;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a listing of those institutions in the representative sample, separated into each category identified under subsection (c)(4) and ranked according to the incidence of prison rape in each institution; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an identification of those institutions in the representative sample that appear to have been successful in deterring prison rape; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a listing of any prisons in the representative sample that did not cooperate with the survey conducted pursuant to this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In preparing the information specified in paragraph (2), the Attorney General shall use established statistical methods to adjust the data as necessary to account for differences among institutions in the representative sample, which are not related to the detection, prevention, reduction and punishment of prison rape, or which are outside the control of the State, prison, or prison system, in order to provide an accurate comparison among prisons. Such differences may include the mission, security level, size, and jurisdiction under which the prison operates. For each such adjustment made, the Attorney General shall identify and explain such adjustment in the report.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Categorization of prisons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report shall divide the prisons surveyed into three categories. One category shall be composed of all Federal and State prisons. The other two categories shall be defined by the Attorney General in order to compare similar institutions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts and grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out its duties under this section, the Attorney General may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide grants for research through the National Institute of Justice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> contract with or provide grants to any other entity the Attorney General deems appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 through 2010 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–79, § 4</ref>, <date date="2003-09-04">Sept. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 975</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–108, title I, § 113(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-11-22">Nov. 22, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2305</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30304.</num>
<heading> Prison rape prevention and prosecution</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information and assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National clearinghouse</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established within the National Institute of Corrections a national clearinghouse for the provision of information and assistance to Federal, State, and local authorities responsible for the prevention, investigation, and punishment of instances of prison rape.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training and education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The National Institute of Corrections shall conduct periodic training and education programs for Federal, State, and local authorities responsible for the prevention, investigation, and punishment of instances of prison rape.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than September 30 of each year, the National Institute of Corrections shall submit a report to Congress and the Secretary of Health and Human Services. This report shall be available to the Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report required under paragraph (1) shall summarize the activities of the Department of Justice regarding prison rape abatement for the preceding calendar year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 through 2010 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–79, § 5</ref>, <date date="2003-09-04">Sept. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 978</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30305.</num>
<heading> Grants to protect inmates and safeguard communities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants authorized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">From amounts made available for grants under this section, the Attorney General shall make grants to States to assist those States in ensuring that budgetary circumstances (such as reduced State and local spending on prisons) do not compromise efforts to protect inmates (particularly from prison rape) and to safeguard the communities to which inmates return. The purpose of grants under this section shall be to provide funds for personnel, training, technical assistance, data collection, and equipment to prevent and prosecute prisoner rape.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of grant amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Amounts received by a grantee under this section may be used by the grantee, directly or through subgrants, only for one or more of the following activities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protecting inmates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Protecting inmates by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> undertaking efforts to more effectively prevent prison rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> investigating incidents of prison rape; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> prosecuting incidents of prison rape.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Safeguarding communities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Safeguarding communities by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> making available, to officials of State and local governments who are considering reductions to prison budgets, training and technical assistance in successful methods for moderating the growth of prison populations without compromising public safety, including successful methods used by other jurisdictions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> developing and utilizing analyses of prison populations and risk assessment instruments that will improve State and local governments’ understanding of risks to the community regarding release of inmates in the prison population;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> preparing maps demonstrating the concentration, on a community-by-community basis, of inmates who have been released, to facilitate the efficient and effective—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> deployment of law enforcement resources (including probation and parole resources); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> delivery of services (such as job training and substance abuse treatment) to those released inmates;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> promoting collaborative efforts, among officials of State and local governments and leaders of appropriate communities, to understand and address the effects on a community of the presence of a disproportionate number of released inmates in that community; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> developing policies and programs that reduce spending on prisons by effectively reducing rates of parole and probation revocation without compromising public safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A grant under this section shall be made for a period of not more than 2 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of a grant under this section may not exceed $1,000,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matching</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Federal share of a grant under this section may not exceed 50 percent of the total costs of the project described in the application submitted under subsection (d) for the fiscal year for which the grant was made under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applications</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To request a grant under this section, the chief executive of a State shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Attorney General may require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Each application required by paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> include the certification of the chief executive that the State receiving such grant has adopted all national prison rape standards that, as of the date on which the application was submitted, have been promulgated under this chapter; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> demonstrate to the Attorney General, in such manner as the Attorney General shall require, that the State receiving such grant is actively working to adopt and achieve full compliance with the national prison rape standards described in clause (i);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> specify with particularity the preventative, prosecutorial, or administrative activities to be undertaken by the State with the amounts received under the grant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an application for a grant for one or more activities specified in paragraph (2) of subsection (b)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> review the extent of the budgetary circumstances affecting the State generally and describe how those circumstances relate to the State’s prisons;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> describe the rate of growth of the State’s prison population over the preceding 10 years and explain why the State may have difficulty sustaining that rate of growth; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> explain the extent to which officials (including law enforcement officials) of State and local governments and victims of crime will be consulted regarding decisions whether, or how, to moderate the growth of the State’s prison population.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports by grantee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Attorney General shall require each grantee to submit, not later than 90 days after the end of the period for which the grant was made under this section, a report on the activities carried out under the grant. The report shall identify and describe those activities and shall contain an evaluation of the effect of those activities on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of incidents of prison rape, and the grantee’s response to such incidents; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the safety of the prisons, and the safety of the communities in which released inmates are present.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dissemination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall ensure that each report submitted under paragraph (1) is made available under the national clearinghouse established under <ref>section 30304 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated for grants under this section $40,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 through 2010.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of amounts made available for grants under this section, not less than 50 percent shall be available only for activities specified in paragraph (1) of subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–79, § 6</ref>, <date date="2003-09-04">Sept. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 978</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–324, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1951</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30306.</num>
<heading> National Prison Rape Elimination Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a commission to be known as the National Prison Rape Elimination Commission (in this section referred to as the “Commission”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Members</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission shall be composed of 9 members, of whom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 3 shall be appointed by the President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 2 shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, unless the Speaker is of the same party as the President, in which case 1 shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives and 1 shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 1 shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives (in addition to any appointment made under subparagraph (B));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> 2 shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate, unless the majority leader is of the same party as the President, in which case 1 shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate and 1 shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> 1 member appointed by the minority leader of the Senate (in addition to any appointment made under subparagraph (D)).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persons eligible</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each member of the Commission shall be an individual who has knowledge or expertise in matters to be studied by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President, the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives, and the majority leader and minority leader of the Senate shall consult with one another prior to the appointment of the members of the Commission to achieve, to the maximum extent possible, fair and equitable representation of various points of view with respect to the matters to be studied by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each member shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for initial appointments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The appointment of the members shall be made not later than 60 days after <date date="2003-09-04">September 4, 2003</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made, and shall be made not later than 60 days after the date on which the vacancy occurred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 15 days after appointments of all the members are made, the President shall appoint a chairperson for the Commission from among its members.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall meet at the call of the chairperson. The initial meeting of the Commission shall take place not later than 30 days after the initial appointment of the members is completed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum to conduct business, but the Commission may establish a lesser quorum for conducting hearings scheduled by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission may establish by majority vote any other rules for the conduct of Commission business, if such rules are not inconsistent with this chapter or other applicable law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comprehensive study of the impacts of prison rape</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission shall carry out a comprehensive legal and factual study of the penalogical, physical, mental, medical, social, and economic impacts of prison rape in the United States on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Federal, State, and local governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> communities and social institutions generally, including individuals, families, and businesses within such communities and social institutions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The study under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a review of existing Federal, State, and local government policies and practices with respect to the prevention, detection, and punishment of prison rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment of the relationship between prison rape and prison conditions, and of existing monitoring, regulatory, and enforcement practices that are intended to address any such relationship;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an assessment of pathological or social causes of prison rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an assessment of the extent to which the incidence of prison rape contributes to the spread of sexually transmitted diseases and to the transmission of HIV;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an assessment of the characteristics of inmates most likely to commit prison rape and the effectiveness of various types of treatment or programs to reduce such likelihood;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an assessment of the characteristics of inmates most likely to be victims of prison rape and the effectiveness of various types of treatment or programs to reduce such likelihood;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> an assessment of the impacts of prison rape on individuals, families, social institutions and the economy generally, including an assessment of the extent to which the incidence of prison rape contributes to recidivism and to increased incidence of sexual assault;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> an examination of the feasibility and cost of conducting surveillance, undercover activities, or both, to reduce the incidence of prison rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an assessment of the safety and security of prison facilities and the relationship of prison facility construction and design to the incidence of prison rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> an assessment of the feasibility and cost of any particular proposals for prison reform;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> an identification of the need for additional scientific and social science research on the prevalence of prison rape in Federal, State, and local prisons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> an assessment of the general relationship between prison rape and prison violence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> an assessment of the relationship between prison rape and levels of training, supervision, and discipline of prison staff; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> an assessment of existing Federal and State systems for reporting incidents of prison rape, including an assessment of whether existing systems provide an adequate assurance of confidentiality, impartiality and the absence of reprisal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 5 years after the date of the initial meeting of the Commission, the Commission shall submit a report on the study carried out under this subsection to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the President;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Congress;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Attorney General;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the Director of the Federal Bureau of Prisons;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the chief executive of each State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the head of the department of corrections of each State.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The report under subparagraph (A) shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the findings and conclusions of the Commission;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> recommended national standards for reducing prison rape;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> recommended protocols for preserving evidence and treating victims of prison rape; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a summary of the materials relied on by the Commission in the preparation of the report.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In conjunction with the report submitted under subsection (d)(3), the Commission shall provide the Attorney General and the Secretary of Health and Human Services with recommended national standards for enhancing the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of prison rape.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The information provided under paragraph (1) shall include recommended national standards relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the classification and assignment of prisoners, using proven standardized instruments and protocols, in a manner that limits the occurrence of prison rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the investigation and resolution of rape complaints by responsible prison authorities, local and State police, and Federal and State prosecution authorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the preservation of physical and testimonial evidence for use in an investigation of the circumstances relating to the rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> acute-term trauma care for rape victims, including standards relating to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the manner and extent of physical examination and treatment to be provided to any rape victim; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the manner and extent of any psychological examination, psychiatric care, medication, and mental health counseling to be provided to any rape victim;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> referrals for long-term continuity of care for rape victims;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> educational and medical testing measures for reducing the incidence of HIV transmission due to prison rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> post-rape prophylactic medical measures for reducing the incidence of transmission of sexual diseases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the training of correctional staff sufficient to ensure that they understand and appreciate the significance of prison rape and the necessity of its eradication;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the timely and comprehensive investigation of staff sexual misconduct involving rape or other sexual assault on inmates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> ensuring the confidentiality of prison rape complaints and protecting inmates who make complaints of prison rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> creating a system for reporting incidents of prison rape that will ensure the confidentiality of prison rape complaints, protect inmates who make prison rape complaints from retaliation, and assure the impartial resolution of prison rape complaints;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<chapeau> data collection and reporting of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> prison rape;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> prison staff sexual misconduct; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the resolution of prison rape complaints by prison officials and Federal, State, and local investigation and prosecution authorities; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> such other matters as may reasonably be related to the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of prison rape.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall not propose a recommended standard that would impose substantial additional costs compared to the costs presently expended by Federal, State, and local prison authorities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with accreditation organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In developing recommended national standards for enhancing the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of prison rape, the Commission shall consider any standards that have already been developed, or are being developed simultaneously to the deliberations of the Commission. The Commission shall consult with accreditation organizations responsible for the accreditation of Federal, State, local or private prisons, that have developed or are currently developing standards related to prison rape. The Commission will also consult with national associations representing the corrections profession that have developed or are currently developing standards related to prison rape.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall hold public hearings. The Commission may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission considers advisable to carry out its duties under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Witness expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Witnesses requested to appear before the Commission shall be paid the same fees as are paid to witnesses under <ref>section 1821 of title 28</ref>. The per diem and mileage allowances for witnesses shall be paid from funds appropriated to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information from Federal or State agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out its duties under this section. The Commission may request the head of any State or local department or agency to furnish such information to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel matters</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The members of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5 while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of service for the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detail of Federal employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With the affirmative vote of ⅔ of the Commission, any Federal Government employee, with the approval of the head of the appropriate Federal agency, may be detailed to the Commission without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status, benefits, or privileges.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procurement of temporary and intermittent services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the request of the Commission, the Attorney General shall provide reasonable and appropriate office space, supplies, and administrative assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts for research</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National Institute of Justice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With a ⅔ affirmative vote, the Commission may select nongovernmental researchers and experts to assist the Commission in carrying out its duties under this chapter. The National Institute of Justice shall contract with the researchers and experts selected by the Commission to provide funding in exchange for their services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the ability of the Commission to enter into contracts with other entities or organizations for research necessary to carry out the duties of the Commission under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subpoenas</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission may issue subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses and the production of written or other matter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of contumacy or refusal to obey a subpoena, the Attorney General may in a Federal court of appropriate jurisdiction obtain an appropriate order to enforce the subpoena.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality of documentary evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Documents provided to the Commission pursuant to a subpoena issued under this subsection shall not be released publicly without the affirmative vote of ⅔ of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall terminate on the date that is 60 days after the date on which the Commission submits the reports required by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall be exempt from chapter 10 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–79, § 7</ref>, <date date="2003-09-04">Sept. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 980</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. B, title I, § 123(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2871</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–108, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-11-22">Nov. 22, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2305</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1181</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–199, title II, § 261</ref>, <date date="2008-04-09">Apr. 9, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 694</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(212)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4329</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30307.</num>
<heading> Adoption and effect of national standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of proposed standards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after receiving the report specified in <ref>section 30306(d)(3) of this title</ref>, the Attorney General shall publish a final rule adopting national standards for the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of prison rape.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent judgment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The standards referred to in paragraph (1) shall be based upon the independent judgment of the Attorney General, after giving due consideration to the recommended national standards provided by the Commission under <ref>section 30306(e) of this title</ref>, and being informed by such data, opinions, and proposals that the Attorney General determines to be appropriate to consider.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall not establish a national standard under this section that would impose substantial additional costs compared to the costs presently expended by Federal, State, and local prison authorities. The Attorney General may, however, provide a list of improvements for consideration by correctional facilities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transmission to States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Within 90 days of publishing the final rule under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall transmit the national standards adopted under such paragraph to the chief executive of each State, the head of the department of corrections of each State, and to the appropriate authorities in those units of local government who oversee operations in one or more prisons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability to Federal Bureau of Prisons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The national standards referred to in subsection (a) shall apply to the Federal Bureau of Prisons immediately upon adoption of the final rule under subsection (a)(4).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability to detention facilities operated by the Department of Homeland Security</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2013-03-07">March 7, 2013</date>, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall publish a final rule adopting national standards for the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of rape and sexual assault in facilities that maintain custody of aliens detained for a violation of the immigrations laws of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The standards adopted under paragraph (1) shall apply to detention facilities operated by the Department of Homeland Security and to detention facilities operated under contract with the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assess compliance with the standards adopted under paragraph (1) on a regular basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> include the results of the assessments in performance evaluations of facilities completed by the Department of Homeland Security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In adopting standards under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall give due consideration to the recommended national standards provided by the Commission under <ref>section 30306(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As used in this section, the term “detention facilities operated under contract with the Department” includes, but is not limited to contract detention facilities and detention facilities operated through an intergovernmental service agreement with the Department of Homeland Security.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability to custodial facilities operated by the Department of Health and Human Services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2013-03-07">March 7, 2013</date>, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall publish a final rule adopting national standards for the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of rape and sexual assault in facilities that maintain custody of unaccompanied alien children (as defined in <ref>section 279(g) of title 6</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The standards adopted under paragraph (1) shall apply to facilities operated by the Department of Health and Human Services and to facilities operated under contract with the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assess compliance with the standards adopted under paragraph (1) on a regular basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> include the results of the assessments in performance evaluations of facilities completed by the Department of Health and Human Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In adopting standards under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall give due consideration to the recommended national standards provided by the Commission under <ref>section 30306(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for Federal funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered programs</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of this subsection, a grant program is covered by this subsection if, and only if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the program is carried out by or under the authority of the Attorney General;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the program may provide amounts to States for prison purposes; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the program is not administered by the Office on Violence Against Women of the Department of Justice.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> List</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For each fiscal year, the Attorney General shall prepare a list identifying each program that meets the criteria of subparagraph (A) and provide that list to each State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adoption of national standards</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For each fiscal year, any amount that a State would otherwise receive for prison purposes for that fiscal year under a grant program covered by this subsection shall be reduced by 5 percent, unless the chief executive officer of the State submits to the Attorney General proof of compliance with this chapter through—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a certification that the State has adopted, and is in full compliance with, the national standards described in subsection (a); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> an assurance that the State intends to adopt and achieve full compliance with those national standards so as to ensure that a certification under clause (i) may be submitted in future years, which includes—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a commitment that not less than 5 percent of such amount shall be used for this purpose; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a request that the Attorney General hold 5 percent of such amount in abeyance pursuant to the requirements of subparagraph (E).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules for certification</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">A chief executive officer of a State who submits a certification under this paragraph shall also provide the Attorney General with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a list of the prisons under the operational control of the executive branch of the State;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a list of the prisons listed under subclause (I) that were audited during the most recently concluded audit year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> all final audit reports for prisons listed under subclause (I) that were completed during the most recently concluded audit year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> a proposed schedule for completing an audit of all the prisons listed under subclause (I) during the following 3 audit years.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit appeal exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Beginning on the date that is 3 years after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, a chief executive officer of a State may submit a certification that the State is in full compliance pursuant to subparagraph (A)(i) even if a prison under the operational control of the executive branch of the State has an audit appeal pending.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules for assurances</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">A chief executive officer of a State who submits an assurance under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall also provide the Attorney General with—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a list of the prisons under the operational control of the executive branch of the State;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a list of the prisons listed under subclause (I) that were audited during the most recently concluded audit year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> an explanation of any barriers the State faces to completing required audits;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> all final audit reports for prisons listed under subclause (I) that were completed during the most recently concluded audit year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> a proposed schedule for completing an audit of all prisons under the operational control of the executive branch of the State during the following 3 audit years; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> an explanation of the State’s current degree of implementation of the national standards.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A chief executive officer of a State who submits an assurance under subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) shall, before receiving the applicable funds described in subparagraph (A)(ii)(I), also provide the Attorney General with a proposed plan for the expenditure of the funds during the applicable grant period.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accounting of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A chief executive officer of a State who submits an assurance under subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) shall, in a manner consistent with the applicable grant reporting requirements, submit to the Attorney General a detailed accounting of how the funds described in subparagraph (A) were used.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sunset of assurance option</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">On the date that is 3 years after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, subclause (II) of subparagraph (A)(ii) shall cease to have effect.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional sunset</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">On the date that is 6 years after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, clause (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall cease to have effect.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency assurances</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Notwithstanding clause (ii), during the 2-year period beginning 6 years after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, a chief executive officer of a State who certifies that the State has audited not less than 90 percent of prisons under the operational control of the executive branch of the State may request that the Attorney General allow the chief executive officer to submit an emergency assurance in accordance with subparagraph (A)(ii) as in effect on the day before the date on which that subparagraph ceased to have effect under clause (ii) of this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant of request</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">The Attorney General shall grant a request submitted under subclause (I) within 60 days upon a showing of good cause.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disposition of funds held in abeyance</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the chief executive officer of a State who has submitted an assurance under subparagraph (A)(ii)(II) subsequently submits a certification under subparagraph (A)(i) during the 3-year period beginning on <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, the Attorney General will release all funds held in abeyance under subparagraph (A)(ii)(II) to be used by the State in accordance with the conditions of the grant program for which the funds were provided.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the chief executive officer of a State who has submitted an assurance under subparagraph (A)(ii)(II) is unable to submit a certification during the 3-year period beginning on <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, but does assure the Attorney General that ⅔ of prisons under the operational control of the executive branch of the State have been audited at least once, the Attorney General shall release all of the funds of the State held in abeyance to be used in adopting and achieving full compliance with the national standards, if the State agrees to comply with the applicable requirements in clauses (ii) and (iii) of subparagraph (C).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redistribution of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the chief executive officer of a State who has submitted an assurance under subparagraph (A)(ii)(II) is unable to submit a certification during the 3-year period beginning on <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, and does not assure the Attorney General that ⅔ of prisons under the operational control of the executive branch of the State have been audited at least once, the Attorney General shall redistribute the funds of the State held in abeyance to other States to be used in accordance with the conditions of the grant program for which the funds were provided.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of audit results</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, the Attorney General shall request from each State, and make available on an appropriate Internet website, all final audit reports completed to date for prisons under the operational control of the executive branch of each State. The Attorney General shall update such website annually with reports received from States under subparagraphs (B)(i) and (C)(i).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on implementation of national standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, the Attorney General shall issue a report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives on the status of implementation of the national standards and the steps the Department, in conjunction with the States and other key stakeholders, is taking to address any unresolved implementation issues.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on noncompliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than September 30 of each year, the Attorney General shall publish a report listing each grantee that is not in compliance with the national standards adopted pursuant to subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with survey</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For each fiscal year, any amount that a State receives for that fiscal year under a grant program covered by this subsection shall not be used for prison purposes (and shall be returned to the grant program if no other authorized use is available), unless the chief executive of the State submits to the Attorney General a certification that neither the State, nor any political subdivision or unit of local government within the State, is listed in a report issued by the Attorney General pursuant to <ref>section 30303(c)(2)(C) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redistribution of amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts under a grant program not granted by reason of a reduction under paragraph (2), or returned by reason of the prohibition in paragraph (4), shall be granted to one or more entities not subject to such reduction or such prohibition, subject to the other laws governing that program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General shall establish procedures to implement this subsection, including procedures for effectively applying this subsection to discretionary grant programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of adoption of standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The first grants to which paragraph (2) applies are grants for the second fiscal year beginning after the date on which the national standards under subsection (a) are finalized.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for cooperation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The first grants to which paragraph (4) applies are grants for the fiscal year beginning after <date date="2003-09-04">September 4, 2003</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards for auditors</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Background checks for auditors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">An individual seeking certification by the Department of Justice to serve as an auditor of prison compliance with the national standards described in subsection (a) shall, upon request, submit fingerprints in the manner determined by the Attorney General for criminal history record checks of the applicable State and Federal Bureau of Investigation repositories.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each auditor certified under this paragraph shall sign a certification agreement that includes the provisions of, or provisions that are substantially similar to, the Bureau of Justice Assistance’s Auditor Certification Agreement in use in April 2018.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Auditor evaluation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The PREA Management Office of the Bureau of Justice Assistance shall evaluate all auditors based on the criteria contained in the certification agreement. In the case that an auditor fails to comply with a certification agreement or to conduct audits in accordance with the PREA Auditor Handbook, audit methodology, and instrument approved by the PREA Management Office, the Office may take remedial or disciplinary action, as appropriate, including decertifying the auditor in accordance with subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Auditor decertification</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The PREA Management Office may suspend an auditor’s certification during an evaluation of an auditor’s performance under subparagraph (A)(iii). The PREA Management Office shall promptly publish the names of auditors who have been decertified, and the reason for decertification. Auditors who have been decertified or are on suspension may not participate in audits described in subsection (a), including as an agent of a certified auditor.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In the case that an auditor is decertified, the PREA Management Office shall inform each facility or agency at which the auditor performed an audit during the relevant 3-year audit cycle, and may recommend that the agency repeat any affected audits, if appropriate.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit assignments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The PREA Management Office shall establish a system, to be administered by the Office, for assigning certified auditors to Federal, State, and local facilities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure of documentation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall comply with each request for documentation necessary to conduct an audit under subsection (a), which is made by a certified auditor in accordance with the provisions of the certification agreement described in subparagraph (A)(ii). The Director of the Bureau of Prisons may require an auditor to sign a confidentiality agreement or other agreement designed to address the auditor’s use of personally identifiable information, except that such an agreement may not limit an auditor’s ability to provide all such documentation to the Department of Justice, as required under section 115.401(j) of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–79, § 8</ref>, <date date="2003-09-04">Sept. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 985</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XI, § 1101(c)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 134</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–324</ref>, §§ 5, 7(2), <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1950</ref>, 1951; <ref>Pub. L. 115–274, § 4</ref>, <date date="2018-10-31">Oct. 31, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4161</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30308.</num>
<heading> Requirement that accreditation organizations adopt accreditation standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for Federal grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an organization responsible for the accreditation of Federal, State, local, or private prisons, jails, or other penal facilities may not receive any new Federal grants during any period in which such organization fails to meet any of the requirements of subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To be eligible to receive Federal grants, an accreditation organization referred to in subsection (a) must meet the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> At all times after 90 days after <date date="2003-09-04">September 4, 2003</date>, the organization shall have in effect, for each facility that it is responsible for accrediting, accreditation standards for the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of prison rape.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> At all times after 1 year after the date of the adoption of the final rule under <ref>section 30307(a)(4) of this title</ref>, the organization shall, in addition to any other such standards that it may promulgate relevant to the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of prison rape, adopt accreditation standards consistent with the national standards adopted pursuant to such final rule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–79, § 9</ref>, <date date="2003-09-04">Sept. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30309.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Carnal knowledge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “carnal knowledge” means contact between the penis and the vulva or the penis and the anus, including penetration of any sort, however slight.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inmate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “inmate” means any person incarcerated or detained in any facility who is accused of, convicted of, sentenced for, or adjudicated delinquent for, violations of criminal law or the terms and conditions of parole, probation, pretrial release, or diversionary program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jail</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “jail” means a confinement facility of a Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency to hold—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> persons pending adjudication of criminal charges; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> persons committed to confinement after adjudication of criminal charges for sentences of 1 year or less.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> HIV</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “HIV” means the human immunodeficiency virus.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oral sodomy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “oral sodomy” means contact between the mouth and the penis, the mouth and the vulva, or the mouth and the anus.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Police lockup</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “police lockup” means a temporary holding facility of a Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency to hold—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> inmates pending bail or transport to jail;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> inebriates until ready for release; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> juveniles pending parental custody or shelter placement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prison</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “prison” means any confinement facility of a Federal, State, or local government, whether administered by such government or by a private organization on behalf of such government, and includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any local jail or police lockup; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any juvenile facility used for the custody or care of juvenile inmates.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prison rape</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “prison rape” includes the rape of an inmate in the actual or constructive control of prison officials.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rape</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “rape” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the carnal knowledge, oral sodomy, sexual assault with an object, or sexual fondling of a person, forcibly or against that person’s will;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the carnal knowledge, oral sodomy, sexual assault with an object, or sexual fondling of a person not forcibly or against the person’s will, where the victim is incapable of giving consent because of his or her youth or his or her temporary or permanent mental or physical incapacity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the carnal knowledge, oral sodomy, sexual assault with an object, or sexual fondling of a person achieved through the exploitation of the fear or threat of physical violence or bodily injury.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexual assault with an object</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “sexual assault with an object” means the use of any hand, finger, object, or other instrument to penetrate, however slightly, the genital or anal opening of the body of another person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sexual fondling</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “sexual fondling” means the touching of the private body parts of another person (including the genitalia, anus, groin, breast, inner thigh, or buttocks) for the purpose of sexual gratification.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The terms and conditions described in paragraphs (9) and (10) shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> custodial or medical personnel gathering physical evidence, or engaged in other legitimate medical treatment, in the course of investigating prison rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use of a health care provider’s hands or fingers or the use of medical devices in the course of appropriate medical treatment unrelated to prison rape; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the use of a health care provider’s hands or fingers and the use of instruments to perform body cavity searches in order to maintain security and safety within the prison or detention facility, provided that the search is conducted in a manner consistent with constitutional requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–79, § 10</ref>, <date date="2003-09-04">Sept. 4, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>