<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 505—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL BLUE ALERT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 50501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordinator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Coordinator” means the Blue Alert Coordinator of the Department of Justice designated under <ref>section 50503(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Blue Alert</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Blue Alert” means information sent through the network relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the serious injury or death of a law enforcement officer in the line of duty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an officer who is missing in connection with the officer’s official duties; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an imminent and credible threat that an individual intends to cause the serious injury or death of a law enforcement officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Blue Alert plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Blue Alert plan” means the plan of a State, unit of local government, or Federal agency participating in the network for the dissemination of information received as a Blue Alert.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “law enforcement officer” shall have the same meaning as in <ref>section 10284 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Network</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “network” means the Blue Alert communications network established by the Attorney General under <ref>section 50502 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–12, § 2</ref>, <date date="2015-05-19">May 19, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50502.</num>
<heading> Blue Alert communications network</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall establish a national Blue Alert communications network within the Department of Justice to issue Blue Alerts through the initiation, facilitation, and promotion of Blue Alert plans, in coordination with States, units of local government, law enforcement agencies, and other appropriate entities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–12, § 3</ref>, <date date="2015-05-19">May 19, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 193</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 50503.</num>
<heading> Blue Alert Coordinator; guidelines</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination within Department of Justice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall assign an existing officer of the Department of Justice to act as the national coordinator of the Blue Alert communications network.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of the Coordinator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Coordinator shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide assistance to States and units of local government that are using Blue Alert plans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> establish voluntary guidelines for States and units of local government to use in developing Blue Alert plans that will promote compatible and integrated Blue Alert plans throughout the United States, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a list of the resources necessary to establish a Blue Alert plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> criteria for evaluating whether a situation warrants issuing a Blue Alert;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> guidelines to protect the privacy, dignity, independence, and autonomy of any law enforcement officer who may be the subject of a Blue Alert and the family of the law enforcement officer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> guidelines that a Blue Alert should only be issued with respect to a law enforcement officer if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the law enforcement agency involved—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> confirms—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the death or serious injury of the law enforcement officer; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the attack on the law enforcement officer and that there is an indication of the death or serious injury of the officer; or</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> concludes that the law enforcement officer is missing in connection with the officer’s official duties;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> there is an indication of serious injury to or death of the law enforcement officer;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the suspect involved has not been apprehended; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> there is sufficient descriptive information of the suspect involved and any relevant vehicle and tag numbers;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> guidelines that a Blue Alert should only be issued with respect to a threat to cause death or serious injury to a law enforcement officer if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a law enforcement agency involved confirms that the threat is imminent and credible;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> at the time of receipt of the threat, the suspect is wanted by a law enforcement agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the suspect involved has not been apprehended; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> there is sufficient descriptive information of the suspect involved and any relevant vehicle and tag numbers;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> guidelines—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> that information should be provided to the National Crime Information Center database operated by the Federal Bureau of Investigation under <ref>section 534 of title 28</ref>, and any relevant crime information repository of the State involved, relating to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a law enforcement officer who is seriously injured or killed in the line of duty; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> an imminent and credible threat to cause the serious injury or death of a law enforcement officer;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> that a Blue Alert should, to the maximum extent practicable (as determined by the Coordinator in consultation with law enforcement agencies of States and units of local governments), be limited to the geographic areas most likely to facilitate the apprehension of the suspect involved or which the suspect could reasonably reach, which should not be limited to State lines;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> for law enforcement agencies of States or units of local government to develop plans to communicate information to neighboring States to provide for seamless communication of a Blue Alert; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> providing that a Blue Alert should be suspended when the suspect involved is apprehended or when the law enforcement agency involved determines that the Blue Alert is no longer effective; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> guidelines for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the issuance of Blue Alerts through the network; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the extent of the dissemination of alerts issued through the network;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> develop protocols for efforts to apprehend suspects that address activities during the period beginning at the time of the initial notification of a law enforcement agency that a suspect has not been apprehended and ending at the time of apprehension of a suspect or when the law enforcement agency involved determines that the Blue Alert is no longer effective, including protocols regulating—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the use of public safety communications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> command center operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> incident review, evaluation, debriefing, and public information procedures;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> work with States to ensure appropriate regional coordination of various elements of the network;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> establish an advisory group to assist States, units of local government, law enforcement agencies, and other entities involved in the network with initiating, facilitating, and promoting Blue Alert plans, which shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the maximum extent practicable, representation from the various geographic regions of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> members who are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> representatives of a law enforcement organization representing rank-and-file officers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> representatives of other law enforcement agencies and public safety communications;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> broadcasters, first responders, dispatchers, and radio station personnel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> representatives of any other individuals or organizations that the Coordinator determines are necessary to the success of the network;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> act as the nationwide point of contact for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the development of the network; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> regional coordination of Blue Alerts through the network; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> determine—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> what procedures and practices are in use for notifying law enforcement and the public when—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a law enforcement officer is killed or seriously injured in the line of duty;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a law enforcement officer is missing in connection with the officer’s official duties; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an imminent and credible threat to kill or seriously injure a law enforcement officer is received; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which of the procedures and practices are effective and that do not require the expenditure of additional resources to implement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voluntary participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The guidelines established under subsection (b)(2), protocols developed under subsection (b)(3), and other programs established under subsection (b), shall not be mandatory.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dissemination of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The guidelines established under subsection (b)(2) shall, to the maximum extent practicable (as determined by the Coordinator in consultation with law enforcement agencies of States and units of local government), provide that appropriate information relating to a Blue Alert is disseminated to the appropriate officials of law enforcement agencies, public health agencies, and other agencies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Privacy and civil liberties protections</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The guidelines established under subsection (b) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide mechanisms that ensure that Blue Alerts comply with all applicable Federal, State, and local privacy laws and regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> include standards that specifically provide for the protection of the civil liberties, including the privacy, of law enforcement officers who are seriously injured or killed in the line of duty, is missing in connection with the officer’s official duties, or who are threatened with death or serious injury, and the families of the officers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with other agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Coordinator shall cooperate with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Transportation, the Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, and appropriate offices of the Department of Justice in carrying out activities under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on Coordinator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Coordinator may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> perform any official travel for the sole purpose of carrying out the duties of the Coordinator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> lobby any officer of a State regarding the funding or implementation of a Blue Alert plan; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> host a conference focused solely on the Blue Alert program that requires the expenditure of Federal funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2015-05-19">May 19, 2015</date>, and annually thereafter, the Coordinator shall submit to Congress a report on the activities of the Coordinator and the effectiveness and status of the Blue Alert plans that are in effect or being developed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–12, § 4</ref>, <date date="2015-05-19">May 19, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 193</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>