<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 107—</num>
<heading>RIGHT TO VOTE AT AGE EIGHTEEN</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10701.</num>
<heading> Enforcement of twenty-sixth amendment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Attorney General is directed to institute, in the name of the United States, such actions against States or political subdivisions, including actions for injunctive relief, as he may determine to be necessary to implement the twenty-sixth article of amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction of proceedings instituted under this chapter, which shall be heard and determined by a court of three judges in accordance with <ref>section 2284 of title 28</ref>, and any appeal shall lie to the Supreme Court. It shall be the duty of the judges designated to hear the case to assign the case for hearing and determination thereof, and to cause the case to be in every way expedited.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whoever shall deny or attempt to deny any person of any right secured by the twenty-sixth article of amendment to the Constitution of the United States shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–110, title III, § 301</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 91–285, § 6</ref>, <date date="1970-06-22">June 22, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 318</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–73, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="1975-08-06">Aug. 6, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 405</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10702.</num>
<heading> “State” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–110, title III, § 302</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 91–285, § 6</ref>, <date date="1970-06-22">June 22, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 318</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–73, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="1975-08-06">Aug. 6, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 405</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>