<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 209—</num>
<heading>ELECTION ADMINISTRATION IMPROVEMENT</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>PAYMENTS TO STATES FOR ELECTION ADMINISTRATION IMPROVEMENTS AND REPLACEMENT OF PUNCH CARD AND LEVER VOTING MACHINES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20901.</num>
<heading> Payments to States for activities to improve administration of elections</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 45 days after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, the Administrator of General Services (in this subchapter referred to as the “Administrator”) shall establish a program under which the Administrator shall make a payment to each State in which the chief executive officer of the State, or designee, in consultation and coordination with the chief State election official, notifies the Administrator not later than 6 months after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, that the State intends to use the payment in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of payment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State shall use the funds provided under a payment made under this section to carry out one or more of the following activities:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Complying with the requirements under subchapter III.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Improving the administration of elections for Federal office.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Educating voters concerning voting procedures, voting rights, and voting technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Training election officials, poll workers, and election volunteers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Developing the State plan for requirements payments to be submitted under subpart 1 of part D of subchapter II.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Improving, acquiring, leasing, modifying, or replacing voting systems and technology and methods for casting and counting votes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Improving the accessibility and quantity of polling places, including providing physical access for individuals with disabilities, providing nonvisual access for individuals with visual impairments, and providing assistance to Native Americans, Alaska Native citizens, and to individuals with limited proficiency in the English language.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Establishing toll-free telephone hotlines that voters may use to report possible voting fraud and voting rights violations, to obtain general election information, and to access detailed automated information on their own voter registration status, specific polling place locations, and other relevant information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State may not use the funds provided under a payment made under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to pay costs associated with any litigation, except to the extent that such costs otherwise constitute permitted uses of a payment under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for the payment of any judgment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds to be consistent with other laws and requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to receive a payment under the program under this section, the State shall provide the Administrator with certifications that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the State will use the funds provided under the payment in a manner that is consistent with each of the laws described in <ref>section 21145 of this title</ref>, as such laws relate to the provisions of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the proposed uses of the funds are not inconsistent with the requirements of subchapter III.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of payment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to <ref>section 20903(b) of this title</ref>, the amount of payment made to a State under this section shall be the minimum payment amount described in paragraph (2) plus the voting age population proportion amount described in paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum payment amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The minimum payment amount described in this paragraph is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of any of the several States or the District of Columbia, one-half of 1 percent of the aggregate amount made available for payments under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, or the United States Virgin Islands, one-tenth of 1 percent of such aggregate amount.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting age population proportion amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The voting age population proportion amount described in this paragraph is the product of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the aggregate amount made available for payments under this section minus the total of all of the minimum payment amounts determined under paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the voting age population proportion for the State (as defined in paragraph (4)).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting age population proportion defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “voting age population proportion” means, with respect to a State, the amount equal to the quotient of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the voting age population of the State (as reported in the most recent decennial census); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total voting age population of all States (as reported in the most recent decennial census).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1668</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20902.</num>
<heading> Replacement of punch card or lever voting machines</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 45 days after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, the Administrator shall establish a program under which the Administrator shall make a payment to each State eligible under subsection (b) in which a precinct within that State used a punch card voting system or a lever voting system to administer the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in November 2000 (in this section referred to as a “qualifying precinct”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State shall use the funds provided under a payment under this section (either directly or as reimbursement, including as reimbursement for costs incurred on or after <date date="2001-01-01">January 1, 2001</date>, under multiyear contracts) to replace punch card voting systems or lever voting systems (as the case may be) in qualifying precincts within that State with a voting system (by purchase, lease, or such other arrangement as may be appropriate) that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> does not use punch cards or levers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not inconsistent with the requirements of the laws described in <ref>section 21145 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> meets the requirements of <ref>section 21081 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a State receiving a payment under the program under this section shall ensure that all of the punch card voting systems or lever voting systems in the qualifying precincts within that State have been replaced in time for the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office to be held in November 2004.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a State certifies to the Administrator not later than <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>, that the State will not meet the deadline described in subparagraph (A) for good cause and includes in the certification the reasons for the failure to meet such deadline, the State shall ensure that all of the punch card voting systems or lever voting systems in the qualifying precincts within that State will be replaced in time for the first election for Federal office held after <date date="2010-11-01">November 1, 2010</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State is eligible to receive a payment under the program under this section if it submits to the Administrator a notice not later than the date that is 6 months after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date> (in such form as the Administrator may require) that contains—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> certifications that the State will use the payment (either directly or as reimbursement, including as reimbursement for costs incurred on or after <date date="2001-01-01">January 1, 2001</date>, under multiyear contracts) to replace punch card voting systems or lever voting systems (as the case may be) in the qualifying precincts within the State by the deadline described in subsection (a)(3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> certifications that the State will continue to comply with the laws described in <ref>section 21145 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> certifications that the replacement voting systems will meet the requirements of <ref>section 21081 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such other information and certifications as the Administrator may require which are necessary for the administration of the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance of States that require changes to State law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a State that requires State legislation to carry out an activity covered by any certification submitted under this subsection, the State shall be permitted to make the certification notwithstanding that the legislation has not been enacted at the time the certification is submitted and such State shall submit an additional certification once such legislation is enacted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of payment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2) and <ref>section 20903(b) of this title</ref>, the amount of payment made to a State under the program under this section shall be equal to the product of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of the qualifying precincts within the State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $4,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the amount of funds appropriated pursuant to the authority of <ref>section 20904(a)(2) of this title</ref> is insufficient to ensure that each State receives the amount of payment calculated under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall reduce the amount specified in paragraph (1)(B) to ensure that the entire amount appropriated under such section is distributed to the States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayment of funds for failure to meet deadlines</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a State receiving funds under the program under this section fails to meet the deadline applicable to the State under subsection (a)(3), the State shall pay to the Administrator an amount equal to the noncompliant precinct percentage of the amount of the funds provided to the State under the program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Noncompliant precinct percentage defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “noncompliant precinct percentage” means, with respect to a State, the amount (expressed as a percentage) equal to the quotient of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of qualifying precincts within the State for which the State failed to meet the applicable deadline; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total number of qualifying precincts in the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Punch card voting system defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, a “punch card voting system” includes any of the following voting systems:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> C.E.S.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Datavote.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> PBC Counter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Pollstar.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Punch Card.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Vote Recorder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Votomatic.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1670</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–28, title VI, § 6301(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-05-25">May 25, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 171</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. D, title VI, § 625(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20903.</num>
<heading> Guaranteed minimum payment amount</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to any other payments made under this subchapter, the Administrator shall make a payment to each State to which a payment is made under either section 20901 or 20902 of this title and with respect to which the aggregate amount paid under such sections is less than $5,000,000 in an amount equal to the difference between the aggregate amount paid to the State under sections 20901 and 20902 of this title and $5,000,000. In the case of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, and the United States Virgin Islands, the previous sentence shall be applied as if each reference to “$5,000,000” were a reference to “$1,000,000”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pro rata reductions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall make such pro rata reductions to the amounts described in sections 20901(d) and 20902(c) of this title as are necessary to comply with the requirements of subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20904.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for payments under this subchapter $650,000,000, of which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 50 percent shall be for payments under <ref>section 20901 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 50 percent shall be for payments under <ref>section 20902 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing availability of funds after appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any payment made to a State under this subchapter shall be available to the State without fiscal year limitation (subject to subsection (c)(2)(B)).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of returned funds and funds remaining unexpended for requirements payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amounts described in paragraph (2) shall be transferred to the Election Assistance Commission (established under subchapter II) and used by the Commission to make requirements payments under subpart 1 of part D of subchapter II.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The amounts referred to in this paragraph are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any amounts paid to the Administrator by a State under <ref>section 20902(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any amounts appropriated for payments under this subchapter which remain unobligated as of <date date="2003-09-01">September 1, 2003</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of amounts in State election fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When a State has established an election fund described in <ref>section 21004(b) of this title</ref>, the State shall ensure that any funds provided to the State under this subchapter are deposited and maintained in such fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations for Administrator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the amounts authorized under subsection (a), there are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator such sums as may be necessary to administer the programs under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20905.</num>
<heading> Administration of programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In administering the programs under this subchapter, the Administrator shall take such actions as the Administrator considers appropriate to expedite the payment of funds to States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20906.</num>
<heading> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator shall implement the programs established under this subchapter in a manner that ensures that the Administrator is able to make payments under the program not later than the expiration of the 45-day period which begins on <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COMMISSION</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Establishment and General Organization</heading>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 1—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">election assistance commission</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20921.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established as an independent entity the Election Assistance Commission (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Commission”), consisting of the members appointed under this subpart. Additionally, there is established the Election Assistance Commission Standards Board (including the Executive Board of such Board) and the Election Assistance Commission Board of Advisors under subpart 2 of this part (hereafter in this subpart referred to as the “Standards Board” and the “Board of Advisors”, respectively) and the Technical Guidelines Development Committee under subpart 3 of this part.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20922.</num>
<heading> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall serve as a national clearinghouse and resource for the compilation of information and review of procedures with respect to the administration of Federal elections by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carrying out the duties described in subpart 3 of this part (relating to the adoption of voluntary voting system guidelines), including the maintenance of a clearinghouse of information on the experiences of State and local governments in implementing the guidelines and in operating voting systems in general;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> carrying out the duties described in part B of this subchapter (relating to the testing, certification, decertification, and recertification of voting system hardware and software);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> carrying out the duties described in part C of this subchapter (relating to conducting studies and carrying out other activities to promote the effective administration of Federal elections);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> carrying out the duties described in part D of this subchapter (relating to election assistance), and providing information and training on the management of the payments and grants provided under such part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> carrying out the duties described in part B of subchapter III (relating to the adoption of voluntary guidance); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> developing and carrying out the Help America Vote College Program under subchapter V.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20923.</num>
<heading> Membership and appointment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall have four members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Before the initial appointment of the members of the Commission and before the appointment of any individual to fill a vacancy on the Commission, the Majority Leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the Senate, and the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives shall each submit to the President a candidate recommendation with respect to each vacancy on the Commission affiliated with the political party of the Member of Congress involved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each member of the Commission shall have experience with or expertise in election administration or the study of elections.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Date of appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The appointments of the members of the Commission shall be made not later than 120 days after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of service</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), members shall serve for a term of 4 years and may be reappointed for not more than one additional term.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of initial appointees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">As designated by the President at the time of nomination, of the members first appointed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> two of the members (not more than one of whom may be affiliated with the same political party) shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> two of the members (not more than one of whom may be affiliated with the same political party) shall be appointed for a term of 4 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A vacancy on the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made and shall be subject to any conditions which applied with respect to the original appointment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expired terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A member of the Commission shall serve on the Commission after the expiration of the member’s term until the successor of such member has taken office as a member of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unexpired terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An individual appointed to fill a vacancy shall be appointed for the unexpired term of the member replaced.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair and vice chair</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall select a chair and vice chair from among its members for a term of 1 year, except that the chair and vice chair may not be affiliated with the same political party.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Number of terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A member of the Commission may serve as the chairperson and vice chairperson for only 1 term each during the term of office to which such member is appointed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each member of the Commission shall be compensated at the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No member appointed to the Commission under subsection (a) may engage in any other business, vocation, or employment while serving as a member of the Commission and shall terminate or liquidate such business, vocation, or employment before sitting as a member of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1674</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20924.</num>
<heading> Staff</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Director, General Counsel, and other staff</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall have an Executive Director, who shall be paid at a rate not to exceed the rate of basic pay for level V of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5316 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of service for Executive Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Executive Director shall serve for a term of 4 years. An Executive Director may serve for a longer period only if reappointed for an additional term or terms by a vote of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedure for appointment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">When a vacancy exists in the position of the Executive Director, the Standards Board and the Board of Advisors shall each appoint a search committee to recommend at least three nominees for the position.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requiring consideration of nominees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the Commission shall consider the nominees recommended by the Standards Board and the Board of Advisors in appointing the Executive Director.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim service of General Counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a vacancy exists in the position of the Executive Director, the General Counsel of the Commission shall serve as the acting Executive Director until the Commission appoints a new Executive Director in accordance with this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules for interim Executive Director</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Convening of search committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Standards Board and the Board of Advisors shall each appoint a search committee and recommend nominees for the position of Executive Director in accordance with subparagraph (A) as soon as practicable after the appointment of their members.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim initial appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Notwithstanding subparagraph (B), the Commission may appoint an individual to serve as an interim Executive Director prior to the recommendation of nominees for the position by the Standards Board or the Board of Advisors, except that such individual’s term of service may not exceed 6 months. Nothing in the previous sentence may be construed to prohibit the individual serving as the interim Executive Director from serving any additional term.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General Counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall have a General Counsel, who shall be appointed by the Commission and who shall serve under the Executive Director. The General Counsel shall serve for a term of 4 years, and may serve for a longer period only if reappointed for an additional term or terms by a vote of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to rules prescribed by the Commission, the Executive Director may appoint and fix the pay of such additional personnel as the Executive Director considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of certain civil service laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Executive Director, General Counsel, and staff of the Commission may be appointed without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, and may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of that title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, except that an individual so appointed may not receive pay in excess of the annual rate of basic pay for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Experts and consultants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to rules prescribed by the Commission, the Executive Director may procure temporary and intermittent services under <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref> by a vote of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staff of Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon request of the Commission, the head of any Federal department or agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that department or agency to the Commission to assist it in carrying out its duties under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Arranging for assistance for Board of Advisors and Standards Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of the Board of Advisors or the Standards Board, the Commission may enter into such arrangements as the Commission considers appropriate to make personnel available to assist the Boards with carrying out their duties under this subchapter (including contracts with private individuals for providing temporary personnel services or the temporary detailing of personnel of the Commission).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with Board of Advisors and Standards Board on certain matters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In preparing the program goals, long-term plans, mission statements, and related matters for the Commission, the Executive Director and staff of the Commission shall consult with the Board of Advisors and the Standards Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1675</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20925.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings and sessions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may hold such hearings for the purpose of carrying out this chapter, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission considers advisable to carry out this chapter. The Commission may administer oaths and affirmations to witnesses appearing before the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information from Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out this chapter. Upon request of the Commission, the head of such department or agency shall furnish such information to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Postal services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative support services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Commission, the Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, the administrative support services that are necessary to enable the Commission to carry out its duties under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may contract with and compensate persons and Federal agencies for supplies and services without regard to <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20926.</num>
<heading> Dissemination of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out its duties, the Commission shall, on an ongoing basis, disseminate to the public (through the Internet, published reports, and such other methods as the Commission considers appropriate) in a manner that is consistent with the requirements of chapter 19 of title 44 information on the activities carried out under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20927.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than January 31 of each year (beginning with 2004), the Commission shall submit a report to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate detailing its activities during the fiscal year which ended on September 30 of the previous calendar year, and shall include in the report the following information:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A detailed description of activities conducted with respect to each program carried out by the Commission under this chapter, including information on each grant or other payment made under such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A copy of each report submitted to the Commission by a recipient of such grants or payments which is required under such a program, including reports submitted by States receiving requirements payments under subpart 1 of part D of this subchapter, and each other report submitted to the Commission under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Information on the voluntary voting system guidelines adopted or modified by the Commission under subpart 3 of this part and information on the voluntary guidance adopted under part B of subchapter III.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> All votes taken by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other information and recommendations as the Commission considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20928.</num>
<heading> Requiring majority approval for actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any action which the Commission is authorized to carry out under this chapter may be carried out only with the approval of at least three of its members.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20929.</num>
<heading> Limitation on rulemaking authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall not have any authority to issue any rule, promulgate any regulation, or take any other action which imposes any requirement on any State or unit of local government, except to the extent permitted under <ref>section 20508(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20930.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the amounts authorized for payments and grants under this subchapter and the amounts authorized to be appropriated for the program under <ref>section 21123 of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated for each of the fiscal years 2003 through 2005 such sums as may be necessary (but not to exceed $10,000,000 for each such year) for the Commission to carry out this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 2—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">election assistance commission standards board and board of advisors</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20941.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are hereby established the Election Assistance Commission Standards Board (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Standards Board”) and the Election Assistance Commission Board of Advisors (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Board of Advisors”).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20942.</num>
<heading> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Standards Board and the Board of Advisors shall each, in accordance with the procedures described in subpart 3 of this part, review the voluntary voting system guidelines under such subpart, the voluntary guidance under subchapter III, and the best practices recommendations contained in the report submitted under <ref>section 20982(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20943.</num>
<heading> Membership of Standards Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to certification by the chair of the Federal Election Commission under subsection (b), the Standards Board shall be composed of 110 members as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Fifty-five shall be State election officials selected by the chief State election official of each State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Fifty-five shall be local election officials selected in accordance with paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> List of local election officials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State’s local election officials, including the local election officials of Puerto Rico and the United States Virgin Islands, shall select (under a process supervised by the chief election official of the State) a representative local election official from the State for purposes of paragraph (1)(B). In the case of the District of Columbia, Guam, and American Samoa, the chief election official shall establish a procedure for selecting an individual to serve as a local election official for purposes of such paragraph, except that under such a procedure the individual selected may not be a member of the same political party as the chief election official.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requiring mix of political parties represented</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The two members of the Standards Board who represent the same State may not be members of the same political party.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures for notice and certification of appointment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice to chair of Federal Election Commission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, the chief State election official of the State shall transmit a notice to the chair of the Federal Election Commission containing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of the State election official who agrees to serve on the Standards Board under this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the name of the representative local election official from the State selected under subsection (a)(2) who agrees to serve on the Standards Board under this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon receiving a notice from a State under paragraph (1), the chair of the Federal Election Commission shall publish a certification that the selected State election official and the representative local election official are appointed as members of the Standards Board under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of failure to provide notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a State does not transmit a notice to the chair of the Federal Election Commission under paragraph (1) within the deadline described in such paragraph, no representative from the State may participate in the selection of the initial Executive Board under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Role of Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the appointment of the members of the Election Assistance Commission, the Election Assistance Commission shall carry out the duties of the Federal Election Commission under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Board</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after the last day on which the appointment of any of its members may be certified under subsection (b), the Standards Board shall select nine of its members to serve as the Executive Board of the Standards Board, of whom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not more than five may be State election officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not more than five may be local election officials; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not more than five may be members of the same political party.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (3), members of the Executive Board of the Standards Board shall serve for a term of 2 years and may not serve for more than 3 consecutive terms.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staggering of initial terms</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Of the members first selected to serve on the Executive Board of the Standards Board—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> three shall serve for 1 term;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> three shall serve for 2 consecutive terms; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> three shall serve for 3 consecutive terms,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">as determined by lot at the time the members are first appointed.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to any other duties assigned under this subchapter, the Executive Board of the Standards Board may carry out such duties of the Standards Board as the Standards Board may delegate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20944.</num>
<heading> Membership of Board of Advisors</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Board of Advisors shall be composed of 37 members appointed as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Two members appointed by the National Governors Association.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Two members appointed by the National Conference of State Legislatures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Two members appointed by the National Association of Secretaries of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Two members appointed by the National Association of State Election Directors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Two members appointed by the National Association of Counties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Two members appointed by the National Association of County Recorders, Election Administrators, and Clerks.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002007">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Two members appointed by the United States Conference of Mayors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Two members appointed by the Election Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Two members appointed by the International Association of County Recorders, Election Officials, and Treasurers.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Two members appointed by the United States Commission on Civil Rights.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Two members appointed by the Architectural and Transportation Barrier <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">3</ref> Compliance Board under <ref>section 792 of title 29</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The chief of the Office of Public Integrity of the Department of Justice,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">4</ref> or the chief’s designee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> The chief of the Voting Section of the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice or the chief’s designee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> The director of the Federal Voting Assistance Program of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<chapeau> Four members representing professionals in the field of science and technology, of whom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> one each shall be appointed by the Speaker and the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> one each shall be appointed by the Majority Leader and the Minority Leader of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<chapeau> Eight members representing voter interests, of whom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> four members shall be appointed by the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, of whom two shall be appointed by the chair and two shall be appointed by the ranking minority member; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> four members shall be appointed by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, of whom two shall be appointed by the chair and two shall be appointed by the ranking minority member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manner of appointments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appointments shall be made to the Board of Advisors under subsection (a) in a manner which ensures that the Board of Advisors will be bipartisan in nature and will reflect the various geographic regions of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term of service; vacancy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Board of Advisors shall serve for a term of 2 years, and may be reappointed. Any vacancy in the Board of Advisors shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board of Advisors shall elect a Chair from among its members.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1680</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20945.</num>
<heading> Powers of Boards; no compensation for service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings and sessions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent that funds are made available by the Commission, the Standards Board (acting through the Executive Board) and the Board of Advisors may each hold such hearings for the purpose of carrying out this chapter, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as each such Board considers advisable to carry out this subchapter, except that the Boards may not issue subpoenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses or the production of any evidence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Standards Board and the Board of Advisors shall each hold a meeting of its members—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less frequently than once every year for purposes of voting on the voluntary voting system guidelines referred to it under <ref>section 20962 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of the Standards Board, not less frequently than once every 2 years for purposes of selecting the Executive Board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> at such other times as it considers appropriate for purposes of conducting such other business as it considers appropriate consistent with this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information from Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Standards Board and the Board of Advisors may each secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Board considers necessary to carry out this chapter. Upon request of the Executive Board (in the case of the Standards Board) or the Chair (in the case of the Board of Advisors), the head of such department or agency shall furnish such information to the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Postal services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Standards Board and the Board of Advisors may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as a department or agency of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative support services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the Executive Board (in the case of the Standards Board) or the Chair (in the case of the Board of Advisors), the Administrator of the General Services Administration shall provide to the Board, on a reimbursable basis, the administrative support services that are necessary to enable the Board to carry out its duties under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No compensation for service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Standards Board and members of the Board of Advisors shall not receive any compensation for their service, but shall be paid travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1681</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20946.</num>
<heading> Status of Boards and members for purposes of claims against Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of chapters 161 and 171 of title 28 shall apply with respect to the liability of the Standards Board, the Board of Advisors, and their members for acts or omissions performed pursuant to and in the course of the duties and responsibilities of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for criminal acts and other willful conduct</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) may not be construed to limit personal liability for criminal acts or omissions, willful or malicious misconduct, acts or omissions for private gain, or any other act or omission outside the scope of the service of a member of the Standards Board or the Board of Advisors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 216</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1681</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 3—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">technical guidelines development committee</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20961.</num>
<heading> Technical Guidelines Development Committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established the Technical Guidelines Development Committee (hereafter in this subpart referred to as the “Development Committee”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Development Committee shall assist the Executive Director of the Commission in the development of the voluntary voting system guidelines.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline for initial set of recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Development Committee shall provide its first set of recommendations under this section to the Executive Director of the Commission not later than 9 months after all of its members have been appointed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Development Committee shall be composed of the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (who shall serve as its chair), together with a group of 14 other individuals appointed jointly by the Commission and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, consisting of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> An equal number of each of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Members of the Standards Board.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Members of the Board of Advisors.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Members of the Architectural and Transportation Barrier Compliance Board under <ref>section 792 of title 29</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A representative of the American National Standards Institute.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A representative of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Two representatives of the National Association of State Election Directors selected by such Association who are not members of the Standards Board or Board of Advisors, and who are not of the same political party.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Other individuals with technical and scientific expertise relating to voting systems and voting equipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A majority of the members of the Development Committee shall constitute a quorum, except that the Development Committee may not conduct any business prior to the appointment of all of its members.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No compensation for service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Development Committee shall not receive any compensation for their service, but shall be paid travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Development Committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical support from National Institute of Standards and Technology</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the request of the Development Committee, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall provide the Development Committee with technical support necessary for the Development Committee to carry out its duties under this part.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical support</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The technical support provided under paragraph (1) shall include intramural research and development in areas to support the development of the voluntary voting system guidelines under this subpart, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the security of computers, computer networks, and computer data storage used in voting systems, including the computerized list required under <ref>section 21083(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> methods to detect and prevent fraud;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the protection of voter privacy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the role of human factors in the design and application of voting systems, including assistive technologies for individuals with disabilities (including blindness) and varying levels of literacy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> remote access voting, including voting through the Internet.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No private sector intellectual property rights in guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No private sector individual or entity shall obtain any intellectual property rights to any guideline or the contents of any guideline (or any modification to any guideline) adopted by the Commission under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of recommendations in Federal Register</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the time the Commission adopts any voluntary voting system guideline pursuant to <ref>section 20962 of this title</ref>, the Development Committee shall cause to have published in the Federal Register the recommendations it provided under this section to the Executive Director of the Commission concerning the guideline adopted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 221</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1682</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20962.</num>
<heading> Process for adoption</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General requirement for notice and comment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Consistent with the requirements of this section, the final adoption of the voluntary voting system guidelines (or modification of such a guideline) shall be carried out by the Commission in a manner that provides for each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Publication of notice of the proposed guidelines in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An opportunity for public comment on the proposed guidelines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An opportunity for a public hearing on the record.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Publication of the final guidelines in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of recommendations of Development Committee; submission of proposed guidelines to Board of Advisors and Standards Board</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of recommendations of Development Committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In developing the voluntary voting system guidelines and modifications of such guidelines under this section, the Executive Director of the Commission shall take into consideration the recommendations provided by the Technical Guidelines Development Committee under <ref>section 20961 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board of Advisors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Executive Director of the Commission shall submit the guidelines proposed to be adopted under this subpart (or any modifications to such guidelines) to the Board of Advisors.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Executive Director of the Commission shall submit the guidelines proposed to be adopted under this subpart (or any modifications to such guidelines) to the Executive Board of the Standards Board, which shall review the guidelines (or modifications) and forward its recommendations to the Standards Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon receipt of voluntary voting system guidelines described in subsection (b) (or a modification of such guidelines) from the Executive Director of the Commission, the Board of Advisors and the Standards Board shall each review and submit comments and recommendations regarding the guideline (or modification) to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final adoption</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A voluntary voting system guideline described in subsection (b) (or modification of such a guideline) shall not be considered to be finally adopted by the Commission unless the Commission votes to approve the final adoption of the guideline (or modification), taking into consideration the comments and recommendations submitted by the Board of Advisors and the Standards Board under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum period for consideration of comments and recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission may not vote on the final adoption of a guideline described in subsection (b) (or modification of such a guideline) until the expiration of the 90-day period which begins on the date the Executive Director of the Commission submits the proposed guideline (or modification) to the Board of Advisors and the Standards Board under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for initial set of guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subpart, the most recent set of voting system standards adopted by the Federal Election Commission prior to <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, shall be deemed to have been adopted by the Commission as of <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, as the first set of voluntary voting system guidelines adopted under this subpart.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 222</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1683</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Testing, Certification, Decertification, and Recertification of Voting System Hardware and Software</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20971.</num>
<heading> Certification and testing of voting systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification and testing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall provide for the testing, certification, decertification, and recertification of voting system hardware and software by accredited laboratories.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Optional use by States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the option of a State, the State may provide for the testing, certification, decertification, or recertification of its voting system hardware and software by the laboratories accredited by the Commission under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Laboratory accreditation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations by National Institute of Standards and Technology</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 6 months after the Commission first adopts voluntary voting system guidelines under subpart 3 of part A of this subchapter, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall conduct an evaluation of independent, non-Federal laboratories and shall submit to the Commission a list of those laboratories the Director proposes to be accredited to carry out the testing, certification, decertification, and recertification provided for under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval by Commission</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission shall vote on the accreditation of any laboratory under this section, taking into consideration the list submitted under paragraph (1), and no laboratory may be accredited for purposes of this section unless its accreditation is approved by a vote of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accreditation of laboratories not on Director list</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission shall publish an explanation for the accreditation of any laboratory not included on the list submitted by the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing review by National Institute of Standards and Technology</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In cooperation with the Commission and in consultation with the Standards Board and the Board of Advisors, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall monitor and review, on an ongoing basis, the performance of the laboratories accredited by the Commission under this section, and shall make such recommendations to the Commission as it considers appropriate with respect to the continuing accreditation of such laboratories, including recommendations to revoke the accreditation of any such laboratory.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval by Commission required for revocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The accreditation of a laboratory for purposes of this section may not be revoked unless the revocation is approved by a vote of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Until such time as the Commission provides for the testing, certification, decertification, and recertification of voting system hardware and software by accredited laboratories under this section, the accreditation of laboratories and the procedure for the testing, certification, decertification, and recertification of voting system hardware and software used as of <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, shall remain in effect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1684</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Studies and Other Activities To Promote Effective Administration of Federal Elections</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20981.</num>
<heading> Periodic studies of election administration issues</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On such periodic basis as the Commission may determine, the Commission shall conduct and make available to the public studies regarding the election administration issues described in subsection (b), with the goal of promoting methods of voting and administering elections which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> will be the most convenient, accessible, and easy to use for voters, including members of the uniformed services and overseas voters, individuals with disabilities, including the blind and visually impaired, and voters with limited proficiency in the English language;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> will yield the most accurate, secure, and expeditious system for voting and tabulating election results;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> will be nondiscriminatory and afford each registered and eligible voter an equal opportunity to vote and to have that vote counted; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> will be efficient and cost-effective for use.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election administration issues described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), the election administration issues described in this subsection are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Methods and mechanisms of election technology and voting systems used in voting and counting votes in elections for Federal office, including the over-vote and under-vote notification capabilities of such technology and systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Ballot designs for elections for Federal office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Methods of voter registration, maintaining secure and accurate lists of registered voters (including the establishment of a centralized, interactive, statewide voter registration list linked to relevant agencies and all polling sites), and ensuring that registered voters appear on the voter registration list at the appropriate polling site.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Methods of conducting provisional voting.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Methods of ensuring the accessibility of voting, registration, polling places, and voting equipment to all voters, including individuals with disabilities (including the blind and visually impaired), Native American or Alaska Native citizens, and voters with limited proficiency in the English language.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Nationwide statistics and methods of identifying, deterring, and investigating voting fraud in elections for Federal office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Identifying, deterring, and investigating methods of voter intimidation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Methods of recruiting, training, and improving the performance of poll workers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Methods of educating voters about the process of registering to vote and voting, the operation of voting mechanisms, the location of polling places, and all other aspects of participating in elections.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> The feasibility and advisability of conducting elections for Federal office on different days, at different places, and during different hours, including the advisability of establishing a uniform poll closing time and establishing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a legal public holiday under <ref>section 6103 of title 5</ref> as the date on which general elections for Federal office are held;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Tuesday next after the 1st Monday in November, in every even numbered year, as a legal public holiday under such section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a date other than the Tuesday next after the 1st Monday in November, in every even numbered year as the date on which general elections for Federal office are held; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any date described in subparagraph (C) as a legal public holiday under such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Federal and State laws governing the eligibility of persons to vote.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Ways that the Federal Government can best assist State and local authorities to improve the administration of elections for Federal office and what levels of funding would be necessary to provide such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The laws and procedures used by each State that govern—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> recounts of ballots cast in elections for Federal office;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> contests of determinations regarding whether votes are counted in such elections; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> standards that define what will constitute a vote on each type of voting equipment used in the State to conduct elections for Federal office.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The best practices (as identified by the Commission) that are used by States with respect to the recounts and contests described in clause (i).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Whether or not there is a need for more consistency among State recount and contest procedures used with respect to elections for Federal office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> The technical feasibility of providing voting materials in eight or more languages for voters who speak those languages and who have limited English proficiency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> Matters particularly relevant to voting and administering elections in rural and urban areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> Methods of voter registration for members of the uniformed services and overseas voters, and methods of ensuring that such voters receive timely ballots that will be properly and expeditiously handled and counted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> The best methods for establishing voting system performance benchmarks, expressed as a percentage of residual vote in the Federal contest at the top of the ballot.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> Broadcasting practices that may result in the broadcast of false information concerning the location or time of operation of a polling place.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> Such other matters as the Commission determines are appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall submit to the President and to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate a report on each study conducted under subsection (a) together with such recommendations for administrative and legislative action as the Commission determines is appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 241</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1686</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20982.</num>
<heading> Study, report, and recommendations on best practices for facilitating military and overseas voting</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall conduct a study on the best practices for facilitating voting by absent uniformed services voters (as defined in <ref>section 20310(1) of this title</ref>) and overseas voters (as defined in <ref>section 20310(5) of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issues considered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In conducting the study under paragraph (1) the Commission shall consider the following issues:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The rights of residence of uniformed services voters absent due to military orders.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The rights of absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters to register to vote and cast absentee ballots, including the right of such voters to cast a secret ballot.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The rights of absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters to submit absentee ballot applications early during an election year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The appropriate preelection deadline for mailing absentee ballots to absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The appropriate minimum period between the mailing of absentee ballots to absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters and the deadline for receipt of such ballots.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The timely transmission of balloting materials to absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Security and privacy concerns in the transmission, receipt, and processing of ballots from absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters, including the need to protect against fraud.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The use of a single application by absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters for absentee ballots for all Federal elections occurring during a year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The use of a single application for voter registration and absentee ballots by absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> The use of facsimile machines and electronic means of transmission of absentee ballot applications and absentee ballots to absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> Other issues related to the rights of absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters to participate in elections.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report and recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than the date that is 18 months after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, the Commission shall submit to the President and Congress a report on the study conducted under subsection (a)(1) together with recommendations identifying the best practices used with respect to the issues considered under subsection (a)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 242</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20983.</num>
<heading> Report on human factor research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, the Commission, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall submit a report to Congress which assesses the areas of human factor research, including usability engineering and human-computer and human-machine interaction, which feasibly could be applied to voting products and systems design to ensure the usability and accuracy of voting products and systems, including methods to improve access for individuals with disabilities (including blindness) and individuals with limited proficiency in the English language and to reduce voter error and the number of spoiled ballots in elections.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 243</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20984.</num>
<heading> Study and report on voters who register by mail and use of Social Security information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registration by mail</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission shall conduct a study of the impact of <ref>section 21083(b) of this title</ref> on voters who register by mail.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific issues studied</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The study conducted under subparagraph (A) shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an examination of the impact of <ref>section 21083(b) of this title</ref> on first time mail registrant voters who vote in person, including the impact of such section on voter registration;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an examination of the impact of such section on the accuracy of voter rolls, including preventing ineligible names from being placed on voter rolls and ensuring that all eligible names are placed on voter rolls; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an analysis of the impact of such section on existing State practices, such as the use of signature verification or attestation procedures to verify the identity of voters in elections for Federal office, and an analysis of other changes that may be made to improve the voter registration process, such as verification or additional information on the registration card.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 18 months after the date on which <ref>section 21083(b)(2) of this title</ref> takes effect, the Commission shall submit a report to the President and Congress on the study conducted under paragraph (1)(A) together with such recommendations for administrative and legislative action as the Commission determines is appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Social Security information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 18 months after the date on which <ref>section 21083(a)(5) of this title</ref> takes effect, the Commission, in consultation with the Commissioner of Social Security, shall study and report to Congress on the feasibility and advisability of using Social Security identification numbers or other information compiled by the Social Security Administration to establish voter registration or other election law eligibility or identification requirements, including the matching of relevant information specific to an individual voter, the impact of such use on national security issues, and whether adequate safeguards or waiver procedures exist to protect the privacy of an individual voter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 244</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1689</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20985.</num>
<heading> Study and report on electronic voting and the electoral process</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall conduct a thorough study of issues and challenges, specifically to include the potential for election fraud, presented by incorporating communications and Internet technologies in the Federal, State, and local electoral process.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issues to be studied</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission may include in the study conducted under paragraph (1) an examination of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the appropriate security measures required and minimum standards for certification of systems or technologies in order to minimize the potential for fraud in voting or in the registration of qualified citizens to register and vote;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the possible methods, such as Internet or other communications technologies, that may be utilized in the electoral process, including the use of those technologies to register voters and enable citizens to vote online, and recommendations concerning statutes and rules to be adopted in order to implement an online or Internet system in the electoral process;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the impact that new communications or Internet technology systems for use in the electoral process could have on voter participation rates, voter education, public accessibility, potential external influences during the elections process, voter privacy and anonymity, and other issues related to the conduct and administration of elections;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> whether other aspects of the electoral process, such as public availability of candidate information and citizen communication with candidates, could benefit from the increased use of online or Internet technologies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the requirements for authorization of collection, storage, and processing of electronically generated and transmitted digital messages to permit any eligible person to register to vote or vote in an election, including applying for and casting an absentee ballot;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the implementation cost of an online or Internet voting or voter registration system and the costs of elections after implementation (including a comparison of total cost savings for the administration of the electoral process by using Internet technologies or systems);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> identification of current and foreseeable online and Internet technologies for use in the registration of voters, for voting, or for the purpose of reducing election fraud, currently available or in use by election authorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the means by which to ensure and achieve equity of access to online or Internet voting or voter registration systems and address the fairness of such systems to all citizens; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the impact of technology on the speed, timeliness, and accuracy of vote counts in Federal, State, and local elections.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 20 months after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, the Commission shall transmit to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a), including such legislative recommendations or model State laws as are required to address the findings of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Internet posting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the dissemination requirements under chapter 19 of title 44, the Election Administration Commission shall post the report transmitted under paragraph (1) on an Internet website.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 245</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20986.</num>
<heading> Study and report on free absentee ballot postage</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study on the establishment of a free absentee ballot postage program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission, in consultation with the Postal Service, shall conduct a study on the feasibility and advisability of the establishment of a program under which the Postal Service shall waive or otherwise reduce the amount of postage applicable with respect to absentee ballots submitted by voters in general elections for Federal office (other than balloting materials mailed under <ref>section 3406 of title 39</ref>) that does not apply with respect to the postage required to send the absentee ballots to voters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public survey</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As part of the study conducted under paragraph (1), the Commission shall conduct a survey of potential beneficiaries under the program described in such paragraph, including the elderly and disabled, and shall take into account the results of such survey in determining the feasibility and advisability of establishing such a program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than the date that is 1 year after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under subsection (a)(1) together with recommendations for such legislative and administrative action as the Commission determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall contain an estimate of the costs of establishing the program described in subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall contain an analysis of the feasibility of implementing the program described in subsection (a)(1) with respect to the absentee ballots to be submitted in the general election for Federal office held in 2004.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations regarding the elderly and disabled</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> include recommendations on ways that program described in subsection (a)(1) would target elderly individuals and individuals with disabilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> identify methods to increase the number of such individuals who vote in elections for Federal office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Postal Service defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term “Postal Service” means the United States Postal Service established under <ref>section 201 of title 39</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 246</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20987.</num>
<heading> Consultation with Standards Board and Board of Advisors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall carry out its duties under this part in consultation with the Standards Board and the Board of Advisors.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 247</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1692</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part D—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Election Assistance</heading>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 1—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">requirements payments</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21001.</num>
<heading> Requirements payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall make a requirements payment each year in an amount determined under <ref>section 21002 of this title</ref> to each State which meets the conditions described in <ref>section 21003 of this title</ref> for the year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), a State receiving a requirements payment shall use the payment only to meet the requirements of subchapter III.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A State may use a requirements payment to carry out other activities to improve the administration of elections for Federal office if the State certifies to the Commission that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the State has implemented the requirements of subchapter III; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount expended with respect to such other activities does not exceed an amount equal to the minimum payment amount applicable to the State under <ref>section 21002(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities under Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A State shall use a requirements payment made using funds appropriated pursuant to the authorization under <ref>section 21007(a)(4) of this title</ref> only to meet the requirements under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act [<ref>52 U.S.C. 20301</ref> et seq.] imposed as a result of the provisions of and amendments made by the Military and Overseas Voter Empowerment Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retroactive payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, including the maintenance of effort requirements of <ref>section 21004(a)(7) of this title</ref>, a State may use a requirements payment as a reimbursement for costs incurred in obtaining voting equipment which meets the requirements of <ref>section 21081 of this title</ref> if the State obtains the equipment after the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in November 2000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule regarding multiyear contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A State may use a requirements payment for any costs for voting equipment which meets the requirements of <ref>section 21081 of this title</ref> that, pursuant to a multiyear contract, were incurred on or after <date date="2001-01-01">January 1, 2001</date>, except that the amount that the State is otherwise required to contribute under the maintenance of effort requirements of <ref>section 21004(a)(7) of this title</ref> shall be increased by the amount of the payment made with respect to such multiyear contract.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adoption of Commission guidelines and guidance not required to receive payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subpart may be construed to require a State to implement any of the voluntary voting system guidelines or any of the voluntary guidance adopted by the Commission with respect to any matter as a condition for receiving a requirements payment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Schedule of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the initial appointment of all members of the Commission (but in no event later than 6 months thereafter), and not less frequently than once each calendar year thereafter, the Commission shall make requirements payments to States under this subpart.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A State may not use any portion of a requirements payment—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to pay costs associated with any litigation, except to the extent that such costs otherwise constitute permitted uses of a requirements payment under this subpart; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for the payment of any judgment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 251</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1692</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 588(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2333</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21002.</num>
<heading> Allocation of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsection (c), the amount of a requirements payment made to a State for a year shall be equal to the product of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the total amount appropriated for requirements payments for the year pursuant to the authorization under <ref>section 21007 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the State allocation percentage for the State (as determined under subsection (b)).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State allocation percentage defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The “State allocation percentage” for a State is the amount (expressed as a percentage) equal to the quotient of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the voting age population of the State (as reported in the most recent decennial census); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the total voting age population of all States (as reported in the most recent decennial census).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum amount of payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The amount of a requirements payment made to a State for a year may not be less than—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of any of the several States or the District of Columbia, one-half of 1 percent of the total amount appropriated for requirements payments for the year under <ref>section 21007 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, or the United States Virgin Islands, one-tenth of 1 percent of such total amount.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pro rata reductions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002011">1</ref> shall make such pro rata reductions to the allocations determined under subsection (a) as are necessary to comply with the requirements of subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing availability of funds after appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A requirements payment made to a State under this subpart shall be available to the State without fiscal year limitation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 252</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21003.</num>
<heading> Condition for receipt of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A State is eligible to receive a requirements payment for a fiscal year if the chief executive officer of the State, or designee, in consultation and coordination with the chief State election official, has filed with the Commission a statement certifying that the State is in compliance with the requirements referred to in subsection (b). A State may meet the requirement of the previous sentence by filing with the Commission a statement which reads as follows: “______ hereby certifies that it is in compliance with the requirements referred to in section 253(b) of the Help America Vote Act of 2002.” (with the blank to be filled in with the name of the State involved).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State plan requirement; certification of compliance with applicable laws and requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The requirements referred to in this subsection are as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The State has filed with the Commission a State plan covering the fiscal year which the State certifies—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contains each of the elements described in <ref>section 21004(a) of this title</ref> (or, for purposes of determining the eligibility of a State to receive a requirements payment appropriated pursuant to the authorization provided under <ref>section 21007(a)(4) of this title</ref>, contains the element described in paragraph (14) of such section) with respect to the fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is developed in accordance with <ref>section 21005 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> meets the public notice and comment requirements of <ref>section 21006 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), the State has filed with the Commission a plan for the implementation of the uniform, nondiscriminatory administrative complaint procedures required under <ref>section 21112 of this title</ref> (or has included such a plan in the State plan filed under paragraph (1)), and has such procedures in place for purposes of meeting the requirements of such section. If the State does not include such an implementation plan in the State plan filed under paragraph (1), the requirements of sections 21005(b) and 21006 of this title shall apply to the implementation plan in the same manner as such requirements apply to the State plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply for purposes of determining the eligibility of a State to receive a requirements payment appropriated pursuant to the authorization provided under <ref>section 21007(a)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The State is in compliance with each of the laws described in <ref>section 21145 of this title</ref>, as such laws apply with respect to this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent that any portion of the requirements payment is used for activities other than meeting the requirements of subchapter III—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the State’s proposed uses of the requirements payment are not inconsistent with the requirements of subchapter III; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use of the funds under this paragraph is consistent with the requirements of <ref>section 21001(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), the State has appropriated funds for carrying out the activities for which the requirements payment is made in an amount equal to 5 percent of the total amount to be spent for such activities (taking into account the requirements payment and the amount spent by the State) and, in the case of a State that uses a requirements payment as a reimbursement under <ref>section 21001(c)(2) of this title</ref>, an additional amount equal to the amount of such reimbursement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply for purposes of determining the eligibility of a State to receive a requirements payment appropriated pursuant to the authorization provided under <ref>section 21007(a)(4) of this title</ref> for fiscal year 2010, except that if the State does not appropriate funds in accordance with subparagraph (A) prior to the last day of fiscal year 2011, the State shall repay to the Commission the requirements payment which is appropriated pursuant to such authorization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methods of compliance left to discretion of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The specific choices on the methods of complying with the elements of a State plan shall be left to the discretion of the State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing for filing of certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A State may not file a statement of certification under subsection (a) until the expiration of the 45-day period (or, in the case of a fiscal year other than the first fiscal year for which a requirements payment is made to the State under this part, the 30-day period) which begins on the date notice of the State plan under this part is published in the Federal Register pursuant to <ref>section 21005(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chief State election official defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this part, the “chief State election official” of a State is the individual designated by the State under section 10 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg–8</ref>) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20509</ref>] to be responsible for coordination of the State’s responsibilities under such Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 253</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1693</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 588(b)(1)(B)</ref>–(3), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2333</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. C, title VI, § 622(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 927</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21004.</num>
<heading> State plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The State plan shall contain a description of each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> How the State will use the requirements payment to meet the requirements of subchapter III, and, if applicable under <ref>section 21001(a)(2) of this title</ref>, to carry out other activities to improve the administration of elections.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> How the State will distribute and monitor the distribution of the requirements payment to units of local government or other entities in the State for carrying out the activities described in paragraph (1), including a description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the criteria to be used to determine the eligibility of such units or entities for receiving the payment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the methods to be used by the State to monitor the performance of the units or entities to whom the payment is distributed, consistent with the performance goals and measures adopted under paragraph (8).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> How the State will provide for programs for voter education, election official education and training, and poll worker training which will assist the State in meeting the requirements of subchapter III.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> How the State will adopt voting system guidelines and processes which are consistent with the requirements of <ref>section 21081 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> How the State will establish a fund described in subsection (b) for purposes of administering the State’s activities under this subpart, including information on fund management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The State’s proposed budget for activities under this subpart, based on the State’s best estimates of the costs of such activities and the amount of funds to be made available, including specific information on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the costs of the activities required to be carried out to meet the requirements of subchapter III;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the portion of the requirements payment which will be used to carry out activities to meet such requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the portion of the requirements payment which will be used to carry out other activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> How the State, in using the requirements payment, will maintain the expenditures of the State for activities funded by the payment at a level that is not less than the level of such expenditures maintained by the State for the fiscal year ending prior to November 2000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> How the State will adopt performance goals and measures that will be used by the State to determine its success and the success of units of local government in the State in carrying out the plan, including timetables for meeting each of the elements of the plan, descriptions of the criteria the State will use to measure performance and the process used to develop such criteria, and a description of which official is to be held responsible for ensuring that each performance goal is met.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> A description of the uniform, nondiscriminatory State-based administrative complaint procedures in effect under <ref>section 21112 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> If the State received any payment under subchapter I, a description of how such payment will affect the activities proposed to be carried out under the plan, including the amount of funds available for such activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> How the State will conduct ongoing management of the plan, except that the State may not make any material change in the administration of the plan unless notice of the change—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is developed and published in the Federal Register in accordance with <ref>section 21005 of this title</ref> in the same manner as the State plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is subject to public notice and comment in accordance with <ref>section 21006 of this title</ref> in the same manner as the State plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> takes effect only after the expiration of the 30-day period which begins on the date notice of the change is published in the Federal Register in accordance with subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> In the case of a State with a State plan in effect under this part during the previous fiscal year, a description of how the plan reflects changes from the State plan for the previous fiscal year and of how the State succeeded in carrying out the State plan for such previous fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> A description of the committee which participated in the development of the State plan in accordance with <ref>section 21005 of this title</ref> and the procedures followed by the committee under such section and <ref>section 21006 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> How the State will comply with the provisions and requirements of and amendments made by the Military and Overseas Voter Empowerment Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for election fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election fund described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of subsection (a)(5), a fund described in this subsection with respect to a State is a fund which is established in the treasury of the State government, which is used in accordance with paragraph (2), and which consists of the following amounts:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Amounts appropriated or otherwise made available by the State for carrying out the activities for which the requirements payment is made to the State under this subpart.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The requirements payment made to the State under this subpart.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Such other amounts as may be appropriated under law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Interest earned on deposits of the fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts in the fund shall be used by the State exclusively to carry out the activities for which the requirements payment is made to the State under this subpart.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of States that require changes to State law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a State that requires State legislation to establish the fund described in this subsection, the Commission shall defer disbursement of the requirements payment to such State until such time as legislation establishing the fund is enacted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection against actions based on information in plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No action may be brought under this chapter against a State or other jurisdiction on the basis of any information contained in the State plan filed under this subpart.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for criminal acts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) may not be construed to limit the liability of a State or other jurisdiction for criminal acts or omissions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 254</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1694</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 588(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2333</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. C, title VI, § 622(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 927</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21005.</num>
<heading> Process for development and filing of plan; publication by Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chief State election official shall develop the State plan under this part through a committee of appropriate individuals, including the chief election officials of the two most populous jurisdictions within the States, other local election officials, stake holders (including representatives of groups of individuals with disabilities), and other citizens, appointed for such purpose by the chief State election official.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of plan by Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After receiving the State plan of a State under this part, the Commission shall cause to have the plan posted on the Commission’s website with a notice published in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 255</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1697</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. C, title VI, § 622(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 926</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21006.</num>
<heading> Requirement for public notice and comment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of section 21001(a)(1)(C) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002012">1</ref> of this title, a State plan meets the public notice and comment requirements of this section if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not later than 30 days prior to the submission of the plan, the State made a preliminary version of the plan available for public inspection and comment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the State publishes notice that the preliminary version of the plan is so available; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the State took the public comments made regarding the preliminary version of the plan into account in preparing the plan which was filed with the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 256</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1697</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21007.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to amounts transferred under <ref>section 20904(c) of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated for requirements payments under this subpart the following amounts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2003, $1,400,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2004, $1,000,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2005, $600,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2010 and subsequent fiscal years, such sums as are necessary for purposes of making requirements payments to States to carry out the activities described in <ref>section 21001(b)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amounts appropriated pursuant to the authority of subsection (a) shall remain available without fiscal year limitation until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 257</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1697</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 588(c)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2334</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21008.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after the end of each fiscal year for which a State received a requirements payment under this subpart, the State shall submit a report to the Commission on the activities conducted with the funds provided during the year, and shall include in the report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a list of expenditures made with respect to each category of activities described in <ref>section 21001(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number and type of articles of voting equipment obtained with the funds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an analysis and description of the activities funded under this subpart to meet the requirements of this chapter and an analysis and description of how such activities conform to the State plan under <ref>section 21004 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 258</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1697</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 2—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">payments to states and units of local government to assure access for individuals with disabilities</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21021.</num>
<heading> Payments to States and units of local government to assure access for individuals with disabilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall make a payment to each eligible State and each eligible unit of local government (as described in <ref>section 21023 of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An eligible State and eligible unit of local government shall use the payment received under this subpart for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> making polling places, including the path of travel, entrances, exits, and voting areas of each polling facility, accessible to individuals with disabilities, including the blind and visually impaired, in a manner that provides the same opportunity for access and participation (including privacy and independence) as for other voters; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> providing individuals with disabilities and the other individuals described in paragraph (1) with information about the accessibility of polling places, including outreach programs to inform the individuals about the availability of accessible polling places and training election officials, poll workers, and election volunteers on how best to promote the access and participation of individuals with disabilities in elections for Federal office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Schedule of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date> (but in no event later than 6 months thereafter), and not less frequently than once each calendar year thereafter, the Secretary shall make payments under this subpart.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 261</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1698</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21022.</num>
<heading> Amount of payment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amount of a payment made to an eligible State or an eligible unit of local government for a year under this subpart shall be determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing availability of funds after appropriation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A payment made to an eligible State or eligible unit of local government under this subpart shall be available without fiscal year limitation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 262</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1698</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21023.</num>
<heading> Requirements for eligibility</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each State or unit of local government that desires to receive a payment under this subpart for a fiscal year shall submit an application for the payment to the Secretary at such time and in such manner and containing such information as the Secretary shall require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each application submitted under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describe the activities for which assistance under this section is sought; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide such additional information and certifications as the Secretary determines to be essential to ensure compliance with the requirements of this subpart.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection against actions based on information in application</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No action may be brought under this chapter against a State or unit of local government on the basis of any information contained in the application submitted under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for criminal acts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) may not be construed to limit the liability of a State or unit of local government for criminal acts or omissions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 263</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1698</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21024.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this subpart the following amounts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2003, $50,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2004, $25,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For fiscal year 2005, $25,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amounts appropriated pursuant to the authority of subsection (a) shall remain available without fiscal year limitation until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 264</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1699</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21025.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports by recipients</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002013">1</ref> 6 months after the end of each fiscal year for which an eligible State or eligible unit of local government received a payment under this subpart, the State or unit shall submit a report to the Secretary on the activities conducted with the funds provided during the year, and shall include in the report a list of expenditures made with respect to each category of activities described in <ref>section 21021(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report by Secretary to Committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to each fiscal year for which the Secretary makes payments under this subpart, the Secretary shall submit a report on the activities carried out under this subpart to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 265</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1699</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 3—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">grants for research on voting technology improvements</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21041.</num>
<heading> Grants for research on voting technology improvements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall make grants to assist entities in carrying out research and development to improve the quality, reliability, accuracy, accessibility, affordability, and security of voting equipment, election systems, and voting technology.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An entity is eligible to receive a grant under this subpart if it submits to the Commission (at such time and in such form as the Commission may require) an application containing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> certifications that the research and development funded with the grant will take into account the need to make voting equipment fully accessible for individuals with disabilities, including the blind and visually impaired, the need to ensure that such individuals can vote independently and with privacy, and the need to provide alternative language accessibility for individuals with limited proficiency in the English language (consistent with the requirements of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 [<ref>52 U.S.C. 10301</ref> et seq.]); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such other information and certifications as the Commission may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of regulations governing patent rights in inventions made with Federal assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any invention made by the recipient of a grant under this subpart using funds provided under this subpart shall be subject to chapter 18 of title 35 (relating to patent rights in inventions made with Federal assistance).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendation of topics for research</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Director”) shall submit to the Commission an annual list of the Director’s suggestions for issues which may be the subject of research funded with grants awarded under this subpart during the year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of grant applications received by Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall submit each application it receives for a grant under this subpart to the Director, who shall review the application and provide the Commission with such comments as the Director considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring and adjustment of grant activities at request of Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After the Commission has awarded a grant under this subpart, the Commission may request that the Director monitor the grant, and (to the extent permitted under the terms of the grant as awarded) the Director may recommend to the Commission that the recipient of the grant modify and adjust the activities carried out under the grant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation of grants at request of Commission</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a grant for which the Commission submits the application to the Director under paragraph (2) or requests that the Director monitor the grant under paragraph (3), the Director shall prepare and submit to the Commission an evaluation of the grant and the activities carried out under the grant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion in reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission shall include the evaluations submitted under subparagraph (A) for a year in the report submitted for the year under <ref>section 20927 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of information on projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may provide to the Technical Guidelines Development Committee under subpart 3 of part A of this subchapter such information regarding the activities funded under this subpart as the Commission deems necessary to assist the Committee in carrying out its duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 271</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1699</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21042.</num>
<heading> Report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each entity which receives a grant under this subpart shall submit to the Commission a report describing the activities carried out with the funds provided under the grant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An entity shall submit a report required under subsection (a) not later than 60 days after the end of the fiscal year for which the entity received the grant which is the subject of the report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 272</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21043.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for grants under this subpart $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2003.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization under this section shall remain available, without fiscal year limitation, until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 273</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 4—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">pilot program for testing of equipment and technology</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21051.</num>
<heading> Pilot program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall make grants to carry out pilot programs under which new technologies in voting systems and equipment are tested and implemented on a trial basis so that the results of such tests and trials are reported to Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An entity is eligible to receive a grant under this subpart if it submits to the Commission (at such time and in such form as the Commission may require) an application containing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> certifications that the pilot programs funded with the grant will take into account the need to make voting equipment fully accessible for individuals with disabilities, including the blind and visually impaired, the need to ensure that such individuals can vote independently and with privacy, and the need to provide alternative language accessibility for individuals with limited proficiency in the English language (consistent with the requirements of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 [<ref>52 U.S.C. 10301</ref> et seq.] and the requirements of this chapter); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such other information and certifications as the Commission may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendation of topics for pilot programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Director”) shall submit to the Commission an annual list of the Director’s suggestions for issues which may be the subject of pilot programs funded with grants awarded under this subpart during the year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of grant applications received by Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall submit each application it receives for a grant under this subpart to the Director, who shall review the application and provide the Commission with such comments as the Director considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring and adjustment of grant activities at request of Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After the Commission has awarded a grant under this subpart, the Commission may request that the Director monitor the grant, and (to the extent permitted under the terms of the grant as awarded) the Director may recommend to the Commission that the recipient of the grant modify and adjust the activities carried out under the grant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation of grants at request of Commission</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a grant for which the Commission submits the application to the Director under paragraph (2) or requests that the Director monitor the grant under paragraph (3), the Director shall prepare and submit to the Commission an evaluation of the grant and the activities carried out under the grant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion in reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Commission shall include the evaluations submitted under subparagraph (A) for a year in the report submitted for the year under <ref>section 20927 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of information on projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may provide to the Technical Guidelines Development Committee under subpart 3 of part A of this subchapter such information regarding the activities funded under this subpart as the Commission deems necessary to assist the Committee in carrying out its duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 281</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1701</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21052.</num>
<heading> Report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each entity which receives a grant under this subpart shall submit to the Commission a report describing the activities carried out with the funds provided under the grant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An entity shall submit a report required under subsection (a) not later than 60 days after the end of the fiscal year for which the entity received the grant which is the subject of the report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 282</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1702</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21053.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for grants under this subpart $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2003.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization under this section shall remain available, without fiscal year limitation, until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 283</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1702</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 5—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">protection and advocacy systems</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21061.</num>
<heading> Payments for protection and advocacy systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to any other payments made under this part, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall pay the protection and advocacy system (as defined in section 102 of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 15002</ref>)) of each State to ensure full participation in the electoral process for individuals with disabilities, including registering to vote, casting a vote and accessing polling places. In providing such services, protection and advocacy systems shall have the same general authorities as they are afforded under subtitle C of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 15041</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum grant amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The minimum amount of each grant to a protection and advocacy system shall be determined and allocated as set forth in subsections (c)(1)(B), (c)(3), (c)(4), (c)(5), (e), and (g) of <ref>section 794e of title 29</ref>, except that the amount of the grants to systems referred to in subsection (c)(3)(B) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002014">1</ref> shall not be less than $70,000, and the amount of the grants to systems referred to in subsections (c)(1)(B) and (c)(4) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002014">1</ref> shall not be less than $35,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible grant recipients</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the purposes of this section, the term “State” shall have the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 15002</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> American Indian consortium eligible</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A system serving the American Indian consortium for which funds have been reserved under <ref>section 794e(c)(1)(B) of title 29</ref> shall be eligible for payments under subsection (a) in the same manner as a protection and advocacy system of a State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training and technical assistance program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the initial appropriation of funds for a fiscal year is made pursuant to the authorization under <ref>section 21062 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall set aside 7 percent of the amount appropriated under such section and use such portion to make payments to eligible entities to provide training and technical assistance with respect to the activities carried out under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A recipient of a payment under this subsection may use the payment to support training in the use of voting systems and technologies, and to demonstrate and evaluate the use of such systems and technologies, by individuals with disabilities (including blindness) in order to assess the availability and use of such systems and technologies for such individuals. At least one of the recipients under this subsection shall use the payment to provide training and technical assistance for nonvisual access.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An entity is eligible to receive a payment under this subsection if the entity—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a public or private nonprofit entity with demonstrated experience in voting issues for individuals with disabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is governed by a board with respect to which the majority of its members are individuals with disabilities or family members of such individuals or individuals who are blind; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> submits to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 291</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1702</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–182, § 2</ref>, <date date="2022-09-30">Sept. 30, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2178</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21062.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to any other amounts authorized to be appropriated under this part, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2003, 2004, 2005, and 2006, and for each subsequent fiscal year such sums as may be necessary, for the purpose of making payments under <ref>section 21061(a) of this title</ref>; except that none of the funds provided by this subsection shall be used to initiate or otherwise participate in any litigation related to election-related disability access, notwithstanding the general authorities that the protection and advocacy systems are otherwise afforded under subtitle C of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 15041</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amounts appropriated pursuant to the authority of this section shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 292</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1703</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
<subpart>
<num class="small-caps">subpart 6—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">national student and parent mock election</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21071.</num>
<heading> National Student and Parent Mock Election</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Election Assistance Commission is authorized to award grants to the National Student and Parent Mock Election, a national nonprofit, nonpartisan organization that works to promote voter participation in American elections to enable it to carry out voter education activities for students and their parents. Such activities may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> include simulated national elections at least 5 days before the actual election that permit participation by students and parents from each of the 50 States in the United States, its territories, the District of Columbia, and United States schools overseas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> school forums and local cable call-in shows on the national issues to be voted upon in an “issues forum”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> speeches and debates before students and parents by local candidates or stand-ins for such candidates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> quiz team competitions, mock press conferences, and speech writing competitions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> weekly meetings to follow the course of the campaign; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> school and neighborhood campaigns to increase voter turnout, including newsletters, posters, telephone chains, and transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The National Student and Parent Mock Election shall present awards to outstanding student and parent mock election projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 295</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1703</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21072.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this part $200,000 for fiscal year 2003 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the 6 succeeding fiscal years.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 296</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1704</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subpart>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>UNIFORM AND NONDISCRIMINATORY ELECTION TECHNOLOGY AND ADMINISTRATION REQUIREMENTS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Requirements</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21081.</num>
<heading> Voting systems standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each voting system used in an election for Federal office shall meet the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the voting system (including any lever voting system, optical scanning voting system, or direct recording electronic system) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> permit the voter to verify (in a private and independent manner) the votes selected by the voter on the ballot before the ballot is cast and counted;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide the voter with the opportunity (in a private and independent manner) to change the ballot or correct any error before the ballot is cast and counted (including the opportunity to correct the error through the issuance of a replacement ballot if the voter was otherwise unable to change the ballot or correct any error); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> if the voter selects votes for more than one candidate for a single office—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> notify the voter that the voter has selected more than one candidate for a single office on the ballot;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> notify the voter before the ballot is cast and counted of the effect of casting multiple votes for the office; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> provide the voter with the opportunity to correct the ballot before the ballot is cast and counted.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A State or jurisdiction that uses a paper ballot voting system, a punch card voting system, or a central count voting system (including mail-in absentee ballots and mail-in ballots), may meet the requirements of subparagraph (A)(iii) by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> establishing a voter education program specific to that voting system that notifies each voter of the effect of casting multiple votes for an office; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> providing the voter with instructions on how to correct the ballot before it is cast and counted (including instructions on how to correct the error through the issuance of a replacement ballot if the voter was otherwise unable to change the ballot or correct any error).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The voting system shall ensure that any notification required under this paragraph preserves the privacy of the voter and the confidentiality of the ballot.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit capacity</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The voting system shall produce a record with an audit capacity for such system.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manual audit capacity</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The voting system shall produce a permanent paper record with a manual audit capacity for such system.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The voting system shall provide the voter with an opportunity to change the ballot or correct any error before the permanent paper record is produced.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The paper record produced under subparagraph (A) shall be available as an official record for any recount conducted with respect to any election in which the system is used.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accessibility for individuals with disabilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The voting system shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be accessible for individuals with disabilities, including nonvisual accessibility for the blind and visually impaired, in a manner that provides the same opportunity for access and participation (including privacy and independence) as for other voters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> satisfy the requirement of subparagraph (A) through the use of at least one direct recording electronic voting system or other voting system equipped for individuals with disabilities at each polling place; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if purchased with funds made available under subchapter II on or after <date date="2007-01-01">January 1, 2007</date>, meet the voting system standards for disability access (as outlined in this paragraph).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternative language accessibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The voting system shall provide alternative language accessibility pursuant to the requirements of <ref>section 10503 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Error rates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The error rate of the voting system in counting ballots (determined by taking into account only those errors which are attributable to the voting system and not attributable to an act of the voter) shall comply with the error rate standards established under section 3.2.1 of the voting systems standards issued by the Federal Election Commission which are in effect on <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uniform definition of what constitutes a vote</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each State shall adopt uniform and nondiscriminatory standards that define what constitutes a vote and what will be counted as a vote for each category of voting system used in the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting system defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “voting system” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the total combination of mechanical, electromechanical, or electronic equipment (including the software, firmware, and documentation required to program, control, and support the equipment) that is used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to define ballots;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to cast and count votes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to report or display election results; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to maintain and produce any audit trail information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the practices and associated documentation used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to identify system components and versions of such components;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to test the system during its development and maintenance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to maintain records of system errors and defects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to determine specific system changes to be made to a system after the initial qualification of the system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to make available any materials to the voter (such as notices, instructions, forms, or paper ballots).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit a State or jurisdiction which used a particular type of voting system in the elections for Federal office held in November 2000 from using the same type of system after the effective date of this section, so long as the system meets or is modified to meet the requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection of paper ballot voting systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of subsection (a)(1)(A)(i), the term “verify” may not be defined in a manner that makes it impossible for a paper ballot voting system to meet the requirements of such subsection or to be modified to meet such requirements.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each State and jurisdiction shall be required to comply with the requirements of this section on and after <date date="2006-01-01">January 1, 2006</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1704</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21082.</num>
<heading> Provisional voting and voting information requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provisional voting requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If an individual declares that such individual is a registered voter in the jurisdiction in which the individual desires to vote and that the individual is eligible to vote in an election for Federal office, but the name of the individual does not appear on the official list of eligible voters for the polling place or an election official asserts that the individual is not eligible to vote, such individual shall be permitted to cast a provisional ballot as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An election official at the polling place shall notify the individual that the individual may cast a provisional ballot in that election.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The individual shall be permitted to cast a provisional ballot at that polling place upon the execution of a written affirmation by the individual before an election official at the polling place stating that the individual is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a registered voter in the jurisdiction in which the individual desires to vote; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> eligible to vote in that election.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An election official at the polling place shall transmit the ballot cast by the individual or the voter information contained in the written affirmation executed by the individual under paragraph (2) to an appropriate State or local election official for prompt verification under paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If the appropriate State or local election official to whom the ballot or voter information is transmitted under paragraph (3) determines that the individual is eligible under State law to vote, the individual’s provisional ballot shall be counted as a vote in that election in accordance with State law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> At the time that an individual casts a provisional ballot, the appropriate State or local election official shall give the individual written information that states that any individual who casts a provisional ballot will be able to ascertain under the system established under subparagraph (B) whether the vote was counted, and, if the vote was not counted, the reason that the vote was not counted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The appropriate State or local election official shall establish a free access system (such as a toll-free telephone number or an Internet website) that any individual who casts a provisional ballot may access to discover whether the vote of that individual was counted, and, if the vote was not counted, the reason that the vote was not counted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">States described in <ref>section 20503(b) of this title</ref> may meet the requirements of this subsection using voter registration procedures established under applicable State law. The appropriate State or local official shall establish and maintain reasonable procedures necessary to protect the security, confidentiality, and integrity of personal information collected, stored, or otherwise used by the free access system established under paragraph (5)(B). Access to information about an individual provisional ballot shall be restricted to the individual who cast the ballot.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting information requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public posting on election day</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The appropriate State or local election official shall cause voting information to be publicly posted at each polling place on the day of each election for Federal office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting information defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this section, the term “voting information” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a sample version of the ballot that will be used for that election;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information regarding the date of the election and the hours during which polling places will be open;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> instructions on how to vote, including how to cast a vote and how to cast a provisional ballot;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> instructions for mail-in registrants and first-time voters under <ref>section 21083(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> general information on voting rights under applicable Federal and State laws, including information on the right of an individual to cast a provisional ballot and instructions on how to contact the appropriate officials if these rights are alleged to have been violated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> general information on Federal and State laws regarding prohibitions on acts of fraud and misrepresentation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voters who vote after the polls close</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any individual who votes in an election for Federal office as a result of a Federal or State court order or any other order extending the time established for closing the polls by a State law in effect 10 days before the date of that election may only vote in that election by casting a provisional ballot under subsection (a). Any such ballot cast under the preceding sentence shall be separated and held apart from other provisional ballots cast by those not affected by the order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date for provisional voting and voting information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each State and jurisdiction shall be required to comply with the requirements of this section on and after <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21083.</num>
<heading> Computerized statewide voter registration list requirements and requirements for voters who register by mail</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Computerized statewide voter registration list requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), each State, acting through the chief State election official, shall implement, in a uniform and nondiscriminatory manner, a single, uniform, official, centralized, interactive computerized statewide voter registration list defined, maintained, and administered at the State level that contains the name and registration information of every legally registered voter in the State and assigns a unique identifier to each legally registered voter in the State (in this subsection referred to as the “computerized list”), and includes the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The computerized list shall serve as the single system for storing and managing the official list of registered voters throughout the State.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The computerized list contains the name and registration information of every legally registered voter in the State.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Under the computerized list, a unique identifier is assigned to each legally registered voter in the State.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The computerized list shall be coordinated with other agency databases within the State.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> Any election official in the State, including any local election official, may obtain immediate electronic access to the information contained in the computerized list.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> All voter registration information obtained by any local election official in the State shall be electronically entered into the computerized list on an expedited basis at the time the information is provided to the local official.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> The chief State election official shall provide such support as may be required so that local election officials are able to enter information as described in clause (vi).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> The computerized list shall serve as the official voter registration list for the conduct of all elections for Federal office in the State.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The requirement under subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a State in which, under a State law in effect continuously on and after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, there is no voter registration requirement for individuals in the State with respect to elections for Federal office.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Computerized list maintenance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The appropriate State or local election official shall perform list maintenance with respect to the computerized list on a regular basis as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> If an individual is to be removed from the computerized list, such individual shall be removed in accordance with the provisions of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg</ref> et seq.) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20501</ref> et seq.], including subsections (a)(4), (c)(2), (d), and (e) of section 8 of such Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg–6</ref>) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20507</ref>].</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of removing names of ineligible voters from the official list of eligible voters—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> under section 8(a)(3)(B) of such Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg–6(a)(3)(B)</ref>) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20507(a)(3)(B)</ref>], the State shall coordinate the computerized list with State agency records on felony status; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> by reason of the death of the registrant under section 8(a)(4)(A) of such Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg–6(a)(4)(A)</ref>) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20507(a)(4)(A)</ref>], the State shall coordinate the computerized list with State agency records on death.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this subparagraph, if a State is described in section 4(b) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg–2(b)</ref>) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20503(b)</ref>], that State shall remove the names of ineligible voters from the computerized list in accordance with State law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conduct</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The list maintenance performed under subparagraph (A) shall be conducted in a manner that ensures that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the name of each registered voter appears in the computerized list;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> only voters who are not registered or who are not eligible to vote are removed from the computerized list; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> duplicate names are eliminated from the computerized list.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technological security of computerized list</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The appropriate State or local official shall provide adequate technological security measures to prevent the unauthorized access to the computerized list established under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum standard for accuracy of State voter registration records</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The State election system shall include provisions to ensure that voter registration records in the State are accurate and are updated regularly, including the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A system of file maintenance that makes a reasonable effort to remove registrants who are ineligible to vote from the official list of eligible voters. Under such system, consistent with the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg</ref> et seq.) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20501</ref> et seq.], registrants who have not responded to a notice and who have not voted in 2 consecutive general elections for Federal office shall be removed from the official list of eligible voters, except that no registrant may be removed solely by reason of a failure to vote.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Safeguards to ensure that eligible voters are not removed in error from the official list of eligible voters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Verification of voter registration information</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requiring provision of certain information by applicants</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Except as provided in clause (ii), notwithstanding any other provision of law, an application for voter registration for an election for Federal office may not be accepted or processed by a State unless the application includes—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> in the case of an applicant who has been issued a current and valid driver’s license, the applicant’s driver’s license number; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in the case of any other applicant (other than an applicant to whom clause (ii) applies), the last 4 digits of the applicant’s social security number.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for applicants without driver’s license or social security number</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If an applicant for voter registration for an election for Federal office has not been issued a current and valid driver’s license or a social security number, the State shall assign the applicant a number which will serve to identify the applicant for voter registration purposes. To the extent that the State has a computerized list in effect under this subsection and the list assigns unique identifying numbers to registrants, the number assigned under this clause shall be the unique identifying number assigned under the list.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of validity of numbers provided</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The State shall determine whether the information provided by an individual is sufficient to meet the requirements of this subparagraph, in accordance with State law.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for State officials</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sharing information in databases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The chief State election official and the official responsible for the State motor vehicle authority of a State shall enter into an agreement to match information in the database of the statewide voter registration system with information in the database of the motor vehicle authority to the extent required to enable each such official to verify the accuracy of the information provided on applications for voter registration.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements with Commissioner of Social Security</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The official responsible for the State motor vehicle authority shall enter into an agreement with the Commissioner of Social Security under section 405(r)(8) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002015">1</ref> of title 42 (as added by subparagraph (C)).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a State which is permitted to use social security numbers, and provides for the use of social security numbers, on applications for voter registration, in accordance with section 7 of the Privacy Act of 1974 (<ref>5 U.S.C. 552a</ref> note), the provisions of this paragraph shall be optional.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for voters who register by mail</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding section 6(c) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg–4(c)</ref>) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20505(c)</ref>] and subject to paragraph (3), a State shall, in a uniform and nondiscriminatory manner, require an individual to meet the requirements of paragraph (2) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the individual registered to vote in a jurisdiction by mail; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the individual has not previously voted in an election for Federal office in the State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the individual has not previously voted in such an election in the jurisdiction and the jurisdiction is located in a State that does not have a computerized list that complies with the requirements of subsection (a).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An individual meets the requirements of this paragraph if the individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an individual who votes in person—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> presents to the appropriate State or local election official a current and valid photo identification; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> presents to the appropriate State or local election official a copy of a current utility bill, bank statement, government check, paycheck, or other government document that shows the name and address of the voter; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an individual who votes by mail, submits with the ballot—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a copy of a current and valid photo identification; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a copy of a current utility bill, bank statement, government check, paycheck, or other government document that shows the name and address of the voter.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fail-safe voting</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">An individual who desires to vote in person, but who does not meet the requirements of subparagraph (A)(i), may cast a provisional ballot under <ref>section 21082(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> By mail</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">An individual who desires to vote by mail but who does not meet the requirements of subparagraph (A)(ii) may cast such a ballot by mail and the ballot shall be counted as a provisional ballot in accordance with <ref>section 21082(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inapplicability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of a person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> who registers to vote by mail under section 6 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg–4</ref>) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20505</ref>] and submits as part of such registration either—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a copy of a current and valid photo identification; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a copy of a current utility bill, bank statement, government check, paycheck, or government document that shows the name and address of the voter;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> who registers to vote by mail under section 6 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg–4</ref>) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20505</ref>] and submits with such registration either—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a driver’s license number; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> at least the last 4 digits of the individual’s social security number; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with respect to whom a State or local election official matches the information submitted under clause (i) with an existing State identification record bearing the same number, name and date of birth as provided in such registration; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> who is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> entitled to vote by absentee ballot under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act [<ref>52 U.S.C. 20301</ref> et seq.];</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provided the right to vote otherwise than in person under <ref>section 20102(b)(2)(B)(ii) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> entitled to vote otherwise than in person under any other Federal law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of mail-in registration form</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The mail voter registration form developed under section 6 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg–4</ref>) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20505</ref>] shall include the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The question “Are you a citizen of the United States of America?” and boxes for the applicant to check to indicate whether the applicant is or is not a citizen of the United States.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The question “Will you be 18 years of age on or before election day?” and boxes for the applicant to check to indicate whether or not the applicant will be 18 years of age or older on election day.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The statement “If you checked ‘no’ in response to either of these questions, do not complete this form.”.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> A statement informing the individual that if the form is submitted by mail and the individual is registering for the first time, the appropriate information required under this section must be submitted with the mail-in registration form in order to avoid the additional identification requirements upon voting for the first time.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incomplete forms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If an applicant for voter registration fails to answer the question included on the mail voter registration form pursuant to subparagraph (A)(i), the registrar shall notify the applicant of the failure and provide the applicant with an opportunity to complete the form in a timely manner to allow for the completion of the registration form prior to the next election for Federal office (subject to State law).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require a State that was not required to comply with a provision of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg</ref> et seq.) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20501</ref> et seq.] before <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, to comply with such a provision after <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permitted use of last 4 digits of social security numbers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The last 4 digits of a social security number described in subsections (a)(5)(A)(i)(II) and (b)(3)(B)(i)(II) shall not be considered to be a social security number for purposes of section 7 of the Privacy Act of 1974 (<ref>5 U.S.C. 552a</ref> note).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Computerized statewide voter registration list requirements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), each State and jurisdiction shall be required to comply with the requirements of subsection (a) on and after <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a State or jurisdiction certifies to the Commission not later than <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>, that the State or jurisdiction will not meet the deadline described in subparagraph (A) for good cause and includes in the certification the reasons for the failure to meet such deadline, subparagraph (A) shall apply to the State or jurisdiction as if the reference in such subparagraph to “<date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>” were a reference to “<date date="2006-01-01">January 1, 2006</date>”.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for voters who register by mail</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each State and jurisdiction shall be required to comply with the requirements of subsection (b) on and after <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>, and shall be prepared to receive registration materials submitted by individuals described in subparagraph (B) on and after the date described in such subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability with respect to individuals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The provisions of subsection (b) shall apply to any individual who registers to vote on or after <date date="2003-01-01">January 1, 2003</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21083a.</num>
<heading> Access for congressional election observers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finding of constitutional authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress finds that, regardless of legislative action, it has the authority to send congressional election observers to observe polling locations, any location where processing, scanning, tabulating, canvassing, recounting, auditing, or certifying voting results is occurring, or any other part of the process associated with elections for Federal office under the authorities granted under article 1, section 5, clause 1 and article 1, section 4, clause 1 of the Constitution of the United States. Procedures described herein do not establish any new authorities or procedures with respect to Congress’ constitutional authority to observe congressional elections but are provided simply to permit a convenient statutory reference for existing congressional authority and activity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requiring States to provide access for observers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A State shall provide each individual who is acting as a designated congressional election observer for an election for Federal office with full access to clearly observe all elements of election administration procedures, including, but not limited to, access to any area in which a ballot is cast, processed, scanned, tabulated, canvassed, recounted, audited, or certified, including during pre- and post-election procedures.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on activities of observers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No designated congressional election observer may handle a ballot or election equipment (whether voting or nonvoting or whether tabulating or nontabulating), advocate for any position or candidate, take any action to reduce ballot secrecy or voter privacy, take any action to interfere with the ability of a voter to cast a ballot or an election administrator to carry the administrator’s duties, or otherwise interfere with the election administration process.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall prohibit a designated congressional election observer from asking questions of an election administrator, election official, or election worker, or any other State or local official.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conduct of observers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization removal by election official</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a State or local election official has a reasonable basis to believe that a designated congressional election observer has engaged in or imminently will engage in intimidation or deceptive practices prohibited by Federal law, or in the disruption of voting, processing, scanning, tabulating, canvassing, or recounting of ballots, or the certification of results, a State or local election official may remove that observer from the area involved.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice to Committee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If a designated congressional election observer is removed from an area under subparagraph (A), the election official shall, within 24 hours of the observer’s removal—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> inform the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, as applicable; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide written notice detailing the reason or reasons the designated congressional election observer was removed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the mere presence of a designated congressional election observer during an observation of election administration procedures, without any additional indicia supporting a reasonable basis for removal, is not a sufficient reason for removal under paragraph (1)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right to replace observer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a designated congressional election observer is properly removed under paragraph (1)(A), the chair or ranking minority member of the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, as appropriate, may send another designated congressional election observer as a replacement for the remaining duration of the observation of election administration procedures.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designated congressional election observer described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, a “designated congressional election observer” is a House or Senate employee who is designated in writing by the chair or ranking minority member of the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, or a successor committee, to gather information with respect to an election, including in the event that the election is contested in the House of Representatives or the Senate and for other purposes permitted by article 1, section 5, clause 1 and article 1, section 4, clause 1 of the Constitution of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “State” means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title III, § 304</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 118–106, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-10-04">Oct. 4, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1591</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21084.</num>
<heading> Minimum requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The requirements established by this subchapter are minimum requirements and nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to prevent a State from establishing election technology and administration requirements that are more strict than the requirements established under this subchapter so long as such State requirements are not inconsistent with the Federal requirements under this subchapter or any law described in <ref>section 21145 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title III, § 305</ref>, formerly § 304, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1714</ref>; renumbered § 305, <ref>Pub. L. 118–106, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-10-04">Oct. 4, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1591</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21085.</num>
<heading> Methods of implementation left to discretion of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The specific choices on the methods of complying with the requirements of this subchapter shall be left to the discretion of the State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title III, § 306</ref>, formerly § 305, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1714</ref>; renumbered § 306, <ref>Pub. L. 118–106, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-10-04">Oct. 4, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1591</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Voluntary Guidance</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21101.</num>
<heading> Adoption of voluntary guidance by Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To assist States in meeting the requirements of part A of this subchapter, the Commission shall adopt voluntary guidance consistent with such requirements in accordance with the procedures described in <ref>section 21102 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadlines</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall adopt the recommendations under this section not later than—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of the recommendations with respect to <ref>section 21081 of this title</ref>, <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of the recommendations with respect to <ref>section 21082 of this title</ref>, <date date="2003-10-01">October 1, 2003</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of the recommendations with respect to <ref>section 21083 of this title</ref>, <date date="2003-10-01">October 1, 2003</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quadrennial update</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall review and update recommendations adopted with respect to <ref>section 21081 of this title</ref> no less frequently than once every 4 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1715</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21102.</num>
<heading> Process for adoption</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The adoption of the voluntary guidance under this part shall be carried out by the Commission in a manner that provides for each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Publication of notice of the proposed recommendations in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An opportunity for public comment on the proposed recommendations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An opportunity for a public hearing on the record.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Publication of the final recommendations in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1715</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>ENFORCEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21111.</num>
<heading> Actions by the Attorney General for declaratory and injunctive relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may bring a civil action against any State or jurisdiction in an appropriate United States District Court for such declaratory and injunctive relief (including a temporary restraining order, a permanent or temporary injunction, or other order) as may be necessary to carry out the uniform and nondiscriminatory election technology and administration requirements under sections 21081, 21082, 21083, and 21083a of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1715</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–106, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-10-04">Oct. 4, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21112.</num>
<heading> Establishment of State-based administrative complaint procedures to remedy grievances</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of State-based administrative complaint procedures to remedy grievances</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of procedures as condition of receiving funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a State receives any payment under a program under this chapter, the State shall be required to establish and maintain State-based administrative complaint procedures which meet the requirements of paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for procedures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The requirements of this paragraph are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The procedures shall be uniform and nondiscriminatory.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Under the procedures, any person who believes that there is a violation of any provision of subchapter III (including a violation which has occurred, is occurring, or is about to occur) may file a complaint.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any complaint filed under the procedures shall be in writing and notarized, and signed and sworn by the person filing the complaint.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The State may consolidate complaints filed under subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> At the request of the complainant, there shall be a hearing on the record.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> If, under the procedures, the State determines that there is a violation of any provision of subchapter III, the State shall provide the appropriate remedy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> If, under the procedures, the State determines that there is no violation, the State shall dismiss the complaint and publish the results of the procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The State shall make a final determination with respect to a complaint prior to the expiration of the 90-day period which begins on the date the complaint is filed, unless the complainant consents to a longer period for making such a determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> If the State fails to meet the deadline applicable under subparagraph (H), the complaint shall be resolved within 60 days under alternative dispute resolution procedures established for purposes of this section. The record and other materials from any proceedings conducted under the complaint procedures established under this section shall be made available for use under the alternative dispute resolution procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requiring Attorney General approval of compliance plan for States not receiving funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>, each nonparticipating State shall elect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to certify to the Commission that the State meets the requirements of subsection (a) in the same manner as a State receiving a payment under this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to submit a compliance plan to the Attorney General which provides detailed information on the steps the State will take to ensure that it meets the requirements of subchapter III.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> States without approved plan deemed out of compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A nonparticipating State (other than a State which makes the election described in paragraph (1)(A)) shall be deemed to not meet the requirements of subchapter III if the Attorney General has not approved a compliance plan submitted by the State under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonparticipating State defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this section, a “nonparticipating State” is a State which, during 2003, does not notify any office which is responsible for making payments to States under any program under this chapter of its intent to participate in, and receive funds under, the program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1715</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>HELP AMERICA VOTE COLLEGE PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21121.</num>
<heading> Establishment of program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after the appointment of its members, the Election Assistance Commission shall develop a program to be known as the “Help America Vote College Program” (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Program”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes of Program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of the Program shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to encourage students enrolled at institutions of higher education (including community colleges) to assist State and local governments in the administration of elections by serving as nonpartisan poll workers or assistants; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to encourage State and local governments to use the services of the students participating in the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21122.</num>
<heading> Activities under Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out the Program, the Commission (in consultation with the chief election official of each State) shall develop materials, sponsor seminars and workshops, engage in advertising targeted at students, make grants, and take such other actions as it considers appropriate to meet the purposes described in <ref>section 21121(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for grant recipients</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making grants under the Program, the Commission shall ensure that the funds provided are spent for projects and activities which are carried out without partisan bias or without promoting any particular point of view regarding any issue, and that each recipient is governed in a balanced manner which does not reflect any partisan bias.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with institutions of higher education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall encourage institutions of higher education (including community colleges) to participate in the Program, and shall make all necessary materials and other assistance (including materials and assistance to enable the institution to hold workshops and poll worker training sessions) available without charge to any institution which desires to participate in the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21123.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to any funds authorized to be appropriated to the Commission under <ref>section 20930 of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2003; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such sums as may be necessary for each succeeding fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1717</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>TRANSFER TO COMMISSION OF FUNCTIONS UNDER CERTAIN LAWS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21131.</num>
<heading> Transfer of functions of Office of Election Administration of Federal Election Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are transferred to the Election Assistance Commission established under <ref>section 20921 of this title</ref> all functions which the Office of Election Administration, established within the Federal Election Commission, exercised before <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title VIII, § 801(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1725</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21132.</num>
<heading> Transfer of functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are transferred to the Election Assistance Commission established under <ref>section 20921 of this title</ref> all functions which the Federal Election Commission exercised under <ref>section 20508(a) of this title</ref> before <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title VIII, § 802(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1726</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21133.</num>
<heading> Transfer of property, records, and personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property and records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The contracts, liabilities, records, property, and other assets and interests of, or made available in connection with, the offices and functions of the Federal Election Commission which are transferred by this subchapter are transferred to the Election Assistance Commission for appropriate allocation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The personnel employed in connection with the offices and functions of the Federal Election Commission which are transferred by this subchapter are transferred to the Election Assistance Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any full-time or part-time personnel employed in permanent positions shall not be separated or reduced in grade or compensation because of the transfer under this subsection during the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1726</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21134.</num>
<heading> Effective date; transition</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter and the amendments made by this subchapter shall take effect upon the appointment of all members of the Election Assistance Commission under <ref>section 20923 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With the consent of the entity involved, the Election Assistance Commission is authorized to utilize the services of such officers, employees, and other personnel of the entities from which functions have been transferred to the Election Assistance Commission under this subchapter or the amendments made by this subchapter for such period of time as may reasonably be needed to facilitate the orderly transfer of such functions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No effect on authorities of Office of Election Administration prior to appointment of members of Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During the period which begins on <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>, and ends on the effective date described in subsection (a), the Office of Election Administration of the Federal Election Commission shall continue to have the authority to carry out any of the functions (including the development of voluntary standards for voting systems and procedures for the certification of voting systems) which it has the authority to carry out as of <date date="2002-10-29">October 29, 2002</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title VIII, § 804</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1726</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 21141.</num>
<heading> “State” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, and the United States Virgin Islands.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21142.</num>
<heading> Audits and repayment of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recordkeeping requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each recipient of a grant or other payment made under this chapter shall keep such records with respect to the payment as are consistent with sound accounting principles, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of funds, the total cost of the project or undertaking for which such funds are used, and the amount of that portion of the cost of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audits and examinations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audits and examinations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (4), each office making a grant or other payment under this chapter, or any duly authorized representative of such office, may audit or examine any recipient of the grant or payment and shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipient which in the opinion of the entity may be related or pertinent to the grant or payment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recipients of assistance subject to provisions of section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of this section shall apply to all recipients of grants or other payments under this chapter, whether by direct grant, cooperative agreement, or contract under this chapter or by subgrant or subcontract from primary grantees or contractors under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for payments by General Services Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to any grant or payment made under this chapter by the Administrator of General Services, the Election Assistance Commission shall be deemed to be the office making the grant or payment for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of grants or payments made under <ref>section 21001 of this title</ref>, audits and examinations conducted under paragraph (1) shall be performed on a regular basis (as determined by the Commission).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules for audits by the Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the audits described in paragraph (1), the Election Assistance Commission may conduct a special audit or special examination of a recipient described in paragraph (1) upon a vote of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recoupment of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Comptroller General determines as a result of an audit conducted under subsection (b) prior to <date date="2014-11-26">November 26, 2014</date>, that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a recipient of funds under this chapter is not in compliance with each of the requirements of the program under which the funds are provided; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an excess payment has been made to the recipient under the program,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the recipient shall pay to the office which made the grant or payment involved a portion of the funds provided which reflects the proportion of the requirements with which the recipient is not in compliance, or the extent to which the payment is in excess, under the program involved.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title IX, § 902</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–188, title IX, § 901(c)</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2020</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21143.</num>
<heading> Review and report on adequacy of existing electoral fraud statutes and penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General shall conduct a review of existing criminal statutes concerning election offenses to determine—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whether additional statutory offenses are needed to secure the use of the Internet for election purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whether existing penalties provide adequate punishment and deterrence with respect to such offenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall submit a report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and House of Representatives, the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives on the review conducted under subsection (a) together with such recommendations for legislative and administrative action as the Attorney General determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1729</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21144.</num>
<heading> Other criminal penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conspiracy to deprive voters of a fair election</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any individual who knowingly and willfully gives false information in registering or voting in violation of <ref>section 10307(c) of this title</ref>, or conspires with another to violate such section, shall be fined or imprisoned, or both, in accordance with such section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> False information in registering and voting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any individual who knowingly commits fraud or knowingly makes a false statement with respect to the naturalization, citizenry, or alien registry of such individual in violation of <ref>section 1015 of title 18</ref> shall be fined or imprisoned, or both, in accordance with such section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title IX, § 905</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1729</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21145.</num>
<heading> No effect on other laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as specifically provided in <ref>section 21083(b) of this title</ref> with regard to the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg</ref> et seq.) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20501</ref> et seq.], nothing in this chapter may be construed to authorize or require conduct prohibited under any of the following laws, or to supersede, restrict, or limit the application of such laws:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973</ref> et seq.) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 10301</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Voting Accessibility for the Elderly and Handicapped Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973ee</ref> et seq.) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20101</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973ff</ref> et seq.) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20301</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973gg</ref> et seq.) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 20501</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No effect on preclearance or other requirements under Voting Rights Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The approval by the Administrator or the Commission of a payment or grant application under subchapter I or subchapter II, or any other action taken by the Commission or a State under such subchapter, shall not be considered to have any effect on requirements for preclearance under section 5 of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973c</ref>) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 10304</ref>] or any other requirements of such Act [<ref>52 U.S.C. 10301</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title IX, § 906</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1729</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>