<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 201—</num>
<heading>VOTING ACCESSIBILITY FOR THE ELDERLY AND HANDICAPPED</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 20101.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the intention of Congress in enacting this chapter to promote the fundamental right to vote by improving access for handicapped and elderly individuals to registration facilities and polling places for Federal elections.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–435, § 2</ref>, <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20102.</num>
<heading> Selection of polling facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accessibility to all polling places as responsibility of each political subdivision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within each State, except as provided in subsection (b), each political subdivision responsible for conducting elections shall assure that all polling places for Federal elections are accessible to handicapped and elderly voters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply to a polling place—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of an emergency, as determined by the chief election officer of the State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> if the chief election officer of the State—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determines that all potential polling places have been surveyed and no such accessible place is available, nor is the political subdivision able to make one temporarily accessible, in the area involved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> assures that any handicapped or elderly voter assigned to an inaccessible polling place, upon advance request of such voter (pursuant to procedures established by the chief election officer of the State)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> will be assigned to an accessible polling place, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> will be provided with an alternative means for casting a ballot on the day of the election.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Federal Election Commission</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than December 31 of each even-numbered year, the chief election officer of each State shall report to the Federal Election Commission, in a manner to be determined by the Commission, the number of accessible and inaccessible polling places in such State on the date of the preceding general Federal election, and the reasons for any instance of inaccessibility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than April 30 of each odd-numbered year, the Federal Election Commission shall compile the information reported under paragraph (1) and shall transmit that information to the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The provisions of this subsection shall only be effective for a period of 10 years beginning on <date date="1984-09-28">September 28, 1984</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–435, § 3</ref>, <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1678</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20103.</num>
<heading> Selection of registration facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each State or political subdivision responsible for registration for Federal elections shall provide a reasonable number of accessible permanent registration facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) does not apply to any State that has in effect a system that provides an opportunity for each potential voter to register by mail or at the residence of such voter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–435, § 4</ref>, <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20104.</num>
<heading> Registration and voting aids</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Printed instructions; telecommunications devices for the deaf</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each State shall make available registration and voting aids for Federal elections for handicapped and elderly individuals, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> instructions, printed in large type, conspicuously displayed at each permanent registration facility and each polling place; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> information by telecommunications devices for the deaf.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Medical certification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No notarization or medical certification shall be required of a handicapped voter with respect to an absentee ballot or an application for such ballot, except that medical certification may be required when the certification establishes eligibility, under State law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to automatically receive an application or a ballot on a continuing basis; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to apply for an absentee ballot after the deadline has passed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of availability of aids</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chief election officer of each State shall provide public notice, calculated to reach elderly and handicapped voters, of the availability of aids under this section, assistance under <ref>section 10508 of this title</ref>, and the procedures for voting by absentee ballot, not later than general public notice of registration and voting is provided.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–435, § 5</ref>, <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20105.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action for declaratory or injunctive relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a State or political subdivision does not comply with this chapter, the United States Attorney General or a person who is personally aggrieved by the noncompliance may bring an action for declaratory or injunctive relief in the appropriate district court.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prerequisite notice of noncompliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An action may be brought under this section only if the plaintiff notifies the chief election officer of the State of the noncompliance and a period of 45 days has elapsed since the date of notification.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorney fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no award of attorney fees may be made with respect to an action under this section, except in any action brought to enforce the original judgment of the court.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–435, § 6</ref>, <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20106.</num>
<heading> Relationship to Voting Rights Act of 1965</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall not be construed to impair any right guaranteed by the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 1973</ref> et seq.) [now <ref>52 U.S.C. 10301</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–435, § 7</ref>, <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20107.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “accessible” means accessible to handicapped and elderly individuals for the purpose of voting or registration, as determined under guidelines established by the chief election officer of the State involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “elderly” means 65 years of age or older;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Federal election” means a general, special, primary, or runoff election for the office of President or Vice President, or of Senator or Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “handicapped” means having a temporary or permanent physical disability; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possesssion <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref> of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–435, § 8</ref>, <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>