<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1—</num>
<heading>NAVY HOSPITALS, ARMY AND NAVY HOSPITAL, AND HOSPITAL RELIEF FOR SEAMEN AND OTHERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1, 2.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XIII, § 1313, <ref>58 Stat. 714</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 3 to 5.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 15, 1943, ch. 125, § 3</ref>, <ref>57 Stat. 153</ref>, eff. <date date="1943-07-01">July 1, 1943</date></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6.</num>
<heading> Pension paid to fund for benefit of naval hospital</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever any officer, seaman, or marine entitled to a pension is admitted to a naval hospital, his pension, while he remains there, shall be deducted from his accounts and paid to the Secretary of the Navy for the benefit of the fund from which such hospital is maintained.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 4813; <ref>May 4, 1898, ch. 234</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 377</ref>; <ref>Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 421</ref>, <ref>30 Stat. 1027</ref>; <ref>June 30, 1914, ch. 130</ref>, <ref>38 Stat. 398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6a.</num>
<heading> Disposition of amounts deducted from pensions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Pensions of inmates of a naval hospital, required by law prior to <date date="1943-07-01">July 1, 1943</date>, to be deducted from the account of the pensioner and applied for the benefit of the fund from which such home or <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002000">1</ref> hospital is maintained, shall be deposited into the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 15, 1943, ch. 125, § 3</ref>, <ref>57 Stat. 153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XV, § 1533(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 7 to 12.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XIII, § 1313, <ref>58 Stat. 714</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13.</num>
<heading> Admission of cases for study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There may be admitted into marine hospitals for study persons with infectious or other diseases affecting the public health, and not to exceed ten cases in any one hospital at one time.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 5, 1920, ch. 235, § 1</ref>, <ref>41 Stat. 884</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Navy hospitals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy shall procure at suitable places proper sites for Navy hospitals, and if the necessary buildings are not procured with the site, shall cause such to be erected, having due regard to economy, and giving preference to such plans as with most convenience and least cost will admit of subsequent additions, when the funds permit and circumstances require; and shall provide, at one of the establishments, a permanent asylum for disabled and decrepit Navy officers, seamen, and marines: <i>Provided</i>, That no sites shall be procured or hospital buildings erected or extensions to existing hospitals made unless authorized by Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 4810; <ref>Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 148</ref>, <ref>37 Stat. 902</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 14a.</num>
<heading> Annual appropriations for maintenance, operation, and improvement of naval hospitals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Commencing with the fiscal year 1944, annual appropriations in such amounts as may be necessary are authorized from the general fund of the Treasury for the maintenance, operation, and improvement of naval hospitals.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 15, 1943, ch. 125, § 1(c)</ref>, <ref>57 Stat. 152</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 15.</num>
<heading> Superintendence of Navy hospitals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy shall have the general charge and superintendence of Navy hospitals.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 4807.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16.</num>
<heading> Allowance of rations to Navy hospitals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For every Navy officer, seaman, or marine admitted into a Navy hospital, the institution shall be allowed one ration per day during his continuance therein, to be deducted from the account of the United States with such officer, seaman, or marine.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 4812.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 16a.</num>
<heading> Additional personnel for patients of Department of Veterans Affairs in naval hospitals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="1945-05-29">May 29, 1945</date>, additional commissioned, warranted, appointed, enlisted, and civilian personnel of the Medical Department of the Navy, required for the care of patients of the Department of Veterans Affairs in naval hospitals, may be employed in addition to the numbers annually appropriated for.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 29, 1945, ch. 130, § 1</ref>, <ref>59 Stat. 208</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 13(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 276</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 17.</num>
<heading> Government of Naval Asylum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The asylum for disabled and decrepit Navy officers, seamen, and marines shall be governed in accordance with the rules and regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 4811.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 18.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations for Army and Navy Hospital</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Army and Navy General Hospital at Hot Springs, Arkansas, shall be subject to such rules, regulations, and restrictions as shall be provided by the President of the United States and shall remain under the jurisdiction and control of the Department of the Army.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 30, 1882, ch. 254, § 1</ref>, <ref>22 Stat. 121</ref>; <ref>June 18, 1930, ch. 525, § 2</ref>, <ref>46 Stat. 781</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 19.</num>
<heading> Tubercular hospital at Fort Bayard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The hospital at Fort Bayard, New Mexico, for the treatment of tuberculosis, shall be opened to the treatment of the officers and men of the Navy and Marine Corps.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 2, 1907, ch. 2511</ref>, <ref>34 Stat. 1172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 20.</num>
<heading> Discipline of patients at Army and Navy Hospital</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All persons admitted to treatment in the Army and Navy General Hospital at Hot Springs, Arkansas, shall, while patients in said hospital, be subject to the rules and articles for the government of the armies of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 3, 1909, ch. 252</ref>, <ref>35 Stat. 748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 21.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 12, 1948, ch. 450, § 4</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 380</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 21a to 25.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XV, § 1532(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1732</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 26 to 28.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XIII, § 1313, <ref>58 Stat. 714</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 29, 29a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 1(45)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 703</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 30.</num>
<heading> Payments to donors of blood for persons undergoing treatment at Government expense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person, whether or not in the employ of the United States, who shall furnish blood from his or her veins for transfusion into the veins of a person entitled to and undergoing treatment at Government expense, whether in a Federal hospital or institution or in a civilian hospital or institution, or who shall furnish blood for blood banks or for other scientific and research purposes in connection with the care of any person entitled to treatment at Government expense, shall be entitled to be paid therefor such reasonable sum, not to exceed $50, for each blood withdrawal as may be determined by the head of the department or independent agency concerned, from public funds available to such department or independent agency for medical and hospital supplies: <i>Provided</i>, That no payment shall be made under this authority to any person for blood withdrawn for the benefit of the person from whom it is withdrawn.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Feb. 9, 1927, ch. 91</ref>, <ref>44 Stat. 1066</ref>; <ref>June 2, 1939, ch. 173</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 803</ref>; <ref>July 30, 1941, ch. 332</ref>, <ref>55 Stat. 609</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 31.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 641</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 32, 33.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 7, 1956, ch. 374, § 306(2)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 254</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 34.</num>
<heading> Hospitalization of persons outside continental limits of United States; persons entitled; availability of other facilities; rate of charges; disposition of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to those persons, including the dependents of naval and Marine Corps personnel, now authorized to receive hospitalization at naval hospitals, hospitalization and dispensary service may be provided at naval hospitals and dispensaries outside of the continental limits of the United States and in Alaska, to the officers and employees of any department or agency of the Federal Government, to employees of a contractor with the United States or his subcontractor, to the dependents of such persons, and in emergencies to such other persons as the Secretary of the Navy may prescribe: <i>Provided</i>, That such hospitalization and dispensary service to other than the dependents of naval and Marine Corps personnel shall be permitted only where facilities are not otherwise available in reasonably accessible and appropriate non-Federal hospitals. The charge for hospitalization or dispensary service for persons other than dependents of naval and Marine Corps personnel as specified in this section shall be at such rates as the President shall from time to time prescribe, and shall be deposited as provided in section 32 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002001">1</ref> of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 10, 1943, ch. 95, § 4</ref>, <ref>57 Stat. 81</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 35.</num>
<heading> Limitation of medical, surgical or hospital services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Hospitalization of the dependents of naval and Marine Corps personnel and of the persons outside the naval service mentioned in <ref>section 34 of this title</ref> shall be furnished only for acute medical and surgical conditions, exclusive of nervous, mental, or contagious diseases or those requiring domiciliary care. Routine dental care, other than dental prosthesis and orthodontia, may be furnished to such persons who are outside the naval service under the same conditions as are prescribed in <ref>section 34 of this title</ref> for hospital and dispensary care for such persons.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>May 10, 1943, ch. 95, § 5</ref>, <ref>57 Stat. 81</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–251, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 26</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 36.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 7, 1956, ch. 374, § 306(2)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 254</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 37.</num>
<heading> Manufacture of products by patients at naval hospitals; ownership of products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Navy is authorized to furnish materials for the manufacture or production by patients of products incident to the convalescence and rehabilitation of such patients in naval hospitals and other naval medical facilities, and ownership thereof shall be vested in the patients manufacturing or producing such products, except that the ownership of items manufactured or produced specifically for the use of a naval hospital or other naval medical facility shall be vested in the Government and such items shall be accounted for and disposed of accordingly.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 756, § 27</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 856</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>