<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 48—</num>
<heading>AGENCY PERSONNEL DEMONSTRATION PROJECT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4801.</num>
<heading> Nonapplicability of chapter 47</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Chapter 47 shall not apply to this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–123, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4802.</num>
<heading> Securities and Exchange Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In this section, the term “Commission” means the Securities and Exchange Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Commission may appoint and fix the compensation of such officers, attorneys, economists, examiners, and other employees as may be necessary for carrying out its functions under the securities laws as defined under section 3 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 78c</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Rates of basic pay for all employees of the Commission may be set and adjusted by the Commission without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 or subchapter III of chapter 53.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Commission may provide additional compensation and benefits to employees of the Commission if the same type of compensation or benefits are then being provided by any agency referred to under section 1206 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1833b</ref>) or, if not then being provided, could be provided by such an agency under applicable provisions of law, rule, or regulation. In setting and adjusting the total amount of compensation and benefits for employees, the Commission shall consult with, and seek to maintain comparability with, the agencies referred to under section 1206 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1833b</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Commission shall consult with the Office of Personnel Management in the implementation of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> This section shall be administered consistent with merit system principles.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–123, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2398</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>