<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 59—</num>
<heading>ALLOWANCES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>UNIFORMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5901.</num>
<heading> Uniform allowances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> There is authorized to be appropriated annually to each agency of the Government of the United States, including a Government owned corporation, and of the government of the District of Columbia, on a showing of necessity or desirability, such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subchapter. The head of the agency concerned, out of funds made available by the appropriation, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> furnish to each of these employees a uniform at a cost not to exceed $400 a year (or such higher maximum amount as the Office of Personnel Management may establish under section 5902); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> pay to each of these employees an allowance for a uniform not to exceed $400 a year (or such higher maximum amount as the Office of Personnel Management may establish under section 5902).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The allowance may be paid only at the times and in the amounts authorized by the regulations prescribed under <ref>section 5903 of this title</ref>. When the agency pays direct to the uniform vendor, the head of the agency may deduct a service charge of not more than 4 percent.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When the furnishing of a uniform or the payment of a uniform allowance is authorized under another statute or regulation existing on <date date="1954-09-01">September 1, 1954</date>, the head of the agency concerned may continue the furnishing of the uniform or the payment of the uniform allowance under that statute or regulation, but in that event a uniform may not be furnished or allowance paid under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An allowance paid under this section is not wages within the meaning of <ref>section 409 of title 42</ref> or chapters 21 and 24 of title 26.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(39)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 206</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title II, § 202(a)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1456; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(50)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5902.</num>
<heading> Increase in maximum uniform allowance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management may, from time to time, by regulation adjust the maximum amount for the cost of uniforms and the maximum allowance for uniforms under section 5901.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(40)(A)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 206</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title II, § 202(b)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1456.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5903.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management may prescribe such regulations as it considers necessary for the administration of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(40)(A)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 206</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 381</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title II, § 202(b)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1456.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>QUARTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5911.</num>
<heading> Quarters and facilities; employees in the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Government” means the Government of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “agency” means an Executive agency, but does not include the Tennessee Valley Authority;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “employee” means an employee of an agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “United States” means the several States, the District of Columbia, and the territories and possessions of the United States including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “quarters” means quarters owned or leased by the Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “facilities” means household furniture and equipment, garage space, utilities, subsistence, and laundry service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The head of an agency may provide, directly or by contract, an employee stationed in the United States with quarters and facilities, when conditions of employment or of availability of quarters warrant the action.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Rental rates for quarters provided for an employee under subsection (b) of this section or occupied on a rental basis by an employee or member of a uniformed service under any other provision of statute, and charges for facilities made available in connection with the occupancy of the quarters, shall be based on the reasonable value of the quarters and facilities to the employee or member concerned, in the circumstances under which the quarters and facilities are provided, occupied, or made available. The amounts of the rates and charges shall be paid by, or deducted from the pay of, the employee or member of a uniformed service, or otherwise charged against him in accordance with law. The amounts of payroll deductions for the rates and charges shall remain in the applicable appropriation or fund. When payment of the rates and charges is made by other than payroll deductions, the amounts of payment shall be credited to the Government as provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> When, as an incidental service in support of a program of the Government, quarters and facilities are provided by appropriate authority of the Government to an individual other than an employee or member of a uniformed service, the rates and charges therefor shall be determined in accordance with this section. The amounts of payment of the rates and charges shall be credited to the Government as provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The head of an agency may not require an employee or member of a uniformed service to occupy quarters on a rental basis, unless the agency head determines that necessary service cannot be rendered, or that property of the Government cannot adequately be protected, otherwise.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The President may prescribe regulations governing the provision, occupancy, and availability of quarters and facilities, the determination of rates and charges therefor, and other related matters, necessary and appropriate to carry out this section. The head of each agency may prescribe regulations, not inconsistent with the regulations of the President, necessary and appropriate to carry out the functions of the agency head under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Subsection (c) of this section does not repeal or modify any provision of statute authorizing the provision of quarters or facilities, either without charge or at rates or charges specifically fixed by statute.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<chapeau> A member of the uniformed service on a permanent change of duty station or temporary duty orders and occupying unaccompanied personnel housing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is exempt from the requirement of subsection (c) to pay a rental rate or charge based on the reasonable value of the quarters and facilities provided; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall pay such lesser rate or charge as the Secretary of Defense establishes by regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 508</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title VIII, § 809(c)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 681</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5912.</num>
<heading> Quarters in Government owned or rented buildings; employees in foreign countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the head of the agency concerned and approved by the President, an employee who is a citizen of the United States permanently stationed in a foreign country may be furnished, without cost to him, living quarters, including heat, fuel, and light, in a Government owned or rented building. The rented quarters may be furnished only within the limits of appropriations made therefor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5913.</num>
<heading> Official residence expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section, “agency” has the meaning given it by <ref>section 5721 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Under such regulations as the President may prescribe, funds available to an agency for administrative expenses may be allotted to posts in foreign countries to defray the unusual expenses incident to the operation and maintenance of official residences suitable for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the chief representatives of the United States at the posts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such other senior officials of the Government of the United States as the President may designate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Funds made available under subsection (b) may be provided in advance to persons eligible to receive reimbursements.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 510</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–140, § 7</ref>, <date date="2005-12-22">Dec. 22, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2652</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>OVERSEAS DIFFERENTIALS AND ALLOWANCES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5921.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Government” means the Government of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “agency” means an Executive agency and the Library of Congress, but does not include a Government controlled corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “employee” means an employee in or under an agency and more specifically defined by regulations prescribed by the President;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, means the several States and the District of Columbia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “continental United States” means the several States and the District of Columbia, but does not include Alaska or Hawaii; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> “foreign area” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other area outside the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Canal Zone, and territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 510</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5922.</num>
<heading> General provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding <ref>section 5536 of this title</ref> and except as otherwise provided by this subchapter, the allowances and differentials authorized by this subchapter may be granted to an employee officially stationed in a foreign area—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who is a citizen of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whose rate of basic pay is fixed by statute or, without taking into consideration the allowances and differentials provided by this subchapter, is fixed by administrative action pursuant to law or is fixed administratively in conformity with rates paid by the Government for work of a comparable level of difficulty and responsibility in the continental United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">To the extent authorized by a provision of statute other than this subchapter, the allowances and differentials provided by this subchapter may be paid to an employee officially stationed in a foreign area who is not a citizen of the United States.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Allowances granted under this subchapter may be paid in advance, or advance of funds may be made therefor, through the proper disbursing official in such sums as are considered advisable in consideration of the need and the period of time during which expenditures must be made in advance by the employee. An advance of funds not subsequently covered by allowances accrued to the employee under this subchapter is recoverable by the Government by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> setoff against accrued pay, compensation, amount of retirement credit, or other amount due the employee from the Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such other method as is provided by law for the recovery of amounts owing to the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The head of the agency concerned, under regulations of the President, may waive in whole or in part a right of recovery under this subsection, if it is shown that the recovery would be against equity and good conscience or against the public interest.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The allowances and differentials authorized by this subchapter shall be paid under regulations prescribed by the President governing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> payments of the allowances and differentials and the respective rates at which the payments are made;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the foreign areas, the groups of positions, and the categories of employees to which the rates apply; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> other related matters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> When a quarters allowance or allowance related to education under this subchapter, or quarters furnished in Government-owned or controlled buildings under section 5912, would be furnished to an employee but for the death of the employee, such allowances or quarters may be furnished or continued for the purpose of allowing any child of the employee to complete the current school year at post or away from post notwithstanding the employee’s death.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> When an allowance related to education away from post under this subchapter would be authorized with respect to an employee but for the evacuation or authorized departure status of the post, such an allowance may be furnished or continued for the purpose of allowing any dependent children of such employee to complete the current school year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If an employee dies at post in a foreign area, a transfer allowance under section 5924(2)(B) may be granted to the spouse or dependents of such employee (or both) for the purpose of providing for their return to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A transfer allowance under this subsection may not be granted with respect to the spouse or a dependent of the employee unless, at the time of death, such spouse or dependent was residing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at the employee’s post of assignment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at a place, outside the United States, for which a separate maintenance allowance was being furnished under section 5924(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The President may prescribe any regulations necessary to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 510</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–138, title I, § 147(c)</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 669</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title III, § 335]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–441.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5923.</num>
<heading> Quarters allowances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> When Government owned or rented quarters are not provided without charge for an employee in a foreign area, one or more of the following quarters allowances may be granted when applicable:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A temporary subsistence allowance for the reasonable cost of temporary quarters (including meals and laundry expenses) incurred by the employee and his family—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for a period not in excess of 90 days after first arrival at a new post of assignment in a foreign area or a period ending with the occupation of residence quarters, whichever is shorter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a period of not more than 30 days immediately before final departure from the post after the necessary evacuation of residence quarters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A living quarters allowance for rent, heat, light, fuel, gas, electricity, and water, without regard to section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Under unusual circumstances, payment or reimbursement for extraordinary, necessary, and reasonable expenses, not otherwise compensated for, incurred in initial repairs, alterations, and improvements to the privately leased residence of an employee at a post of assignment in a foreign area, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the expenses are administratively approved in advance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the duration and terms of the lease justify payment of the expenses by the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The 90-day period under subsection (a)(1)(A) and the 30-day period under subsection (a)(1)(B) may each be extended for not more than 60 additional days if the head of the agency concerned or his designee determines that there are compelling reasons beyond the control of the employee for the continued occupancy of temporary quarters.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–138, title I, § 147(d)</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5924.</num>
<heading> Cost-of-living allowances</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following cost-of-living allowances may be granted, when applicable, to an employee in a foreign area:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A post allowance to offset the difference between the cost of living at the post of assignment of the employee in a foreign area and the cost of living in the District of Columbia, except that employees receiving the temporary subsistence allowance under section 5923(1) are ineligible for a post allowance under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A transfer allowance for extraordinary, necessary, and reasonable subsistence and other relocation expenses (including unavoidable lease penalties), not otherwise compensated for, incurred by an employee incident to establishing himself at a post of assignment in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a foreign area (including costs incurred in the United States, its territories or possessions, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the areas and installations in the Republic of Panama made available to the United States pursuant to the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977 and related agreements prior to departure for a post of assignment in a foreign area); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the United States after the employee agrees in writing to remain in Government service for 12 months after transfer, unless separated for reasons beyond the control of the employee that are acceptable to the agency concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A separate maintenance allowance to assist an employee who is compelled or authorized, because of dangerous, notably unhealthful, or excessively adverse living conditions at the employee’s post of assignment in a foreign area, or for the convenience of the Government, or who requests such an allowance because of special needs or hardship involving the employee or the employee’s spouse or dependents, to meet the additional expenses of maintaining, elsewhere than at the post, the employee’s spouse or dependents, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> An education allowance or payment of travel costs to assist an employee with the extraordinary and necessary expenses, not otherwise compensated for, incurred because of his service in a foreign area or foreign areas in providing adequate education for his dependents (or, to the extent education away from post is involved, official assignment to service in such area or areas), as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An allowance not to exceed the cost of obtaining such kindergarten, elementary and secondary educational services as are ordinarily provided without charge by the public schools in the United States (including such educational services as are provided by the States under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act), plus, in those cases when adequate schools are not available at the post of the employee, board and room, and periodic transportation between that post and the school chosen by the employee, not to exceed the total cost to the Government of the dependent attending an adequate school in the nearest United States locality where an adequate school is available, without regard to section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31. When travel from school to post is infeasible, travel may be allowed between the school attended and the home of a designated relative or family friend or to join a parent at any location, with the allowable travel expense not to exceed the cost of travel between the school and the post. The amount of the allowance granted shall be determined on the basis of the educational facility used.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The travel expenses of dependents of an employee to and from a secondary or post-secondary educational institution, not to exceed one annual trip each way for each dependent, except that an allowance payment under subparagraph (A) may not be made for a dependent during the 12 months following the arrival of the dependent at the selected educational institution under authority contained in this subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In those cases in which an adequate school is available at the post of the employee, if the employee chooses to educate the dependent at a school away from post, the education allowance which includes board and room, and periodic travel between the post and the school chosen, shall not exceed the total cost to the Government of the dependent attending an adequate school at the post of the employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Allowances provided pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) may include, at the election of the employee, payment or reimbursement of the costs incurred to store baggage for the employee’s dependent at or in the vicinity of the dependent’s school during one trip per year by the dependent between the school and the employee’s duty station, except that such payment or reimbursement may not exceed the cost that the Government would incur to transport the baggage in connection with the trip, and such payment or reimbursement shall be in lieu of transportation of the baggage.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–187, § 2</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 644</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–126, § 12</ref>, <date date="1973-10-18">Oct. 18, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 454</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–475, § 13</ref>, <date date="1974-10-26">Oct. 26, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1443</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–141, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1975-11-29">Nov. 29, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–53, title V, § 510</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 380</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–100, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1979-11-02">Nov. 2, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 734</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–132, § 4(h)</ref>, <date date="1979-11-30">Nov. 30, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 1045</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–465, title II</ref>, §§ 2307, 2308, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2165</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–251, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 26</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1206(h)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–138, title I, § 147(e)</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 670</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 176</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXV, § 3548(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2869</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title III, § 336]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–442; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title III, § 319</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1380</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–472, § 3</ref>, <date date="2007-01-11">Jan. 11, 2007</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5925.</num>
<heading> Post differentials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A post differential may be granted on the basis of conditions of environment which differ substantially from conditions of environment in the continental United States and warrant additional pay as a recruitment and retention incentive. A post differential may be granted to an employee officially stationed in the United States who is on extended detail in a foreign area. A post differential under this subsection may not exceed 35 percent of the rate of basic pay.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Any employee granted a differential under subsection (a) of this section may be granted an additional differential for an assignment to a post determined to have especially adverse conditions of environment which warrant additional pay as a recruitment and retention incentive for the filling of positions at that post. An additional differential for any employee under this subsection—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may be paid for each assignment to a post determined to have such conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may be paid periodically or in a lump sum; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may not exceed 15 percent of the rate of basic pay of that employee for the period served under that assignment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2309</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2165</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title V, § 591(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 207</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–140, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-22">Dec. 22, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2651</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5926.</num>
<heading> Compensatory time off at certain posts in foreign areas</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations prescribed pursuant to this subchapter, and notwithstanding subchapter V of chapter 55 of this title or any other law, the head of an agency may, on request of an employee serving in a foreign area—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at an isolated post performing functions required to be maintained on a substantially continuous basis, grant the employee compensatory time off for an equal amount of time spent in regularly scheduled overtime work; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at a post in a locality that customarily observes irregular hours of work or where other special conditions are present, in order to cope with those special circumstances, grant the employee compensatory time off for an equal amount of time spent in regularly scheduled overtime work for use during the pay period in which it is earned.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Credit for compensatory time off earned under paragraph (2) shall not form the basis for any additional compensation.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Compensatory time earned under this section shall be for use only while the employee is assigned to the post where it is earned. Any such compensatory time not used at the time the employee is reassigned to another post shall be forfeited.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–426, title IV, § 411(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-07">Oct. 7, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 980</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5927.</num>
<heading> Advances of pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Up to three months’ pay may be paid in advance—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to an employee upon the assignment of the employee to a post in a foreign area;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to an employee, other than an employee appointed under section 303 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (and employed under section 311 of such Act), who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a citizen of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is officially stationed or located outside the United States pursuant to Government authorization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> requires (or has a family member who requires) medical treatment outside the United States, in circumstances specified by the President in regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to an employee compensated pursuant to section 408 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980, who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pursuant to United States Government authorization is located outside the country of employment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> requires medical treatment outside the country of employment in circumstances specified by the President in regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section, the term “country of employment”, as used with respect to an individual under subsection (a)(3), means the country (or other area) outside the United States where such individual is hired (as described in subsection (a)(3)) by the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2310(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2166</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title III, § 337]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–442; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5928.</num>
<heading> Danger pay allowance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employee serving in a foreign area may be granted a danger pay allowance on the basis of civil insurrection, civil war, terrorism, or wartime conditions which threaten physical harm or imminent danger to the health or well-being of the employee. A danger pay allowance may not exceed 35 percent of the basic pay of the employee, except that if an employee is granted an additional differential under <ref>section 5925(b) of this title</ref> with respect to an assignment, the sum of that additional differential and any danger pay allowance granted to the employee with respect to that assignment may not exceed 35 percent of the basic pay of the employee. The presence of nonessential personnel or dependents shall not preclude payment of an allowance under this section. In each instance where an allowance under this section is initiated or terminated, the Secretary of State shall inform the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate of the action taken and the circumstances justifying it.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2311(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2166</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–164, title I, § 131</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1028</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title V, § 591(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 207</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–140, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-22">Dec. 22, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2651</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS ALLOWANCES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5941.</num>
<heading> Allowances based on living costs and conditions of environment; employees stationed outside continental United States or in Alaska</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Appropriations or funds available to an Executive agency, except a Government controlled corporation, for pay of employees stationed outside the continental United States or in Alaska whose rates of basic pay are fixed by statute, are available for allowances to these employees. The allowance is based on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> living costs substantially higher than in the District of Columbia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conditions of environment which differ substantially from conditions of environment in the continental United States and warrant an allowance as a recruitment incentive; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> both of these factors.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The allowance may not exceed 25 percent of the rate of basic pay. Except as otherwise specifically authorized by statute, the allowance is paid only in accordance with regulations prescribed by the President establishing the rates and defining the area, groups of positions, and classes of employees to which each rate applies. Notwithstanding any preceding provision of this subsection, the cost-of-living allowance rate based on paragraph (1) shall be the cost-of-living allowance rate in effect on the date of enactment of the Non-Foreign Area Retirement Equity Assurance Act of 2009, except as adjusted under subsection (c).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section shall apply only to areas that are designated as cost-of-living allowance areas as in effect on <date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The cost-of-living allowance rate payable under this section shall be adjusted on the first day of the first applicable pay period beginning on or after—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><date date="2010-01-01">January 1, 2010</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> January 1 of each calendar year in which a locality-based comparability adjustment takes effect under paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively, of section 1914 of the Non-Foreign Area Retirement Equity Assurance Act of 2009.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In this paragraph, the term “applicable locality-based comparability pay percentage” means, with respect to calendar year 2010 and each calendar year thereafter, the applicable percentage under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of section 1914 of Non-Foreign Area Retirement Equity Assurance Act of 2009.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Each adjusted cost-of-living allowance rate under paragraph (1) shall be computed by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> subtracting 65 percent of the applicable locality-based comparability pay percentage from the cost-of-living allowance percentage rate in effect on <date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> dividing the resulting percentage determined under clause (i) by the sum of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> one; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the applicable locality-based comparability payment percentage expressed as a numeral.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No allowance rate computed under paragraph (2) may be less than zero.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Each allowance rate computed under paragraph (2) shall be paid as a percentage of basic pay (including any applicable locality-based comparability payment under section 5304 or similar provision of law and any applicable special rate of pay under section 5305 or similar provision of law).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> An employee entitled to a cost-of-living allowance under <ref>section 5924 of this title</ref> may not be paid an allowance under subsection (a) of this section based on living costs substantially higher than in the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XIX, § 1912(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2620</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5942.</num>
<heading> Allowance based on duty at remote worksites</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 5536 of this title</ref>, an employee of an Executive department or an independent establishment who is assigned to duty, except temporary duty, at a site so remote from the nearest established communities or suitable places of residence as to require an appreciable degree of expense, hardship, and inconvenience, beyond that normally encountered in metropolitan commuting, on the part of the employee in commuting to and from his residence and such worksite, is entitled, in addition to pay otherwise due him, to an allowance of not to exceed $10 a day. The allowance shall be paid under regulations prescribed by the President establishing the rates at which the allowance will be paid and defining and designating those sites, areas, and groups of positions to which the rates apply.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Under procedures prescribed by the President, the maximum allowance specified in subsection (a) may be adjusted from time to time in the interest of recruiting and retaining employees for performance of duty at remote worksites.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 513</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(41)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 207</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–656, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-01-08">Jan. 8, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1206(g)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1662</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5942a.</num>
<heading> Separate maintenance allowance for duty at Johnston Island</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding <ref>section 5536 of this title</ref>, and under regulations prescribed by the President, an employee of an Executive agency (other than a Government corporation) who is assigned to a post of duty at Johnston Island, a possession of the United States in the Pacific Ocean, is entitled to receive a separate maintenance allowance if the head of the employing agency finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> it is necessary for the employee to maintain the employee’s spouse or dependents, or both, at a location other than Johnston Island—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by reason of dangerous or adverse living conditions at Johnston Island; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for the convenience of the Federal Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the allowance is needed to help the employee meet the additional expenses involved in maintaining the employee’s spouse or dependents, or both, at such other location rather than at the post.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The regulations prescribed by the President shall include provisions for determining the rate at which an allowance under this section shall be paid.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1092(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1486</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5943.</num>
<heading> Foreign currency appreciation allowances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President, under such regulations as he may prescribe, may meet losses sustained by employees and members of the uniformed services while serving in a foreign country due to the appreciation of foreign currency in its relation to the American dollar. Allowances and expenditures under this section are not subject to income taxes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Annual appropriations are authorized to carry out subsection (a) of this section and to cover any deficiency in the accounts of the Secretary of the Treasury, including interest, arising out of the arrangement approved by the President on <date date="1933-07-27">July 27, 1933</date>, for the conversion into foreign currency of checks and drafts of employees and members of the uniformed services for pay and expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Payment under subsection (a) of this section may not be made to an employee or member of a uniformed service for a period during which his check or draft was converted into foreign currency under the arrangement referred to by subsection (b) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The President shall report annually to Congress all expenditures made under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 513</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(37)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 383</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 5944.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–164, title I, § 127(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1027</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5945.</num>
<heading> Notary public commission expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employee as defined by <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref> or an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia who is required to serve as a notary public in connection with the performance of official business is entitled to an allowance, established by the agency concerned, not in excess of the expense required to obtain the commission. Funds available to an agency concerned for personal services or general administrative expenses are available to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 514</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5946.</num>
<heading> Membership fees; expenses of attendance at meetings; limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as authorized by a specific appropriation, by express terms in a general appropriation, or by sections 4109 and 4110 of this title, appropriated funds may not be used for payment of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> membership fees or dues of an employee as defined by <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref> or an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia in a society or association; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expenses of attendance of an individual at meetings or conventions of members of a society or association.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">This section does not prevent the use of appropriations for the Department of Agriculture for expenses incident to the delivery of lectures, the giving of instructions, or the acquiring of information at meetings by its employees on subjects relating to the authorized work of the Department.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 514</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5947.</num>
<heading> Quarters, subsistence, and allowances for employees of the Corps of Engineers, Department of the Army, engaged in floating plant operations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An employee of the Corps of Engineers, Department of the Army, engaged in floating plant operations may be furnished quarters or subsistence, or both, on vessels, without charge, when the furnishing of the quarters or subsistence, or both, is determined to be equitable to the employee concerned, and necessary in the public interest, in connection with such operations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding <ref>section 5536 of this title</ref>, an employee entitled to the benefits of subsection (a) of this section while on a vessel, may be paid, in place of these benefits, an allowance for quarters or subsistence, or both, when—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adverse weather conditions or similar circumstances beyond the control of the employee or the Corps of Engineers prevent transportation of the employee from shore to the vessel; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> quarters or subsistence, or both, are not available on the vessel while it is undergoing repairs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The quarters or subsistence, or both, or allowance in place thereof, may be furnished or paid only under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Army.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–656, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-01-08">Jan. 8, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1954</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5948.</num>
<heading> Physicians comparability allowances</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and in order to recruit and retain highly qualified Government physicians, the head of an agency, subject to the provisions of this section, section 5307, and such regulations as the President or his designee may prescribe, may enter into a service agreement with a Government physician which provides for such physician to complete a specified period of service in such agency in return for an allowance for the duration of such agreement in an amount to be determined by the agency head and specified in the agreement, but not to exceed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $14,000 per annum if, at the time the agreement is entered into, the Government physician has served as a Government physician for twenty-four months or less, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $30,000 per annum if the Government physician has served as a Government physician for more than twenty-four months.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For the purpose of determining length of service as a Government physician, service as a physician under section 4104 or 4114 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002124">1</ref> of title 38 or active service as a medical officer in the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service under Title II of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. ch. 6A) shall be deemed service as a Government physician.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An allowance may not be paid pursuant to this section to any physician who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is employed on less than a half-time or intermittent basis,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> occupies an internship or residency training position,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is a reemployed annuitant, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is fulfilling a scholarship obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The head of an agency, pursuant to such regulations, criteria, and conditions as the President or his designee may prescribe, shall determine categories of positions applicable to physicians in such agency with respect to which there is a significant recruitment and retention problem. Only physicians serving in such positions shall be eligible for an allowance pursuant to this section. The amounts of each such allowance shall be determined by the agency head, subject to such regulations, criteria, and conditions as the President or his designee may prescribe, and shall be the minimum amount necessary to deal with the recruitment and retention problem for each such category of physicians.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Any agreement entered into by a physician under this section shall be for a period of one year of service in the agency involved unless the physician requests an agreement for a longer period of service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Unless otherwise provided for in the agreement under subsection (f) of this section, an agreement under this section shall provide that the physician, in the event that such physician voluntarily, or because of misconduct, fails to complete at least one year of service pursuant to such agreement, shall be required to refund the total amount received under this section, unless the head of the agency, pursuant to such regulations as may be prescribed under this section by the President or his designee, determines that such failure is necessitated by circumstances beyond the control of the physician.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Any agreement under this section shall specify, subject to such regulations as the President or his designee may prescribe, the terms under which the head of the agency and the physician may elect to terminate such agreement, and the amounts, if any, required to be refunded by the physician for each reason for termination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “Government physician” means any individual employed as a physician or dentist who is paid under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>section 5332 of this title</ref>, relating to the General Schedule;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subchapter VIII of chapter 53 of this title, relating to the Senior Executive Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> section 5371, relating to certain health care positions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> section 3 of the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 831b</ref>), relating to the Tennessee Valley Authority;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> chapter 4 of title I of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 3961</ref> and following), relating to the Foreign Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> section 10 of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 403j</ref>),<sup>1</sup> relating to the Central Intelligence Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> section 1202 of the Panama Canal Act of 1979, relating to the Panama Canal Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content><ref>section 2 of the Act of May 29, 1959</ref> (<ref>Public Law 86–36</ref>, as amended, <ref>50 U.S.C. 402</ref> note),<sup>1</sup> relating to the National Security Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> section 5376, relating to certain senior-level positions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> section 5377, relating to critical positions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> subchapter IX of chapter 53, relating to special occupational pay systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “agency” means an Executive agency, as defined in <ref>section 105 of this title</ref>, the Library of Congress, and the District of Columbia government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any allowance paid under this section shall not be considered as basic pay for the purposes of subchapter VI and section 5595 of chapter 55, chapter 81 or 87 of this title, or other benefits related to basic pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any allowance under this section for a Government physician shall be paid in the same manner and at the same time as the physician’s basic pay is paid.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Any regulations, criteria, or conditions that may be prescribed under this section by the President or his designee shall not be applicable to the Tennessee Valley Authority, and the Tennessee Valley Authority shall have sole responsibility for administering the provisions of this section with respect to Government physicians employed by the Authority.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than June 30 of each year, the President shall submit to each House of Congress a written report on the operation of this section. Each report shall include, with respect to the year covered by such report, information as to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which agencies entered into agreements under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the nature and extent of the recruitment or retention problems justifying the use of authority by each agency under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the number of physicians with whom agreements were entered into by each agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the size of the allowances and the duration of the agreements entered into; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the degree to which the recruitment or retention problems referred to in paragraph (2) were alleviated under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–603, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3018</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–166, § 2</ref>, <date date="1979-12-29">Dec. 29, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 1273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–141, § 2</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–168, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-29">Nov. 29, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–615, title II, § 204(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3216</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–140, § 1</ref>, <date date="1987-10-26">Oct. 26, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 830</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–420, § 1(a)</ref>, formerly § 1, <date date="1990-10-12">Oct. 12, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 908</ref>, renumbered § 1(a), <ref>Pub. L. 103–114, § 1(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-26">Oct. 26, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(51)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–89, § 3(b)(1)(M)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 982</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–114</ref>, §§ 1(a)(1), 2(a), <date date="1993-10-26">Oct. 26, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1115</ref>, 1116; <ref>Pub. L. 105–61, title V, § 517(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-10-10">Oct. 10, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–266, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-19">Oct. 19, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2369</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title II, § 218(a)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–28; <ref>Pub. L. 106–571</ref>, §§ 2(a)(1), (b), 3(d), <date date="2000-12-28">Dec. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 3054</ref>, 3057.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5949.</num>
<heading> Hostile fire pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The head of an Executive agency may pay an employee hostile fire pay at the rate of $150 for any month in which the employee was—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subject to hostile fire or explosion of hostile mines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on duty in an area in which the employee was in imminent danger of being exposed to hostile fire or explosion of hostile mines and in which, during the period on duty in that area, other employees were subject to hostile fire or explosion of hostile mines; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> killed, injured, or wounded by hostile fire, explosion of a hostile mine, or any other hostile action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An employee covered by subsection (a)(3) who is hospitalized for the treatment of his or her injury or wound may be paid hostile fire pay under this section for not more than three additional months during which the employee is so hospitalized.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An employee may be paid hostile fire pay under this section in addition to other pay and allowances to which entitled, except that an employee may not be paid hostile fire pay under this section for periods of time during which the employee receives payment under <ref>section 5925 of this title</ref> because of exposure to political violence or payment under <ref>section 5928 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XI, § 1111(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>