<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 75—</num>
<heading>ADVERSE ACTIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>SUSPENSION FOR 14 DAYS OR LESS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “employee” means an individual in the competitive service who is not serving a probationary or trial period under an initial appointment or who has completed 1 year of current continuous employment in the same or similar positions under other than a temporary appointment limited to 1 year or less; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “suspension” means the placing of an employee, for disciplinary reasons, in a temporary status without duties and pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1134</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XI, § 1105(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1024</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XI, § 1106(b)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1950</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7502.</num>
<heading> Actions covered</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter applies to a suspension for 14 days or less, but does not apply to a suspension under section 7521 or 7532 of this title or any action initiated under <ref>section 1215 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1135</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 9(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 35</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7503.</num>
<heading> Cause and procedure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, an employee may be suspended for 14 days or less for such cause as will promote the efficiency of the service (including discourteous conduct to the public confirmed by an immediate supervisor’s report of four such instances within any one-year period or any other pattern of discourteous conduct).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An employee against whom a suspension for 14 days or less is proposed is entitled to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an advance written notice stating the specific reasons for the proposed action;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a reasonable time to answer orally and in writing and to furnish affidavits and other documentary evidence in support of the answer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> be represented by an attorney or other representative; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a written decision and the specific reasons therefor at the earliest practicable date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Copies of the notice of proposed action, the answer of the employee if written, a summary thereof if made orally, the notice of decision and reasons therefor, and any order effecting <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002141">1</ref> the suspension, together with any supporting material, shall be maintained by the agency and shall be furnished to the Merit Systems Protection Board upon its request and to the employee affected upon the employee’s request.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7504.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management may prescribe regulations to carry out the purpose of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>REMOVAL, SUSPENSION FOR MORE THAN 14 DAYS, REDUCTION IN GRADE OR PAY, OR FURLOUGH FOR 30 DAYS OR LESS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7511.</num>
<heading> Definitions; application</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “employee” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> an individual in the competitive service—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who is not serving a probationary or trial period under an initial appointment; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who has completed 1 year of current continuous service under other than a temporary appointment limited to 1 year or less;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a preference eligible in the excepted service who has completed 1 year of current continuous service in the same or similar positions—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in an Executive agency; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the United States Postal Service or Postal Regulatory Commission; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> an individual in the excepted service (other than a preference eligible)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who is not serving a probationary or trial period under an initial appointment pending conversion to the competitive service; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who has completed 2 years of current continuous service in the same or similar positions in an Executive agency under other than a temporary appointment limited to 2 years or less;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “suspension” has the same meaning as set forth in <ref>section 7501(2) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “grade” means a level of classification under a position classification system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “pay” means the rate of basic pay fixed by law or administrative action for the position held by an employee; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “furlough” means the placing of an employee in a temporary status without duties and pay because of lack of work or funds or other nondisciplinary reasons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> This subchapter does not apply to an employee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whose appointment is made by and with the advice and consent of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> whose position has been determined to be of a confidential, policy-determining, policy-making or policy-advocating character by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the President for a position that the President has excepted from the competitive service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Office of Personnel Management for a position that the Office has excepted from the competitive service; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the President or the head of an agency for a position excepted from the competitive service by statute;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> whose appointment is made by the President;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> who is receiving an annuity from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund, or the Foreign Service Retirement and Disability Fund, based on the service of such employee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>[(5)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 512(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2112</ref>.]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> who is a member of the Foreign Service, as described in section 103 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> whose position is within the Central Intelligence Agency or the Government Accountability Office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> whose position is within the United States Postal Service, the Postal Regulatory Commission, the Panama Canal Commission, the Tennessee Valley Authority, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, an intelligence component of the Department of Defense (as defined in <ref>section 1614 of title 10</ref>), or an intelligence activity of a military department covered under subchapter I of chapter 83 of title 10, unless subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section or <ref>section 1005(a) of title 39</ref> is the basis for this subchapter’s applicability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> who is described in <ref>section 5102(c)(11) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> who holds a position within the Veterans Health Administration which has been excluded from the competitive service by or under a provision of title 38, unless such employee was appointed to such position under section 7401(3) of such title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Office may provide for the application of this subchapter to any position or group of positions excepted from the competitive service by regulation of the Office which is not otherwise covered by this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1135</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–376, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-17">Aug. 17, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 461</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1358</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title V, § 501</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3430</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1634(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title VI, § 604(b)</ref>, (f), <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3241</ref>, 3242; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XI, § 1105(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1024</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 512(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2112</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XI, § 1106(b)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1950</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7512.</num>
<heading> Actions covered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This subchapter applies to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a removal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a suspension for more than 14 days;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a reduction in grade;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a reduction in pay; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a furlough of 30 days or less;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">but does not apply to—</continuation>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a suspension or removal under <ref>section 7532 of this title</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a reduction-in-force action under <ref>section 3502 of this title</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the reduction in grade of a supervisor or manager who has not completed the probationary period under <ref>section 3321(a)(2) of this title</ref> if such reduction is to the grade held immediately before becoming such a supervisor or manager,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a reduction in grade or removal under <ref>section 4303 of this title</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an action initiated under section 1215 or 7521 of this title, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a suitability action taken by the Office under regulations prescribed by the Office, subject to the rules prescribed by the President under this title for the administration of the competitive service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1136</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 9(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1086(f)(9)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1010</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7513.</num>
<heading> Cause and procedure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, an agency may take an action covered by this subchapter against an employee only for such cause as will promote the efficiency of the service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An employee against whom an action is proposed is entitled to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at least 30 days’ advance written notice, unless there is reasonable cause to believe the employee has committed a crime for which a sentence of imprisonment may be imposed, stating the specific reasons for the proposed action;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a reasonable time, but not less than 7 days, to answer orally and in writing and to furnish affidavits and other documentary evidence in support of the answer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> be represented by an attorney or other representative; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a written decision and the specific reasons therefor at the earliest practicable date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An agency may provide, by regulation, for a hearing which may be in lieu of or in addition to the opportunity to answer provided under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> An employee against whom an action is taken under this section is entitled to appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board under <ref>section 7701 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Copies of the notice of proposed action, the answer of the employee when written, a summary thereof when made orally, the notice of decision and reasons therefor, and any order effecting an action covered by this subchapter, together with any supporting material, shall be maintained by the agency and shall be furnished to the Board upon its request and to the employee affected upon the employee’s request.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1136</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7514.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management may prescribe regulations to carry out the purpose of this subchapter, except as it concerns any matter with respect to which the Merit Systems Protection Board may prescribe regulations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1137</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7515.</num>
<heading> Discipline of supervisors based on retaliation against whistleblowers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “agency”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has the meaning given the term in section 2302(a)(2)(C), without regard to whether any other provision of this chapter is applicable to the entity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include any entity that is an element of the intelligence community, as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “prohibited personnel action” means taking or failing to take an action in violation of paragraph (8), (9), or (14) of section 2302(b) against an employee of an agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “supervisor” means an employee who would be a supervisor, as defined in section 7103(a), if the entity employing the employee was an agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Proposed Disciplinary Actions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to section 1214(f), if the head of the agency in which a supervisor is employed, an administrative law judge, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Special Counsel, a judge of the United States, or the Inspector General of the agency in which a supervisor is employed has determined that the supervisor committed a prohibited personnel action, the head of the agency in which the supervisor is employed, consistent with the procedures required under paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for the first prohibited personnel action committed by the supervisor—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall propose suspending the supervisor for a period that is not less than 3 days; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may propose an additional action determined appropriate by the head of the agency, including a reduction in grade or pay; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for the second prohibited personnel action committed by the supervisor, shall propose removing the supervisor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procedures.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A supervisor against whom an action is proposed to be taken under paragraph (1) is entitled to written notice that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> states the specific reasons for the proposed action; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> informs the supervisor about the right of the supervisor to review the material that is relied on to support the reasons given in the notice for the proposed action.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Answer and evidence.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A supervisor who receives notice under subparagraph (A) may, not later than 14 days after the date on which the supervisor receives the notice, submit an answer and furnish evidence in support of that answer.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No evidence furnished; insufficient evidence furnished</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, after the end of the 14-day period described in clause (i), a supervisor does not furnish any evidence as described in that clause, or if the head of the agency in which the supervisor is employed determines that the evidence furnished by the supervisor is insufficient, the head of the agency shall carry out the action proposed under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1), as applicable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An action carried out under this section—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> except as provided in clause (ii), shall be subject to the same requirements and procedures, including those with respect to an appeal, as an action under section 7503, 7513, or 7543; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> shall not be subject to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 7503(b);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) and subsection (c) of section 7513; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) and subsection (c) of section 7543.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the head of an agency is responsible for determining whether a supervisor has committed a prohibited personnel action for purposes of paragraph (1), the head of the agency may not delegate that responsibility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(e)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1621</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATIVE LAW JUDGES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7521.</num>
<heading> Actions against administrative law judges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An action may be taken against an administrative law judge appointed under <ref>section 3105 of this title</ref> by the agency in which the administrative law judge is employed only for good cause established and determined by the Merit Systems Protection Board on the record after opportunity for hearing before the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The actions covered by this section are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a removal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a suspension;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a reduction in grade;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a reduction in pay; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a furlough of 30 days or less;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">but do not include—</continuation>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a suspension or removal under <ref>section 7532 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a reduction-in-force action under <ref>section 3502 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any action initiated under <ref>section 1215 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1137</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 9(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 35</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL SECURITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7531.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter, “agency” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Department of State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Department of Commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Department of Justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a military department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Coast Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the Atomic Energy Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the National Aeronautics and Space Administration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> such other agency of the Government of the United States as the President designates in the best interests of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The President shall report any designation to the Committees on the Armed Services of the Congress.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7532.</num>
<heading> Suspension and removal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding other statutes, the head of an agency may suspend without pay an employee of his agency when he considers that action necessary in the interests of national security. To the extent that the head of the agency determines that the interests of national security permit, the suspended employee shall be notified of the reasons for the suspension. Within 30 days after the notification, the suspended employee is entitled to submit to the official designated by the head of the agency statements or affidavits to show why he should be restored to duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (c) of this section, the head of an agency may remove an employee suspended under subsection (a) of this section when, after such investigation and review as he considers necessary, he determines that removal is necessary or advisable in the interests of national security. The determination of the head of the agency is final.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> An employee suspended under subsection (a) of this section who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has a permanent or indefinite appointment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has completed his probationary or trial period; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is a citizen of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is entitled, after suspension and before removal, to—</continuation>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a written statement of the charges against him within 30 days after suspension, which may be amended within 30 days thereafter and which shall be stated as specifically as security considerations permit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an opportunity within 30 days thereafter, plus an additional 30 days if the charges are amended, to answer the charges and submit affidavits;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a hearing, at the request of the employee, by an agency authority duly constituted for this purpose;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a review of his case by the head of the agency or his designee, before a decision adverse to the employee is made final; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a written statement of the decision of the head of the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7533.</num>
<heading> Effect on other statutes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter does not impair the powers vested in the Atomic Energy Commission by chapter 23 of title 42, or the requirement in <ref>section 2201(d) of title 42</ref> that adequate provision be made for administrative review of a determination to dismiss an employee of the Atomic Energy Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 529</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>SENIOR EXECUTIVE SERVICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7541.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “employee” means a career appointee in the Senior Executive Service who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has completed the probationary period prescribed under <ref>section 3393(d) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> was covered by the provisions of subchapter II of this chapter immediately before appointment to the Senior Executive Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “suspension” has the meaning set forth in <ref>section 7501(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, § 411(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1174</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XI, § 1105(c)(5)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1024</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XI, § 1106(b)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1950</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7542.</num>
<heading> Actions covered</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter applies to a removal from the civil service or suspension for more than 14 days, but does not apply to an action initiated under <ref>section 1215 of this title</ref>, to a suspension or removal under <ref>section 7532 of this title</ref>, or to a removal under section 3592 or 3595 of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, § 411(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1174</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XVII, § 1704(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 758</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 9(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 35</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7543.</num>
<heading> Cause and procedure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, an agency may take an action covered by this subchapter against an employee only for misconduct, neglect of duty, malfeasance, or failure to accept a directed reassignment or to accompany a position in a transfer of function.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An employee against whom an action covered by this subchapter is proposed is entitled to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at least 30 days’ advance written notice, unless there is reasonable cause to believe that the employee has committed a crime for which a sentence of imprisonment can be imposed, stating specific reasons for the proposed action;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a reasonable time, but not less than 7 days, to answer orally and in writing and to furnish affidavits and other documentary evidence in support of the answer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> be represented by an attorney or other representative; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a written decision and specific reasons therefor at the earliest practicable date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An agency may provide, by regulation, for a hearing which may be in lieu of or in addition to the opportunity to answer provided under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> An employee against whom an action is taken under this section is entitled to appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board under <ref>section 7701 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Copies of the notice of proposed action, the answer of the employee when written, and a summary thereof when made orally, the notice of decision and reasons therefor, and any order effecting an action covered by this subchapter, together with any supporting material, shall be maintained by the agency and shall be furnished to the Merit Systems Protection Board upon its request and to the employee affected upon the employee’s request.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, § 411(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1174</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XVII, § 1704(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 758</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–615, title III, § 304(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3219</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>