<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 43—</num>
<heading>PERFORMANCE APPRAISAL</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise expressly provided, for the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an Executive agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Government Publishing Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">but does not include—</continuation>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a Government corporation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Central Intelligence Agency, the Defense Intelligence Agency, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, the National Security Agency, or any Executive agency or unit thereof which is designated by the President and the principal function of which is the conduct of foreign intelligence or counterintelligence activities; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Government Accountability Office;</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “employee” means an individual employed in or under an agency, but does not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an employee outside the United States who is paid in accordance with local native prevailing wage rates for the area in which employed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an individual in the Foreign Service of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a physician, dentist, nurse, or other employee in the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs whose pay is fixed under chapter 73 of title 38;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an administrative law judge appointed under <ref>section 3105 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an individual in the Senior Executive Service or the Federal Bureau of Investigation and Drug Enforcement Administration Senior Executive Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an individual appointed by the President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> an individual occupying a position not in the competitive service excluded from coverage of this subchapter by regulations of the Office of Personnel Management; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> an individual who (i) is serving in a position under a temporary appointment for less than one year, (ii) agrees to serve without a performance evaluation, and (iii) will not be considered for a reappointment or for an increase in pay based in whole or in part on performance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “unacceptable performance” means performance of an employee which fails to meet established performance standards in one or more critical elements of such employee’s position.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 6(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 776</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–251, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-03-27">Mar. 27, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 183</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1131</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–325, § 2(f)</ref>, <date date="1988-05-30">May 30, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 581</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–474, § 5(e)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1206(e)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 13(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 274</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title V, § 501(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1122(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 931(a)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4575</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1621</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4302.</num>
<heading> Establishment of performance appraisal systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Each agency shall develop one or more performance appraisal systems which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide for periodic appraisals of job performance of employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage employee participation in establishing performance standards; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> use the results of performance appraisals as a basis for training, rewarding, reassigning, promoting, reducing in grade, retaining, and removing employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The head of each agency, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the Special Counsel, shall develop criteria that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the head of the agency shall use as a critical element for establishing the job requirements of a supervisory employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promote the protection of whistleblowers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The criteria required under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> principles for the protection of whistleblowers, such as the degree to which supervisory employees—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> respond constructively when employees of the agency make disclosures described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 2302(b)(8);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> take responsible actions to resolve the disclosures described in clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> foster an environment in which employees of the agency feel comfortable making disclosures described in clause (i) to supervisory employees or other appropriate authorities; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for each supervisory employee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> whether the agency entered into an agreement with an individual who alleged that the supervisory employee committed a prohibited personnel practice; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the agency entered into an agreement described in clause (i), the number of instances in which the agency entered into such an agreement with respect to the supervisory employee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “agency” means any entity the employees of which are covered under paragraphs (8) and (9) of section 2302(b), without regard to whether any other provision of this section is applicable to the entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “prohibited personnel practice” has the meaning given the term in section 2302(a)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “supervisory employee” means an employee who would be a supervisor, as defined in section 7103(a), if the agency employing the employee was an agency for purposes of chapter 71; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the term “whistleblower” means an employee who makes a disclosure described in section 2302(b)(8).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Under regulations which the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe, each performance appraisal system shall provide for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establishing performance standards which will, to the maximum extent feasible, permit the accurate evaluation of job performance on the basis of objective criteria (which may include the extent of courtesy demonstrated to the public) related to the job in question for each employee or position under the system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as soon as practicable, but not later than <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, with respect to initial appraisal periods, and thereafter at the beginning of each following appraisal period, communicating to each employee the performance standards and the critical elements of the employee’s position;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> evaluating each employee during the appraisal period on such standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> recognizing and rewarding employees whose performance so warrants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> assisting employees in improving unacceptable performance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> reassigning, reducing in grade, or removing employees who continue to have unacceptable performance but only after an opportunity to demonstrate acceptable performance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In accordance with regulations which the Office shall prescribe, the head of an agency may administer and maintain a performance appraisal system electronically.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1132</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(18)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1347</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1104], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–311; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1619</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 4302a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–89, § 3(b)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 981</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4303.</num>
<heading> Actions based on unacceptable performance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisions of this section, an agency may reduce in grade or remove an employee for unacceptable performance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An employee whose reduction in grade or removal is proposed under this section is entitled to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> 30 days’ advance written notice of the proposed action which identifies—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> specific instances of unacceptable performance by the employee on which the proposed action is based; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the critical elements of the employee’s position involved in each instance of unacceptable performance;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be represented by an attorney or other representative;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a reasonable time to answer orally and in writing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> a written decision which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a reduction in grade or removal under this section, specifies the instances of unacceptable performance by the employee on which the reduction in grade or removal is based, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> unless proposed by the head of the agency, has been concurred in by an employee who is in a higher position than the employee who proposed the action.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An agency may, under regulations prescribed by the head of such agency, extend the notice period under subsection (b)(1)(A) of this section for not more than 30 days. An agency may extend the notice period for more than 30 days only in accordance with regulations issued by the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The decision to retain, reduce in grade, or remove an employee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be made within 30 days after the date of expiration of the notice period, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a reduction in grade or removal, may be based only on those instances of unacceptable performance by the employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which occurred during the 1-year period ending on the date of the notice under subsection (b)(1)(A) of this section in connection with the decision; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for which the notice and other requirements of this section are complied with.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If, because of performance improvement by the employee during the notice period, the employee is not reduced in grade or removed, and the employee’s performance continues to be acceptable for 1 year from the date of the advance written notice provided under subsection (b)(1)(A) of this section, any entry or other notation of the unacceptable performance for which the action was proposed under this section shall be removed from any agency record relating to the employee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> Any employee who is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a preference eligible;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the competitive service; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the excepted service and covered by subchapter II of chapter 75,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">and who has been reduced in grade or removed under this section is entitled to appeal the action to the Merit Systems Protection Board under section 7701.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> This section does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the reduction to the grade previously held of a supervisor or manager who has not completed the probationary period under <ref>section 3321(a)(2) of this title</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the reduction in grade or removal of an employee in the competitive service who is serving a probationary or trial period under an initial appointment or who has not completed 1 year of current continuous employment under other than a temporary appointment limited to 1 year or less,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the reduction in grade or removal of an employee in the excepted service who has not completed 1 year of current continuous employment in the same or similar positions, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any removal or demotion under <ref>section 714 of title 38</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1133</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–376, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-17">Aug. 17, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 462</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–41, title II, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2017-06-23">June 23, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 873</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4304.</num>
<heading> Responsibilities of the Office of Personnel Management</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall make technical assistance available to agencies in the development of performance appraisal systems.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Office shall review each performance appraisal system developed by any agency under this section and determine whether the performance appraisal system meets the requirements of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Comptroller General shall from time to time review on a selected basis performance appraisal systems established under this subchapter to determine the extent to which any such system meets the requirements of this subchapter and shall periodically report its findings to the Office and to the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Office determines that a system does not meet the requirements of this subchapter (including regulations prescribed under section 4305), the Office shall direct the agency to implement an appropriate system or to correct operations under the system, and any such agency shall take any action so required.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 440</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1134</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4305.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management may prescribe regulations to carry out the purpose of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1134</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4306 to 4308.</num>
<heading> Omitted]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>PERFORMANCE APPRAISAL IN THE SENIOR EXECUTIVE SERVICE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4311.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter, “agency”, “senior executive”, and “career appointee” have the meanings set forth in <ref>section 3132(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1167</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4312.</num>
<heading> Senior Executive Service performance appraisal systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Each agency shall, in accordance with standards established by the Office of Personnel Management, develop one or more performance appraisal systems designed to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> permit the accurate evaluation of performance in any position on the basis of criteria which are related to the position and which specify the critical elements of the position;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide for systematic appraisals of performance of senior executives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> encourage excellence in performance by senior executives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide a basis for making eligibility determinations for retention in the Senior Executive Service and for Senior Executive Service performance awards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Each performance appraisal system established by an agency under subsection (a) of this section shall provide—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that, on or before the beginning of each rating period, performance requirements for each senior executive in the agency are established in consultation with the senior executive and communicated to the senior executive;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that written appraisals of performance are based on the individual and organizational performance requirements established for the rating period involved; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that each senior executive in the agency is provided a copy of the appraisal and rating under <ref>section 4314 of this title</ref> and is given an opportunity to respond in writing and have the rating reviewed by an employee, or (with the consent of the senior executive) a commissioned officer in the uniformed services serving on active duty, in a higher level in the agency before the rating becomes final.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Office shall review each agency’s performance appraisal system under this section, and determine whether the agency performance appraisal system meets the requirements of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Comptroller General shall from time to time review performance appraisal systems under this section to determine the extent to which any such system meets the requirements under this subchapter and shall periodically report its findings to the Office and to each House of the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Office determines that an agency performance appraisal system does not meet the requirements under this subchapter (including regulations prescribed under section 4315), the agency shall take such corrective action as may be required by the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A senior executive may not appeal any appraisal and rating under any performance appraisal system under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1167</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–615, title III, § 306(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3220</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4313.</num>
<heading> Criteria for performance appraisals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Appraisals of performance in the Senior Executive Service shall be based on both individual and organizational performance, taking into account such factors as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improvements in efficiency, productivity, and quality of work or service, including any significant reduction in paperwork;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> cost efficiency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> timeliness of performance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> other indications of the effectiveness, productivity, and performance quality of the employees for whom the senior executive is responsible;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> meeting affirmative action goals, achievement of equal employment opportunity requirements, and compliance with the merit systems principles set forth under <ref>section 2301 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> protecting whistleblowers, as described in section 4302(b)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1168</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–424, § 6</ref>, <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1620</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4314.</num>
<heading> Ratings for performance appraisals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Each performance appraisal system shall provide for annual summary ratings of levels of performance as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> one or more fully successful levels,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a minimally satisfactory level, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an unsatisfactory level.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Each performance appraisal system shall provide that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> any appraisal and any rating under such system—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are made only after review and evaluation by a performance review board established under subsection (c) of this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are conducted at least annually, subject to the limitation of subsection (c)(3) of this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of a career appointee, may not be made within 120 days after the beginning of a new Presidential administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> are based on performance during a performance appraisal period the duration of which shall be determined under guidelines established by the Office of Personnel Management, but which may be terminated in any case in which the agency making an appraisal determines that an adequate basis exists on which to appraise and rate the senior executive’s performance;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any career appointee receiving a rating at any of the fully successful levels under subsection (a)(1) of this section may be given a performance award under <ref>section 5384 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any senior executive receiving an unsatisfactory rating under subsection (a)(3) of this section shall be reassigned or transferred within the Senior Executive Service, or removed from the Senior Executive Service, but any senior executive who receives 2 unsatisfactory ratings in any period of 5 consecutive years shall be removed from the Senior Executive Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any senior executive who twice in any period of 3 consecutive years receives less than fully successful ratings shall be removed from the Senior Executive Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each agency shall establish, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Office, one or more performance review boards, as appropriate. It is the function of the boards to make recommendations to the appropriate appointing authority of the agency relating to the performance of senior executives in the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The supervising official of the senior executive shall provide to the performance review board, an initial appraisal of the senior executive’s performance. Before making any recommendation with respect to the senior executive, the board shall review any response by the senior executive to the initial appraisal and conduct such further review as the board finds necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Performance appraisals under this subchapter with respect to any senior executive shall be made by the appointing authority only after considering the recommendations by the performance review board with respect to such senior executive under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Members of performance review boards shall be appointed in such a manner as to assure consistency, stability, and objectivity in performance appraisal. Notice of the appointment of an individual to serve as a member shall be published in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In the case of an appraisal of a career appointee, more than one-half of the members of the performance review board shall consist of career appointees. The requirement of the preceding sentence shall not apply in any case in which the Office determines that there exists an insufficient number of career appointees available to comply with the requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1169</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title II, § 2181(b)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 732</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4315.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations to carry out the purpose of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1170</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>