<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 63—</num>
<heading>LEAVE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ANNUAL AND SICK LEAVE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6301.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “United States”, when used in a geographical sense means the several States and the District of Columbia; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “employee” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an employee as defined by <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an individual first employed by the government of the District of Columbia before <date date="1987-10-01">October 1, 1987</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">but does not include—</continuation>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a teacher or librarian of the public schools of the District of Columbia;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a part-time employee who does not have an established regular tour of duty during the administrative workweek;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a temporary employee engaged in construction work at an hourly rate;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> an employee of the Panama Canal Commission when employed on the Isthmus of Panama;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> an employee of the Veterans Health Administration who is covered by a leave system established under <ref>section 7421 of title 38</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> an employee of either House of Congress or of the two Houses;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> an employee of a corporation supervised by the Farm Credit Administration if private interests elect or appoint a member of the board of directors;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> an alien employee who occupies a position outside the United States, except as provided by <ref>section 6310 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> a “teacher” or an individual holding a “teaching position” as defined by <ref>section 901 of title 20</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> an officer in the executive branch or in the government of the District of Columbia who is appointed by the President and whose rate of basic pay exceeds the highest rate payable under <ref>section 5332 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> an officer in the executive branch or in the government of the District of Columbia who is designated by the President, except a postmaster, United States attorney, or United States marshal;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(xii)</num>
<content> a chief of mission (as defined in section 102(a)(3) of the Foreign Service Act of 1980); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(xiii)</num>
<content> an officer in the legislative or judicial branch who is appointed by the President.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding clauses (x)–(xii) of paragraph (2), the term “employee” includes any member of the Senior Foreign Service or any Foreign Service officer (other than a member or officer serving as chief of mission or in a position which requires appointment by and with the advice and consent of the Senate) and any member of the Foreign Service commissioned as a diplomatic or consular officer, or both, under section 312 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 517</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 6(c)(17)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 776</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–519, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-10-25">Oct. 25, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1819</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–70, title III, § 3302(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1979-09-27">Sept. 27, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–465, title II</ref>, §§ 2312(a), 2314(f)(1), <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2166</ref>, 2168; <ref>Pub. L. 99–335, title II, § 207(c)(1)</ref>, formerly § 207(c), <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 595</ref>, renumbered § 207(c)(1), <ref>Pub. L. 99–556, title II, § 201(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3135</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 13(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 274</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1103(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3889</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6302.</num>
<heading> General provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The days of leave provided by this subchapter are days on which an employee would otherwise work and receive pay and are exclusive of holidays and nonworkdays established by Federal statute, Executive order, or administrative order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this subchapter an employee is deemed employed for a full biweekly pay period if he is employed during the days within that period, exclusive of holidays and nonworkdays established by Federal statute, Executive order, or administrative order, which fall within his basic administrative workweek.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A part-time employee, unless otherwise excepted, is entitled to the benefits provided by subsection (d) of this section and sections 6303, 6304(a), (b), 6305(a), 6307, and 6310 of this title on a pro rata basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The annual leave provided by this subchapter, including annual leave that will accrue to an employee during the year, may be granted at any time during the year as the head of the agency concerned may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If an officer excepted from this subchapter by section 6301(2)(x)–(xiii) of this title, without a break in service, again becomes subject to this subchapter on completion of his service as an excepted officer, the unused annual and sick leave standing to his credit when he was excepted from this subchapter is deemed to have remained to his credit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> An employee who uses excess annual leave credited because of administrative error may elect to refund the amount received for the days of excess leave by lump-sum or installment payments or to have the excess leave carried forward as a charge against later-accruing annual leave, unless repayment is waived under <ref>section 5584 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> An employee who is being involuntarily separated from an agency due to a reduction in force or transfer of function under subchapter I of chapter 35 or section 3595 may elect to use annual leave to the employee’s credit to remain on the agency’s rolls after the date the employee would otherwise have been separated if, and only to the extent that, such additional time in a pay status will enable the employee to qualify for an immediate annuity under section 8336, 8412, 8414, or to qualify to carry health benefits coverage into retirement under section 8905(b).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 517</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–181, § 4</ref>, <date date="1973-12-14">Dec. 14, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–519, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-10-25">Oct. 25, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1819</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 634]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–363; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(h) [title VI, § 653]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–480</ref>, 2681–528.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6303.</num>
<heading> Annual leave; accrual</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An employee is entitled to annual leave with pay which accrues as follows—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> one-half day for each full biweekly pay period for an employee with less than 3 years of service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> three-fourths day for each full biweekly pay period, except that the accrual for the last full biweekly pay period in the year is one and one-fourth days, for an employee with 3 but less than 15 years of service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> one day for each full biweekly pay period for an employee with 15 or more years of service.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In determining years of service, an employee is entitled to credit for all service of a type that would be creditable under section 8332, regardless of whether or not the employee is covered by subchapter III of chapter 83, and for all service which is creditable by virtue of subsection (e). However, an employee who is a retired member of a uniformed service as defined by <ref>section 3501 of this title</ref> is entitled to credit for active military service only if—</continuation>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> his retirement was based on disability—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> resulting from injury or disease received in line of duty as a direct result of armed conflict; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> caused by an instrumentality of war and incurred in line of duty during a period of war as defined by sections 101 and 1101 of title 38;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that service was performed in the armed forces during a war, or in a campaign or expedition for which a campaign badge has been authorized; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> on <date date="1964-11-30">November 30, 1964</date>, he was employed in a position to which this subchapter applies and thereafter he continued to be so employed without a break in service of more than 30 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The determination of years of service may be made on the basis of an affidavit of the employee. Leave provided by this subchapter accrues to an employee who is not paid on the basis of biweekly pay periods on the same basis as it would accrue if the employee were paid on the basis of biweekly pay periods.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, an employee whose current employment is limited to less than 90 days is entitled to annual leave under this subchapter only after being currently employed for a continuous period of 90 days under successive appointments without a break in service. After completing the 90-day period, the employee is entitled to be credited with the leave that would have accrued to him under subsection (a) of this section except for this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A change in the rate of accrual of annual leave by an employee under this section takes effect at the beginning of the pay period after the pay period, or corresponding period for an employee who is not paid on the basis of biweekly pay periods, in which the employee completed the prescribed period of service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Leave granted under this subchapter is exclusive of time actually and necessarily occupied in going to or from a post of duty and time necessarily occupied awaiting transportation, in the case of an employee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to whom <ref>section 6304(b) of this title</ref> applies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whose post of duty is outside the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> who returns on leave to the United States, or to his place of residence, which is outside the area of employment, in its territories or possessions including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">This subsection does not apply to more than one period of leave in a prescribed tour of duty at a post outside the United States.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations under which, for purposes of determining years of service under subsection (a), credit shall, in the case of a newly appointed employee, be given for any prior service of such employee that would not otherwise be creditable for such purposes, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> such service—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> was performed in a position the duties of which directly relate to the duties of the position to which such employee is so appointed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> meets such other requirements as the Office may prescribe; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the judgment of the head of the appointing agency, the application of this subsection is necessary in order to achieve an important agency mission or performance goal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Service described in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be creditable, for the purposes described in paragraph (1), as of the effective date of the employee’s appointment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall not thereafter cease to be so creditable, unless the employee fails to complete a full year of continuous service with the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An employee shall not be eligible for the application of paragraph (1) on the basis of any appointment if, within 90 days before the effective date of such appointment, such employee has held any position in the civil service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the rate of accrual of annual leave under subsection (a) shall be 1 day for each full biweekly pay period in the case of any employee who holds a position which is subject to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> section 5376 or 5383; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a pay system equivalent to either of the foregoing, as determined by the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 518</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–181, § 2</ref>, <date date="1973-12-14">Dec. 14, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–335, title II, § 207(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 595</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(52)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–411, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2312</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6304.</num>
<heading> Annual leave; accumulation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided by subsections (b), (d), (e), (f), and (g) of this section, annual leave provided by <ref>section 6303 of this title</ref>, which is not used by an employee, accumulates for use in succeeding years until it totals not more than 30 days at the beginning of the first full biweekly pay period, or corresponding period for an employee who is not paid on the basis of biweekly pay periods, occurring in a year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Annual leave not used by an employee of the Government of the United States in one of the following classes of employees stationed outside the United States accumulates for use in succeeding years until it totals not more than 45 days at the beginning of the first full biweekly pay period, or corresponding period for an employee who is not paid on the basis of biweekly pay periods, occurring in a year:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Individuals directly recruited or transferred by the Government of the United States from the United States or its territories or possessions including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico for employment outside the area of recruitment or from which transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Individuals employed locally but—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who were originally recruited from the United States or its territories or possessions including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico but outside the area of employment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who have been in substantially continuous employment by other agencies of the United States, United States firms, interests, or organizations, international organizations in which the United States participates, or foreign governments; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> whose conditions of employment provide for their return transportation to the United States or its territories or possessions including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who were at the time of employment temporarily absent, for the purpose of travel or formal study, from the United States, or from their respective places of residence in its territories or possessions including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who, during the temporary absence, have maintained residence in the United States or its territories or possessions including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico but outside the area of employment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Individuals who are not normally residents of the area concerned and who are discharged from service in the armed forces to accept employment with an agency of the Government of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Annual leave in excess of the amount allowable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> under subsection (a) or (b) of this section which was accumulated under earlier statute; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> under subsection (a) of this section which was accumulated under subsection (b) of this section by an employee who becomes subject to subsection (a) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">remains to the credit of the employee until used. The excess annual leave is reduced at the beginning of the first full biweekly pay period, or corresponding period for an employee who is not paid on the basis of biweekly pay periods, occurring in a year, by the amount of annual leave the employee used during the preceding year in excess of the amount which accrued during that year, until the employee’s accumulated leave does not exceed the amount allowed under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, as appropriate.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Annual leave which is lost by operation of this section because of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> administrative error when the error causes a loss of annual leave otherwise accruable after <date date="1960-06-30">June 30, 1960</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> exigencies of the public business when the annual leave was scheduled in advance; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> sickness of the employee when the annual leave was scheduled in advance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be restored to the employee.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Annual leave restored under paragraph (1) of this subsection, or under clause (2) of <ref>section 5562(a) of this title</ref>, which is in excess of the maximum leave accumulation permitted by law shall be credited to a separate leave account for the employee and shall be available for use by the employee within the time limits prescribed by regulations of the Office of Personnel Management. Leave credited under this paragraph but unused and still available to the employee under the regulations prescribed by the Office shall be included in the lump-sum payment under section 5551 or 5552(1) of this title but may not be retained to the credit of the employee under <ref>section 5552(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this subsection, the closure of, and any realignment with respect to, an installation of the Department of Defense pursuant to the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (part A of title XXIX of <ref>Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref>10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note) during any period, the closure of an installation of the Department of Defense in the Republic of Panama in accordance with the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977, and the closure of any other installation of the Department of Defense, during the period beginning on <date date="1992-10-01">October 1, 1992</date>, and ending on <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>, shall be deemed to create an exigency of the public business and any leave that is lost by an employee of such installation by operation of this section (regardless of whether such leave was scheduled) shall be restored to the employee and shall be credited and available in accordance with paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For the purpose of subparagraph (A), the term “realignment” means a base realignment (as defined in subsection (e)(3) of <ref>section 2687 of title 10</ref>) that meets the requirements of subsection (a)(2) of such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this subsection, service of a Department of Defense emergency essential employee in a combat zone is an exigency of the public business for that employee. Any leave that, by reason of such service, is lost by the employee by operation of this section (regardless of whether such leave was scheduled) shall be restored to the employee and shall be credited and available in accordance with paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> As used in subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the term “Department of Defense emergency essential employee” means an employee of the Department of Defense who is designated under <ref>section 1580 of title 10</ref> as an emergency essential employee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the term “combat zone” has the meaning given such term in section 112(c)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Annual leave otherwise accruable after <date date="1960-06-30">June 30, 1960</date>, which is lost by operation of this section because of administrative error and which is not credited under subsection (d)(2) of this section because the employee is separated before the error is discovered, is subject to credit and liquidation by lump-sum payment only if a claim therefor is filed within 3 years immediately following the date of discovery of the error. Payment shall be made by the agency of employment when the lump-sum payment provisions of <ref>section 5551 of this title</ref> last became applicable to the employee at the rate of basic pay in effect on the date the lump-sum provisions became applicable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> This subsection applies with respect to annual leave accrued by an individual while serving in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a position in the Senior Executive Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a position in the Senior Foreign Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a position in the Defense Intelligence Senior Executive Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a position in the Senior Cryptologic Executive Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a position in the Federal Bureau of Investigation and Drug Enforcement Administration Senior Executive Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a position to which section 5376 applies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a position designated under <ref>section 1607(a) of title 10</ref> as an Intelligence Senior Level position; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002127">1</ref> a position in the Library of Congress the compensation for which is set at a rate equal to the annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> <sup>1</sup> a position in the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division at the rank of Deputy Chief, Assistant Chief, or Chief.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of applying any limitation on accumulation under this section with respect to any annual leave described in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> “30 days” in subsection (a) shall be deemed to read “90 days”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> “45 days” in subsection (b) shall be deemed to read “90 days”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 519</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–181, § 3</ref>, <date date="1973-12-14">Dec. 14, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 705</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, § 410</ref>, title IX, § 906(a)(2), (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1173</ref>, 1224; <ref>Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(39)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 383</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2312(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2166</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–89, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="1981-12-04">Dec. 4, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1161</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–325, § 2(k)</ref>, <date date="1988-05-30">May 30, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 582</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(53)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1354</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV, § 4434</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 341(c)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2816(a), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2720</ref>, 3056; <ref>Pub. L. 103–356, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3411</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title XI, § 1105</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2142</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title XI, § 1103(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 776</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XI, § 1112</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–68, div. A, title I, § 1404(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2038</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–282, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3038</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6305.</num>
<heading> Home leave; leave for Chiefs of Missions; leave for crews of vessels</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> After 24 months of continuous service outside the United States (or after a shorter period of such service if the employee’s assignment is terminated for the convenience of the Government), an employee may be granted leave of absence, under regulations of the President, at a rate not to exceed 1 week for each 4 months of that service without regard to other leave provided by this subchapter. Leave so granted—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is for use in the United States, or if the employee’s place of residence is outside the area of employment, in its territories or possessions including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> accumulates for future use without regard to the limitation in <ref>section 6304(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may not be made the basis for terminal leave or for a lump-sum payment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The President may authorize leave of absence to a chief of mission excepted from this subchapter by <ref>section 6301(2)(xii) of this title</ref> for use in the United States and its territories or possessions. Leave so authorized does not constitute a leave system and may not be made the basis for a lump-sum payment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> An officer, crewmember, or other employee serving aboard an oceangoing vessel on an extended voyage may be granted leave of absence, under regulations of the Office of Personnel Management, at a rate not to exceed 2 days for each 30 calendar days of that service without regard to other leave provided by this subchapter. Leave so granted—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> accumulates for future use without regard to the limitation in <ref>section 6304(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may not be made the basis for a lump-sum payment, except that civil service mariners of the Military Sealift Command on temporary promotion aboard ship may be paid the difference between their temporary and permanent rates of pay for leave accrued under this section and section 6303 and not otherwise used during the temporary promotion upon the expiration or termination of the temporary promotion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may not be made the basis for terminal leave except under such special or emergency circumstances as may be prescribed under the regulations of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> With respect to an officer, crewmember, or other employee of the Department of Defense serving aboard an oceangoing vessel on an extended voyage, the first sentence in the matter preceding paragraph (1) of subsection (c) of this section shall be applied by substituting “7 calendar days” for “30 calendar days”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–747, § 1(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1179</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–623, § 1(16)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1313</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–465, title II</ref>, §§ 2312(c), 2314(f)(2), <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2167</ref>, 2168; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1133], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–318; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XI, § 1110</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 428</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6306.</num>
<heading> Annual leave; refund of lump-sum payment; recredit of annual leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When an individual who received a lump-sum payment for leave under <ref>section 5551 of this title</ref> is reemployed before the end of the period covered by the lump-sum payment in or under the Government of the United States or the government of the District of Columbia, except in a position excepted from this subchapter by section 6301(2)(ii), (iii), (vi), or (vii) of this title, he shall refund to the employing agency an amount equal to the pay covering the period between the date of reemployment and the expiration of the lump-sum period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An amount refunded under subsection (a) of this section shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the employing agency. When an individual is reemployed under the same leave system, an amount of leave equal to the leave represented by the refund shall be recredited to him in the employing agency. When an individual is reemployed under a different leave system, an amount of leave equal to the leave represented by the refund shall be recredited to him in the employing agency on an adjusted basis under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management. When an individual is reemployed in a position excepted from this subchapter by section 6301(2)(x)–(xiii) of this title, an amount of leave equal to the leave represented by the refund is deemed, on separation from the service, death, or transfer to another position in the service, to have remained to his credit.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–519, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-10-25">Oct. 25, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307.</num>
<heading> Sick leave; accrual and accumulation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An employee is entitled to sick leave with pay which accrues on the basis of one-half day for each full biweekly pay period, except that sick leave with pay accrues to a member of the Firefighting Division of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia on the basis of two-fifths of a day for each full biweekly pay period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Sick leave provided by this section, which is not used by an employee, accumulates for use in succeeding years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Sick leave provided by this section may be used for purposes relating to the adoption of a child.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> When required by the exigencies of the situation, a maximum of 30 days sick leave with pay may be advanced for serious disability or ailment, or for purposes relating to the adoption of a child, except that a maximum of 24 days sick leave with pay may be advanced to a member of the Firefighting Division of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau class="indent0">(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002128">1</ref> For the purpose of this subsection, the term “family member” shall have such meaning as the Office of Personnel Management shall by regulation prescribe, except that such term shall include any individual who meets the definition given that term, for purposes of the leave transfer program under subchapter III, under regulations prescribed by the Office (as in effect on <date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>).</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (3) and in addition to any other allowable purpose, sick leave may be used by an employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to give care or otherwise attend to a family member having an illness, injury, or other condition which, if an employee had such condition, would justify the use of sick leave by such an employee; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for purposes relating to the death of a family member, including to make arrangements for or attend the funeral of such family member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Sick leave may be used by an employee for the purposes provided under paragraph (2) only to the extent the amount used for such purposes does not exceed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 40 hours in any year, plus</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> up to an additional 64 hours in any year, but only to the extent the use of such additional hours does not cause the amount of sick leave to the employee’s credit to fall below 80 hours.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of a part-time employee or an employee on an uncommon tour of duty, the Office of Personnel Management shall establish limitations that are proportional to those prescribed under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> This subsection shall be effective during the 3-year period that begins upon the expiration of the 2-month period that begins on the date of the enactment of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Not later than 6 months before the date on which this subsection is scheduled to cease to be effective, the Office shall submit a report to Congress in which it shall evaluate the operation of this subsection and make recommendations as to whether or not this subsection should be continued beyond such date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–329, title VI, § 629(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-30">Sept. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2423</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–388, § 2</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6308.</num>
<heading> Transfers between positions under different leave systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The annual and sick leave to the credit of an employee who transfers between positions under different leave systems without a break in service shall be transferred to his credit in the employing agency on an adjusted basis under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, unless the individual is excepted from this subchapter by section 6301(2)(ii), (iii), (vi), or (vii) of this title. However, when a former member receiving a retirement annuity under sections 521–535 of title 4, District of Columbia Code, is reemployed in a position to which this subchapter applies, his sick leave balance may not be recredited to his account on the later reemployment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The annual leave, sick leave, and home leave to the credit of a nonappropriated fund employee of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard described in section 2105(c) who moves without a break in service of more than 3 days to a position in the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively, that is subject to this subchapter shall be transferred to the employee’s credit. The annual leave, sick leave, and home leave to the credit of an employee of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard who is subject to this subchapter and who moves without a break in service of more than 3 days to a position under a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively, described in section 2105(c), shall be transferred to the employee’s credit under the nonappropriated fund instrumentality. The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, may provide for a transfer of funds in an amount equal to the value of the transferred annual leave to compensate the gaining entity for the cost of a transfer of annual leave under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title VII, § 7202(h)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–336</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title IX, § 902(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 566</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 6309.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–183, § 2(26)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1058</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6310.</num>
<heading> Leave of absence; aliens</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of the agency concerned may grant leave of absence with pay, not in excess of the amount of annual and sick leave allowable to citizen employees under this subchapter, to alien employees who occupy positions outside the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 521</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6311.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management may prescribe regulations necessary for the administration of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6312.</num>
<heading> Accrual and accumulation for former ASCS county office and nonappropriated fund employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Credit shall be given in determining years of service for the purpose of section 6303(a) for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> service as an employee of a county committee established pursuant to section 8(b) of the Soil Conservation and Allotment Act or of a committee or an association of producers described in section 10(b) of the Agricultural Adjustment Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> service under a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard described in section 2105(c) by an employee who has moved without a break in service of more than 3 days to a position subject to this subchapter in the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of section 6308 for transfer of leave between leave systems shall apply to the leave systems established for such county office employees and employees of such Department of Defense and Coast Guard nonappropriated fund instrumentalities, respectively.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–367, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-06-29">June 29, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 277</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 90–623, § 1(25)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–251, title III, § 306(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title VII, § 7202(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–337</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>OTHER PAID LEAVE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6321.</num>
<heading> Absence of veterans to attend funeral services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employee in or under an Executive agency who is a veteran of a war, or of a campaign or expedition for which a campaign badge has been authorized, or a member of an honor or ceremonial group of an organization of those veterans, may be excused from duty without loss of pay or deduction from annual leave for the time necessary, not to exceed 4 hours in any one day, to enable him to participate as an active pallbearer or as a member of a firing squad or a guard of honor in a funeral ceremony for a member of the armed forces whose remains are returned from abroad for final interment in the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 521</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6322.</num>
<heading> Leave for jury or witness service; official duty status for certain witness service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An employee as defined by <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref> (except an individual whose pay is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate or the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives) or an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia is entitled to leave, without loss of, or reduction in, pay, leave to which he otherwise is entitled, credit for time or service, or performance of efficiency rating, during a period of absence with respect to which he is summoned, in connection with a judicial proceeding, by a court or authority responsible for the conduct of that proceeding, to serve—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> as a juror; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other than as provided in subsection (b) of this section, as a witness on behalf of any party in connection with any judicial proceeding to which the United States, the District of Columbia, or a State or local government is a party;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">in the District of Columbia, a State, territory, or possession of the United States including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands. For the purpose of this subsection, “judicial proceeding” means any action, suit, or other judicial proceeding, including any condemnation, preliminary, informational, or other proceeding of a judicial nature, but does not include an administrative proceeding.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An employee as defined by <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref> (except an individual whose pay is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate or the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives) or an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia is performing official duty during the period with respect to which he is summoned, or assigned by his agency, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> testify or produce official records on behalf of the United States or the District of Columbia; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> testify in his official capacity or produce official records on behalf of a party other than the United States or the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management may prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 522</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–563, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-19">Dec. 19, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1476</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–310, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-06-15">June 15, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–70, title I, § 1251</ref>, <date date="1979-09-27">Sept. 27, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 476</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 215(10)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1746</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXV, § 3548(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6323.</num>
<heading> Military leave: Reserves, National Guard members, and certain members of the Space Force</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an employee as defined by <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref> or an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia, permanent or temporary indefinite, is entitled to leave without loss in pay, time, or performance or efficiency rating for active duty, inactive-duty training (as defined in <ref>section 101 of title 37</ref>), funeral honors duty (as described in <ref>section 12503 of title 10</ref> and <ref>section 115 of title 32</ref>), or engaging in field or coast defense training under sections 502–505 of title 32 as a Reserve of the armed forces, a member of the National Guard, or a member of the Space Force in space force active status (as defined in <ref>section 101(e)(1) of title 10</ref>) and not on sustained duty under <ref>section 20105 of title 10</ref>. Leave under this subsection accrues for an employee or individual at the rate of 20 days per fiscal year and, to the extent that it is not used in a fiscal year, accumulates for use in the succeeding fiscal year until it totals 20 days at the beginning of a fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of an employee or individual employed on a part-time career employment basis (as defined in <ref>section 3401(2) of this title</ref>), the rate at which leave accrues under this subsection shall be a percentage of the rate prescribed under paragraph (1) which is determined by dividing 40 into the number of hours in the regularly scheduled workweek of that employee or individual during that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The minimum charge for leave under this subsection is one hour, and additional charges are in multiples thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided by <ref>section 5519 of this title</ref>, an employee as defined by <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref> or an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia, permanent or temporary indefinite, who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is a member of a Reserve component of the Armed Forces, as described in <ref>section 10101 of title 10</ref>, or the National Guard, as described in <ref>section 101 of title 32</ref> or is a member of the Space Force in space force active status (as defined in <ref>section 101(e)(1) of title 10</ref>) and not on sustained duty under <ref>section 20105 of title 10</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> performs, for the purpose of providing military aid to enforce the law or for the purpose of providing assistance to civil authorities in the protection or saving of life or property or the prevention of injury—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Federal service under section 331, 332, 333,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002129">1</ref> or 12406 of title 10, or other provision of law, as applicable, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> full-time military service for his State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or a territory of the United States; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> performs full-time military service as a result of a call or order to active duty in support of a contingency operation as defined in <ref>section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is entitled, during and because of such service, to leave without loss of, or reduction in, pay, leave to which he otherwise is entitled, credit for time or service, or performance or efficiency rating. Leave granted by this subsection shall not exceed 22 workdays in a calendar year. Upon the request of an employee, the period for which an employee is absent to perform service described in paragraph (2) may be charged to the employee’s accrued annual leave or to compensatory time available to the employee instead of being charged as leave to which the employee is entitled under this subsection. The period of absence may not be charged to sick leave.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An employee as defined by <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref> or an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia, who is a member of the National Guard of the District of Columbia, is entitled to leave without loss in pay or time for each day of a parade or encampment ordered or authorized under title 39, District of Columbia Code. This subsection covers each day of service the National Guard, or a portion thereof, is ordered to perform by the commanding general.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A military reserve technician described in section 8401(30) <sup>1</sup> is entitled at such person’s request to leave without loss of, or reduction in, pay, leave to which such person is otherwise entitled, credit for time or service, or performance or efficiency rating for each day, not to exceed 44 workdays in a calendar year, in which such person is on active duty without pay, as authorized pursuant to <ref>section 12315 of title 10</ref>, under section 12301(b) or 12301(d) of title 10 for participation in operations outside the United States, its territories and possessions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An employee who requests annual leave or compensatory time to which the employee is otherwise entitled, for a period during which the employee would have been entitled upon request to leave under this subsection, may be granted such annual leave or compensatory time without regard to this section or section 5519.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 522</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–588, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–623, § 1(17)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1313</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–375, § 6(c)(18)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 776</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(40)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 383</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–70, title III, § 3302(e)(5)</ref>, <date date="1979-09-27">Sept. 27, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–431, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1850</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 528</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1677(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3019</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 516(a)</ref>, title X, § 1039, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 309</ref>, 432; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title VI, § 672(b)</ref>, title XI, §§ 1105(a), 1106(a), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 674</ref>, 777; <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(3) [title VI, § 642]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–169; <ref>Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 563</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 1120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1113(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1635</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 523</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1888</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XI</ref>, §§ 1109, 1114(a), (b)(1), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2089</ref>, 2091.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6324.</num>
<heading> Absence of certain police and firemen</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Sick leave may not be charged to the account of a member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, or the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division for an absence due to injury or illness resulting from the performance of duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The determination of whether an injury or illness resulted from the performance of duty shall be made under regulations prescribed by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia Council for members of the Metropolitan Police force and the Fire Department of the District of Columbia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Interior for the United States Park Police force; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Homeland Security for the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply to members of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division who are covered under chapter 84 for the purpose of retirement benefits.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 522</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–623, § 1(18)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1313</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–183, § 2(28)</ref>, (29), <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1058</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–282, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3038</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6325.</num>
<heading> Absence resulting from hostile action abroad</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Leave may not be charged to the account of an employee for absence, not to exceed one year, due to an injury—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> incurred while serving abroad and resulting from war, insurgency, mob violence, or similar hostile action; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not due to vicious habits, intemperance, or willful misconduct on the part of the employee.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The preceding provisions of this section shall apply in the case of an alien employee referred to in <ref>section 6301(2)(viii) of this title</ref> with respect to any leave granted to such alien employee under <ref>section 6310 of this title</ref> or section 408 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–221, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1967-12-23">Dec. 23, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 671</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(41)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 383</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–399, title VIII, § 804</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 883</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6326.</num>
<heading> Absence in connection with funerals of immediate relatives in the Armed Forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An employee of an executive agency or an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia is entitled to not more than three days of leave without loss of, or reduction in, pay, leave to which he is otherwise entitled, credit for time or service, or performance or efficiency rating, to make arrangements for, or attend the funeral of, or memorial service for, an immediate relative who died as a result of wounds, disease, or injury incurred while serving as a member of the Armed Forces in a combat zone (as determined by the President in accordance with section 112 of the Internal Revenue Code).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management is authorized to issue regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section shall not be considered as affecting the authority of an Executive agency, except to the extent and under the conditions covered under this section, to grant administrative leave excusing an employee from work when it is in the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–588, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 1151</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6327.</num>
<heading> Absence in connection with serving as a bone-marrow or organ donor</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An employee in or under an Executive agency is entitled to leave without loss of or reduction in pay, leave to which otherwise entitled, credit for time or service, or performance or efficiency rating, for the time necessary to permit such employee to serve as a bone-marrow or organ donor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An employee may, in any calendar year, use—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not to exceed 7 days of leave under this section to serve as a bone-marrow donor; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not to exceed 30 days of leave under this section to serve as an organ donor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management may prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–329, title VI, § 629(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-30">Sept. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2423</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–56, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-09-24">Sept. 24, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 407</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6328.</num>
<heading> Absence in connection with funerals of fellow Federal law enforcement officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Federal law enforcement officer or a Federal firefighter may be excused from duty without loss of, or reduction in, pay or leave to which such officer is otherwise entitled, or credit for time or service, or performance or efficiency rating, to attend the funeral of a fellow Federal law enforcement officer or Federal firefighter, who was killed in the line of duty. When so excused from duty, attendance at such service shall for the purposes of <ref>section 1345(a) of title 31</ref>, be considered to be an official duty of the officer or firefighter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–329, title VI, § 642</ref>, <date date="1994-09-30">Sept. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2432</ref>, § 6327; renumbered § 6328, <ref>Pub. L. 106–56, § 1(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-09-24">Sept. 24, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 407</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6329.</num>
<heading> Disabled veteran leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> During the 12-month period beginning on the first day of employment, any employee who is a veteran with a service-connected disability rated at 30 percent or more is entitled to leave, without loss or reduction in pay, for purposes of undergoing medical treatment for such disability for which sick leave could regularly be used.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The leave credited to an employee under subsection (a) may not exceed 104 hours.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any leave credited to an employee pursuant to subsection (a) that is not used during the 12-month period described in such subsection may not be carried over and shall be forfeited.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In order to verify that leave credited to an employee pursuant to subsection (a) is used for treating a service-connected disability, such employee shall submit to the head of the employing agency certification, in such form and manner as the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe, that such employee used such leave for purposes of being furnished treatment for such disability by a health care provider.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of an employee of an office of the legislative branch, the certification described in paragraph (1) shall be prescribed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an employee of the House of Representatives, by the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an employee of the Senate, by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of an employee of any other office of the legislative branch, by the head of the office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “employee” has the meaning given such term in section 2105, and includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an officer or employee of the United States Postal Service or the Postal Regulatory Commission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> notwithstanding subsection (a) of <ref>section 7421 of title 38</ref>, an individual occupying a position listed in subsection (b) of such section;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “service-connected” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 101(16) of title 38</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “veteran” has the meaning given such term in section 101(2) of such title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–75, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-05">Nov. 5, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 640</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–238, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-09-07">Sept. 7, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–364, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5088</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6329a.</num>
<heading> Administrative leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “administrative leave” means leave—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> without loss of or reduction in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> pay;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> leave to which an employee is otherwise entitled under law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> credit for time or service; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is not authorized under any other provision of law;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “agency”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means an Executive agency (as defined in <ref>section 105 of this title</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> does not include the Government Accountability Office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “employee”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has the meaning given the term in section 2105; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include an intermittent employee who does not have an established regular tour of duty during the administrative workweek.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Administrative Leave.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>During any calendar year, an agency may place an employee in administrative leave for a period of not more than a total of 10 work days.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agency shall record administrative leave separately from leave authorized under any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Regulations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">OPM regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 270 calendar days after the date of enactment of this section, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prescribe regulations to carry out this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> prescribe regulations that provide guidance to agencies regarding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> acceptable agency uses of administrative leave; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the proper recording of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> administrative leave; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> other leave authorized by law.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 270 calendar days after the date on which the Director of the Office of Personnel Management prescribes regulations under paragraph (1), each agency shall revise and implement the internal policies of the agency to meet the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relation to Other Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of <ref>section 7421 of title 38</ref>, this section shall apply to an employee described in subsection (b) of that section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XI, § 1138(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2461</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6329b.</num>
<heading> Investigative leave and notice leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “agency”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means an Executive agency (as defined in <ref>section 105 of this title</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> does not include the Government Accountability Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “Chief Human Capital Officer” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Chief Human Capital Officer of an agency designated or appointed under section 1401; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the equivalent;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “committees of jurisdiction”, with respect to an agency, means each committee of the Senate or House of Representatives with jurisdiction over the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Personnel Management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> the term “employee”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has the meaning given the term in section 2105; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an intermittent employee who does not have an established regular tour of duty during the administrative workweek; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Inspector General of an agency;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> the term “investigative entity” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an internal investigative unit of an agency granting investigative leave under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Office of Inspector General of an agency granting investigative leave under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Attorney General; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Office of Special Counsel;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> the term “investigative leave” means leave—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> without loss of or reduction in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> pay;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> leave to which an employee is otherwise entitled under law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> credit for time or service;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is not authorized under any other provision of law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in which an employee who is the subject of an investigation is placed;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> the term “notice leave” means leave—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> without loss of or reduction in—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> pay;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> leave to which an employee is otherwise entitled under law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> credit for time or service;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is not authorized under any other provision of law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in which an employee who is in a notice period is placed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the term “notice period” means a period beginning on the date on which an employee is provided notice required under law of a proposed adverse action against the employee and ending on the date on which an agency may take the adverse action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Leave for Employees Under Investigation or in a Notice Period.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An agency may, in accordance with paragraph (2), place an employee in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> investigative leave if the employee is the subject of an investigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> notice leave if the employee is in a notice period; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> notice leave following a placement in investigative leave if, not later than the day after the last day of the period of investigative leave—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the agency proposes or initiates an adverse action against the employee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the agency determines that the employee continues to meet 1 or more of the criteria described in paragraph (2)(A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An agency may place an employee in leave under paragraph (1) only if the agency has—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> made a determination with respect to the employee that the continued presence of the employee in the workplace during an investigation of the employee or while the employee is in a notice period, as applicable, may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> pose a threat to the employee or others;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> result in the destruction of evidence relevant to an investigation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> result in loss of or damage to Government property; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> otherwise jeopardize legitimate Government interests;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> considered—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assigning the employee to duties in which the employee no longer poses a threat described in clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (A);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> allowing the employee to take leave for which the employee is eligible;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if the employee is absent from duty without approved leave, carrying the employee in absence without leave status; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> for an employee subject to a notice period, curtailing the notice period if there is reasonable cause to believe the employee has committed a crime for which a sentence of imprisonment may be imposed; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> determined that none of the available options under clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (B) is appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Duration of leave.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Investigative leave</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon the expiration of the 10 work day period described in section 6329a(b)(1) with respect to an employee, and if an agency determines that an extended investigation of the employee is necessary, the agency may place the employee in investigative leave for a period of not more than 30 work days.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice leave</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Placement of an employee in notice leave shall be for a period not longer than the duration of the notice period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Explanation of leave.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an agency places an employee in leave under this subsection, the agency shall provide the employee a written explanation of whether the employee was placed in investigative leave or notice leave.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Explanation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The written notice under subparagraph (A) shall describe the limitations of the leave placement, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the applicable limitations under paragraph (3); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a placement in investigative leave, an explanation that, at the conclusion of the period of leave, the agency shall take an action under paragraph (5).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency action</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than the day after the last day of a period of investigative leave for an employee under paragraph (1), an agency shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> return the employee to regular duty status;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> take 1 or more of the actions under clauses (i) through (iv) of paragraph (2)(B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> propose or initiate an adverse action against the employee as provided under law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> extend the period of investigative leave under subsections (c) and (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in paragraph (5) shall be construed to prevent the continued investigation of an employee, except that the placement of an employee in investigative leave may not be extended for that purpose except as provided in subsections (c) and (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Initial Extension of Investigative Leave.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraph (4), if the Chief Human Capital Officer of an agency, or the designee of the Chief Human Capital Officer, approves such an extension after consulting with the investigator responsible for conducting the investigation to which an employee is subject, the agency may extend the period of investigative leave for the employee under subsection (b) for not more than 30 work days.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Maximum number of extensions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The total period of additional investigative leave for an employee under paragraph (1) may not exceed 90 work days.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Chief Human Capital Officers Council shall issue guidance to ensure that if the Chief Human Capital Officer of an agency delegates the authority to approve an extension under paragraph (1) to a designee, the designee is at a sufficiently high level within the agency to make an impartial and independent determination regarding the extension.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Extensions for OIG employees.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the case of an employee of an Office of Inspector General—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Inspector General or the designee of the Inspector General, rather than the Chief Human Capital Officer or the designee of the Chief Human Capital Officer, shall approve an extension of a period of investigative leave for the employee under paragraph (1); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> at the request of the Inspector General, the head of the agency within which the Office of Inspector General is located shall designate an official of the agency to approve an extension of a period of investigative leave for the employee under paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 270 calendar days after the date of enactment of this section, the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency shall issue guidance to ensure that if the Inspector General or the head of an agency, at the request of the Inspector General, delegates the authority to approve an extension under subparagraph (A) to a designee, the designee is at a sufficiently high level within the Office of Inspector General or the agency, as applicable, to make an impartial and independent determination regarding the extension.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Further Extension of Investigative Leave.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>After reaching the limit under subsection (c)(2) and if an investigative entity submits a certification under paragraph (2) of this subsection, an agency may further extend a period of investigative leave for an employee for periods of not more than 30 work days each if, not later than 5 business days after granting each further extension, the agency submits to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, along with any other committees of jurisdiction, a report containing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the title, position, office or agency subcomponent, job series, pay grade, and salary of the employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a description of the duties of the employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the reason the employee was placed in investigative leave;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> an explanation as to why—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the employee poses a threat described in clauses (i) through (iv) of subsection (b)(2)(A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the agency is not able to reassign the employee to another position within the agency;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an employee required to telework under section 6502(c) during the investigation of the employee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the reasons that the agency required the employee to telework under that section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the duration of the teleworking requirement;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the status of the investigation of the employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the certification described in paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a completed investigation of the employee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the results of the investigation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the reason that the employee remains in investigative leave.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If, after an employee has reached the limit under subsection (c)(2), an investigative entity determines that additional time is needed to complete the investigation of the employee, the investigative entity shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> certify to the appropriate agency that additional time is needed to complete the investigation of the employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> include in the certification an estimate of the amount of time that is necessary to complete the investigation of the employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No extensions after completion of investigation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agency may not further extend a period of investigative leave of an employee under paragraph (1) on or after the date that is 30 calendar days after the completion of the investigation of the employee by an investigative entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consultation Guidance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 270 calendar days after the date of enactment of this section, the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Special Counsel, shall issue guidance on best practices for consultation between an investigator and an agency on the need to place an employee in investigative leave during an investigation of the employee, including during a criminal investigation, because the continued presence of the employee in the workplace during the investigation may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pose a threat to the employee or others;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> result in the destruction of evidence relevant to an investigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> result in loss of or damage to Government property; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> otherwise jeopardize legitimate Government interests.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reporting and Records.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An agency shall keep a record of the placement of an employee in investigative leave or notice leave by the agency, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the basis for the determination made under subsection (b)(2)(A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an explanation of why an action under clauses (i) through (iv) of subsection (b)(2)(B) was not appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the length of the period of leave;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the amount of salary paid to the employee during the period of leave;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the reasons for authorizing the leave, including, if applicable, the recommendation made by an investigator under subsection (c)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> whether the employee is required to telework under section 6502(c) during the investigation, including the reasons for requiring the employee to telework; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the action taken by the agency at the end of the period of leave, including, if applicable, the granting of any extension of a period of investigative leave under subsection (c) or (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of records</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An agency shall make a record kept under paragraph (1) available—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to any committee of jurisdiction, upon request;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the Office of Personnel Management; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> as otherwise required by law, including for the purposes of the Administrative Leave Act of 2016 and the amendments made by that Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recourse to the Office of Special Counsel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of subchapter II of chapter 12 and section 1221, placement on investigative leave under subsection (b) of this section for a period of not less than 70 work days shall be considered a personnel action under paragraph (8) or (9) of section 2302(b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Regulations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">OPM action</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 270 calendar days after the date of enactment of this section, the Director shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section, including guidance to agencies regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> acceptable purposes for the use of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> investigative leave; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> notice leave;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the proper recording of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the leave categories described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> other leave authorized by law;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> baseline factors that an agency shall consider when making a determination that the continued presence of an employee in the workplace may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> pose a threat to the employee or others;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> result in the destruction of evidence relevant to an investigation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> result in loss or damage to Government property; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> otherwise jeopardize legitimate Government interests; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> procedures and criteria for the approval of an extension of a period of investigative leave under subsection (c) or (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agency action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 270 calendar days after the date on which the Director prescribes regulations under paragraph (1), each agency shall revise and implement the internal policies of the agency to meet the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relation to Other Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of <ref>section 7421 of title 38</ref>, this section shall apply to an employee described in subsection (b) of that section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XI, § 1138(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6329c.</num>
<heading> Weather and safety leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “agency”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means an Executive agency (as defined in <ref>section 105 of this title</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> does not include the Government Accountability Office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “employee”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has the meaning given the term in section 2105; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> does not include an intermittent employee who does not have an established regular tour of duty during the administrative workweek.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leave for Weather and Safety Issues</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An agency may approve the provision of leave under this section to an employee or a group of employees without loss of or reduction in the pay of the employee or employees, leave to which the employee or employees are otherwise entitled, or credit to the employee or employees for time or service only if the employee or group of employees is prevented from safely traveling to or performing work at an approved location due to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an act of God;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a terrorist attack; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> another condition that prevents the employee or group of employees from safely traveling to or performing work at an approved location.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agency shall record leave provided under this section separately from leave authorized under any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> guidance to agencies regarding the appropriate purposes for providing leave under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the proper recording of leave provided under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relation to Other Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of <ref>section 7421 of title 38</ref>, this section shall apply to an employee described in subsection (b) of that section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XI, § 1138(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2469</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6329d.</num>
<heading> Parental bereavement leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the terms “employee” and “son or daughter” have the meanings given those terms in section 6381; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “paid leave” means, with respect to an employee, leave without loss of or reduction in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pay;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> leave to which the employee is otherwise entitled under law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> credit for time or service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Bereavement Leave.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), an employee shall be entitled to a total of 2 administrative workweeks of paid leave during any 12-month period because of the death of a son or daughter of the employee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Leave under paragraph (1) may not be taken by an employee intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule unless the employee and the employing agency of the employee agree otherwise.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any case in which the necessity for leave under this subsection is foreseeable, the employee shall provide the employing agency with such notice as is reasonable and practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XI, § 1111(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>VOLUNTARY TRANSFERS OF LEAVE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6331.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “employee” means an employee as defined by section 6301(2), excluding an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “leave recipient” means an employee whose application to receive donations of leave under this subchapter is approved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “leave donor” means an employee whose application to make 1 or more donations of leave under this subchapter is approved; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “medical emergency” means a medical condition of an employee or a family member of such employee that is likely to require the prolonged absence of such employee from duty and to result in a substantial loss of income to such employee because of the unavailability of paid leave (disregarding any advanced leave).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2834</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–103, § 3</ref>, <date date="1993-10-08">Oct. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6332.</num>
<heading> General authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any provision of subchapter I, and subject to the provisions of this subchapter, the Office of Personnel Management shall establish a program under which annual leave accrued or accumulated by an employee may be transferred to the annual leave account of any other employee if such other employee requires additional leave because of a medical emer­gency.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6333.</num>
<heading> Receipt and use of transferred leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An application to receive donations of leave under this subchapter, whether submitted by or on behalf of an employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be submitted to the employing agency of the proposed leave recipient; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the name, position title, and grade or pay level of the proposed leave recipient;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the reasons why transferred leave is needed, including a brief description of the nature, severity, anticipated duration, and, if it is a recurring one, the approximate frequency of the medical emergency involved;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if the employing agency so requires, certification from 1 or more physicians, or other appropriate experts, with respect to any matter under clause (ii); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other information which the employing agency may reasonably require.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If an agency requires that an employee obtain certification under paragraph (1)(B)(iii) from 2 or more sources, the agency shall ensure, either by direct payment to the expert involved or by reimbursement, that the employee is not required to pay for the expenses associated with obtaining certification from more than 1 of such sources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An employing agency shall approve or disapprove an application of a proposed leave recipient for leave under this subchapter, and, to the extent practicable, shall notify the proposed leave recipient (or other person acting on behalf of the proposed recipient, if appropriate) of the decision of the agency, in writing, within 10 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal public holidays) after receiving such application.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A leave recipient may use annual leave received under this subchapter in the same manner and for the same purposes as if such leave recipient had accrued that leave under section 6303, except that any annual leave, and any sick leave, accrued or accumulated by the leave recipient and available for the purpose involved must be exhausted before any transferred annual leave may be used.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The requirement under paragraph (1) relating to exhaustion of annual and sick leave shall not apply in the case of a leave recipient who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> sustains a combat-related disability while a member of the armed forces, including a reserve component of the armed forces; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is undergoing medical treatment for that disability.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) shall apply to a member described in such subparagraph only so long as the member continues to undergo medical treatment for the disability, but in no event for longer than 5 years from the start of such treatment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the term “combat-related disability” has the meaning given such term by <ref>section 1413a(e) of title 10</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the term “medical treatment” has such meaning as the Office of Personnel Management shall by regulation prescribe.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Transferred annual leave—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may accumulate without regard to any limitation under section 6304; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may be substituted retroactively for any period of leave without pay, or used to liquidate an indebtedness for any period of advanced leave, which began on or after a date fixed by the employing agency of the employee as the beginning of the medical emergency involved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2834</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XVI, § 1675(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 484</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6334.</num>
<heading> Donations of leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An employee may, by written application to the employing agency of such employee, request that a specified number of hours be transferred from the annual leave account of such employee to the annual leave account of a leave recipient in accordance with section 6332.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In any one leave year, a leave donor may donate no more than a total of one-half of the amount of annual leave such donor would be entitled to accrue during the leave year in which the donation is made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A leave donor who is projected to have annual leave that otherwise would be subject to forfeiture at the end of the leave year under section 6304(a) may donate no more than the number of hours remaining in the leave year (as of the date of the transfer) for which the leave donor is scheduled to work and receive pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The employing agency of a leave donor may waive the limitation under paragraphs (1) and (2). Any such waiver shall be made in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations to include procedures to carry out this subchapter when the leave donor and the leave recipient are employed by different agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2835</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6335.</num>
<heading> Termination of medical emergency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The medical emergency affecting a leave recipient shall, for purposes of this subchapter, be considered to have terminated on the date as of which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the leave recipient notifies the employing agency of such leave recipient, in writing, that the medical emergency no longer exists;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the employing agency of such leave recipient determines, after written notice and opportunity for the leave recipient (or, if appropriate, another person acting on behalf of the leave recipient) to answer orally or in writing, that the medical emergency no longer exists; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the leave recipient is separated from service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The employing agency of a leave recipient shall, consistent with guidelines prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, establish procedures to ensure that a leave recipient is not permitted to use or receive any transferred leave under this subchapter after the medical emergency terminates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in section 5551, 5552, or 6306 shall apply with respect to any annual leave transferred to a leave recipient under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6336.</num>
<heading> Restoration of transferred leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall establish procedures under which, except as provided in paragraph (2), any transferred leave remaining to the credit of a leave recipient when the medical emergency affecting the leave recipient terminates shall be restored on a prorated basis by transfer to the appropriate accounts of the respective leave donors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in paragraph (1) shall require the restoration of leave to a leave donor—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the amount of leave which would be restored to such donor would be less than 1 hour or any other shorter period of time which the Office may by regulation prescribe;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if such donor retires, dies, or is otherwise separated from service, before the date on which such restoration would otherwise be made; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if such restoration is not administratively feasible, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> At the election of the leave donor, transferred annual leave restored to such leave donor under subsection (a) may be restored by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> crediting such leave to the leave donor’s annual leave account in the then current leave year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> crediting such leave to the leave donor’s annual leave account, effective as of the first day of the first leave year beginning after the date of the election; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> donating such leave in whole or part to another leave recipient; if a leave donor elects to donate only part of restored leave to another recipient, the donor may elect to have the remaining leave credited to the donor’s annual leave account in accordance with paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Office shall prescribe regulations under which this section shall be applied in the case of an employee who is paid other than on the basis of biweekly pay periods.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Restorations of leave under this section shall be carried out in a manner consistent with regulations prescribed to carry out section 6334(c), if applicable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6337.</num>
<heading> Accrual of leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “paid leave status under subchapter I”, as used with respect to an employee, means the administrative status of such employee while such employee is using sick leave, or annual leave, accrued or accumulated under subchapter I; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “transferred leave status”, as used with respect to an employee, means the administrative status of such employee while such employee is using transferred leave under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as otherwise provided in this section, while an employee is in a transferred leave status, annual leave and sick leave shall accrue to the credit of such employee at the same rate as if such employee were then in a paid leave status under subchapter I, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the maximum amount of annual leave which may be accrued by an employee while in transferred leave status in connection with any particular medical emergency may not exceed 5 days; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the maximum amount of sick leave which may be accrued by an employee while in transferred leave status in connection with any particular medical emergency may not exceed 5 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Any annual or sick leave accrued by an employee under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be credited to an annual leave or sick leave account, as appropriate, separate from any leave account of such employee under subchapter I; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall not become available for use by such employee, and may not otherwise be taken into account under subchapter I, until, in accordance with subsection (c), it is transferred to the appropriate leave account of such employee under subchapter I.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Any annual or sick leave accrued by an employee under this section shall be transferred to the appropriate leave account of such employee under subchapter I, and shall be available for use—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as of the beginning of the first applicable pay period beginning after the date on which the employee’s medical emergency terminates as described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 6335(a); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the employee’s medical emergency has not yet terminated, once the employee has exhausted all transferred leave made available to such employee under this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the event that the employee’s medical emergency terminates as described in section 6335(a)(3)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any leave accrued but not yet transferred under this section shall not be credited to such employee; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if there remains, as of the date the emergency so terminates, any leave which became available to such employee under paragraph (1)(B), such leave shall cease to be available for any purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be considered to prevent, with respect to a continuing medical emergency, further transfers of leave for use after leave accrued under this section has been exhausted by the employee.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2837</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–103, § 4</ref>, <date date="1993-10-08">Oct. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6338.</num>
<heading> Prohibition of coercion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An employee may not directly or indirectly intimidate, threaten, or coerce, or attempt to intimidate, threaten, or coerce, any other employee for the purpose of interfering with any right which such employee may have with respect to contributing, receiving, or using annual leave under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purpose of subsection (a), the term “intimidate, threaten, or coerce” includes promising to confer or conferring any benefit (such as an appointment, promotion, or compensation), or effecting or threatening to effect any reprisal (such as deprivation of appointment, promotion, or compensation).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6339.</num>
<heading> Additional leave transfer programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “excepted agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Central Intelligence Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Defense Intelligence Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the National Security Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> as determined by the President, any Executive agency or unit thereof, the principal function of which is the conduct of foreign intelligence or counterintelligence activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “head of an excepted agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to the Central Intelligence Agency, the Director of Central Intelligence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to the Defense Intelligence Agency, the Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> with respect to the National Security Agency, the Director of the National Security Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> with respect to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> with respect to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> with respect to an Executive agency designated under paragraph (1)(F), the head of such Executive agency, and with respect to a unit of an Executive agency designated under paragraph (1)(F), such individual as the President may determine.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The head of an excepted agency shall, by regulation, establish a program under which annual leave accrued or accumulated by an employee of such agency may be transferred to the annual leave account of any other employee of such agency if such other employee requires additional leave because of a medical emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> To the extent practicable, and consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods (if applicable), each program under this subsection shall be established—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in a manner consistent with the provisions of this subchapter applicable to the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> without regard to any provisions relating to transfers or restorations of leave between employees in different agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any provision of subsection (b), the head of an excepted agency may, at his sole discretion, by regulation establish a program under which an individual employed in or under such excepted agency may participate in a leave transfer program established under the provisions of this subchapter outside of this section, including provisions permitting the transfer of annual leave accrued or accumulated by such employee to, or permitting such employee to receive transferred leave from, an employee of any other agency (including another excepted agency having a program under this subsection).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To the extent practicable and consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods, any program established under paragraph (1) shall be consistent with the provisions of this subchapter outside of this section and with any regulations issued by the Office of Personnel Management implementing this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Office shall provide the head of an excepted agency with such advice and assistance as the head of such agency may request in order to carry out the purposes of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2838</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title V, § 501(i)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1122(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–306, title III, § 322</ref>, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2391</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 931(a)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4575</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6340.</num>
<heading> Inapplicability of certain provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except to the extent that the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe regulations, nothing in section 7351 shall apply with respect to a solicitation, donation, or acceptance of leave under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2838</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>VOLUNTARY LEAVE BANK PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6361.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “employee” means an employee as defined by section 6301(2), but shall exclude any individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “executive agency” means any executive agency or any administrative unit thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “leave bank” means a leave bank established under section 6363;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “leave contributor” means an employee who contributes leave to an agency leave bank under section 6365;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “leave recipient” means an employee whose application under section 6367 to receive contributions of leave from a leave bank is approved; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “medical emergency” means a medical condition of an employee or a family member of such employee that is likely to require the prolonged absence of such employee from duty and to result in a substantial loss of income to such employee because of the unavailability of paid leave (disregarding any advanced leave).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2839</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–103, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-08">Oct. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6362.</num>
<heading> General authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any provision of subchapter I, and subject to the provisions of this subchapter, the Office of Personnel Management shall establish a program under which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> annual leave accrued or accumulated by an employee may be contributed to a leave bank established by the employing agency of such employee; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> leave from such a leave bank may be made available to an employee who requires such leave because of a medical emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2839</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–103, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-08">Oct. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1023</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6363.</num>
<heading> Establishment of leave banks</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each agency that establishes a leave bank program under section 6362 shall establish 1 or more leave banks in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6364.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Leave Bank Boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each agency that establishes a leave bank shall establish a Leave Bank Board consisting of 3 members, at least one of whom shall represent a labor organization or employee group, to administer the leave bank under the provisions of this subchapter, in consultation with the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An agency may establish more than 1 Leave Bank Board based upon the administrative units within the agency. No more than 1 board may be established for each leave bank.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Each such Board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review and approve applications to the leave bank under section 6367;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> monitor each case of a leave recipient;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> monitor the amount of leave in the leave bank and the number of applications for use of leave from the bank; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> maintain an adequate amount of leave in the leave bank to the greatest extent practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6365.</num>
<heading> Contributions of annual leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee may, by written application to the Leave Bank Board, request that a specified number of hours be transferred from the annual leave account of such employee to the leave bank established by such agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An employee may state a concern and desire to aid a specified proposed leave recipient or a leave recipient in the application filed under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon approving an application under subsection (a), the employing agency of the leave contributor may transfer all or any part of the number of hours requested for transfer, except that the number of hours so transferred may not exceed the limitations under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In any one leave year, a leave contributor may contribute no more than a total of one-half of the amount of annual leave such contributor would be entitled to accrue during the leave year in which the contribution is made.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A leave contributor who is projected to have annual leave that otherwise would be subject to forfeiture at the end of the leave year under section 6304(a) may contribute no more than the number of hours remaining in the leave year (as of the date of the contribution) for which the leave contributor is scheduled to work and receive pay.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Leave Bank Board of a leave contributor may waive the limitations under subsection (b)(2). Any such waiver shall be in writing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations establishing an open enrollment period during which an employee may contribute leave under subsection (a) for a leave year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6366.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for leave recipients</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An employee is eligible to be a leave recipient if such employee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> experiences a medical emergency and submits an application pursuant to section 6367(a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contributes the minimum number of hours as required under subsection (b) of accrued or accumulated annual leave to the leave bank of the employing agency of such employee, in the leave year (beginning in and including any part of a leave year in which such leave bank is established) that such employee submits an application to be a leave recipient under section 6367(a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such contribution is made before such employee submits an application under section 6367(a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An employee shall contribute the minimum number of hours required under subsection (a)(2)(A), if such employee is an employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for less than 3 years of service and contributes a minimum of 4 hours;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for between 3 years and less than 15 years of service and contributes a minimum of 6 hours; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for 15 years or more of service and contributes a minimum of 8 hours.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1), the Leave Bank Board of an agency, after consultation with the Office of Personnel Management, may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reduce the minimum number of hours required under paragraph (1) for any leave year, if such Board determines there is a surplus of leave in the leave bank; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increase the number of minimum hours required under paragraph (1) for the succeeding leave year, in any leave year in which the Board determines there is a shortage of leave in the leave bank.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An employee shall meet the requirements of subsection (a)(2)(A) if such employee contributes the minimum number of hours as required under subsection (b) of accrued or accumulated annual leave to the leave bank with which such employee submits an application to be a leave recipient under section 6367(a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The provisions of subsection (a) may not be construed to limit the amount of the voluntary contribution of annual leave to a leave bank, which does not exceed the limitations of section 6365(b).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6367.</num>
<heading> Receipt and use of leave from a leave bank</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An application to receive contributions of leave from a leave bank, whether submitted by or on behalf of an employee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be submitted to the Leave Bank Board of the employing agency of the proposed leave recipient; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name, position title, and grade or pay level of the proposed leave recipient;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the reasons why leave is needed, including a brief description of the nature, severity, anticipated duration, and, if it is a recurring one, the approximate frequency of the medical emergency involved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if such Board so requires, certification from 1 or more physicians, or other appropriate experts, with respect to any matter under subparagraph (B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other information which such Board may reasonably require.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">If a Board requires that an employee obtain certification under paragraph (2)(C) from 2 or more sources, the agency shall ensure, either by direct payment to the expert involved or by reimbursement, that the employee is not required to pay for the expenses associated with obtaining certification from more than 1 of such sources.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Leave Bank Board of an employing agency may approve an application submitted under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A leave recipient may use annual leave received from the leave bank established by the employing agency of such employee under this subchapter in the same manner and for the same purposes as if such leave recipient had accrued such leave under section 6303, except that any annual leave and, if applicable, any sick leave accrued or accumulated to the leave recipient shall be used before any leave from the leave bank may be used.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Transferred annual leave—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may accumulate without regard to any limitation under section 6304; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may be substituted retroactively for any period of leave without pay, or used to liquidate an indebtedness for any period of advanced leave, which began on or after a date fixed by the employing agency of the employee as the beginning of the medical emergency involved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Except to the extent that the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe regulations, nothing in the provisions of section 7351 shall apply to any solicitation, contribution, or use of leave to or from a leave bank under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6368.</num>
<heading> Termination of medical emergency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The medical emergency affecting a leave recipient shall, for purposes of this subchapter, be considered to have terminated on the date as of which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the leave recipient notifies the Leave Bank Board in writing, that the medical emergency no longer exists;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Leave Bank Board of such leave recipient determines, after written notice and opportunity for the leave recipient (or, if appropriate, another person acting on behalf of the leave recipient) to answer orally or in writing, that the medical emergency no longer exists; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the leave recipient is separated from service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Leave Bank Board of a recipient shall, consistent with guidelines prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, establish procedures to ensure that a leave recipient is not permitted to use or receive any transferred leave under this subchapter after the medical emergency terminates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in section 5551, 5552, or 6306 shall apply with respect to any annual leave transferred to a leave recipient under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2842</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6369.</num>
<heading> Restoration of transferred leave</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management shall establish procedures under which any transferred leave remaining to the credit of a leave recipient when the medical emergency affecting the leave recipient terminates, shall be restored to the leave bank.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2842</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6370.</num>
<heading> Prohibition of coercion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An employee may not directly or indirectly intimidate, threaten, or coerce, or attempt to intimidate, threaten, or coerce, any other employee for the purpose of interfering with any right which such employee may have with respect to contributing, receiving, or using annual leave under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purpose of subsection (a), the term “intimidate, threaten, or coerce” includes promising to confer or conferring any benefit (such as an appointment, promotion, or compensation), or effecting or threatening to effect any reprisal (such as deprivation of appointment, promotion, or compensation).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2842</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6371.</num>
<heading> Accrual of leave</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">While using leave made available to an employee from a leave bank, annual and sick leave shall accrue to the credit of such employee and shall become available for use by such employee in the same manner as provided for under section 6337.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2843</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6372.</num>
<heading> Additional leave bank programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “excepted agency” has the same meaning as such term is defined under <ref>section 6339(a)(1) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “head of an excepted agency” has the same meaning as such term is defined under <ref>section 6339(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) and notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, neither an excepted agency nor any individual employed in or under an excepted agency may be included in a leave bank program established under any of the preceding provisions of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation may authorize an individual employed by the Bureau to participate in a leave bank program administered by the Department of Justice under this subchapter if in the Director’s judgment such participation will not adversely affect the protection of intelligence sources and methods.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The head of an excepted agency may, by regulation, establish a voluntary leave bank program under which annual leave accrued or accumulated by an employee of such agency may be contributed to a leave bank, and any other employee of such agency may receive additional leave from such leave bank because of a medical emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To the extent practicable, and consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods (if applicable), each program under this section shall be established in a manner consistent with the provisions of this subchapter applicable to the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall provide the head of an excepted agency with such advice and assistance as the head of such agency may request in order to carry out the purposes of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2843</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–87, title IV, § 432</ref>, <date date="2012-01-03">Jan. 3, 2012</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6373.</num>
<heading> Authority to participate in both programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations under which an employee participating in a leave bank program under this subchapter may, subject to such terms or conditions as the Office may establish, also make or receive donations of leave under subchapter III.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any provision of section 6337 or 6371, if an employee uses leave transferred to such employee under subchapter III and leave made available to such employee under this subchapter in connection with the same medical emergency, the maximum number of days of annual leave and sick leave, respectively, which may accrue to such employee in connection with such medical emergency shall be the same as if all of that leave had been made available to such employee under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–566, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-31">Oct. 31, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2843</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–103, § 5(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-08">Oct. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1023</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>FAMILY AND MEDICAL LEAVE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6381.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “employee” means any individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is an “employee”, as defined by section 6301(2), including any individual employed in a position referred to in clause (ix) of section 6301(2), but excluding any individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002130">1</ref> any individual employed on a temporary or intermittent basis, and any employee of the Government Accountability Office or the Library of Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> has completed at least 12 months of service—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> as an employee (as that term is defined in section 2105) of the Government of the United States, including service with the United States Postal Service, the Postal Regulatory Commission, and a nonappropriated fund instrumentality as described in section 2105(c); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> which qualifies as honorable active service in the Army, Navy, Air Force, Space Force, or Marine Corps of the United States;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “health care provider” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a doctor of medicine or osteopathy who is authorized to practice medicine or surgery (as appropriate) by the State in which the doctor practices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other person determined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to be capable of providing health care services;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “parent” means the biological parent of an employee or an individual who stood in loco parentis to an employee when the employee was a son or daughter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “reduced leave schedule” means a leave schedule that reduces the usual number of hours per workweek, or hours per workday, of an employee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> the term “serious health condition” means an illness, injury, impairment, or physical or mental condition that involves—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> inpatient care in a hospital, hospice, or residential medical care facility; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> continuing treatment by a health care provider;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> the term “son or daughter” means a biological, adopted, or foster child, a stepchild, a legal ward, or a child of a person standing in loco parentis, who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> under 18 years of age; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 18 years of age or older and incapable of self-care because of a mental or physical disability;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> the term “covered active duty” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of a regular component of the Armed Forces, duty during the deployment of the member with the Armed Forces to a foreign country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces, duty during the deployment of the member with the Armed Forces to a foreign country under a call or order to active duty under a provision of law referred to in <ref>section 101(a)(13)(B) of title 10</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> the term “covered servicemember” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves) who is undergoing medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy, is otherwise in outpatient status, or is otherwise on the temporary disability retired list, for a serious injury or illness; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a veteran who is undergoing medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy, for a serious injury or illness and who was a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves) at any time during the period of 5 years preceding the date on which the veteran undergoes that medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> the term “outpatient status”, with respect to a covered servicemember, means the status of a member of the Armed Forces assigned to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a military medical treatment facility as an outpatient; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a unit established for the purpose of providing command and control of members of the Armed Forces receiving medical care as outpatients;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the term “next of kin”, used with respect to an individual, means the nearest blood relative of that individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> the term “serious injury or illness”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves), means an injury or illness that was incurred by the member in line of duty on active duty in the Armed Forces (or existed before the beginning of the member’s active duty and was aggravated by service in line of duty on active duty in the Armed Forces) and that may render the member medically unfit to perform the duties of the member’s office, grade, rank, or rating; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a veteran who was a member of the Armed Forces (including a member of the National Guard or Reserves) at any time during a period described in paragraph (8)(B), means an injury or illness that was incurred by the member in line of duty on active duty in the Armed Forces (or existed before the beginning of the member’s active duty and was aggravated by service in line of duty on active duty in the Armed Forces) and that manifested itself before or after the member became a veteran; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the term “veteran” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 101 of title 38</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title II, § 201(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 19</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 202(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 585(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 131</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 565(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2), (3), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2311</ref>, 2312; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1103(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3889</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XI, § 1114(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6382.</num>
<heading> Leave requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to section 6383 and subsection (d)(2) of this section, an employee shall be entitled to a total of 12 administrative workweeks of leave during any 12-month period for one or more of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Because of the birth of a son or daughter of the employee and in order to care for such son or daughter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Because of the placement of a son or daughter with the employee for adoption or foster care.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In order to care for the spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent, of the employee, if such spouse, son, daughter, or parent has a serious health condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Because of a serious health condition that makes the employee unable to perform the functions of the employee’s position.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Because of any qualifying exigency arising out of the fact that the spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent of the employee is on covered active duty (or has been notified of an impending call or order to covered active duty) in the Armed Forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The entitlement to leave under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) based on the birth or placement of a son or daughter shall expire at the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date of such birth or placement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Subject to section 6383, an employee who is the spouse, son, daughter, parent, or next of kin of a covered servicemember shall be entitled to a total of 26 administrative workweeks of leave during a 12-month period to care for the servicemember. The leave described in this paragraph shall only be available during a single 12-month period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (d)(2), during the single 12-month period described in paragraph (3), an employee shall be entitled to a combined total of 26 administrative workweeks of leave under paragraphs (1) and (3). Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit the availability of leave under paragraph (1) during any other 12-month period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Leave under subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) shall not be taken by an employee intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule unless the employee and the employing agency of the employee agree otherwise. Subject to paragraph (2), subsection (e)(2), and subsection (b)(5) or (f) (as appropriate) of section 6383, leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of subsection (a)(1) or under subsection (a)(3) may be taken intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule when medically necessary. Subject to subsection (e)(3) and section 6383(f), leave under subsection (a)(1)(E) may be taken intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule. In the case of an employee who takes leave intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule pursuant to this paragraph, any hours of leave so taken by such employee shall be subtracted from the total amount of leave remaining available to such employee under subsection (a), for purposes of the 12-month period involved, on an hour-for-hour basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If an employee requests intermittent leave, or leave on a reduced leave schedule, under subparagraph (C) or (D) of subsection (a)(1) or under subsection (a)(3), that is foreseeable based on planned medical treatment, the employing agency may require such employee to transfer temporarily to an available alternative position offered by the employing agency for which the employee is qualified and that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has equivalent pay and benefits; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> better accommodates recurring periods of leave than the regular employment position of the employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (d), leave granted under subsection (a) shall be leave without pay.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee may elect to substitute for leave under subparagraph (C), (D), or (E) of subsection (a)(1) any of the employee’s accrued or accumulated annual or sick leave for any part of the 12-week period of leave under such subsection, except that nothing in this subchapter shall require an employing agency to provide paid sick leave in any situation in which such employing agency would not normally provide any such paid leave. An employee may elect to substitute for leave under subsection (a)(3) any of the employee’s accrued or accumulated annual or sick leave for any part of the 26-week period of leave under such subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An employee may elect to substitute for any leave without pay under subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) any paid leave which is available to such employee for that purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The paid leave that is available to an employee for purposes of subparagraph (A) is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 12 administrative workweeks of paid parental leave under this subparagraph in connection with the birth or placement involved; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> during the 12-month period referred to in subsection (a)(1), and in addition to the 12 administrative workweeks under clause (i), any annual or sick leave accrued or accumulated by such employee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Nothing in this subsection shall be considered to require that an employee first use all or any portion of the leave described in subparagraph (B)(ii) before being allowed to use the paid parental leave described in subparagraph (B)(i).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Paid parental leave under subparagraph (B)(i)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be payable from any appropriation or fund available for salaries or expenses for positions within the employing agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall not be considered to be annual or vacation leave for purposes of section 5551 or 5552 or for any other purpose; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if not used by the employee before the end of the 12-month period (as referred to in subsection (a)(1)) to which it relates, shall not accumulate for any subsequent use.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to modify the requirement to complete at least 12 months of service as an employee (within the meaning of section 6381(1)(A)) before the date of the applicable birth or placement involved to be eligible for paid parental leave under subparagraph (B)(i) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(F)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> An employee may not take leave under this paragraph unless the employee agrees (in writing), before the commencement of such leave, to work for the applicable employing agency for not less than a period of 12 weeks beginning on the date such leave concludes.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The head of the agency shall waive the requirement in clause (i) in any instance where the employee is unable to return to work because of the continuation, recurrence, or onset of a serious health condition (including mental health), related to the applicable birth or placement of a child, of the employee or the child.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The head of the employing agency may require that an employee who claims to be unable to return to work because of a health condition described under clause (ii) provide certification supporting such claim by the health care provider of the employee or the child (as the case may be). The employee shall provide such certification to the head in a timely manner.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(G)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> If an employee fails to return from paid leave provided under this paragraph after the date such leave concludes, the employing agency may recover, from such employee, an amount equal to the total amount of Government contributions paid by the agency under section 8906 on behalf of the employee for maintaining such employee’s health coverage under chapter 89 during the period of such leave.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> Clause (i) shall not apply to any employee who fails to return from such leave due to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the continuation, recurrence, or onset of a serious health condition as described under, and consistent with the requirements of, subparagraph (F); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any other circumstance beyond the control of the employee.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In any case in which the necessity for leave under subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) or under subsection (a)(3) is foreseeable based on an expected birth or placement, the employee shall provide the employing agency with not less than 30 days’ notice, before the date the leave is to begin, of the employee’s intention to take leave under such subparagraph, except that if the date of the birth or placement requires leave to begin in less than 30 days, the employee shall provide such notice as is practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In any case in which the necessity for leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of subsection (a)(1) or under subsection (a)(3) is foreseeable based on planned medical treatment, the employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall make a reasonable effort to schedule the treatment so as not to disrupt unduly the operations of the employing agency, subject to the approval of the health care provider of the employee or the health care provider of the son, daughter, spouse, parent, or covered servicemember of the employee, as appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall provide the employing agency with not less than 30 days’ notice, before the date the leave is to begin, of the employee’s intention to take leave under such subparagraph, except that if the date of the treatment requires leave to begin in less than 30 days, the employee shall provide such notice as is practicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In any case in which the necessity for leave under subsection (a)(1)(E) is foreseeable, whether because the spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent, of the employee is on covered active duty, or because of notification of an impending call or order to covered active duty, the employee shall provide such notice to the employer as is reasonable and practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title II, § 201(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 20</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 585(b)(2)</ref>–(3)(C), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 132</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title X, § 1061(b)(2), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4612</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 565(b)(1)(B)</ref>, (4), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2311</ref>, 2312; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. F, title LXXVI, § 7602(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2304</ref>, 2305; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1103(f)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3889</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6383.</num>
<heading> Certification</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An employing agency may require that a request for leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of section 6382(a)(1) be supported by certification issued by the health care provider of the employee or of the son, daughter, spouse, or parent of the employee, as appropriate. The employee shall provide, in a timely manner, a copy of such certification to the employing agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A certification provided under subsection (a) shall be sufficient if it states—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which the serious health condition commenced;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the probable duration of the condition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the appropriate medical facts within the knowledge of the health care provider regarding the condition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for purposes of leave under section 6382(a)(1)(C), a statement that the employee is needed to care for the son, daughter, spouse, or parent, and an estimate of the amount of time that such employee is needed to care for such son, daughter, spouse, or parent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for purposes of leave under section 6382(a)(1)(D), a statement that the employee is unable to perform the functions of the position of the employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> in the case of certification for intermittent leave, or leave on a reduced leave schedule, for planned medical treatment, the dates on which such treatment is expected to be given and the duration of such treatment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In any case in which the employing agency has reason to doubt the validity of the certification provided under subsection (a) for leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of section 6382(a)(1), the employing agency may require, at the expense of the agency, that the employee obtain the opinion of a second health care provider designated or approved by the employing agency concerning any information certified under subsection (b) for such leave.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any health care provider designated or approved under paragraph (1) shall not be employed on a regular basis by the employing agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In any case in which the second opinion described in subsection (c) differs from the original certification provided under subsection (a), the employing agency may require, at the expense of the agency, that the employee obtain the opinion of a third health care provider designated or approved jointly by the employing agency and the employee concerning the information certified under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The opinion of the third health care provider concerning the information certified under subsection (b) shall be considered to be final and shall be binding on the employing agency and the employee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The employing agency may require, at the expense of the agency, that the employee obtain subsequent recertifications on a reasonable basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> An employing agency may require that a request for leave under paragraph (1)(E) or (3) of section 6382(a) be supported by a certification issued at such time and in such manner as the Office of Personnel Management may by regulation prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title II, § 201(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 21</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 585(b)(3)(D)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 132</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 565(b)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2311</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6384.</num>
<heading> Employment and benefits protection</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Any employee who takes leave under section 6382 for the intended purpose of the leave shall be entitled, upon return from such leave—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to be restored by the employing agency to the position held by the employee when the leave commenced; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to be restored to an equivalent position with equivalent benefits, pay, status, and other terms and conditions of employment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The taking of leave under section 6382 shall not result in the loss of any employment benefit accrued prior to the date on which the leave commenced.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Except as otherwise provided by or under law, nothing in this section shall be construed to entitle any restored employee to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the accrual of any employment benefits during any period of leave; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any right, benefit, or position of employment other than any right, benefit, or position to which the employee would have been entitled had the employee not taken the leave.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> As a condition to restoration under subsection (a) for an employee who takes leave under section 6382(a)(1)(D), the employing agency may have a uniformly applied practice or policy that requires each such employee to receive certification from the health care provider of the employee that the employee is able to resume work.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit an employing agency from requiring an employee on leave under section 6382 to report periodically to the employing agency on the status and intention of the employee to return to work.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title II, § 201(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 22</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6385.</num>
<heading> Prohibition of coercion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An employee shall not directly or indirectly intimidate, threaten, or coerce, or attempt to intimidate, threaten, or coerce, any other employee for the purpose of interfering with the exercise of any rights which such other employee may have under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “intimidate, threaten, or coerce” includes promising to confer or conferring any benefit (such as appointment, promotion, or compensation), or taking or threatening to take any reprisal (such as deprivation of appointment, promotion, or compensation); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “employee” means any “employee”, as defined by section 2105.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title II, § 201(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 22</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6386.</num>
<heading> Health insurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employee enrolled in a health benefits plan under chapter 89 who is placed in a leave status under section 6382 may elect to continue the health benefits enrollment of the employee while in such leave status and arrange to pay currently into the Employees Health Benefits Fund (described in section 8909), the appropriate employee contributions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title II, § 201(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 23</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6387.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations necessary for the administration of this subchapter. The regulations prescribed under this subchapter shall, to the extent appropriate, be consistent with the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Labor to carry out title I of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–3, title II, § 201(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-02-05">Feb. 5, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 23</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>LEAVE TRANSFER IN DISASTERS AND EMERGENCIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6391.</num>
<heading> Authority for leave transfer program in disasters and emergencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “employee” means an employee as defined in section 6331(1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “agency” means an Executive agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In the event of a major disaster or emergency, as declared by the President, that results in severe adverse effects for a substantial number of employees, the President may direct the Office of Personnel Management to establish an emergency leave transfer program under which any employee in any agency may donate unused annual leave for transfer to employees of the same or other agencies who are adversely affected by such disaster or emergency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Office shall establish appropriate requirements for the operation of the emergency leave transfer program under subsection (b), including appropriate limitations on the donation and use of annual leave under the program. An employee may receive and use leave under the program without regard to any requirement that any annual leave and sick leave to a leave recipient’s credit must be exhausted before any transferred annual leave may be used.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A leave bank established under subchapter IV may, to the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Office, donate annual leave to the emergency leave transfer program established under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Except to the extent that the Office may prescribe by regulation, nothing in section 7351 shall apply to any solicitation, donation, or acceptance of leave under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> After consultation with the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, the Office of Personnel Management shall provide for the participation of employees in the judicial branch in any emergency leave transfer program under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The Office shall prescribe regulations necessary for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–18, title II, § 9004(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-06-12">June 12, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 196</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–229, § 1</ref>, <date date="2006-05-31">May 31, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 390</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>