<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 4—</num>
<heading>INSPECTORS GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 401.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “establishment” means the Department of Agriculture, Commerce, Defense, Education, Energy, Health and Human Services, Housing and Urban Development, the Interior, Justice, Labor, State, Transportation, Homeland Security, the Treasury, or Veterans Affairs; the Agency for International Development, the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Federal Communications Commission, the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the General Services Administration, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Office of Personnel Management, the Railroad Retirement Board, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Small Business Administration, the Corporation for National and Community Service, the Social Security Administration, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Tennessee Valley Authority, the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the Commissions established under <ref>section 15301 of title 40</ref>, the National Security Agency, or the National Reconnaissance Office, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal agency</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Federal agency” means an agency as defined in <ref>section 552(f) of this title</ref> (including an establishment as defined in paragraph (1)), but shall not be construed to include the Government Accountability Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Head of the establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “head of the establishment” means the Secretary of Agriculture, Commerce, Defense, Education, Energy, Health and Human Services, Housing and Urban Development, the Interior, Labor, State, Transportation, Homeland Security, the Treasury, or Veterans Affairs; the Attorney General; the Administrator of the Agency for International Development, Environmental Protection, General Services, National Aeronautics and Space, Small Business, or the Federal Emergency Management Agency; the Director of the Office of Personnel Management; the Chairman of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Federal Communications Commission, or the Railroad Retirement Board; the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service; the Administrator of the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund; the Chairperson of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; the Commissioner of Social Security, Social Security Administration; the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency; the Board of Directors of the Tennessee Valley Authority; the President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States; the Federal Cochairpersons of the Commissions established under <ref>section 15301 of title 40</ref>; the Director of the National Security Agency; or the Director of the National Reconnaissance Office; as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspector general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Inspector General” means the Inspector General of an establishment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Office</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Office” means the Office of Inspector General of an establishment.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 402.</num>
<heading> Establishment and purpose of Offices of Inspector General</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Establishment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraph (2), in each of the establishments listed in <ref>section 401(1) of this title</ref>, there is established an Office of Inspector General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Department of the treasury</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the establishment of the Department of the Treasury, there is established—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an Office of Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an Office of Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The offices established under subsection (a) are established in order to create independent and objective units—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to conduct and supervise audits and investigations relating to the programs and operations of the establishments listed in <ref>section 401(1) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to provide leadership and coordination and recommend policies for activities designed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to promote economy, efficiency, and effectiveness in the administration of those programs and operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to prevent and detect fraud and abuse in those programs and operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to provide a means for keeping the head of the establishments and Congress fully and currently informed about problems and deficiencies relating to the administration of those programs and operations and the necessity for and progress of corrective action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 403.</num>
<heading> Appointments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be at the head of each Office an Inspector General who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations. Each Inspector General shall report to and be under the general supervision of the head of the establishment involved or, to the extent such authority is delegated, the officer next in rank below such head, but shall not report to, or be subject to supervision by, any other officer of the establishment. Neither the head of the establishment nor the officer next in rank below the head shall prevent or prohibit the Inspector General from initiating, carrying out, or completing any audit or investigation, or from issuing any subpoena during the course of any audit or investigation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal or Transfer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Inspector General may be removed from office by the President. If an Inspector General is removed from office or is transferred to another position or location within an establishment, the President shall communicate in writing the reasons for any such removal or transfer to both Houses of Congress, not later than 30 days before the removal or transfer. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a personnel action otherwise authorized by law, other than transfer or removal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Not Employee Determining Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purposes of <ref>section 7324 of this title</ref>, an Inspector General shall not be considered to be an employee who determines policies to be pursued by the United States in the nationwide administration of Federal laws.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Assistant Inspectors General and Whistleblower Protection Coordinator.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each Inspector General shall, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations governing the civil service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appoint an Assistant Inspector General for Auditing who shall have the responsibility for supervising the performance of auditing activities relating to programs and operations of the establishment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> appoint an Assistant Inspector General for Investigations who shall have the responsibility for supervising the performance of investigative activities relating to such programs and operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> designate a Whistleblower Protection Coordinator who shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> educate agency employees—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> about prohibitions against retaliation for protected disclosures; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> who have made or are contemplating making a protected disclosure about the rights and remedies against retaliation for protected disclosures, including—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the means by which employees may seek review of any allegation of reprisal, including the roles of the Office of the Inspector General, the Office of Special Counsel, the Merit Systems Protection Board, and any other relevant entities; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> general information about the timeliness of such cases, the availability of any alternative dispute mechanisms, and avenues for potential relief;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assist the Inspector General in promoting the timely and appropriate handling and consideration of protected disclosures and allegations of reprisal, to the extent practicable, by the Inspector General; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> assist the Inspector General in facilitating communication and coordination with the Special Counsel, the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, the establishment, Congress, and any other relevant entity regarding the timely and appropriate handling and consideration of protected disclosures, allegations of reprisal, and general matters regarding the implementation and administration of whistleblower protection laws, rules, and regulations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Whistleblower protection coordinator not to act as legal representative, agent, or advocate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Whistleblower Protection Coordinator shall not act as a legal representative, agent, or advocate of the employee or former employee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Whistleblower protection coordinator access to inspector general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Whistleblower Protection Coordinator shall have direct access to the Inspector General as needed to accomplish the requirements of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Whistleblower protection coordinator exception for intelligence activity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For the purposes of this section, the requirement of the designation of a Whistleblower Protection Coordinator under paragraph (1)(C) shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any agency that is an element of the intelligence community (as defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</ref>)); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as determined by the President, any executive agency or unit thereof the principal function of which is the conduct of foreign intelligence or counter intelligence activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rate of Pay</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The annual rate of basic pay for an Inspector General (as defined under <ref>section 401 of this title</ref>) shall be the rate payable for level III of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5314 of this title</ref>, plus 3 percent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Cash Awards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Inspector General (as defined under section 401 or 415(a) of this title) may not receive any cash award or cash bonus, including any cash award under chapter 45 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Legal Advice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Inspector General shall, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations governing the civil service, obtain legal advice from a counsel either reporting directly to the Inspector General or another Inspector General.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 404.</num>
<heading> Duties and responsibilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>It shall be the duty and responsibility of each Inspector General, with respect to the establishment within which the Inspector General’s Office is established—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide policy direction for and to conduct, supervise, and coordinate audits and investigations relating to the programs and operations of the establishment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to review existing and proposed legislation and regulations relating to programs and operations of the establishment and to make recommendations in the semiannual reports required by <ref>section 405(b) of this title</ref> concerning the impact of the legislation and regulations on the economy and efficiency in the administration of programs and operations administered or financed by the establishment, or the prevention and detection of fraud and abuse in the programs and operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to recommend policies for, and to conduct, supervise, or coordinate other activities carried out or financed by, the establishment for the purpose of promoting economy and efficiency in the administration of, or preventing and detecting fraud and abuse in, its programs and operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> to recommend policies for the establishment, and to conduct, supervise, or coordinate relationships between the establishment and other Federal agencies, State and local governmental agencies, and nongovernmental entities, with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all matters relating to the promotion of economy and efficiency in the administration of, or the prevention and detection of fraud and abuse in, programs and operations administered or financed by the establishment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the identification and prosecution of participants in fraud or abuse referred to in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to keep the head of the establishment and Congress fully and currently informed, by means of the reports required by <ref>section 405 of this title</ref> and otherwise, concerning fraud and other serious problems, abuses, and deficiencies relating to the administration of programs and operations administered or financed by the establishment, to recommend corrective action concerning the problems, abuses, and deficiencies, and to report on the progress made in implementing the corrective action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Standards and Guidelines.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the responsibilities specified in subsection (a)(1), each Inspector General shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> comply with standards established by the Comptroller General of the United States for audits of Federal establishments, organizations, programs, activities, and functions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish guidelines for determining when it shall be appropriate to use non-Federal auditors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> take appropriate steps to ensure that any work performed by non-Federal auditors complies with the standards established by the Comptroller General as described in paragraph (1).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reviews performed exclusively by audit entities in federal government</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of determining compliance with paragraph (1)(A) with respect to whether internal quality controls are in place and operating and whether established audit standards, policies, and procedures are being followed by Offices of Inspector General of establishments defined under <ref>section 401 of this title</ref>, Offices of Inspector General of designated Federal entities defined under <ref>section 415(a) of this title</ref>, and any audit office established within a Federal entity defined under <ref>section 415(a) of this title</ref>, reviews shall be performed exclusively by an audit entity in the Federal Government, including the Government Accountability Office or the Office of Inspector General of each establishment defined under <ref>section 401 of this title</ref>, or the Office of Inspector General of each designated Federal entity defined under <ref>section 415(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective Coordination and Cooperation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the duties and responsibilities established under this chapter, each Inspector General shall give particular regard to the activities of the Comptroller General of the United States with a view toward avoiding duplication and ensuring effective coordination and cooperation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting Violation of Federal Criminal Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the duties and responsibilities established under this chapter, each Inspector General shall report expeditiously to the Attorney General whenever the Inspector General has reasonable grounds to believe there has been a violation of Federal criminal law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Recommendations for Corrective Actions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of documents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the duties and responsibilities established under this chapter, whenever an Inspector General issues a recommendation for corrective action to the agency, the Inspector General—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> shall submit the document making a recommendation for corrective action to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the head of the establishment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the congressional committees of jurisdiction; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if the recommendation for corrective action was initiated upon request by an individual or entity other than the Inspector General, that individual or entity;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may submit the document making a recommendation for corrective action to any Member of Congress upon request; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not later than 3 days after the recommendation for corrective action is submitted in final form to the head of the establishment, post the document making a recommendation for corrective action on the website of the Office of Inspector General.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public disclosure otherwise prohibited by law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as authorizing an Inspector General to publicly disclose information otherwise prohibited from disclosure by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 405.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disallowed cost</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “disallowed cost” means a questioned cost that management, in a management decision, has sustained or agreed should not be charged to the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Final action</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “final action” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the completion of all actions that the management of an establishment has concluded, in its management decision, are necessary with respect to the findings and recommendations included in an audit report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the event that the management of an establishment concludes no action is necessary, final action occurs when a management decision has been made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Management decision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “management decision” means the evaluation by the management of an establishment of the findings and recommendations included in an audit report and the issuance of a final decision by management concerning its response to the findings and recommendations, including actions concluded to be necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Questioned cost</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “questioned cost” means a cost that is questioned by the Office because of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an alleged violation of a provision of a law, regulation, contract, grant, cooperative agreement, or other agreement or document governing the expenditure of funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a finding that, at the time of the audit, the cost is not supported by adequate documentation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a finding that the expenditure of funds for the intended purpose is unnecessary or unreasonable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recommendation that funds be put to better use</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “recommendation that funds be put to better use” means a recommendation by the Office that funds could be used more efficiently if management of an establishment took actions to implement and complete the recommendation, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reductions in outlays;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> deobligation of funds from programs or operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> withdrawal of interest subsidy costs on loans or loan guarantees, insurance, or bonds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> costs not incurred by implementing recommended improvements related to the operations of the establishment, a contractor, or grantee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> avoidance of unnecessary expenditures noted in preaward reviews of contract or grant agreements; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any other savings which are specifically identified.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Senior government employee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “senior Government employee” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an officer or employee in the executive branch (including a special Government employee as defined in <ref>section 202 of title 18</ref>) who occupies a position classified at or above GS–15 of the General Schedule or, in the case of positions not under the General Schedule, for which the rate of basic pay is equal to or greater than 120 percent of the minimum rate of basic pay payable for GS–15 of the General Schedule; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any commissioned officer in the Armed Forces in pay grades O–6 and above.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unsupported cost</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “unsupported cost” means a cost that is questioned by the Office because the Office found that, at the time of the audit, such cost is not supported by adequate documentation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Semiannual Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each Inspector General shall, not later than April 30 and October 31 of each year, prepare semiannual reports summarizing the activities of the Office during the immediately preceding 6-month periods ending March 31 and September 30. The reports shall include, but need not be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of significant problems, abuses, and deficiencies relating to the administration of programs and operations of such establishment disclosed by such activities during the reporting period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the recommendations for corrective action made by the Office during the reporting period with respect to significant problems, abuses, or deficiencies identified pursuant to paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an identification of each significant recommendation described in previous semiannual reports on which corrective action has not been completed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a summary of matters referred to prosecutive authorities and the prosecutions and convictions which have resulted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a summary of each report made to the head of the establishment under <ref>section 406(c)(2) of this title</ref> during the reporting period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a listing, subdivided according to subject matter, of each audit report, inspection report, and evaluation report issued by the Office during the reporting period and for each report, where applicable, the total dollar value of questioned costs (including a separate category for the dollar value of unsupported costs) and the dollar value of recommendations that funds be put to better use;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a summary of each particularly significant report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> statistical tables showing the total number of audit reports, inspection reports, and evaluation reports and the total dollar value of questioned costs (including a separate category for the dollar value of unsupported costs), for reports—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for which no management decision had been made by the commencement of the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which were issued during the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> for which a management decision was made during the reporting period, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the dollar value of disallowed costs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the dollar value of costs not disallowed; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for which no management decision has been made by the end of the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> statistical tables showing the total number of audit reports, inspection reports, and evaluation reports and the dollar value of recommendations that funds be put to better use by management, for reports—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for which no management decision had been made by the commencement of the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which were issued during the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> for which a management decision was made during the reporting period, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the dollar value of recommendations that were agreed to by management; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the dollar value of recommendations that were not agreed to by management; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for which no management decision has been made by the end of the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> a summary of each audit report, inspection report, and evaluation report issued before the commencement of the reporting period—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for which no management decision has been made by the end of the reporting period (including the date and title of each such report), an explanation of the reasons such management decision has not been made, and a statement concerning the desired timetable for achieving a management decision on each such report;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for which no establishment comment was returned within 60 days of providing the report to the establishment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for which there are any outstanding unimplemented recommendations, including the aggregate potential cost savings of those recommendations;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> a description and explanation of the reasons for any significant revised management decision made during the reporting period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> information concerning any significant management decision with which the Inspector General is in disagreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the information described under section 804(b) of the Federal Financial Management Improvement Act of 1996 (<ref>Public Law 104–208</ref>, §101(f) [title VIII], <ref>31 U.S.C. 3512</ref> note);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an appendix containing the results of any peer review conducted by another Office of Inspector General during the reporting period; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if no peer review was conducted within that reporting period, a statement identifying the date of the last peer review conducted by another Office of Inspector General;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> a list of any outstanding recommendations from any peer review conducted by another Office of Inspector General that have not been fully implemented, including a statement describing the status of the implementation and why implementation is not complete;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> a list of any peer reviews conducted by the Inspector General of another Office of the Inspector General during the reporting period, including a list of any outstanding recommendations made from any previous peer review (including any peer review conducted before the reporting period) that remain outstanding or have not been fully implemented;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<chapeau> statistical tables showing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the total number of investigative reports issued during the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total number of persons referred to the Department of Justice for criminal prosecution during the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the total number of persons referred to State and local prosecuting authorities for criminal prosecution during the reporting period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the total number of indictments and criminal informations during the reporting period that resulted from any prior referral to prosecuting authorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> a description of the metrics used for developing the data for the statistical tables under paragraph (17);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<chapeau> a report on each investigation conducted by the Office involving a senior Government employee where allegations of misconduct were substantiated, including the name of the senior government official (as defined by the department or agency) if already made public by the Office, and a detailed description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the facts and circumstances of the investigation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the status and disposition of the matter, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> if the matter was referred to the Department of Justice, the date of the referral; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the Department of Justice declined the referral, the date of the declination;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a detailed description of any instance of whistleblower retaliation, including information about the official found to have engaged in retaliation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> what, if any, consequences the establishment actually imposed to hold the official described in subparagraph (A) accountable;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<chapeau> a detailed description of any attempt by the establishment to interfere with the independence of the Office, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with budget constraints designed to limit the capabilities of the Office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> incidents where the establishment has resisted or objected to oversight activities of the Office or restricted or significantly delayed access to information, including the justification of the establishment for such action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<chapeau> detailed descriptions of the particular circumstances of each—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> inspection, evaluation, and audit conducted by the Office that is closed and was not disclosed to the public; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> investigation conducted by the Office involving a senior Government employee that is closed and was not disclosed to the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Furnishing Semiannual Reports to Head of Establishment and Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Semiannual reports of each Inspector General shall be furnished to the head of the establishment involved not later than April 30 and October 31 of each year and shall be transmitted by the head of the establishment to the appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress within 30 days after receipt of the report, together with a report by the head of the establishment containing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any comments the head of the establishment determines appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> statistical tables showing the total number of audit reports, inspection reports, and evaluation reports and the dollar value of disallowed costs, for reports—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for which final action had not been taken by the commencement of the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on which management decisions were made during the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> for which final action was taken during the reporting period, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the dollar value of disallowed costs that were recovered by management through collection, offset, property in lieu of cash, or otherwise; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the dollar value of disallowed costs that were written off by management; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for which no final action has been taken by the end of the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> statistical tables showing the total number of audit reports, inspection reports, and evaluation reports and the dollar value of recommendations that funds be put to better use by management agreed to in a management decision, for reports—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for which final action had not been taken by the commencement of the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on which management decisions were made during the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> for which final action was taken during the reporting period, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the dollar value of recommendations that were actually completed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the dollar value of recommendations that management has subsequently concluded should not or could not be implemented or completed; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for which no final action has been taken by the end of the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> whether the establishment entered into a settlement agreement with the official described in subsection (b)(20)(A), which shall be reported regardless of any confidentiality agreement relating to the settlement agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> information relating to cases under chapter 38 of title 31, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of reports submitted by investigating officials to reviewing officials under section 3803(a)(1) of such title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> actions taken in response to reports described in subparagraph (A), which shall include statistical tables showing—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> pending cases;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> resolved cases;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the average length of time to resolve each case;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the number of final agency decisions that were appealed to a district court of the United States or a higher court; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> if the total number of cases in a report is greater than 2—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the number of cases that were settled; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the total penalty or assessment amount recovered in each case, including through a settlement or compromise; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> instances in which the reviewing official declined to proceed on a case reported by an investigating official; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> a statement with respect to audit reports on which management decisions have been made but final action has not been taken, other than audit reports on which a management decision was made within the preceding year, containing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a list of such audit reports and the date each such report was issued;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the dollar value of disallowed costs for each report;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the dollar value of recommendations that funds be put to better use agreed to by management for each report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an explanation of the reasons final action has not been taken with respect to each audit report,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">except that the statement may exclude any audit reports that are under formal administrative or judicial appeal or upon which management of an establishment has agreed to pursue a legislative solution, but the statement shall identify the number of reports in each category so excluded.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports Available to Public</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Within 60 days of the transmission of the semiannual reports of each Inspector General to Congress, the head of each establishment shall make copies of the report available to the public upon request and at a reasonable cost. Within 60 days after the transmission of the semiannual reports of each establishment head to Congress, the head of each establishment shall make copies of the report available to the public upon request and at a reasonable cost.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting Serious Problems, Abuses, or Deficiencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Inspector General shall report immediately to the head of the establishment involved whenever the Inspector General becomes aware of particularly serious or flagrant problems, abuses, or deficiencies relating to the administration of programs and operations of the establishment. The head of the establishment shall transmit any such report to the appropriate committees or subcommittees of Congress within 7 calendar days, together with a report by the head of the establishment containing any comments the establishment head deems appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Public Disclosure of Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the public disclosure of information that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> specifically prohibited from disclosure by any other provision of law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> specifically required by Executive order to be protected from disclosure in the interest of national defense or national security or in the conduct of foreign affairs; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a part of an ongoing criminal investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Criminal investigation information in public records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(C), any report under this section may be disclosed to the public in a form which includes information with respect to a part of an ongoing criminal investigation if such information has been included in a public record.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No authorization to withhold information from congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except to the extent and in the manner provided under section 6103(f) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 6103(f)</ref>), nothing in this section or in any other provision of this chapter shall be construed to authorize or permit the withholding of information from Congress, or from any committee or subcommittee of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Provision of information to members of congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to any other provision of law that would otherwise prohibit disclosure of such information, the information described in paragraph (1) may be provided to any Member of Congress upon request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Protection of personally identifiable information of whistleblowers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An Office may not provide to Congress or the public any information that reveals the personally identifiable information of a whistleblower under this section unless the Office first obtains the consent of the whistleblower.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LII, § 5203(e)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2441</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 406.</num>
<heading> Authority of Inspector General</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the authority otherwise provided by this chapter, each Inspector General, in carrying out the provisions of this chapter, is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to have timely access to all records, reports, audits, reviews, documents, papers, recommendations, or other materials available to the applicable establishment which relate to the programs and operations with respect to which that Inspector General has responsibilities under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to have access under subparagraph (A) notwithstanding any other provision of law, except pursuant to any provision of law enacted by Congress that expressly—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> refers to the Inspector General; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> limits the right of access of the Inspector General; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> except as provided in subsection (i), with regard to Federal grand jury materials protected from disclosure pursuant to rule 6(e) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, to have timely access to such information if the Attorney General grants the request in accordance with subsection (h);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to make such investigations and reports relating to the administration of the programs and operations of the applicable establishment as are, in the judgment of the Inspector General, necessary or desirable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to request such information or assistance as may be necessary for carrying out the duties and responsibilities provided by this chapter from any Federal, State, or local governmental agency or unit thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to require by subpoena the production of all information, documents, reports, answers, records, accounts, papers, and other data in any medium (including electronically stored information), as well as any tangible thing and documentary evidence necessary in the performance of the functions assigned by this chapter, which subpoena, in the case of contumacy or refusal to obey, shall be enforceable by order of any appropriate United States district court, but procedures other than subpoenas shall be used by the Inspector General to obtain documents and information from Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to administer to or take from any person an oath, affirmation, or affidavit, whenever necessary in the performance of the functions assigned by this chapter, which oath, affirmation, or affidavit when administered or taken by or before an employee of an Office of Inspector General designated by the Inspector General shall have the same force and effect as if administered or taken by or before an officer having a seal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to have direct and prompt access to the head of the establishment involved when necessary for any purpose pertaining to the performance of functions and responsibilities under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees as may be necessary for carrying out the functions, powers, and duties of the Office subject to the provisions of this title, governing appointments in the competitive service, and the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of this title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to obtain services as authorized by <ref>section 3109 of this title</ref>, at daily rates not to exceed the maximum rate payable under <ref>section 5376 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> to the extent and in such amounts as may be provided in advance by appropriations Acts, to enter into contracts and other arrangements for audits, studies, analyses, and other services with public agencies and with private persons, and to make such payments as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Disclosure Otherwise Prohibited by Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing an Inspector General to publicly disclose information otherwise prohibited from disclosure by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Requests for Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compliance in general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon request of an Inspector General for information or assistance under subsection (a)(3), the head of any Federal agency involved shall, insofar as is practicable and not in contravention of any existing statutory restriction or regulation of the Federal agency from which the information is requested, furnish to the Inspector General, or to an authorized designee, the requested information or assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Unreasonable refusal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever information or assistance requested under subsection (a)(1) or (a)(3) is, in the judgment of an Inspector General, unreasonably refused or not provided, the Inspector General shall report the circumstances to the head of the establishment involved without delay.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Office Space and Supplies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each head of an establishment shall provide the Office within the establishment with appropriate and adequate office space at central and field office locations of the establishment, together with such equipment, office supplies, and communications facilities and services as may be necessary for the operation of the offices, and shall provide necessary maintenance services for the offices and the equipment and facilities provided.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Applying Certain Provisions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Each office considered separate agency.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of applying the provisions of law identified in subparagraph (B)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> each Office of Inspector General shall be considered to be a separate agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Inspector General who is the head of an office referred to in clause (i) shall, with respect to that office, have the functions, powers, and duties of an agency head or appointing authority under such provisions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> This paragraph applies with respect to the following provisions of this title:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Subchapter II of chapter 35.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Sections 8335(b), 8336, 8344, 8414, 8425(b), and 8468.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> All provisions relating to the Senior Executive Service (as determined by the Office of Personnel Management), subject to paragraph (2).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applying section </inline>4507(b).—</heading>
<content>For purposes of applying <ref>section 4507(b) of this title</ref>, paragraph (1)(A)(ii) shall be applied by substituting “the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (established by <ref>section 424 of this title</ref>) shall” for “the Inspector General who is the head of an office referred to in clause (i) shall, with respect to that office,”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Additional Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the authority otherwise provided by this chapter, each Inspector General, any Assistant Inspector General for Investigations under such an Inspector General, and any special agent supervised by such an Assistant Inspector General may be authorized by the Attorney General to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> carry a firearm while engaged in official duties as authorized under this chapter or other statute, or as expressly authorized by the Attorney General;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make an arrest without a warrant while engaged in official duties as authorized under this chapter or other statute, or as expressly authorized by the Attorney General, for any offense against the United States committed in the presence of such Inspector General, Assistant Inspector General, or agent, or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if such Inspector General, Assistant Inspector General, or agent has reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such felony; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> seek and execute warrants for arrest, search of a premises, or seizure of evidence issued under the authority of the United States upon probable cause to believe that a violation has been committed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Attorney General may authorize exercise of the powers under this subsection only upon an initial determination that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the affected Office of Inspector General is significantly hampered in the performance of responsibilities established by this chapter as a result of the lack of such powers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> available assistance from other law enforcement agencies is insufficient to meet the need for such powers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> adequate internal safeguards and management procedures exist to ensure proper exercise of such powers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exemptions from requirement of initial determination of eligibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General offices of the Department of Commerce, Department of Education, Department of Energy, Department of Health and Human Services, Department of Homeland Security, Department of Housing and Urban Development, Department of the Interior, Department of Justice, Department of Labor, Department of State, Department of Transportation, Department of the Treasury, Department of Veterans’ Affairs, Agency for International Development, Environmental Protection Agency, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, Federal Emergency Management Agency, General Services Administration, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Office of Personnel Management, Railroad Retirement Board, Small Business Administration, Social Security Administration, and the Tennessee Valley Authority are exempt from the requirement of paragraph (2) for an initial determination of eligibility by the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General shall promulgate, and revise as appropriate, guidelines which shall govern the exercise of the law enforcement powers established under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Rescinding or suspending powers.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Powers authorized for an office of inspector general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Powers authorized for an Office of Inspector General under paragraph (1) may be rescinded or suspended upon a determination by the Attorney General that any of the requirements under paragraph (2) is no longer satisfied or that the exercise of authorized powers by that Office of Inspector General has not complied with the guidelines promulgated by the Attorney General under paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Powers authorized to be exercised by an individual</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Powers authorized to be exercised by any individual under paragraph (1) may be rescinded or suspended with respect to that individual upon a determination by the Attorney General that such individual has not complied with guidelines promulgated by the Attorney General under paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Not reviewable</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A determination by the Attorney General under paragraph (2) or (5) shall not be reviewable in or by any court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Memorandum of understanding</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To ensure the proper exercise of the law enforcement powers authorized by this subsection, the Offices of Inspector General described under paragraph (3) shall, not later than 180 days after <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, collectively enter into a memorandum of understanding to establish an external review process for ensuring that adequate internal safeguards and management procedures continue to exist within each Office and within any Office that later receives an authorization under paragraph (2). The review process shall be established in consultation with the Attorney General, who shall be provided with a copy of the memorandum of understanding that establishes the review process. Under the review process, the exercise of the law enforcement powers by each Office of Inspector General shall be reviewed periodically by another Office of Inspector General or by a committee of Inspectors General. The results of each review shall be communicated in writing to the applicable Inspector General and to the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Not a limitation on other law enforcement powers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No provision of this subsection shall limit the exercise of law enforcement powers established under any other statutory authority, including United States Marshals Service special deputation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of inspector general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “Inspector General” means an Inspector General appointed under <ref>section 403 of this title</ref> or an Inspector General appointed under <ref>section 415 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Budgets.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspector general’s budget estimate and request transmitted to head of establishment or designated federal entity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each fiscal year, an Inspector General shall transmit a budget estimate and request to the head of the establishment or designated Federal entity to which the Inspector General reports. The budget request shall specify the aggregate amount of funds requested for such fiscal year for the operations of that Inspector General and shall specify the amount requested for all training needs, including a certification from the Inspector General that the amount requested satisfies all training requirements for the Inspector General’s office for that fiscal year, and any resources necessary to support the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency. Resources necessary to support the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency shall be specifically identified and justified in the budget request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Head of establishment or designated federal entity’s proposed budget transmitted to president</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In transmitting a proposed budget to the President for approval, the head of each establishment or designated Federal entity shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an aggregate request for the Inspector General;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> amounts for Inspector General training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> amounts for support of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any comments of the affected Inspector General with respect to the proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">President’s budget submitted to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The President shall include in each budget of the United States Government submitted to Congress—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a separate statement of the budget estimate prepared in accordance with paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount requested by the President for each Inspector General;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the amount requested by the President for training of Inspectors General;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the amount requested by the President for support for the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any comments of the affected Inspector General with respect to the proposal if the Inspector General concludes that the budget submitted by the President would substantially inhibit the Inspector General from performing the duties of the office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Federal Grand Jury Materials.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of attorney general of request</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Inspector General of an establishment submits a request to the head of the establishment for Federal grand jury materials pursuant to subsection (a)(1), the head of the establishment shall immediately notify the Attorney General of such request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination by attorney general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 15 days after the date on which a request is submitted to the Attorney General under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall determine whether to grant or deny the request for Federal grand jury materials and shall immediately notify the head of the establishment of such determination. The Attorney General shall grant the request unless the Attorney General determines that granting access to the Federal grand jury materials would be likely to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> interfere with an ongoing criminal investigation or prosecution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> interfere with an undercover operation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> result in disclosure of the identity of a confidential source, including a protected witness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> pose a serious threat to national security; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> result in significant impairment of the trade or economic interests of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Comments.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement to inform inspector general of determination by attorney general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of the establishment shall inform the Inspector General of the establishment of the determination made by the Attorney General with respect to the request for Federal grand jury materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of comments by inspector general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General of the establishment described under subparagraph (A) may submit comments on the determination submitted pursuant to such subparagraph to the committees listed under paragraph (4) that the Inspector General considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statement of attorney general regarding denial of request</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 30 days after notifying the head of an establishment of a denial pursuant to paragraph (2), the Attorney General shall submit a statement that the request for Federal grand jury materials by the Inspector General was denied and the reason for the denial to each of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Committee on Oversight and Reform, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Other appropriate committees and subcommittees of Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-applicability of Certain Provisions to Requests From Inspector General of Department of Justice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsections (a)(1)(C) and (h) shall not apply to requests from the Inspector General of the Department of Justice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Computerized Comparisons.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the terms “agency”, “matching program”, “record”, and “system of records” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 552a(a) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-consideration of computerized comparisons as matching programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref> or any other provision of law, a computerized comparison of two or more automated Federal systems of records, or a computerized comparison of a Federal system of records with other records or non-Federal records, performed by an Inspector General or by an agency in coordination with an Inspector General in conducting an audit, investigation, inspection, evaluation, or other review authorized under this chapter shall not be considered a matching program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to impede the exercise by an Inspector General of any matching program authority established under any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-Applicability of Federal Information Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subchapter I of chapter 35 of title 44 shall not apply to the collection of information during the conduct of an audit, investigation, inspection, evaluation, or other review conducted by the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency or any Office of Inspector General, including any Office of Special Inspector General.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4218</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 407.</num>
<heading> Complaints by employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Receipt and Investigation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General may receive and investigate complaints or information from an employee of the establishment concerning the possible existence of an activity constituting a violation of law, rules, or regulations, or mismanagement, gross waste of funds, abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to the public health and safety.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Disclosure of Identity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General shall not, after receipt of a complaint or information from an employee, disclose the identity of the employee without the consent of the employee, unless the Inspector General determines the disclosure is unavoidable during the course of the investigation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Reprisal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any employee who has authority to take, direct others to take, recommend, or approve any personnel action, shall not, with respect to that authority, take or threaten to take any action against any employee as a reprisal for making a complaint or disclosing information to an Inspector General, unless the complaint was made or the information disclosed with the knowledge that it was false or with willful disregard for its truth or falsity.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 408.</num>
<heading> Additional provisions with respect to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspector General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member of the Armed Forces, active or reserve, shall not be appointed Inspector General of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority of Secretary of Defense.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding the last two sentences of <ref>section 403(a) of this title</ref>, the Inspector General shall be under the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense with respect to audits or investigations, or the issuance of subpoenas, which require access to information concerning—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sensitive operational plans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> intelligence matters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> counterintelligence matters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> ongoing criminal investigations by other administrative units of the Department of Defense related to national security; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> other matters the disclosure of which would constitute a serious threat to national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to prohibit audit or investigation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to the information described in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense may prohibit the Inspector General from initiating, carrying out, or completing any audit or investigation, from accessing information described in paragraph (1), or from issuing any subpoena, after the Inspector General has decided to initiate, carry out, or complete such audit or investigation, access such information, or to issue such subpoena, if the Secretary determines that such prohibition is necessary to preserve the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statement concerning exercise of power</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of Defense exercises any power under paragraph (1) or (2), the Inspector General shall submit a statement concerning that exercise of power within 30 days to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statement of reasons for exercise of power</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall, within 30 days after submission of a statement under paragraph (3), transmit a statement of the reasons for the exercise of power under paragraph (1) or (2) to the congressional committees specified in paragraph (3) and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Duties and Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the other duties and responsibilities specified in this chapter, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be the principal adviser to the Secretary of Defense for matters relating to the prevention and detection of fraud, waste, and abuse in the programs and operations of the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> initiate, conduct, and supervise such audits and investigations in the Department of Defense (including the military departments) as the Inspector General considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provide policy direction for audits and investigations relating to fraud, waste, and abuse and program effectiveness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> investigate fraud, waste, and abuse uncovered as a result of other contract and internal audits, as the Inspector General considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> develop policy, monitor and evaluate program performance, and provide guidance with respect to all Department activities relating to criminal investigation programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> monitor and evaluate the adherence of Department auditors to internal audit, contract audit, and internal review principles, policies, and procedures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> develop policy, evaluate program performance, and monitor actions taken by all components of the Department in response to contract audits, internal audits, internal review reports, and audits conducted by the Comptroller General of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> request assistance as needed from other audit, inspection, and investigative units of the Department of Defense (including military departments);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> give particular regard to the activities of the internal audit, inspection, and investigative units of the military departments with a view toward avoiding duplication and ensuring effective coordination and cooperation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> conduct, or approve arrangements for the conduct of, external peer reviews of Department of Defense audit agencies in accordance with, and in such frequency as provided by, Government auditing standards as established by the Comptroller General of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting Violations of Chapter</inline> 47 <inline class="small-caps">of Title</inline> 10.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 404(d) of this title</ref>, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense shall expeditiously report suspected or alleged violations of chapter 47 of title 10 (Uniform Code of Military Justice), to the Secretary of the military department concerned or the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Member of Armed Forces Deemed To Be Employee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purposes of <ref>section 407 of this title</ref>, a member of the Armed Forces shall be deemed to be an employee of the Department of Defense, except that, when the Coast Guard operates as a service of another department or agency of the Federal Government, a member of the Coast Guard shall be deemed to be an employee of that department or agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports transmitted to congressional committees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each semiannual report prepared by the Inspector General of the Department of Defense under <ref>section 405(b) of this title</ref> shall be transmitted by the Secretary of Defense to the Committees on Armed Services and on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committees on Armed Services and on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees of Congress. Each report shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information concerning the numbers and types of contract audits conducted by the Department during the reporting period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> information concerning any Department of Defense audit agency that, during the reporting period, has either received a failed opinion from an external peer review or is overdue for an external peer review required to be conducted in accordance with subsection (c)(10).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional reports transmitted to congressional committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any report required to be transmitted by the Secretary of Defense to the appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress under <ref>section 405(e) of this title</ref> shall also be transmitted, within the 7-day period specified in <ref>section 405(e) of this title</ref>, to the congressional committees specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Non-Applicability of Section</inline> 1385 <inline class="small-caps">of Title</inline> 18.—</heading>
<content>The provisions of <ref>section 1385 of title 18</ref>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">1</ref> shall not apply to audits and investigations conducted by, under the direction of, or at the request of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">General Counsel to Inspector General of Department of Defense.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is a General Counsel to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense, who shall be appointed by the Inspector General of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Duties and functions.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 140(b) of title 10</ref>, the General Counsel is the chief legal officer of the Office of the Inspector General.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Inspector General is the exclusive legal client of the General Counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The General Counsel shall perform such functions as the Inspector General may prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The General Counsel shall serve at the discretion of the Inspector General.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Office of general counsel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is an Office of the General Counsel to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense. The Inspector General may appoint to the Office to serve as staff of the General Counsel such legal counsel as the Inspector General considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority To Require Attendance and Testimony of Witnesses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subpoena</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General of the Department of Defense is authorized to require by subpoena the attendance and testimony of witnesses as necessary in the performance of functions assigned to the Inspector General by this chapter, except that the Inspector General shall use procedures other than subpoenas to obtain attendance and testimony from Federal employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enforcement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A subpoena issued under this subsection, in the case of contumacy or refusal to obey, shall be enforceable by order of any appropriate United States district court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General shall notify the Attorney General 7 days before issuing any subpoena under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 409.</num>
<heading> Special provisions concerning the Agency for International Development</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of Agency for International Development</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As used in this chapter, the term “Agency for International Development” includes any successor agency primarily responsible for administering part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members of Foreign Service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to the officers and employees provided for in <ref>section 406(a)(7) of this title</ref>, members of the Foreign Service may, at the request of the Inspector General of the Agency for International Development, be assigned as employees of the Inspector General. Members of the Foreign Service so assigned shall be responsible solely to the Inspector General, and the Inspector General (or the Inspector General’s designee) shall prepare the performance evaluation reports for the members assigned as employees of the Inspector General.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Field Offices</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In establishing and staffing field offices pursuant to <ref>section 406(d) of this title</ref>, the Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall not be bound by overseas personnel ceilings.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Officer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General of the Agency for International Development shall be in addition to the officers provided for in section 624(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2384(a)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4227</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 410.</num>
<heading> Special provisions concerning the Nuclear Regulatory Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chairman of the Commission may delegate the authority specified in the 2d sentence of <ref>section 403(a) of this title</ref> to another member of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, but shall not delegate such authority to any other officer or employee of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding paragraphs (7) and (8) of <ref>section 406(a) of this title</ref>, the Inspector General of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission is authorized to select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees as may be necessary for carrying out the functions, powers, and duties of the Office of Inspector General and to obtain the temporary or intermittent services of experts or consultants or an organization of experts or consultants, subject to the applicable laws and regulations that govern such selections, appointments, and employment, and the obtaining of such services, within the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4228</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 411.</num>
<heading> Special provisions concerning the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chairperson of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation may delegate the authority specified in the 2d sentence of <ref>section 403(a) of this title</ref> to the Vice Chairperson of the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, but may not delegate such authority to any other officer or employee of the Corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding paragraphs (7) and (8) of <ref>section 406(a) of this title</ref>, the Inspector General of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation may select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees as may be necessary for carrying out the functions, powers, and duties of the Office of Inspector General and may obtain the temporary or intermittent services of experts or consultants or an organization of experts or consultants, subject to the applicable laws and regulations that govern such selections, appointments, and employment, and the obtaining of such services, within the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4228</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 412.</num>
<heading> Special provisions concerning the Department of the Treasury</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of secretary of treasury over certain audits and investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding the 2d sentence and last sentence of <ref>section 403(a) of this title</ref>, the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall be under the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of the Treasury with respect to audits or investigations, or the issuance of subpoenas, which require access to sensitive information concerning—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ongoing criminal investigations or proceedings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> undercover operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the identity of confidential sources, including protected witnesses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> deliberations and decisions on policy matters, including documented information used as a basis for making policy decisions, the disclosure of which could reasonably be expected to have a significant influence on the economy or market behavior;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> intelligence or counterintelligence matters; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> other matters the disclosure of which would constitute a serious threat to national security or to the protection of any person or property authorized protection by <ref>section 3056 of title 18</ref>, <ref>section 3056A of title 18</ref>, or any provision of the Presidential Protection Assistance Act of 1976 (<ref>Public Law 94–524</ref>, <ref>18 U.S.C. 3056</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of secretary of treasury to prohibit carrying out or completing certain audits and investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to the information described under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury may prohibit the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury from carrying out or completing any audit or investigation, from accessing information described in paragraph (1), or from issuing any subpoena, after such Inspector General has decided to initiate, carry out, or complete such audit or investigation, access such information, or to issue such subpoena, if the Secretary determines that such prohibition is necessary to prevent the disclosure of any information described under paragraph (1) or to prevent significant impairment to the national interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification and statement of reasons for exercise of power</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary of the Treasury exercises any power under paragraph (1) or (2), the Secretary of the Treasury shall notify the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury in writing, stating the reasons for such exercise. Within 30 days after receipt of any such notice, the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall transmit a copy of such notice to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Reform and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception relating to treasury inspector general for tax administration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of the Treasury may not exercise any power under paragraph (1) or (2) with respect to the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Oversight Responsibility for Internal Investigations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the duties and responsibilities specified in this chapter, the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall have oversight responsibility for the internal investigations performed by the Office of Internal Affairs of the Tax and Trade Bureau. The head of such office shall promptly report to the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury the significant activities being carried out by such office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exercise of duties and responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall exercise all duties and responsibilities of an Inspector General for the Department of the Treasury other than the duties and responsibilities exercised by the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment of procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish procedures under which the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury and the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration will—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determine how audits and investigations are allocated in cases of overlapping jurisdiction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for coordination, cooperation, and efficiency in the conduct of such audits and investigations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Audits and Investigations in Department of Treasury</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury may initiate, conduct and supervise such audits and investigations in the Department of the Treasury (including the bureau referred to in subsection (b)) as the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Provide Written Notice to Tax and Trade Bureau</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury initiates an audit or investigation under subsection (c) concerning the bureau referred to in subsection (b), the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury may provide the head of the office of such bureau referred to in subsection (b) with written notice that the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury has initiated such an audit or investigation. If the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury issues a notice under the preceding sentence, no other audit or investigation shall be initiated into the matter under audit or investigation by the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury, and any other audit or investigation of such matter shall cease.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access to returns and return information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration shall have access to returns and return information, as defined in section 6103(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 6103(b)</ref>), only in accordance with the provisions of section 6103 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 6103</ref>) and this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standardized records and accountings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Internal Revenue Service shall maintain the same system of standardized records or accountings of all requests from the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration for inspection or disclosure of returns and return information (including the reasons for and dates of such requests), and of returns and return information inspected or disclosed pursuant to such requests, as described under section 6103(p)(3)(A) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 6103(p)(3)(A)</ref>). Such system of standardized records or accountings shall also be available for examination in the same manner as provided under section 6103(p)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 6103(p)(3)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safeguards and conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration shall be subject to the same safeguards and conditions for receiving returns and return information as are described under section 6103(p)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 6103(p)(4)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Audit or Investigation Shall Not Affect Final Decision Under Section</inline> 6406 <inline class="small-caps">of Internal Revenue Code of</inline> 1986.—</heading>
<content>An audit or investigation conducted by the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury or the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration shall not affect a final decision of the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary’s delegate under section 6406 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 6406</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports to congressional committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any report required to be transmitted by the Secretary of the Treasury to the appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress under <ref>section 405(e) of this title</ref> shall also be transmitted, within the 7-day period specified under such section, to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Reform and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports made by treasury inspector general for tax administration to congressional committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any report made by the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration that is required to be transmitted by the Secretary of the Treasury to the appropriate committees or subcommittees of Congress under <ref>section 405(e) of this title</ref> shall also be transmitted, within the 7-day period specified under such subsection, to the Internal Revenue Service Oversight Board and the Commissioner of Internal Revenue.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties and Responsibilities of Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration shall exercise all duties and responsibilities of an Inspector General of an establishment with respect to the Department of the Treasury and the Secretary of the Treasury on all matters relating to the Internal Revenue Service. The Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration shall have sole authority under this chapter to conduct an audit or investigation of the Internal Revenue Service Oversight Board and the Chief Counsel for the Internal Revenue Service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ability To Lead Large and Complex Organization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to the requirements of the 1st sentence of <ref>section 403(a) of this title</ref>, the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration should have demonstrated ability to lead a large and complex organization.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Appointment of Employee of Internal Revenue Service to Certain Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An individual appointed to the position of Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration, the Assistant Inspector General for Auditing of the Office of the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration under <ref>section 403(d)(1)(B)(i) of this title</ref> (or, effective <date date="2017-11-27">November 27, 2017</date>, <ref>section 403(d)(2)(B)(i) of this title</ref>), the Assistant Inspector General for Investigations of the Office of the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration under <ref>section 403(d)(1)(B)(ii) of this title</ref> (or, effective <date date="2017-11-27">November 27, 2017</date>, <ref>section 403(d)(2)(B)(ii) of this title</ref>), or any position of Deputy Inspector General of the Office of the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration may not be an employee of the Internal Revenue Service—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> during the 2-year period preceding the date of appointment to such position; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> during the 5-year period following the date such individual ends service in such position.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Additional Duties and Responsibilities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to the duties and responsibilities exercised by an inspector general of an establishment, the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall have the duty to enforce criminal provisions under section 7608(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 7608(b)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in addition to the functions authorized under section 7608(b)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<ref>26 U.S.C. 7608(b)(2)</ref>), may carry firearms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall be responsible for protecting the Internal Revenue Service against external attempts to corrupt or threaten employees of the Internal Revenue Service, but shall not be responsible for the conducting of background checks and the providing of protection to the Commissioner of Internal Revenue; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> may designate any employee in the Office of the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration to enforce such laws and perform such functions referred to under subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reporting violations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting reasonable grounds to believe a violation of federal criminal law occurred</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In performing a law enforcement function under paragraph (1), the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration shall report any reasonable grounds to believe there has been a violation of Federal criminal law to the Attorney General at an appropriate time as determined by the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration, notwithstanding <ref>section 404(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting problems, abuses, or deficiencies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the administration of <ref>section 405(e) of this title</ref> and subsection (g)(2) of this section, the Secretary of the Treasury may transmit the required report with respect to the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration at an appropriate time as determined by the Secretary, if the problem, abuse, or deficiency relates to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the performance of a law enforcement function under paragraph (1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> sensitive information concerning matters under subsection (a)(1)(A) through (F).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect the authority of any other person to carry out or enforce any provision specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Request for Audit or Investigation Relating to Internal Revenue Service.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commissioner of Internal Revenue or the Internal Revenue Service Oversight Board may request, in writing, the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration to conduct an audit or investigation relating to the Internal Revenue Service. If the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration determines not to conduct such audit or investigation, the Inspector General shall timely provide a written explanation for such determination to the person making the request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Final report of audit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any final report of an audit conducted by the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration shall be timely submitted by the Inspector General to the Commissioner of Internal Revenue and the Internal Revenue Service Oversight Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Periodic list of investigations for which final report completed</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration shall periodically submit to the Commissioner and Board a list of investigations for which a final report has been completed by the Inspector General and shall provide a copy of any such report upon request of the Commissioner or Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This paragraph applies regardless of whether the applicable audit or investigation is requested under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4229</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 413.</num>
<heading> Special provisions concerning the Department of Justice</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of attorney general over certain audits and investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding the 2d sentence and last sentence of <ref>section 403(a) of this title</ref>, the Inspector General shall be under the authority, direction, and control of the Attorney General with respect to audits or investigations, or the issuance of subpoenas, which require access to sensitive information concerning—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ongoing civil or criminal investigations or proceedings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> undercover operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the identity of confidential sources, including protected witnesses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> intelligence or counterintelligence matters; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> other matters the disclosure of which would constitute a serious threat to national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of attorney general to prohibit carrying out or completing certain audits and investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to the information described under paragraph (1), the Attorney General may prohibit the Inspector General from carrying out or completing any audit or investigation, from accessing information described in paragraph (1), or from issuing any subpoena, after such Inspector General has decided to initiate, carry out, or complete such audit or investigation, access such information, or to issue such subpoena, if the Attorney General determines that such prohibition is necessary to prevent the disclosure of any information described under paragraph (1) or to prevent significant impairment to the national interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification and statement of reasons for exercise of power</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Attorney General exercises any power under paragraph (1) or (2), the Attorney General shall notify the Inspector General in writing, stating the reasons for such exercise. Within 30 days after receipt of any such notice, the Inspector General shall transmit a copy of such notice to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Reform and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Carrying Out Duties and Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the duties and responsibilities specified in this chapter, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may initiate, conduct and supervise such audits and investigations in the Department of Justice as the Inspector General considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> except as specified in subsection (a) and paragraph (3), may investigate allegations of criminal wrongdoing or administrative misconduct by an employee of the Department of Justice, or may, in the discretion of the Inspector General, refer such allegations to the Office of Professional Responsibility or the internal affairs office of the appropriate component of the Department of Justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall refer to the Counsel, Office of Professional Responsibility of the Department of Justice, allegations of misconduct involving Department attorneys, investigators, or law enforcement personnel, where the allegations relate to the exercise of the authority of an attorney to investigate, litigate, or provide legal advice, except that no such referral shall be made if the attorney is employed in the Office of Professional Responsibility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> may investigate allegations of criminal wrongdoing or administrative misconduct by a person who is the head of any agency or component of the Department of Justice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> shall forward the results of any investigation conducted under paragraph (4), along with any appropriate recommendation for disciplinary action, to the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any report required to be transmitted by the Attorney General to the appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress under <ref>section 405(e) of this title</ref> shall also be transmitted, within the 7-day period specified under that section, to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulation To Ensure Reporting of Certain Allegations to Inspector General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General shall ensure by regulation that any component of the Department of Justice receiving a nonfrivolous allegation of criminal wrongdoing or administrative misconduct by an employee of the Department of Justice, except with respect to allegations described in subsection (b)(3), shall report that information to the Inspector General.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–71, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-07-25">July 25, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 414.</num>
<heading> Special provisions concerning the Corporation for National and Community Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraphs (7) and (8) of <ref>section 406(a) of this title</ref>, it is within the exclusive jurisdiction of the Inspector General of the Corporation for National and Community Service to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> appoint and determine the compensation of such officers and employees in accordance with section 195(b) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 12651f(b)</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> procure the temporary and intermittent services of and compensate such experts and consultants, in accordance with <ref>section 3109(b) of this title</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">as may be necessary to carry out the functions, powers, and duties of the Inspector General.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports to Board of Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than the date on which the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service transmits any report to the Congress under subsection (b) or (c) of <ref>section 405 of this title</ref>, the Chief Executive Officer shall transmit such report to the Board of Directors of such Corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Review of Audit Reports by Board of Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than the date on which the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service transmits a report described under <ref>section 405(c) of this title</ref> to the Board of Directors as provided under subsection (b) of this section, the Chief Executive Officer shall also transmit any audit report which is described in the statement required under section 405(c)(4) to the Board of Directors. All such audit reports shall be placed on the agenda for review at the next scheduled meeting of the Board of Directors following such transmittal. The Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation shall be present at such meeting to provide any information relating to such audit reports.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report of Problem, Abuse, or Deficiency to Board of Directors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than the date on which the Inspector General of the Corporation for National and Community Service reports a problem, abuse, or deficiency under <ref>section 405(e) of this title</ref> to the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation, the Chief Executive Officer shall report such problem, abuse, or deficiency to the Board of Directors.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 415.</num>
<heading> Requirements for Federal entities and designated Federal entities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding <ref>section 401 of this title</ref>, in this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Designated federal entity.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “designated Federal entity” means Amtrak, the Appalachian Regional Commission, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Committee for Purchase From People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Consumer Product Safety Commission, the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, the Defense Intelligence Agency, the Denali Commission, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Farm Credit Administration, the Federal Election Commission, the Election Assistance Commission, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, the Federal Maritime Commission, the Federal Trade Commission, the Legal Services Corporation, the National Archives and Records Administration, the National Credit Union Administration, the National Endowment for the Arts, the National Endowment for the Humanities, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, the National Labor Relations Board, the National Science Foundation, the Peace Corps, the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Smithsonian Institution, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the United States International Trade Commission, the Postal Regulatory Commission, and the United States Postal Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amtrak</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Effective at the beginning of the first fiscal year after a fiscal year for which Amtrak receives no Federal subsidy, subparagraph (A) is amended by striking “Amtrak,”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal entity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “Federal entity” means any Government corporation (within the meaning of <ref>section 103(1) of this title</ref>), any Government controlled corporation (within the meaning of <ref>section 103(2) of this title</ref>), or any other entity in the executive branch of the Government, or any independent regulatory agency, but does not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an establishment (as defined under <ref>section 401 of this title</ref>) or part of an establishment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a designated Federal entity (as defined under paragraph (1) of this subsection) or part of a designated Federal entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Executive Office of the President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Central Intelligence Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Government Accountability Office; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any entity in the judicial or legislative branches of the Government, including the Administrative Office of the United States Courts and the Architect of the Capitol and any activities under the direction of the Architect of the Capitol.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Head of the designated federal entity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “head of the designated Federal entity” means the board or commission of the designated Federal entity, or in the event the designated Federal entity does not have a board or commission, any person or persons designated by statute as the head of a designated Federal entity and if no such designation exists, the chief policymaking officer or board of a designated Federal entity as identified in the list published pursuant to subsection (h)(1) of this section, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to the National Science Foundation, such term means the National Science Board;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to the United States Postal Service, such term means the Governors (within the meaning of <ref>section 102(3) of title 39</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> with respect to the Federal Labor Relations Authority, such term means the members of the Authority (described under <ref>section 7104 of this title</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> with respect to the Committee for Purchase From People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled, such term means the Chairman of the Committee for Purchase From People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> with respect to the National Archives and Records Administration, such term means the Archivist of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> with respect to the National Credit Union Administration, such term means the National Credit Union Administration Board (described under section 102 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1752a</ref>));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> with respect to the National Endowment of the Arts, such term means the National Council on the Arts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> with respect to the National Endowment for the Humanities, such term means the National Council on the Humanities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> with respect to the Peace Corps, such term means the Director of the Peace Corps; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> with respect to the United States International Development Finance Corporation, such term means the Board of Directors of the United States International Development Finance Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Head of the federal entity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “head of the Federal entity” means any person or persons designated by statute as the head of a Federal entity, and if no such designation exists, the chief policymaking officer or board of a Federal entity as identified in the list published pursuant to subsection (h)(1) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspector general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Inspector General” means an Inspector General of a designated Federal entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Office of inspector general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Office of Inspector General” means an Office of Inspector General of a designated Federal entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Office of Inspector General in Each Designated Federal Entity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 180 days after <date date="1988-10-18">October 18, 1988</date>, there shall be established and maintained in each designated Federal entity an Office of Inspector General. The head of the designated Federal entity shall transfer to such office the offices, units, or other components, and the functions, powers, or duties thereof, that such head determines are properly related to the functions of the Office of Inspector General and would, if so transferred, further the purposes of this section. There shall not be transferred to such office any program operating responsibilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment of Inspector General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided under subsection (f) of this section, the Inspector General shall be appointed by the head of the designated Federal entity in accordance with the applicable laws and regulations governing appointments within the designated Federal entity. Each Inspector General shall be appointed without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations. For purposes of implementing this section, the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall appoint the Inspector General of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection. The Inspector General of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall have all of the authorities and responsibilities provided by this Act with respect to the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, as if the Bureau were part of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Supervision.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Inspector General shall report to and be under the general supervision of the head of the designated Federal entity, but shall not report to, or be subject to supervision by, any other officer or employee of such designated Federal entity. Except as provided in paragraph (2), the head of the designated Federal entity shall not prevent or prohibit the Inspector General from initiating, carrying out, or completing any audit or investigation, or from issuing any subpoena during the course of any audit or investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exception relating to intelligence community.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, may prohibit the inspector general of an element of the intelligence community specified in subparagraph (D) from initiating, carrying out, or completing any audit or investigation, or from accessing information available to an element of the intelligence community specified in subparagraph (D), if the Secretary determines that the prohibition is necessary to protect vital national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Statement of reasons for exercise of authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary exercises the authority under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit to the committees of Congress specified in subparagraph (E) an appropriately classified statement of the reasons for the exercise of such authority not later than 7 days after the exercise of such authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification to inspector general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>At the same time the Secretary submits under subparagraph (B) a statement on the exercise of the authority in subparagraph (A) to the committees of Congress specified in subparagraph (E), the Secretary shall notify the inspector general of such element of the submittal of such statement and, to the extent consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods, provide such inspector general with a copy of such statement. Such inspector general may submit to such committees of Congress any comments on a notice or statement received by the inspector general under this subparagraph that the inspector general considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements of the intelligence community</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The elements of the intelligence community specified in this subparagraph are as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Defense Intelligence Agency.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The National Reconnaissance Office.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The National Security Agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Committees of congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The committees of Congress specified in this subparagraph are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Removal.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Board, chairman of committee, or commission is head of designated federal entity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a designated Federal entity for which a board, chairman of a committee, or commission is the head of the designated Federal entity, a removal under this subsection may only be made upon the written concurrence of a ⅔ majority of the board, committee, or commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspector general removed or transferred</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an Inspector General is removed from office or is transferred to another position or location within a designated Federal entity, the head of the designated Federal entity shall communicate in writing the reasons for any such removal or transfer to both Houses of Congress, not later than 30 days before the removal or transfer. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a personnel action otherwise authorized by law, other than transfer or removal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">United States Postal Service.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of carrying out subsection (c) with respect to the United States Postal Service, the appointment provisions of <ref>section 202(e) of title 39</ref> shall be applied.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Oversight responsibility of inspector general for activities of postal inspection service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out the duties and responsibilities specified in this chapter, the Inspector General of the United States Postal Service (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the “Inspector General”) shall have oversight responsibility for all activities of the Postal Inspection Service, including any internal investigation performed by the Postal Inspection Service. The Chief Postal Inspector shall promptly report the significant activities being carried out by the Postal Inspection Service to such Inspector General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Audits and investigations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority, direction, and control of governors.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access to sensitive information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (d), the Inspector General shall be under the authority, direction, and control of the Governors with respect to audits or investigations, or the issuance of subpoenas, which require access to sensitive information concerning—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> ongoing civil or criminal investigations or proceedings;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> undercover operations;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the identity of confidential sources, including protected witnesses;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> intelligence or counterintelligence matters; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> other matters the disclosure of which would constitute a serious threat to national security.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to prohibit inspector general from carrying out or completing audit or investigation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to the information described under clause (i), the Governors may prohibit the Inspector General from carrying out or completing any audit or investigation, or from issuing any subpoena, after such Inspector General has decided to initiate, carry out, or complete such audit or investigation or to issue such subpoena, if the Governors determine that such prohibition is necessary to prevent the disclosure of any information described under clause (i) or to prevent significant impairment to the national interests of the United States.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of reasons for exercise of power</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Governors exercise any power under clause (i) or (ii), the Governors shall notify the Inspector General in writing, stating the reasons for such exercise. Within 30 days after receipt of any such notice, the Inspector General shall transmit a copy of such notice to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives, and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Initiating, conducting, and supervising audits and investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out the duties and responsibilities specified in this chapter, the Inspector General—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> may initiate, conduct, and supervise such audits and investigations in the United States Postal Service as the Inspector General considers appropriate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall give particular regard to the activities of the Postal Inspection Service with a view toward avoiding duplication and ensuring effective coordination and cooperation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting serious problems, abuses, or deficiencies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any report required to be transmitted by the Governors to the appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress under <ref>section 405(e) of this title</ref> shall also be transmitted, within the 7-day period specified under such section, to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this chapter shall restrict, eliminate, or otherwise adversely affect any of the rights, privileges, or benefits of either employees of the United States Postal Service, or labor organizations representing employees of the United States Postal Service, under chapter 12 of title 39, the National Labor Relations Act, any handbook or manual affecting employee labor relations with the United States Postal Service, or any collective bargaining agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of governors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “Governors” has the meaning given the term by <ref>section 102(3) of title 39</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There are authorized to be appropriated, out of the Postal Service Fund, such sums as may be necessary for the Office of Inspector General of the United States Postal Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special Application.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sections 404, 405, 406, and 407</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Sections 404, 405, 406 (other than paragraphs (7) and (8) of section 406(a)), and 407 of this title shall apply to each Inspector General and Office of Inspector General of a designated Federal entity, and such sections shall be applied to each designated Federal entity and head of the designated Federal entity (as defined under subsection (a)) by substituting—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> “designated Federal entity” for “establishment”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> “head of the designated Federal entity” for “head of the establishment”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In addition to the other authorities specified in this chapter, an Inspector General is authorized to select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees as may be necessary for carrying out the functions, powers, and duties of the Office of Inspector General and to obtain the temporary or intermittent services of experts or consultants or an organization of experts or consultants, subject to the applicable laws and regulations that govern such selections, appointments, and employment, and the obtaining of such services, within the designated Federal entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of section </inline>412(a).—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding the last sentence of subsection (d)(1) of this section, the provisions of subsection (a) of <ref>section 412 of this title</ref> (other than the provisions of subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (E) of subsection (a)(1) of <ref>section 412 of this title</ref>) shall apply to the Inspector General of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection and the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System in the same manner as such provisions apply to the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury and the Secretary of the Treasury, respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Counsel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each Inspector General shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in accordance with applicable laws and regulations governing appointments within the designated Federal entity, appoint a Counsel to the Inspector General who shall report to the Inspector General;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> obtain the services of a counsel appointed by and directly reporting to another Inspector General on a reimbursable basis; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> obtain the services of appropriate staff of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency on a reimbursable basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Annual Listing and Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Listing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each year, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, after consultation with the Comptroller General of the United States, shall publish in the Federal Register a list of the Federal entities and designated Federal entities and if the designated Federal entity is not a board or commission, include the head of each such entity (as defined under subsection (a)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>On October 31 of each year, the head of each Federal entity (as defined under subsection (a)) shall prepare and transmit to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and to each House of the Congress a report that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> states whether there has been established in the Federal entity an office that meets the requirements of this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> specifies the actions taken by the Federal entity otherwise to ensure that audits are conducted of its programs and operations in accordance with the standards for audit of governmental organizations, programs, activities, and functions issued by the Comptroller General of the United States, and includes a list of each audit report completed by a Federal or non-Federal auditor during the reporting period and a summary of any particularly significant findings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> summarizes any matters relating to the personnel, programs, and operations of the Federal entity referred to prosecutive authorities, including a summary description of any preliminary investigation conducted by or at the request of the Federal entity concerning these matters, and the prosecutions and convictions which have resulted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 416.</num>
<heading> Additional provisions with respect to Inspectors General of the intelligence community</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Intelligence committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “intelligence committees” means the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Urgent concern</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “urgent concern” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A serious or flagrant problem, abuse, violation of law or Executive order, or deficiency relating to the funding, administration, or operations of an intelligence activity involving classified information, but does not include differences of opinions concerning public policy matters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A false statement to Congress, or a willful withholding from Congress, on an issue of material fact relating to the funding, administration, or operation of an intelligence activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An action, including a personnel action described in <ref>section 2302(a)(2)(A) of this title</ref> constituting reprisal or threat of reprisal prohibited under <ref>section 407(c) of this title</ref> in response to an employee’s reporting an urgent concern in accordance with this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “employee” includes a former employee or former contractor, if the complaint or information reported pursuant to this section arises from or relates to the period during which the former employee or former contractor was an employee or contractor, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Intelligence community</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “intelligence community” has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Complaint or Information With Respect to Urgent Concern.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">To whom reports may be made; support for written submission.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspector general of department of defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An employee of the Defense Intelligence Agency, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, the National Reconnaissance Office, or the National Security Agency, or of a contractor of any of those Agencies, who intends to report to Congress a complaint or information with respect to an urgent concern may report the complaint or information in writing to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense (or designee).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspector general of intelligence community</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An employee of an element of the intelligence community, an employee assigned or detailed to an element of the intelligence community, or an employee of a contractor to the intelligence community, who intends to report to Congress a complaint or information with respect to an urgent concern may report such complaint or information in writing to the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspector general of department of justice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An employee of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or of a contractor of the Bureau, who intends to report to Congress a complaint or information with respect to an urgent concern may report the complaint or information in writing to the Inspector General of the Department of Justice (or designee).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other appropriate inspector general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any other employee of, or contractor to, an executive agency, or element or unit thereof, determined by the President under <ref>section 2302(a)(2)(C)(ii) of this title</ref>, to have as its principal function the conduct of foreign intelligence or counterintelligence activities, who intends to report to Congress a complaint or information with respect to an urgent concern may report the complaint or information in writing to the appropriate Inspector General (or designee) under this chapter, section 17 of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3517</ref>), or section 103H(k) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3033(k)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support for written submission</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Inspector General shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provide reasonable support necessary to ensure that an employee can submit a complaint or information under this paragraph in writing; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if such submission is not feasible, shall create a written record of the employee’s verbal complaint or information and treat such written record as a written submission.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designee to report complaint or information to inspector general within 7 days</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a designee of an Inspector General under this section receives a complaint or information of an employee with respect to an urgent concern, that designee shall report the complaint or information to the Inspector General within 7 calendar days of receipt.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designees of inspector general of department of defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspectors General of the Defense Intelligence Agency, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, the National Reconnaissance Office, and the National Security Agency shall be designees of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Initial Determinations and Transmittals.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Credibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In accordance with paragraph (2), the Inspector General shall determine whether a complaint or information reported under subsection (b) appears credible. Upon making such a determination, the Inspector General shall transmit to the head of the establishment notice of that determination, together with the complaint or information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deadline for compliance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General shall make the determination under paragraph (1) with respect to a complaint or information reported under subsection (b) not later than the end of the 14-calendar-day period beginning on the date on which the employee who reported the complaint or information confirms to the Inspector General the intent of the employee to report to Congress that complaint or information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conflict of interest</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the head of an establishment determines that a complaint or information transmitted under paragraph (1) would create a conflict of interest for the head of the establishment, the head of the establishment shall return the complaint or information to the Inspector General with that determination and the Inspector General shall make the transmission to the Director of National Intelligence and, if the establishment is within the Department of Defense, to the Secretary of Defense. In such a case, the requirements of this section for the head of the establishment apply to each recipient of the Inspector General’s transmission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Forwarding Transmittals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon receipt of a transmittal from the Inspector General under subsection (c), the head of the establishment shall, within 7 calendar days of such receipt, forward such transmittal to the intelligence committees, together with any comments the head of the establishment considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Submitting Complaint or Information to Congress.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Inspector General does not find credible under subsection (c) a complaint or information submitted to the Inspector General under subsection (b), or does not transmit the complaint or information to the head of the establishment in accurate form under subsection (c), the employee (subject to paragraph (2)) may submit the complaint or information to Congress by contacting either or both of the intelligence committees directly.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The employee may contact the intelligence committees directly as described in paragraph (1) only if the employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> before making such a contact, furnishes to the head of the establishment, through the Inspector General, a statement of the employee’s complaint or information and notice of the employee’s intent to contact the intelligence committees directly; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> obtains and follows from the head of the establishment, through the Inspector General, direction on how to contact the intelligence committees in accordance with appropriate security practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Intelligence committee receipt of complaint or information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member or employee of one of the intelligence committees who receives a complaint or information under paragraph (1) does so in that member or employee’s official capacity as a member or employee of that committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General shall notify an employee who reports a complaint or information under this section of each action taken under this section with respect to the complaint or information. Such notice shall be provided not later than 3 days after any such action is taken.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Judicial Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An action taken by the head of an establishment or an Inspector General under subsections (b) through (f) shall not be subject to judicial review.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice of Submission and Date</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual who has submitted a complaint or information to an Inspector General under this section may notify any member of the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives or the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, or a staff member of either such Committee, of the fact that such individual has made a submission to that particular Inspector General, and of the date on which such submission was made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Protection for Individuals Making Authorized Disclosures.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclosure</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual may disclose classified information to an Inspector General of an element of the intelligence community in accordance with the applicable security standards and procedures established under section 102A or 803 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3024</ref>, 3162a), chapter 12 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2161</ref> et seq.), Executive Order 13526 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3161</ref> note; relating to Classified National Security Information), or any applicable provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Disclosure without clearance or authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A disclosure under paragraph (1) of classified information made by an individual without appropriate clearance or authority to access such classified information at the time of the disclosure, but that is otherwise made in accordance with applicable security standards and procedures, shall be treated as an authorized disclosure that does not violate a covered provision.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in subparagraph (A) may be construed to limit or modify the obligation of an individual to appropriately store, handle, or disseminate classified information in accordance with applicable security guidance and procedures, including with respect to the removal or retention of classified information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered provision defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this paragraph, the term “covered provision” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any otherwise applicable nondisclosure agreement;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any otherwise applicable regulation or order issued under the authority of chapter 18 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2271</ref> et seq.) or Executive Order 13526;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content><ref>section 798 of title 18</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any other provision of law with respect to the unauthorized disclosure of national security information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. F, title LXVII</ref>, §§ 6701(c), 6702(c), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2512</ref>, 2514.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 417.</num>
<heading> Special provisions concerning the Department of Homeland Security</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of secretary of homeland security over certain audits and investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding the 2d sentence and last sentence of <ref>section 403(a) of this title</ref>, the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall be under the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to audits or investigations, or the issuance of subpoenas, that require access to sensitive information concerning—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> intelligence, counterintelligence, or counterterrorism matters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ongoing criminal investigations or proceedings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> undercover operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the identity of confidential sources, including protected witnesses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> other matters the disclosure of which would, in the Secretary’s judgment, constitute a serious threat to the protection of any person or property authorized protection by <ref>section 3056 of title 18</ref>, <ref>section 3056A of title 18</ref>, or any provision of the Presidential Protection Assistance Act of 1976 (<ref>18 U.S.C. 3056</ref> note); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> other matters the disclosure of which would constitute a serious threat to national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of secretary of homeland security to prohibit carrying out or completing audits or investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to the information described in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security may prohibit the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security from carrying out or completing any audit or investigation, from accessing information described in paragraph (1), or from issuing any subpoena, after such Inspector General has decided to initiate, carry out, or complete such audit or investigation, access such information, or to issue such subpoena, if the Secretary determines that such prohibition is necessary to prevent the disclosure of any information described in paragraph (1), to preserve the national security, or to prevent a significant impairment to the interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification of exercise of power</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the Secretary of Homeland Security exercises any power under paragraph (1) or (2), the Secretary shall notify the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security in writing within 7 days, stating the reasons for such exercise. Within 30 days after receipt of any such notice, the Inspector General shall transmit to the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and appropriate committees and subcommittees of Congress the following—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a copy of such notice; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a written response to such notice that includes a statement regarding whether the Inspector General agrees or disagrees with such exercise, and the reasons for any disagreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Not a Limitation on Congressional Access to Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The exercise of authority by the Secretary described in subsection (a)(2) should not be construed as limiting the right of Congress or any committee of Congress to access any information it seeks.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of Inspector General To Initiate, Conduct, and Supervise Audits and Investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the conditions established in subsections (a) and (b), in carrying out the duties and responsibilities specified in this chapter, the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security may initiate, conduct, and supervise such audits and investigations in the Department of Homeland Security as the Inspector General considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any report required to be transmitted by the Secretary of Homeland Security to the appropriate committees or subcommittees of Congress under <ref>section 405(e) of this title</ref> shall be transmitted, within the 7-day period specified in <ref>section 405(e) of this title</ref>, to the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and appropriate committees and subcommittees of Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Oversight Responsibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in carrying out the duties and responsibilities specified in this chapter, the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall have oversight responsibility for the internal investigations performed by the Office of Internal Affairs of the United States Customs Service, the Office of Inspections of the United States Secret Service, the Bureau of Border Security, and the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services. The head of each such office or bureau shall promptly report to the Inspector General the significant activities being carried out by such office or bureau.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Designated Senior Official.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall designate a senior official within the Office of Inspector General, who shall be a career member of the civil service at the equivalent to the GS–15 level or a career member of the Senior Executive Service, to perform the functions described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The senior official designated under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordinate the activities of the Office of Inspector General with respect to investigations of abuses of civil rights or civil liberties;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> receive and review complaints and information from any source alleging abuses of civil rights and civil liberties by employees or officials of the Department and employees or officials of independent contractors or grantees of the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> initiate investigations of alleged abuses of civil rights or civil liberties by employees or officials of the Department and employees or officials of independent contractors or grantees of the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> ensure that personnel within the Office of Inspector General receive sufficient training to conduct effective civil rights and civil liberties investigations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> consult with the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties regarding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> alleged abuses of civil rights or civil liberties; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any policy recommendations regarding civil rights and civil liberties that may be founded upon an investigation by the Office of Inspector General;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> provide the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties with information regarding the outcome of investigations of alleged abuses of civil rights and civil liberties;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> refer civil rights and civil liberties matters that the Inspector General decides not to investigate to the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that the Office of the Inspector General publicizes and provides convenient public access to information regarding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the procedure to file complaints or comments concerning civil rights and civil liberties matters; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the status of corrective actions taken by the Department in response to Office of the Inspector General reports; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> inform the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of any weaknesses, problems, and deficiencies within the Department relating to civil rights or civil liberties.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 418.</num>
<heading> Rule of construction of special provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The special provisions under section 408, 409, 410, 411, 412, 413, 414, 416, or 421 of this title relate only to the establishment named in such section and no inference shall be drawn from the presence or absence of a provision in any such section with respect to an establishment not named in such section or with respect to a designated Federal entity as defined under <ref>section 415(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 419.</num>
<heading> Special provisions concerning overseas contingency operations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Responsibilities of Chair of Council of Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Chair of the Council of Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (CIGIE) shall, in consultation with the members of the Council, have the additional responsibilities specified in subsection (b) with respect to the Inspectors General specified in subsection (c) upon the earlier of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the commencement or designation of a military operation as an overseas contingency operation that exceeds 60 days; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> receipt of a notification under section 113(n) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">1</ref> of title 10 with respect to an overseas contingency operation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specific Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The responsibilities specified in this subsection are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designate lead inspector general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In consultation with the Inspectors General specified in subsection (c), to designate a lead Inspector General in accordance with subsection (d) to discharge the authorities of the lead Inspector General for the overseas contingency operation concerned as set forth in subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Resolve conflicts of jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To resolve conflicts of jurisdiction among the Inspectors General specified in subsection (c) on investigations, inspections, and audits with respect to such contingency operation in accordance with subsection (d)(2)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identify office personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To assist in identifying for the lead inspector general for such contingency operation, Inspectors General and inspector general office personnel available to assist the lead Inspector General and the other Inspectors General specified in subsection (c) on matters relating to such contingency operation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspectors General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Inspectors General specified in this subsection are the Inspectors General as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Inspector General of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Inspector General of the Department of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Inspector General of the United States Agency for International Development.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Lead Inspector General for Overseas Contingency Operation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A lead Inspector General for an overseas contingency operation shall be designated by the Chair of the Council of Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency under subsection (b)(1) not later than 30 days after the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the commencement or designation of the military operation concerned as an overeas <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002011">2</ref> contingency operation that exceeds 60 days; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> receipt of a notification under section 113(n) <sup>1</sup> of title 10 with respect to an overseas contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The lead Inspector General for a contingency operation shall be designated from among the Inspectors General specified in subsection (c).</continuation>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The lead Inspector General for an overseas contingency operation shall have the following responsibilities:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appoint associate inspector general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To appoint, from among the offices of the other Inspectors General specified in subsection (c), an Inspector General to act as associate Inspector General for the contingency operation who shall act in a coordinating role to assist the lead Inspector General in the discharge of responsibilities under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Strategic plan to conduct comprehensive oversight</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To develop and carry out, in coordination with the offices of the other Inspectors General specified in subsection (c), a joint strategic plan to conduct comprehensive oversight over all aspects of the contingency operation and to ensure through either joint or individual audits, inspections, and investigations, independent and effective oversight of all programs and operations of the Federal Government in support of the contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accuracy of information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To review and ascertain the accuracy of information provided by Federal agencies relating to obligations and expenditures, costs of programs and projects, accountability of funds, and the award and execution of major contracts, grants, and agreements in support of the contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Jurisdictional matters.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No inspector general with principal jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If none of the Inspectors General specified in subsection (c) has principal jurisdiction over a matter with respect to the contingency operation, to identify and coordinate with the Inspector General who has principal jurisdiction over the matter to ensure effective oversight.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">More than one inspector general with jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If more than one of the Inspectors General specified in subsection (c) has jurisdiction over a matter with respect to the contingency operation, to determine principal jurisdiction for discharging oversight responsibilities in accordance with this chapter with respect to such matter.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Investigations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Request by inspector general with principal jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon written request by the Inspector General with principal jurisdiction over a matter with respect to the contingency operation, and with the approval of the lead Inspector General, an Inspector General specified in subsection (c) may provide investigative support or conduct an independent investigation of an allegation of criminal activity by any United States personnel, contractor, subcontractor, grantee, or vendor in the applicable theater of operations.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No inspector general with principal jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In the case of a determination by the lead Inspector General that no Inspector General has principal jurisdiction over a matter with respect to the contingency operation, the lead Inspector General may—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> conduct an independent investigation of an allegation described in subclause (I); or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> request that an Inspector General specified in subsection (c) conduct such investigation.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To employ, or authorize the employment by the other Inspectors General specified in subsection (c), on a temporary basis using the authorities in <ref>section 3161 of this title</ref> (without regard to subsection (b)(2) of that section), such auditors, investigators, and other personnel as the lead Inspector General considers appropriate to assist the lead Inspector General and such other Inspectors General on matters relating to the contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report on activity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To submit to Congress on a bi-annual basis, and to make available on an internet website available to the public, a report on the activities of the lead Inspector General and the other Inspectors General specified in subsection (c) with respect to the contingency operation, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the status and results of investigations, inspections, and audits and of referrals to the Department of Justice; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> overall plans for the review of the contingency operation by inspectors general, including plans for investigations, inspections, and audits.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report on contingency operation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To submit to Congress on a quarterly basis, and to make available on an Internet website available to the public, a report on the contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To carry out such other responsibilities relating to the coordination and efficient and effective discharge by the Inspectors General specified in subsection (c) of duties relating to the contingency operation as the lead Inspector General shall specify.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enhancing cooperation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To enhance cooperation among Inspectors General and encourage comprehensive oversight of the contingency operation, any Inspector General responsible for conducting oversight of any program or operation performed in support of the contingency operation may, to the maximum extent practicable and consistent with the duties, responsibilities, policies, and procedures of that Inspector General—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> coordinate such oversight activities with the lead Inspector General; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide information requested by the lead Inspector General relating to the responsibilities of the lead Inspector General described in subparagraphs (B), (C), and (G).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Employment of annuitants.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The lead Inspector General for an overseas contingency operation may employ, or authorize the employment by the other Inspectors General specified in subsection (c) of, annuitants covered by <ref>section 9902(g) of this title</ref>, for purposes of assisting the lead Inspector General in discharging responsibilities under this subsection with respect to the contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deemed department of defense</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The employment of annuitants under this paragraph shall be subject to the provisions of <ref>section 9902(g) of this title</ref> as if the lead Inspector General concerned was the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Foreign service annuitants.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuance of annuity</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An annuitant receiving an annuity under the Foreign Service Retirement and Disability System or the Foreign Service Pension System under chapter 8 of title I of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 4041</ref> et seq.) who is reemployed under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> shall continue to receive the annuity; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> shall not be considered a participant for purposes of chapter 8 of title I of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 4041</ref> et seq.) or an employee for purposes of subchapter III of chapter 83 or chapter 84 of this title.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Election regarding reemployment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An annuitant described in clause (i) may elect in writing for the reemployment of the annuitant under this subsection to be subject to section 824 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 4064</ref>). A reemployed annuitant shall make an election under this clause not later than 90 days after the date of the reemployment of the annuitant.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Discharge of responsibilities in accordance with chapter</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The lead Inspector General for an overseas contingency operation shall discharge the responsibilities for the contingency operation under this subsection in a manner consistent with the authorities and requirements of this chapter generally and the authorities and requirements applicable to the Inspectors General specified in subsection (c) under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Ccompetitive</inline> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002012">3</ref> <inline class="small-caps">status for appointment.—</inline></heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A person employed by a lead Inspector General for an overseas contingency operation under this section shall acquire competitive status for appointment to any position in the competitive service for which the employee possesses the required qualifications upon the completion of 2 years of continuous service as an employee under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No person who is first employed as described in subparagraph (A) more than 10 years after <date date="2019-12-19">December 19, 2019</date>,<sup>1</sup> may acquire competitive status under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sunset for Particular Contingency Operations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirements and authorities of this section with respect to an overseas contingency operation shall cease at the end of the first fiscal year after the commencement or designation of the contingency operation in which the total amount appropriated for the contingency operation is less than $100,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction of Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the ability of the Inspectors General specified in subsection (c) to enter into agreements to conduct joint audits, inspections, or investigations in the exercise of their oversight responsibilities in accordance with this chapter with respect to overseas contingency operations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XI, § 1106</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 427</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LVII, § 5704</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 420.</num>
<heading> Information on websites of Offices of Inspectors General</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Direct Links to Inspectors General Offices.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Federal agency and designated Federal entity shall establish and maintain on the homepage of the website of that Federal agency or designated Federal entity, a direct link to the website of the Office of the Inspector General of that Federal agency or designated Federal entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Accessibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The direct link under paragraph (1) shall be obvious and facilitate accessibility to the website of the Office of the Inspector General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Inspectors General Websites.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Posting of reports and audits</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Inspector General of each Federal agency and designated Federal entity shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not later than 3 days after any audit report, inspection report, or evaluation report (or portion of any such report) is submitted in final form to the head of the Federal agency or the head of the designated Federal entity, as applicable, post that report (or portion of that report) on the website of the Office of Inspector General; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that any posted report (or portion of that report) described under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is easily accessible from a direct link on the homepage of the website of the Office of the Inspector General;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> includes a summary of the findings of the Inspector General; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> is in a format that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is searchable and downloadable; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> facilitates printing by individuals of the public accessing the website.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reporting of fraud, waste, and abuse.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General of each Federal agency and designated Federal entity shall establish and maintain a direct link on the homepage of the website of the Office of the Inspector General for individuals to report fraud, waste, and abuse. Individuals reporting fraud, waste, or abuse using the direct link established under this paragraph shall not be required to provide personally identifying information relating to that individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Anonymity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Inspector General of each Federal agency and designated Federal entity shall not disclose the identity of any individual making a report under this paragraph without the consent of the individual unless the Inspector General determines that such a disclosure is unavoidable during the course of the investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as authorizing an Inspector General to publicly disclose information otherwise prohibited from disclosure by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the terms “designated Federal entity” and “head of the designated Federal entity” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 415(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4251</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 421.</num>
<heading> Additional provisions with respect to the Department of Energy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Prohibit Access to Certain Materials</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Energy may prohibit the Inspector General of the Department of Energy from accessing Restricted Data and nuclear safeguards information protected from disclosure under chapter 12 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2161</ref> et seq.) and intelligence or counterintelligence, as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>), if the Secretary of Energy determines that the prohibition is necessary to protect the national security or prevent the significant impairment to the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification to Inspector General and Statement to Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 7 days after the date on which the Secretary of Energy exercises any power authorized under subsection (a), the Secretary shall notify the Inspector General of the Department of Energy in writing of the reasons for such exercise. Within 30 days after receipt of any such notice, the Inspector General of the Department of Energy shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a statement concerning such exercise.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4252</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 422.</num>
<heading> Transfer of functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There shall be transferred—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to the Office of Inspector General—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> of the Department of Agriculture, the offices of that department referred to as the “Office of Investigation” and the “Office of Audit”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> of the Department of Commerce, the offices of that department referred to as the “Office of Audits” and the “Investigations and Inspections Staff” and that portion of the office referred to as the “Office of Investigations and Security” which has responsibility for investigation of alleged criminal violations and program abuse;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> of the Department of Defense, the offices of that department referred to as the “Defense Audit Service” and the “Office of Inspector General, Defense Logistics Agency”, and that portion of the office of that department referred to as the “Defense Investigative Service” which has responsibility for the investigation of alleged criminal violations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> of the Department of Education, all functions of the Inspector General of Health, Education, and Welfare or of the Office of Inspector General of Health, Education, and Welfare relating to functions transferred by section 301 of the Department of Education Organization Act (<ref>20 U.S.C. 3441</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> of the Department of Energy, the Office of Inspector General (as established by section 208 of the Department of Energy Organization Act);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> of the Department of Health and Human Services, the Office of Inspector General (as established by title II of <ref>Public Law 94–505</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the office of that department referred to as the “Office of Inspector General”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> of the Department of the Interior, the office of that department referred to as the “Office of Audit and Investigation”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<chapeau> of the Department of Justice—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the offices of that Department referred to as—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the “Audit Staff, Justice Management Division”;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the “Policy and Procedures Branch, Office of the Comptroller, Immigration and Naturalization Service”, the “Office of Professional Responsibility, Immigration and Naturalization Service”, and the “Office of Program Inspections, Immigration and Naturalization Service”;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the “Office of Internal Inspection, United States Marshals Service”; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the “Financial Audit Section, Office of Financial Management, Bureau of Prisons” and the “Office of Inspections, Bureau of Prisons”; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> from the Drug Enforcement Administration, that portion of the “Office of Inspections” which is engaged in internal audit activities, and that portion of the “Office of Planning and Evaluation” which is engaged in program review activities;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> of the Department of Labor, the office of that department referred to as the “Office of Special Investigations”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> of the Department of Transportation, the offices of that department referred to as the “Office of Investigations and Security” and the “Office of Audit” of the Department, the “Offices of Investigations and Security, Federal Aviation Administration”, and “External Audit Divisions, Federal Aviation Administration”, the “Investigations Division and the External Audit Division of the Office of Program Review and Investigation, Federal Highway Administration”, and the “Office of Program Audits, Federal Transit Administration”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of the Department of the Treasury, the office of that department referred to as the “Office of Inspector General”, and, notwithstanding any other provision of law, that portion of each of the offices of that department referred to as the “Office of Internal Affairs, Tax and Trade Bureau”, the “Office of Internal Affairs, United States Customs Service”, and the “Office of Inspections, United States Secret Service” which is engaged in internal audit activities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> of the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration, effective 180 days after <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, the Office of Chief Inspector of the Internal Revenue Service;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> of the Environmental Protection Agency, the offices of that agency referred to as the “Office of Audit” and the “Security and Inspection Division”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the office of that agency referred to as the “Office of Inspector General”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> of the General Services Administration, the offices of that agency referred to as the “Office of Audits” and the “Office of Investigations”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the offices of that agency referred to as the “Management Audit Office” and the “Office of Inspections and Security”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the office of that commission referred to as the “Office of Inspector and Auditor”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(R)</num>
<content> of the Office of Personnel Management, the offices of that agency referred to as the “Office of Inspector General”, the “Insurance Audits Division, Retirement and Insurance Group”, and the “Analysis and Evaluation Division, Administration Group”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(S)</num>
<content> of the Railroad Retirement Board, the Office of Inspector General (as established by section 23 of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(T)</num>
<content> of the Small Business Administration, the office of that agency referred to as the “Office of Audits and Investigations”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(U)</num>
<content> of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the offices of that department referred to as the “Office of Audits” and the “Office of Investigations”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> of the Corporation for National and Community Service, the Office of Inspector General of ACTION; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(W)</num>
<content> of the Social Security Administration, the functions of the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services which are transferred to the Social Security Administration by the Social Security Independence and Program Improvements Act of 1994 (other than functions performed pursuant to section 105(a)(2) of such Act), except that such transfers shall be made in accordance with the provisions of such Act and shall not be subject to subsections (b) through (d) of this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to the Office of the Inspector General, such other offices or agencies, or functions, powers, or duties thereof, as the head of the establishment involved may determine are properly related to the functions of the Office and would, if so transferred, further the purposes of this chapter,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">except that there shall not be transferred to an Inspector General under paragraph (2) program operating responsibilities.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Related Transfers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The personnel, assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, held, used, arising from, available or to be made available, of any office or agency the functions, powers, and duties of which are transferred under subsection (a) are hereby transferred to the applicable Office of Inspector General.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Personnel transferred pursuant to subsection (b) shall be transferred in accordance with applicable laws and regulations relating to the transfer of functions except that the classification and compensation of such personnel shall not be reduced for one year after such transfer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Lapse of Office or Agency and Compensation for Transferred Positions With Comparable Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In any case in which all the functions, powers, and duties of any office or agency are transferred pursuant to this subsection, such office or agency shall lapse. Any person who, on <date date="1978-10-01">October 1, 1978</date>, held a position compensated in accordance with the General Schedule, and who, without a break in service, is appointed in an Office of Inspector General to a position having duties comparable to those performed immediately preceding such appointment shall continue to be compensated in the new position at not less than the rate provided for the previous position, for the duration of service in the new position.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4252</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 423.</num>
<heading> Pay of Inspectors General</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Certain Inspectors General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the annual rate of basic pay of the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, the Inspector General of the Central Intelligence Agency, and the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction shall be that of an Inspector General as defined under <ref>section 401 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition of cash bonus or awards</inline>.—</heading>
<content><ref>Section 403(f) of this title</ref> shall apply to the Inspectors General described under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inspectors General of Designated Federal Entities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Inspector General of each designated Federal entity (as those terms are defined under <ref>section 415(a) of this title</ref>) shall, for pay and all other purposes, be classified at a grade, level, or rank designation, as the case may be, at or above those of a majority of the senior level executives of that designated Federal entity (such as a General Counsel, Chief Information Officer, Chief Financial Officer, Chief Human Capital Officer, or Chief Acquisition Officer). The pay of an Inspector General of a designated Federal entity (as those terms are defined under <ref>section 415(a) of this title</ref>) shall be not less than the average total compensation (including bonuses) of the senior level executives of that designated Federal entity calculated on an annual basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Savings Provision for Newly Appointed Inspectors General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The provisions of <ref>section 3392 of this title</ref>, other than the terms “performance awards” and “awarding of ranks” in subsection (c)(1) of that section, shall apply to career appointees of the Senior Executive Service who are appointed to the position of Inspector General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nonreduction in pay</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, career Federal employees serving on an appointment made pursuant to statutory authority found other than in <ref>section 3392 of this title</ref> shall not suffer a reduction in pay, not including any bonus or performance award, as a result of being appointed to the position of Inspector General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 424.</num>
<heading> Establishment of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Establishment and Mission.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established as an independent entity within the executive branch the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mission</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The mission of the Council shall be to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> address integrity, economy, and effectiveness issues that transcend individual Government agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> increase the professionalism and effectiveness of personnel by developing policies, standards, and approaches to aid in the establishment of a well-trained and highly skilled workforce in the offices of the Inspectors General.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall consist of the following members:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> All Inspectors General whose offices are established under—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content><ref>section 402 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content><ref>section 415 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Inspectors General of the Intelligence Community and the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Controller of the Office of Federal Financial Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A senior level official of the Federal Bureau of Investigation designated by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The Director of the Office of Government Ethics.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel of the Office of Special Counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Deputy Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The Inspectors General of the Library of Congress, Capitol Police, Government Publishing Office, Government Accountability Office, and the Architect of the Capitol.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Chairperson and executive chairperson.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive chairperson</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget shall be the Executive Chairperson of the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairperson</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall elect 1 of the Inspectors General referred to in paragraph (1)(A) or (B) to act as Chairperson of the Council. The term of office of the Chairperson shall be 2 years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Functions of chairperson and executive chairperson.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Executive chairperson</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Executive Chairperson shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> preside over meetings of the Council;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide to the heads of agencies and entities represented on the Council summary reports of the activities of the Council; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provide to the Council such information relating to the agencies and entities represented on the Council as assists the Council in performing its functions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chairperson</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Chairperson shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> convene meetings of the Council—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> at least 6 times each year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> monthly to the extent possible; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> more frequently at the discretion of the Chairperson;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> carry out the functions and duties of the Council under subsection (c);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> appoint a Vice Chairperson to assist in carrying out the functions of the Council and act in the absence of the Chairperson, from a category of Inspectors General described in subparagraph (A)(i), (A)(ii), or (B) of paragraph (1), other than the category from which the Chairperson was elected;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> make such payments from funds otherwise available to the Council as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the Council;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> select, appoint, and employ personnel as needed to carry out the functions of the Council subject to the provisions of this title governing appointments in the competitive service, and the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of this title, relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> to the extent and in such amounts as may be provided in advance by appropriations Acts, made available from the revolving fund established under subsection (c)(3)(B), or as otherwise provided by law, enter into contracts and other arrangements with public agencies and private persons to carry out the functions and duties of the Council;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> establish, in consultation with the members of the Council, such committees as determined by the Chairperson to be necessary and appropriate for the efficient conduct of Council functions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<chapeau> prepare and transmit an annual report on behalf of the Council on the activities of the Council to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the President;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the appropriate committees of jurisdiction of the Senate and the House of Representatives;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Functions and Duties of Council.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> continually identify, review, and discuss areas of weakness and vulnerability in Federal programs and operations with respect to fraud, waste, and abuse;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop plans for coordinated, Governmentwide activities that address these problems and promote economy and efficiency in Federal programs and operations, including interagency and interentity audit, investigation, inspection, and evaluation programs and projects to deal efficiently and effectively with those problems concerning fraud and waste that exceed the capability or jurisdiction of an individual agency or entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> develop policies that will aid in the maintenance of a corps of well-trained and highly skilled Office of Inspector General personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> maintain an Internet website and other electronic systems for the benefit of all Inspectors General, as the Council determines are necessary or desirable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> maintain 1 or more academies as the Council considers desirable for the professional training of auditors, investigators, inspectors, evaluators, and other personnel of the various offices of Inspector General;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> submit recommendations of individuals to the appropriate appointing authority for any appointment to an office of Inspector General described under subsection (b)(1)(A) or (B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> make such reports to Congress as the Chairperson determines are necessary or appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> except for matters coordinated among Inspectors General under section 103H of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3033</ref>), receive, review, and mediate any disputes submitted in writing to the Council by an Office of Inspector General regarding an audit, investigation, inspection, evaluation, or project that involves the jurisdiction of more than one Office of Inspector General; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> perform other duties within the authority and jurisdiction of the Council, as appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adherence and participation by members</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To the extent permitted under law, and to the extent not inconsistent with standards established by the Comptroller General of the United States for audits of Federal establishments, organizations, programs, activities, and functions, each member of the Council, as appropriate, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> adhere to professional standards developed by the Council; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> participate in the plans, programs, and projects of the Council, except that in the case of a member described under subsection (b)(1)(I), the member shall participate only to the extent requested by the member and approved by the Executive Chairperson and Chairperson.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Additional administrative authorities.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interagency funding</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding <ref>section 1532 of title 31</ref>, or any other provision of law prohibiting the interagency funding of activities described under subclause (I), (II), or (III) of clause (i), in the performance of the responsibilities, authorities, and duties of the Council—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the Executive Chairperson may authorize the use of interagency funding for—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Governmentwide training of employees of the Offices of the Inspectors General;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the functions of the Integrity Committee of the Council; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> any other authorized purpose determined by the Council; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> upon the authorization of the Executive Chairperson, any Federal agency or designated Federal entity (as defined in <ref>section 415(a) of this title</ref>) which has a member on the Council shall fund or participate in the funding of such activities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Revolving fund.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council may—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> establish in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund to be called the Inspectors General Council Fund; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> enter into an arrangement with a department or agency to use an existing revolving fund.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Amounts in revolving fund.—</inline>
</heading>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts transferred to the Council under this subsection shall be deposited in the revolving fund described under clause (i)(I) or (II).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any remaining unexpended balances appropriated for or otherwise available to the Inspectors General Criminal Investigator Academy and the Inspectors General Auditor Training Institute shall be transferred to the revolving fund described under clause (i)(I) or (II).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Use of revolving fund.—</inline>
</heading>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided under subclause (II), amounts in the revolving fund described under clause (i)(I) or (II) may be used to carry out the functions and duties of the Council under this subsection.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts transferred into the revolving fund described under clause (i)(I) or (II) may be used for the purpose of maintaining any training academy as determined by the Council.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Availability of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts in the revolving fund described under clause (i)(I) or (II) shall remain available to the Council without fiscal year limitation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Superseding provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No provision of law enacted after <date date="2008-10-14">October 14, 2008</date>, shall be construed to limit or supersede any authority under subparagraph (A) or (B), unless such provision makes specific reference to the authority in that subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Existing authorities and responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The establishment and operation of the Council shall not affect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the role of the Department of Justice in law enforcement and litigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the authority or responsibilities of any Government agency or entity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the authority or responsibilities of individual members of the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional responsibilities relating to whistleblower protection</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> facilitate the work of the Whistleblower Protection Coordinators designated under <ref>section 403(d)(1)(C) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in consultation with the Office of Special Counsel and Whistleblower Protection Coordinators from the member offices of the Inspector General, develop best practices for coordination and communication in promoting the timely and appropriate handling and consideration of protected disclosures, allegations of reprisal, and general matters regarding the implementation and administration of whistleblower protection laws, in accordance with Federal law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Integrity Committee.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall have an Integrity Committee, which shall receive, review, and refer for investigation allegations of wrongdoing that are made against Inspectors General and staff members of the various Offices of Inspector General described under paragraph (4)(C).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Integrity Committee shall consist of the following members:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The official of the Federal Bureau of Investigation serving on the Council.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Four Inspectors General described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (b)(1) appointed by the Chairperson of the Council, representing both establishments and designated Federal entities (as that term is defined in <ref>section 415(a) of this title</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The Director of the Office of Government Ethics or the designee of the Director.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Chairperson.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Integrity Committee shall elect one of the Inspectors General referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) to act as Chairperson of the Integrity Committee.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term of office of the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee shall be 2 years.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Legal advisor</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief of the Public Integrity Section of the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice, or the Chief’s designee, shall serve as a legal advisor to the Integrity Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Referral of allegations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition of staff member</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this paragraph, the term “staff member” means any employee of an Office of Inspector General who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> reports directly to an Inspector General; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is designated by an Inspector General under subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An Inspector General shall refer to the Integrity Committee any allegation of wrongdoing against a staff member of the office of that Inspector General, if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> review of the substance of the allegation cannot be assigned to an agency of the executive branch with appropriate jurisdiction over the matter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the Inspector General determines that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an objective internal investigation of the allegation is not feasible; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> an internal investigation of the allegation may appear not to be objective.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation of staff members</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Inspector General shall annually submit to the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee a designation of positions whose holders are staff members for purposes of subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Review of allegations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 7 days after the date on which the Integrity Committee receives an allegation of wrongdoing against an Inspector General or against a staff member of an Office of Inspector General described under paragraph (4)(C), the allegation of wrongdoing shall be reviewed and referred to the Department of Justice or the Office of Special Counsel for investigation, or to the Integrity Committee for review, as appropriate, by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a representative of the Department of Justice, as designated by the Attorney General;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a representative of the Office of Special Counsel, as designated by the Special Counsel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a representative of the Integrity Committee, as designated by the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Referral to the chairperson.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in clause (ii), not later than 30 days after the date on which an allegation of wrongdoing is referred to the Integrity Committee under subparagraph (A), the Integrity Committee shall determine whether to refer the allegation of wrongdoing to the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee to initiate an investigation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extension</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The 30-day period described in clause (i) may be extended for an additional period of 30 days if the Integrity Committee provides written notice to the congressional committees described in paragraph (8)(A)(iii) that includes a detailed, case-specific description of why the additional time is needed to evaluate the allegation of wrongdoing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority to investigate allegations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chairperson of the Integrity Committee shall cause a thorough and timely investigation of each allegation referred under paragraph (5)(B) to be conducted in accordance with this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Resources</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At the request of the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee, the head of each agency or entity represented on the Council—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall provide assistance necessary to the Integrity Committee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may detail employees from that agency or entity to the Integrity Committee, subject to the control and direction of the Chairperson, to conduct an investigation under this subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procedures for investigations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards applicable</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Investigations initiated under this subsection shall be conducted in accordance with the most current Quality Standards for Investigations issued by the Council or by its predecessors (the President’s Council on Integrity and Efficiency and the Executive Council on Integrity and Efficiency).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Additional policies and procedures.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Integrity Committee, in conjunction with the Chairperson of the Council, shall establish additional policies and procedures necessary to ensure fairness and consistency in—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> determining whether to initiate an investigation;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> conducting investigations;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> reporting the results of an investigation;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> providing the person who is the subject of an investigation with an opportunity to respond to any Integrity Committee report;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> except as provided in clause (ii), ensuring, to the extent possible, that investigations are conducted by Offices of Inspector General of similar size;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> creating a process for rotation of Inspectors General assigned to investigate allegations through the Integrity Committee; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VII)</num>
<content> creating procedures to avoid conflicts of interest for Integrity Committee investigations.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The requirement under clause (i)(V) shall not apply to any Office of Inspector General with less than 50 employees who are authorized to conduct audits or investigations.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Council shall submit a copy of the policies and procedures established under clause (i) to the congressional committees of jurisdiction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Completion of investigation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If an allegation of wrongdoing is referred to the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee under paragraph (5)(B), the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall complete the investigation not later than 150 days after the date on which the Integrity Committee made the referral; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> if the investigation cannot be completed within the 150-day period described in clause (i), shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> promptly notify the congressional committees described in paragraph (8)(A)(iii); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> brief the congressional committees described in paragraph (8)(A)(iii) every 30 days regarding the status of the investigation and the general reasons for delay until the investigation is complete.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Concurrent investigation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an allegation of wrongdoing against an Inspector General or a staff member of an Office of Inspector General described under paragraph (4)(C) is referred to the Department of Justice or the Office of Special Counsel under paragraph (5)(A), the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee may conduct any related investigation referred to the Chairperson under paragraph (5)(B) concurrently with the Department of Justice or the Office of Special Counsel, as applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Integrity committee investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each investigation of an allegation of wrongdoing referred to the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee under paragraph (5)(B), the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee shall submit to members of the Integrity Committee and to the Chairperson of the Council a report containing the results of the investigation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other investigations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For each allegation of wrongdoing referred to the Department of Justice or the Office of Special Counsel under paragraph (5)(A), the Attorney General or the Special Counsel, as applicable, shall submit to the Integrity Committee a report containing the results of the investigation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Availability to congress.—</inline>
</heading>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The congressional committees described in paragraph (8)(A)(iii) shall have access to any report authored by the Integrity Committee.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Members of congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to any other provision of law that would otherwise prohibit disclosure of such information, the Integrity Committee may provide any report authored by the Integrity Committee to any Member of Congress.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Assessment and final disposition.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With respect to any report received under paragraph (7)(E), the Integrity Committee shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assess the report;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> forward the report, with the recommendations of the Integrity Committee, including those on disciplinary action, within 30 days (to the maximum extent practicable) after the completion of the investigation, to the Executive Chairperson of the Council and to the President (in the case of a report relating to an Inspector General of an establishment or any employee of that Inspector General) or the head of a designated Federal entity (in the case of a report relating to an Inspector General of such an entity or any employee of that Inspector General) for resolution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> submit the report, with the recommendations of the Integrity Committee, to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives, and other congressional committees of jurisdiction; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> following the submission of the report under clause (iii) and upon request by any Member of Congress, submit the report, with the recommendations of the Integrity Committee, to that Member.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disposition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Executive Chairperson of the Council shall report to the Integrity Committee the final disposition of the matter, including what action was taken by the President or agency head.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Annual report</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall submit to Congress and the President by December 31 of each year a report on the activities of the Integrity Committee during the preceding fiscal year, which shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The number of allegations received.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The number of allegations referred to the Department of Justice or the Office of Special Counsel, including the number of allegations referred for criminal investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The number of allegations referred to the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee for investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The number of allegations closed without referral.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The date each allegation was received and the date each allegation was finally disposed of.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> In the case of allegations referred to the Chairperson of the Integrity Committee, a summary of the status of the investigation of the allegations and, in the case of investigations completed during the preceding fiscal year, a summary of the findings of the investigations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Other matters that the Council considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requests for more information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to paragraphs (8) and (9), the Council shall provide more detailed information about specific allegations upon request from any Member of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No right or benefit</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection is not intended to create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law by a person against the United States, its agencies, its officers, or any person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Allegations of wrongdoing against special counsel or deputy special counsel.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special counsel defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this paragraph, the term “Special Counsel” means the Special Counsel appointed under <ref>section 1211(b) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority of integrity committee.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An allegation of wrongdoing against the Special Counsel or the Deputy Special Counsel may be received, reviewed, and referred for investigation to the same extent and in the same manner as in the case of an allegation against an Inspector General or against a staff member of an Office of Inspector General described under paragraph (4)(C), subject to the requirement that the representative designated by the Special Counsel under paragraph (5)(A)(ii) shall recuse himself or herself from the consideration of any allegation brought under this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination with existing provisions of law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This paragraph shall not eliminate access to the Merit Systems Protection Board for review under <ref>section 7701 of title 5</ref>. To the extent that an allegation brought under this paragraph involves <ref>section 2302(b)(8) of title 5</ref>, a failure to obtain corrective action within 120 days after the date on which the allegation is received by the Integrity Committee shall, for purposes of <ref>section 1221 of title 5</ref>, be considered to satisfy <ref>section 1214(a)(3)(B) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Integrity Committee may prescribe any rules or regulations necessary to carry out this paragraph, subject to such consultation or other requirements as may otherwise apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Committee records</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chairperson of the Council shall maintain the records of the Integrity Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading> Oversight.gov.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this subsection, the term “Office of Inspector General” means the Office of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an Inspector General described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (I) of subsection (b)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction established under section 1229 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (<ref>Public Law 110–181</ref>; <ref>122 Stat. 378</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Special Inspector General for the Troubled Asset Relief Program established under section 121 of title I of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (<ref>12 U.S.C. 5231</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Special Inspector General for Pandemic Recovery established under section 4018 of the Coronavirus Economic Stabilization Act of 2020 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 9053</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Council shall establish and maintain a website entitled “oversight.gov”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to consolidate all public reports from each Office of Inspector General to improve the access of the public to any audit report, inspection report, or evaluation report (or portion of any such report) made by an Office of Inspector General; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that shall include any additional resources, information, and enhancements as the Council determines are necessary or desirable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Participation of offices of inspectors general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Office of Inspector General that publishes an audit report, inspection report, or evaluation report (or portion of any such report) on the website of the Office of Inspector General shall, or in the case of the office of an Inspector General described in subparagraph (I) of subsection (b)(1) may, contemporaneously publish the report (or portion of the report) on oversight.gov in a manner prescribed by the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection shall take effect on the date that is 30 days after the date of receipt by the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency of an appropriation for the implementation of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>