<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 77—</num>
<heading>APPEALS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7701.</num>
<heading> Appellate procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An employee, or applicant for employment, may submit an appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board from any action which is appealable to the Board under any law, rule, or regulation. An appellant shall have the right—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to a hearing for which a transcript will be kept; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to be represented by an attorney or other representative.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Appeals shall be processed in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Board.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Board may hear any case appealed to it or may refer the case to an administrative law judge appointed under <ref>section 3105 of this title</ref> or other employee of the Board designated by the Board to hear such cases, except that in any case involving a removal from the service, the case shall be heard by the Board, an employee experienced in hearing appeals, or an administrative law judge. The Board, administrative law judge, or other employee (as the case may be) shall make a decision after receipt of the written representations of the parties to the appeal and after opportunity for a hearing under subsection (a)(1) of this section. A copy of the decision shall be furnished to each party to the appeal and to the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> If an employee or applicant for employment is the prevailing party in an appeal under this subsection, the employee or applicant shall be granted the relief provided in the decision effective upon the making of the decision, and remaining in effect pending the outcome of any petition for review under subsection (e), unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the deciding official determines that the granting of such relief is not appropriate; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the relief granted in the decision provides that such employee or applicant shall return or be present at the place of employment during the period pending the outcome of any petition for review under subsection (e); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the employing agency, subject to the provisions of subparagraph (B), determines that the return or presence of such employee or applicant is unduly disruptive to the work environment.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If an agency makes a determination under subparagraph (A)(ii)(II) that prevents the return or presence of an employee at the place of employment, such employee shall receive pay, compensation, and all other benefits as terms and conditions of employment during the period pending the outcome of any petition for review under subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Nothing in the provisions of this paragraph may be construed to require any award of back pay or attorney fees be paid before the decision is final.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> With respect to an appeal from an adverse action covered by subchapter V of chapter 75, authority to mitigate the personnel action involved shall be available, subject to the same standards as would apply in an appeal involving an action covered by subchapter II of chapter 75 with respect to which mitigation authority under this section exists.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the decision of the agency shall be sustained under subsection (b) only if the agency’s decision—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an action based on unacceptable performance described in section 4303, is supported by substantial evidence; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any other case, is supported by a preponderance of the evidence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the agency’s decision may not be sustained under subsection (b) of this section if the employee or applicant for employment—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shows harmful error in the application of the agency’s procedures in arriving at such decision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shows that the decision was based on any prohibited personnel practice described in <ref>section 2302(b) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shows that the decision was not in accordance with law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In any case in which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the interpretation or application of any civil service law, rule, or regulation, under the jurisdiction of the Office of Personnel Management is at issue in any proceeding under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Director of the Office of Personnel Management is of the opinion that an erroneous decision would have a substantial impact on any civil service law, rule, or regulation under the jurisdiction of the Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Director may as a matter of right intervene or otherwise participate in that proceeding before the Board. If the Director exercises his right to participate in a proceeding before the Board, he shall do so as early in the proceeding as practicable. Nothing in this title shall be construed to permit the Office to interfere with the independent decisionmaking of the Merit Systems Protection Board.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Board shall promptly notify the Director whenever the interpretation of any civil service law, rule, or regulation under the jurisdiction of the Office is at issue in any proceeding under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in <ref>section 7702 of this title</ref>, any decision under subsection (b) of this section shall be final unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a party to the appeal or the Director petitions the Board for review within 30 days after the receipt of the decision; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Board reopens and reconsiders a case on its own motion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Board, for good cause shown, may extend the 30-day period referred to in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph. One member of the Board may grant a petition or otherwise direct that a decision be reviewed by the full Board. The preceding sentence shall not apply if, by law, a decision of an administrative law judge is required to be acted upon by the Board.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Director may petition the Board for a review under paragraph (1) of this subsection only if the Director is of the opinion that the decision is erroneous and will have a substantial impact on any civil service law, rule, or regulation under the jurisdiction of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> The Board, or an administrative law judge or other employee of the Board designated to hear a case, may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consolidate appeals filed by two or more appellants, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> join two or more appeals filed by the same appellant and hear and decide them concurrently,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">if the deciding official or officials hearing the cases are of the opinion that the action could result in the appeals’ being processed more expeditiously and would not adversely affect any party.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board, or an administrative law judge or other employee of the Board designated to hear a case, may require payment by the agency involved of reasonable attorney fees incurred by an employee or applicant for employment if the employee or applicant is the prevailing party and the Board, administrative law judge, or other employee (as the case may be) determines that payment by the agency is warranted in the interest of justice, including any case in which a prohibited personnel practice was engaged in by the agency or any case in which the agency’s action was clearly without merit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If an employee or applicant for employment is the prevailing party and the decision is based on a finding of discrimination prohibited under <ref>section 2302(b)(1) of this title</ref>, the payment of attorney fees shall be in accordance with the standards prescribed under section 706(k) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e–5(k)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The Board may, by regulation, provide for one or more alternative methods for settling matters subject to the appellate jurisdiction of the Board which shall be applicable at the election of an applicant for employment or of an employee who is not in a unit for which a labor organization is accorded exclusive recognition, and shall be in lieu of other procedures provided for under this section. A decision under such a method shall be final, unless the Board reopens and reconsiders a case at the request of the Office of Personnel Management under subsection (e) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon the submission of any appeal to the Board under this section, the Board, through reference to such categories of cases, or other means, as it determines appropriate, shall establish and announce publicly the date by which it intends to complete action on the matter. Such date shall assure expeditious consideration of the appeal, consistent with the interests of fairness and other priorities of the Board. If the Board fails to complete action on the appeal by the announced date, and the expected delay will exceed 30 days, the Board shall publicly announce the new date by which it intends to complete action on the appeal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than March 1 of each year, the Board shall submit to the Congress a report describing the number of appeals submitted to it during the preceding fiscal year, the number of appeals on which it completed action during that year, and the number of instances during that year in which it failed to conclude a proceeding by the date originally announced, together with an explanation of the reasons therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Board shall by rule indicate any other category of significant Board action which the Board determines should be subject to the provisions of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> It shall be the duty of the Board, an administrative law judge, or employee designated by the Board to hear any proceeding under this section to expedite to the extent practicable that proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> In determining the appealability under this section of any case involving a removal from the service (other than the removal of a reemployed annuitant), neither an individual’s status under any retirement system established by or under Federal statute nor any election made by such individual under any such system may be taken into account.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> The Board may prescribe regulations to carry out the purpose of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 530</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(45)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–386, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1986-08-22">Aug. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 824</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 6</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 33</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–194, title V, § 506(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1758</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–280, § 6(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-05-04">May 4, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 160</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–376, § 3</ref>, <date date="1990-08-17">Aug. 17, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 462</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–175, § 5</ref>, <date date="1991-12-02">Dec. 2, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(56)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1354</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XIII, § 1321(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7702.</num>
<heading> Actions involving discrimination</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, in the case of any employee or applicant for employment who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has been affected by an action which the employee or applicant may appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> alleges that a basis for the action was discrimination prohibited by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> section 717 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e–16</ref>),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> section 6(d) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 206(d)</ref>),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> section 501 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 791</ref>),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> sections 12 and 15 of the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 631</ref>, 633a), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any rule, regulation, or policy directive prescribed under any provision of law described in clauses (i) through (iv) of this subparagraph,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Board shall, within 120 days of the filing of the appeal, decide both the issue of discrimination and the appealable action in accordance with the Board’s appellate procedures under <ref>section 7701 of this title</ref> and this section.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In any matter before an agency which involves—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any action described in paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any issue of discrimination prohibited under any provision of law described in paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the agency shall resolve such matter within 120 days. The decision of the agency in any such matter shall be a judicially reviewable action unless the employee appeals the matter to the Board under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Any decision of the Board under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be a judicially reviewable action as of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of issuance of the decision if the employee or applicant does not file a petition with the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission under subsection (b)(1) of this section, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date the Commission determines not to consider the decision under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee or applicant may, within 30 days after notice of the decision of the Board under subsection (a)(1) of this section, petition the Commission to consider the decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commission shall, within 30 days after the date of the petition, determine whether to consider the decision. A determination of the Commission not to consider the decision may not be used as evidence with respect to any issue of discrimination in any judicial proceeding concerning that issue.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> If the Commission makes a determination to consider the decision, the Commission shall, within 60 days after the date of the determination, consider the entire record of the proceedings of the Board and, on the basis of the evidentiary record before the Board, as supplemented under paragraph (4) of this subsection, either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> concur in the decision of the Board; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> issue in writing another decision which differs from the decision of the Board to the extent that the Commission finds that, as a matter of law—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the decision of the Board constitutes an incorrect interpretation of any provision of any law, rule, regulation, or policy directive referred to in subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the decision involving such provision is not supported by the evidence in the record as a whole.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In considering any decision of the Board under this subsection, the Commission may refer the case to the Board, or provide on its own, for the taking (within such period as permits the Commission to make a decision within the 60-day period prescribed under this subsection) of additional evidence to the extent it considers necessary to supplement the record.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If the Commission concurs pursuant to paragraph (3)(A) of this subsection in the decision of the Board, the decision of the Board shall be a judicially reviewable action.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If the Commission issues any decision under paragraph (3)(B) of this subsection, the Commission shall immediately refer the matter to the Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Within 30 days after receipt by the Board of the decision of the Commission under subsection (b)(5)(B) of this section, the Board shall consider the decision and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> concur and adopt in whole the decision of the Commission; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to the extent that the Board finds that, as a matter of law, (A) the Commission decision constitutes an incorrect interpretation of any provision of any civil service law, rule, regulation or policy directive, or (B) the Commission decision involving such provision is not supported by the evidence in the record as a whole—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> reaffirm the initial decision of the Board; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reaffirm the initial decision of the Board with such revisions as it determines appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">If the Board takes the action provided under paragraph (1), the decision of the Board shall be a judicially reviewable action.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If the Board takes any action under subsection (c)(2) of this section, the matter shall be immediately certified to a special panel described in paragraph (6) of this subsection. Upon certification, the Board shall, within 5 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays), transmit to the special panel the administrative record in the proceeding, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the factual record compiled under this section,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the decisions issued by the Board and the Commission under this section, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any transcript of oral arguments made, or legal briefs filed, before the Board or the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The special panel shall, within 45 days after a matter has been certified to it, review the administrative record transmitted to it and, on the basis of the record, decide the issues in dispute and issue a final decision which shall be a judicially reviewable action.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The special panel shall give due deference to the respective expertise of the Board and Commission in making its decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The special panel shall refer its decision under paragraph (2) of this subsection to the Board and the Board shall order any agency to take any action appropriate to carry out the decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The special panel shall permit the employee or applicant who brought the complaint and the employing agency to appear before the panel to present oral arguments and to present written arguments with respect to the matter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Upon application by the employee or applicant, the Commission may issue such interim relief as it determines appropriate to mitigate any exceptional hardship the employee or applicant might otherwise incur as a result of the certification of any matter under this subsection, except that the Commission may not stay, or order any agency to review on an interim basis, the action referred to in subsection (a)(1) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Each time the Board takes any action under subsection (c)(2) of this section, a special panel shall be convened which shall consist of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an individual appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to serve for a term of 6 years as chairman of the special panel each time it is convened;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> one member of the Board designated by the Chairman of the Board each time a panel is convened; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> one member of the Commission designated by the Chairman of the Commission each time a panel is convened.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The chairman of the special panel may be removed by the President only for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The chairman is entitled to pay at a rate equal to the maximum annual rate of basic pay payable under the General Schedule for each day he is engaged in the performance of official business on the work of the special panel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Board and the Commission shall provide such administrative assistance to the special panel as may be necessary and, to the extent practicable, shall equally divide the costs of providing the administrative assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if at any time after—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the 120th day following the filing of any matter described in subsection (a)(2) of this section with an agency, there is no judicially reviewable action under this section or an appeal under paragraph (2) of this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the 120th day following the filing of an appeal with the Board under subsection (a)(1) of this section, there is no judicially reviewable action (unless such action is not as the result of the filing of a petition by the employee under subsection (b)(1) of this section); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the 180th day following the filing of a petition with the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission under subsection (b)(1) of this section, there is no final agency action under subsection (b), (c), or (d) of this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">an employee shall be entitled to file a civil action to the same extent and in the same manner as provided in section 717(c) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e–16(c)</ref>), section 15(c) of the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 633a(c)</ref>), or section 16(b) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 216(b)</ref>).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If, at any time after the 120th day following the filing of any matter described in subsection (a)(2) of this section with an agency, there is no judicially reviewable action, the employee may appeal the matter to the Board under subsection (a)(1) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the right to trial de novo under any provision of law described in subsection (a)(1) of this section after a judicially reviewable action, including the decision of an agency under subsection (a)(2) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> In any case in which an employee is required to file any action, appeal, or petition under this section and the employee timely files the action, appeal, or petition with an agency other than the agency with which the action, appeal, or petition is to be filed, the employee shall be treated as having timely filed the action, appeal, or petition as of the date it is filed with the proper agency.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1140</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(46)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 384</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7703.</num>
<heading> Judicial review of decisions of the Merit Systems Protection Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any employee or applicant for employment adversely affected or aggrieved by a final order or decision of the Merit Systems Protection Board may obtain judicial review of the order or decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Board shall be named respondent in any proceeding brought pursuant to this subsection, unless the employee or applicant for employment seeks review of a final order or decision on the merits on the underlying personnel action or on a request for attorney fees, in which case the agency responsible for taking the personnel action shall be the respondent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B) and paragraph (2) of this subsection, a petition to review a final order or final decision of the Board shall be filed in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any petition for review shall be filed within 60 days after the Board issues notice of the final order or decision of the Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A petition to review a final order or final decision of the Board that raises no challenge to the Board’s disposition of allegations of a prohibited personnel practice described in section 2302(b) other than practices described in section 2302(b)(8), or 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D) shall be filed in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit or any court of appeals of competent jurisdiction. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any petition for review shall be filed within 60 days after the Board issues notice of the final order or decision of the Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Cases of discrimination subject to the provisions of <ref>section 7702 of this title</ref> shall be filed under section 717(c) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e–16(c)</ref>), section 15(c) of the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 633a(c)</ref>), and section 16(b) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended (<ref>29 U.S.C. 216(b)</ref>), as applicable. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any such case filed under any such section must be filed within 30 days after the date the individual filing the case received notice of the judicially reviewable action under such section 7702.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> In any case filed in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, the court shall review the record and hold unlawful and set aside any agency action, findings, or conclusions found to be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> obtained without procedures required by law, rule, or regulation having been followed; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> unsupported by substantial evidence;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">except that in the case of discrimination brought under any section referred to in subsection (b)(2) of this section, the employee or applicant shall have the right to have the facts subject to trial de novo by the reviewing court.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided under paragraph (2), this paragraph shall apply to any review obtained by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management. The Director may obtain review of any final order or decision of the Board by filing, within 60 days after the Board issues notice of the final order or decision of the Board, a petition for judicial review in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit if the Director determines, in the discretion of the Director, that the Board erred in interpreting a civil service law, rule, or regulation affecting personnel management and that the Board’s decision will have a substantial impact on a civil service law, rule, regulation, or policy directive. If the Director did not intervene in a matter before the Board, the Director may not petition for review of a Board decision under this section unless the Director first petitions the Board for a reconsideration of its decision, and such petition is denied. In addition to the named respondent, the Board and all other parties to the proceedings before the Board shall have the right to appear in the proceeding before the Court of Appeals. The granting of the petition for judicial review shall be at the discretion of the Court of Appeals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> This paragraph shall apply to any review obtained by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management that raises no challenge to the Board’s disposition of allegations of a prohibited personnel practice described in section 2302(b) other than practices described in section 2302(b)(8), or 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D). The Director may obtain review of any final order or decision of the Board by filing, within 60 days after the Board issues notice of the final order or decision of the Board, a petition for judicial review in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit or any court of appeals of competent jurisdiction if the Director determines, in the discretion of the Director, that the Board erred in interpreting a civil service law, rule, or regulation affecting personnel management and that the Board’s decision will have a substantial impact on a civil service law, rule, regulation, or policy directive. If the Director did not intervene in a matter before the Board, the Director may not petition for review of a Board decision under this section unless the Director first petitions the Board for a reconsideration of its decision, and such petition is denied. In addition to the named respondent, the Board and all other parties to the proceedings before the Board shall have the right to appear in the proceeding before the court of appeals. The granting of the petition for judicial review shall be at the discretion of the court of appeals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1143</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 144</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 45</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 10</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 35</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–311, § 10(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–199, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1469</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–170, § 2</ref>, <date date="2014-09-26">Sept. 26, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1894</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–195, § 2(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2018-07-07">July 7, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1510</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>