<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 45—</num>
<heading>INCENTIVE AWARDS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>AWARDS FOR SUPERIOR ACCOMPLISHMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4501.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an Executive agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Library of Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Office of the Architect of the Capitol;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Botanic Garden;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Government Publishing Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the government of the District of Columbia; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the United States Sentencing Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">but does not include—</continuation>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Tennessee Valley Authority; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Central Bank for Cooperatives;</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “employee” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an employee as defined by section 2105; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Government” means the Government of the United States and the government of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1183</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XVII, § 1703(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 756</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–615, title II, § 204(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3216</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7106(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4418</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–474, § 5(f)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–89, § 3(b)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 981</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4502.</num>
<heading> General provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided by subsection (b) of this section, a cash award under this subchapter may not exceed $10,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When the head of an agency certifies to the Office of Personnel Management that the suggestion, invention, superior accomplishment, or other meritorious effort for which the award is proposed is highly exceptional and unusually outstanding, a cash award in excess of $10,000 but not in excess of $25,000 may be granted with the approval of the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A cash award under this subchapter is in addition to the regular pay of the recipient. Acceptance of a cash award under this subchapter constitutes an agreement that the use by the Government of an idea, method, or device for which the award is made does not form the basis of a further claim of any nature against the Government by the employee, his heirs, or assigns.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A cash award to, and expense for the honorary recognition of, an employee may be paid from the fund or appropriation available to the activity primarily benefiting or the various activities benefiting. The head of the agency concerned determines the amount to be paid by each activity for an agency award under <ref>section 4503 of this title</ref>. The President determines the amount to be paid by each activity for a Presidential award under <ref>section 4504 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management may by regulation permit agencies to grant employees time off from duty, without loss of pay or charge to leave, as an award in recognition of superior accomplishment or other personal effort that contributes to the quality, efficiency, or economy of Government operations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense may grant a cash award under subsection (b) of this section without regard to the requirements for certification and approval provided in that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 442</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title V, § 503(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1183</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XVII, § 1703(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 756</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title II, § 201]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1455; <ref>Pub. L. 103–89, § 3(b)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 981</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1132], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–318.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4503.</num>
<heading> Agency awards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of an agency may pay a cash award to, and incur necessary expense for the honorary recognition of, an employee who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by his suggestion, invention, superior accomplishment, or other personal effort contributes to the efficiency, economy, or other improvement of Government operations or achieves a significant reduction in paperwork; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> performs a special act or service in the public interest in connection with or related to his official employment.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 443</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4504.</num>
<heading> Presidential awards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may pay a cash award to, and incur necessary expense for the honorary recognition of, an employee who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by his suggestion, invention, superior accomplishment, or other personal effort contributes to the efficiency, economy, or other improvement of Government operations or achieves a significant reduction in paperwork; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> performs an exceptionally meritorious special act or service in the public interest in connection with or related to his official employment.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">A Presidential award may be in addition to an agency award under <ref>section 4503 of this title</ref>.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 443</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1183</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4505.</num>
<heading> Awards to former employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An agency may pay or grant an award under this subchapter notwithstanding the death or separation from the service of the employee concerned, if the suggestion, invention, superior accomplishment, other personal effort, or special act or service in the public interest for which the award is proposed was made or performed while the employee was in the employ of the Government.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 443</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XVII, § 1703(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 756</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4505a.</num>
<heading> Performance-based cash awards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee whose most recent performance rating was at the fully successful level or higher (or the equivalent thereof) may be paid a cash award under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A cash award under this section shall be equal to an amount determined appropriate by the head of the agency, but may not be more than 10 percent of the employee’s annual rate of basic pay. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the agency head may authorize a cash award equal to an amount exceeding 10 percent of the employee’s annual rate of basic pay if the agency head determines that exceptional performance by the employee justifies such an award, but in no case may an award under this section exceed 20 percent of the employee’s annual rate of basic pay.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A cash award under this section shall be paid as a lump sum, and may not be considered to be part of the basic pay of an employee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The failure to pay a cash award under this section, or the amount of such an award, may not be appealed. The preceding sentence shall not be construed to extinguish or lessen any right or remedy under subchapter II of chapter 12, chapter 71, or any of the laws referred to in section 2302(d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe such regulations as it considers necessary for the administration of subsections (a) and (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The preceding provisions of this section shall be applicable with respect to any employee to whom subchapter III of chapter 53 applies, and to any category of employees provided for under subsection (e).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> At the request of the head of an Executive agency, the President may authorize the application of subsections (a) through (c) with respect to any category of employees within such agency who would not otherwise be covered by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title II, § 207(a)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1457; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(19)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1347</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–411, title III, § 301(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2317</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–73, title I, § 107(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2017-10-26">Oct. 26, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(b)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1617</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4506.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations and instructions under which the awards programs set forth by this subchapter shall be carried out.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 443</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title V, § 503(d)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1184</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XVII, § 1703(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 756</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–67, title VI, § 641(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4507.</num>
<heading> Awarding of ranks in the Senior Executive Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section, “agency”, “senior executive”, and “career appointee” have the meanings set forth in <ref>section 3132(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each agency shall submit annually to the Office recommendations of career appointees in the agency to be awarded the rank of Meritorious Executive or Distinguished Executive. The recommendations may take into account the individual’s performance over a period of years. The Office shall review such recommendations and provide to the President recommendations as to which of the agency recommended appointees should receive such rank.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> During any fiscal year, the President may, subject to subsection (d) of this section, award to any career appointee recommended by the Office the rank of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Meritorious Executive, for sustained accomplishment, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Distinguished Executive, for sustained extraordinary accomplishment.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">A career appointee awarded a rank under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection shall not be entitled to be awarded that rank during the following 4 fiscal years.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> During any fiscal year—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of career appointees awarded the rank of Meritorious Executive may not exceed 5 percent of the Senior Executive Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of career appointees awarded the rank of Distinguished Executive may not exceed 1 percent of the Senior Executive Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Receipt by a career appointee of the rank of Meritorious Executive entitles such individual to a lump-sum payment of an amount equal to 20 percent of annual basic pay, which shall be in addition to the basic pay paid under <ref>section 5382 of this title</ref> or any award paid under <ref>section 5384 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Receipt by a career appointee of the rank of Distinguished Executive entitles the individual to a lump-sum payment of an amount equal to 35 percent of annual basic pay, which shall be in addition to the basic pay paid under <ref>section 5382 of this title</ref> or any award paid under <ref>section 5384 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, § 406(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1170</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(h) [title VI, § 631(a), (b)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–480</ref>, 2681–523.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4507a.</num>
<heading> Awarding of ranks to other senior career employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section, the term “senior career employee” means an individual appointed to a position classified above GS–15 and paid under section 5376 who is not serving—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> under a time-limited appointment; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in a position that is excepted from the competitive service because of its confidential or policy-making character.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each agency employing senior career employees shall submit annually to the Office of Personnel Management recommendations of senior career employees in the agency to be awarded the rank of Meritorious Senior Professional or Distinguished Senior Professional, which may be awarded by the President for sustained accomplishment or sustained extraordinary accomplishment, respectively.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The recommendations shall be made, reviewed, and awarded under the same terms and conditions (to the extent determined by the Office of Personnel Management) that apply to rank awards for members of the Senior Executive Service under section 4507.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–67, title VI, § 641(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4508.</num>
<heading> Limitation of awards during a Presidential election year</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Presidential election period” means any period beginning on June 1 in a calendar year in which the popular election of the President occurs, and ending on January 20 following the date of such election; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “senior politically appointed officer” means any officer who during a Presidential election period serves—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in a Senior Executive Service position and is not a career appointee as defined under section 3132(a)(4); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in a position of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> No senior politically appointed officer may receive an award under the provisions of this subchapter during a Presidential election period.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–425, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4369</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4509.</num>
<heading> Prohibition of cash award to Executive Schedule officers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No officer may receive a cash award under the provisions of this subchapter, if such officer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> serves in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an Executive Schedule position under subchapter II of chapter 53; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a position for which the compensation is set in statute by reference to a section or level under subchapter II of chapter 53; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> was appointed to such position by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–425, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>AWARDS FOR COST SAVINGS DISCLOSURES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4511.</num>
<heading> Definition and general provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subchapter, the term “agency” means any Executive agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A cash award under this subchapter is in addition to the regular pay of the recipient. Acceptance of a cash award under this subchapter constitutes an agreement that the use by the Government of an idea, method, or device for which the award is made does not form the basis of a further claim of any nature against the Government by the employee, his heirs, or assigns.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XVII, § 1703(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 755</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4512.</num>
<heading> Agency awards for cost savings disclosures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Inspector General of an agency, or any other agency employee designated under subsection (b), may pay a cash award to any employee of such agency whose disclosure of fraud, waste, or mismanagement to the Inspector General of the agency, or to such other designated agency employee, has resulted in cost savings for the agency. The amount of an award under this section may not exceed the lesser of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $10,000; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an amount equal to 1 percent of the agency’s cost savings which the Inspector General, or other employee designated under subsection (b), determines to be the total savings attributable to the employee’s disclosure.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of paragraph (2), the Inspector General or other designated employee may take into account agency cost savings projected for subsequent fiscal years which will be attributable to such disclosure.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In the case of an agency for which there is no Inspector General, the head of the agency shall designate an agency employee who shall have the authority to make the determinations and grant the awards permitted under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XVII, § 1703(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 755</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1225(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 730</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4513.</num>
<heading> Presidential awards for cost savings disclosures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may pay a cash award in the amount of $20,000 to any employee whose disclosure of fraud, waste, or mismanagement has resulted in substantial cost savings for the Government. In evaluating the significance of a cost savings disclosure made by an employee for purposes of determining whether to make an award to such employee under this section, the President may take into account cost savings projected for subsequent fiscal years which will be attributable to the disclosure. During any fiscal year, the President may not make more than 50 awards under this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XVII, § 1703(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 755</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 4514.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 102–487, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3134</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>AWARD TO LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS FOR FOREIGN LANGUAGE CAPABILITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4521.</num>
<heading> Definition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter, the term “law enforcement officer” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a law enforcement officer within the meaning of section 5541(3) and to whom the provisions of chapter 51 apply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a member of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a member of the United States Park Police;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a special agent in the Diplomatic Security Service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a probation officer (referred to in <ref>section 3672 of title 18</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a pretrial services officer (referred to in <ref>section 3153 of title 18</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title IV, § 408(a)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1467; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–141, title VI, § 627</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(21)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1348</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4522.</num>
<heading> General provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An award under this subchapter is in addition to the basic pay of the recipient.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title IV, § 408(a)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1467.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4523.</num>
<heading> Award authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An agency may pay a cash award, up to 5 percent of basic pay, to any law enforcement officer employed in or under such agency who possesses and makes substantial use of 1 or more foreign languages in the performance of official duties.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Awards under this section shall be paid under regulations prescribed by the head of the agency involved (or designee thereof). Regulations prescribed by an agency head (or designee) under this subsecton <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002080">1</ref> shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> procedures under which foreign language proficiency shall be ascertained;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> criteria for the selection of individuals for recognition under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other provisions which may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title IV, § 408(a)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1467.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>