<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 87—</num>
<heading>LIFE INSURANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this chapter, “employee” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an employee as defined by <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a Member of Congress as defined by <ref>section 2106 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a Congressional employee as defined by <ref>section 2107 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the President;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a justice or judge of the United States appointed to hold office during good behavior (i) who is in regular active judicial service, or (ii) who is retired from regular active service under section 371(b) or 372(a) of title 28, United States Code, or (iii) who has resigned the judicial office under <ref>section 371(a) of title 28</ref> with the continued right during the remainder of his lifetime to receive the salary of the office at the time of his resignation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> an individual first employed by the government of the District of Columbia before <date date="1987-10-01">October 1, 1987</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> an individual employed by Gallaudet College; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002186">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> an individual employed by a county committee established under <ref>section 590h(b) of title 16</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> an individual appointed to a position on the office staff of a former President under <ref>section 1(b) of the Act of August 25, 1958</ref> (<ref>72 Stat. 838</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> an individual appointed to a position on the office staff of a former President, or a former Vice President under section 5 of the Presidential Transition Act of 1963, as amended (<ref>78 Stat. 153</ref>), who immediately before the date of such appointment was an employee as defined under any other paragraph of this subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">but does not include—</continuation>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an employee of a corporation supervised by the Farm Credit Administration if private interests elect or appoint a member of the board of directors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an individual who is not a citizen or national of the United States and whose permanent duty station is outside the United States, unless the individual was an employee for the purpose of this chapter on <date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>, by reason of service in an Executive agency, the United States Postal Service, or the Smithsonian Institution in the area which was then known as the Canal Zone; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an employee excluded by regulation of the Office of Personnel Management under <ref>section 8716(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the employment of a teacher in the recess period between two school years in a position other than a teaching position in which he served immediately before the recess period does not qualify the individual as an employee for the purpose of this chapter. For the purpose of this subsection, “teacher” and “teaching position” have the meanings given them by <ref>section 901 of title 20</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this chapter, “basic insurance amount” means, in the case of any employee under this chapter, an amount equal to the greater of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the annual rate of basic pay payable to the employee, rounded to the next higher multiple of $1,000, plus $2,000, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $10,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In the case of any former employee entitled to coverage under this chapter, the term means the basic insurance amount applicable for the employee at the time the insurance to which the employee is entitled as an employee under this chapter stops pursuant to <ref>section 8706(a) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this chapter, “family member”, when used with respect to any individual, means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the spouse of the individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> an unmarried dependent child of the individual (other than a stillborn child), including an adopted child, stepchild or foster child (but only if the stepchild or foster child lived with the individual in a regular parent-child relationship), or recognized natural child—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who is less than 22 years of age, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who is 22 years of age or older and is incapable of self-support because of a mental or physical disability which existed before the child became 22 years of age.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this subsection, “dependent”, in the case of any child, means that the individual involved was, at the time of the child’s death, either living with or contributing to the support of the child, as determined in accordance with the regulations the Office shall prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 592</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–418, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-09-25">Sept. 25, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 869</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–160, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-27">Nov. 27, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 635</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(51)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–70, title I, § 1209(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-09-27">Sept. 27, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 463</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–427</ref>, §§ 2(a), 8(b), <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1831</ref>, 1837; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 350</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–335, title II, § 207(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–679, § 13(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4071</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–311</ref>, §§ 3(1), 4, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2950</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–136, § 2(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2016-03-18">Mar. 18, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 305</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8702.</num>
<heading> Automatic coverage</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An employee is automatically insured on the date he becomes eligible for insurance and each policy of insurance purchased by the Office of Personnel Management under this chapter shall provide for that automatic coverage.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An employee desiring not to be insured shall give written notice to his employing office on a form prescribed by the Office. If the notice is received before he has become insured, he shall not be insured. If the notice is received after he has become insured, his insurance stops at the end of the pay period in which the notice is received.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding a notice previously given under subsection (b), an employee who is deployed in support of a contingency operation (as that term is defined in <ref>section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>) or an employee of the Department of Defense who is designated as an emergency essential employee under <ref>section 1580 of title 10</ref> shall be insured if the employee, within 60 days after the date of notification of deployment or designation, elects to be insured under a policy of insurance under this chapter. An election under the preceding sentence shall be effective when provided to the Office in writing, in the form prescribed by the Office, within such 60-day period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Any services by an officer or employee under this chapter relating to benefits under this chapter shall be deemed, for purposes of <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, services for emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XI, § 1134(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–318; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title XI, § 1103(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4616</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XI, § 1110(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1600</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8703.</num>
<heading> Benefit certificate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management shall arrange to have each insured employee receive a certificate setting forth the benefits to which he is entitled, to whom the benefits are payable, to whom the claims shall be submitted, and summarizing the provisions of the policy principally affecting him. The certificate is issued instead of the certificate which the insurance company would otherwise be required to issue.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8704.</num>
<heading> Group insurance; amounts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An employee eligible for insurance is entitled to be insured for an amount of group life insurance equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the employee’s basic insurance amount, multiplied by</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the appropriate factor determined on the basis of the employee’s age in accordance with the following schedule:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p>If the age of the employee is</p></th><th><p>The appropriate factor is:</p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>35 or under</span></p></td><td><p>2.0   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>36</span></p></td><td><p>1.9   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>37</span></p></td><td><p>1.8   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>38</span></p></td><td><p>1.7   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>39</span></p></td><td><p>1.6   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>40</span></p></td><td><p>1.5   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>41</span></p></td><td><p>1.4   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>42</span></p></td><td><p>1.3   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>43</span></p></td><td><p>1.2   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>44</span></p></td><td><p>1.1   </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>45 or over</span></p></td><td><p>1.0.    </p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An employee eligible for insurance is entitled to be insured for group accidental death and dismemberment insurance in accordance with this subsection. Subject to the conditions and limitations approved by the Office of Personnel Management which are contained in the policy purchased by the Office, the group accidental death and dismemberment insurance provides payment as follows:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p>Loss</p></th><th><p>Amount payable</p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>For loss of life</span></p></td><td><p>Full amount of the employee’s basic insurance amount.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Loss of one hand or of one foot or loss of sight of one eye</p></td><td><p>One-half the amount of the employee’s basic insurance amount.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Loss of two or more such members</p></td><td><p>Full amount of the employee’s basic insurance amount.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
<p class="indent0 firstIndent0">For any one accident the aggregate amount of group accidental death and dismemberment insurance that may be paid may not exceed an amount equal to the employee’s basic insurance amount.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Office shall prescribe regulations providing for the conversion of other than annual rates of pay to annual rates of pay and shall specify the types of pay included in annual pay. For the purpose of this chapter, “annual pay” includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> premium pay under <ref>section 5545(c)(1) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with respect to a law enforcement officer as defined in section 8331(20) or 8401(17) of this title, premium pay under <ref>section 5545(c)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> In determining the amount of insurance to which an employee is entitled—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a change in rate of pay under subchapter VI of chapter 53 of this title is deemed effective as of the first day of the pay period after the pay period in which the payroll change is approved; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a change in rate of pay under section 5344 or 5349 of this title is deemed effective as of the date of issuance of the order granting the increase or the effective date of the increase, whichever is later, except, that in the case of an employee who dies or retires during the period beginning on the effective date of the increase and ending on the date of the issuance of the order granting the increase, a change in rate of pay under either of such sections shall be deemed as having been in effect for such employee during that period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–737, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–206, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 646</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–392, § 11</ref>, <date date="1972-08-19">Aug. 19, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 575</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VIII, § 801(a)(3)(E)</ref>, title IX, § 906(a)(2), (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1222</ref>, 1224; <ref>Pub. L. 96–427, § 2(b)</ref>–(d), <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1831</ref>, 1832; <ref>Pub. L. 100–238, title I, § 103(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-01-08">Jan. 8, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1744</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8705.</num>
<heading> Death claims; order of precedence; escheat</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (e), the amount of group life insurance and group accidental death insurance in force on an employee at the date of his death shall be paid, on the establishment of a valid claim, to the person or persons surviving at the date of his death, in the following order of precedence:<p class="indent1" role="listItem">First, to the beneficiary or beneficiaries designated by the employee in a signed and witnessed writing received before death in the employing office or, if insured because of receipt of annuity or of benefits under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title as provided by <ref>section 8706(b) of this title</ref>, in the Office of Personnel Management. For this purpose, a designation, change, or cancellation of beneficiary in a will or other document not so executed and filed has no force or effect.</p>
<p class="indent1" role="listItem">Second, if there is no designated beneficiary, to the widow or widower of the employee.</p>
<p class="indent1">Third, if none of the above, to the child or children of the employee and descendants of deceased children by representation.</p>
<p class="indent1">Fourth, if none of the above, to the parents of the employee or the survivor of them.</p>
<p class="indent1">Fifth, if none of the above, to the duly appointed executor or administrator of the estate of the employee.</p>
<p class="indent1">Sixth, if none of the above, to other next of kin of the employee entitled under the laws of the domicile of the employee at the date of his death.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If, within 1 year after the death of the employee, no claim for payment has been filed by a person entitled under the order of precedence named by subsection (a) of this section, or if payment to the person within that period is prohibited by Federal statute or regulation, payment may be made in the order of precedence as if the person had predeceased the employee, and the payment bars recovery by any other person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If, within 2 years after the death of the employee, no claim for payment has been filed by a person entitled under the order of precedence named by subsection (a) of this section, and neither the Office nor the administrative office established by the company concerned pursuant to <ref>section 8709(b) of this title</ref> has received notice that such a claim will be made, payment may be made to the claimant who in the judgment of the Office is equitably entitled thereto, and the payment bars recovery by any other person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If, within 4 years after the death of the employee, payment has not been made under this section and no claim for payment by a person entitled under this section is pending, the amount payable escheats to the credit of the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any amount which would otherwise be paid to a person determined under the order of precedence named by subsection (a) shall be paid (in whole or in part) by the Office to another person if and to the extent expressly provided for in the terms of any court decree of divorce, annulment, or legal separation, or the terms of any court order or court-approved property settlement agreement incident to any court decree of divorce, annulment, or legal separation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, a decree, order, or agreement referred to in paragraph (1) shall not be effective unless it is received, before the date of the covered employee’s death, by the employing agency or, if the employee has separated from service, by the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> A designation under this subsection with respect to any person may not be changed except—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with the written consent of such person, if received as described in paragraph (2); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by modification of the decree, order, or agreement, as the case may be, if received as described in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Office shall prescribe any regulations necessary to carry out this subsection, including regulations for the application of this subsection in the event that two or more decrees, orders, or agreements, are received with respect to the same amount.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 594</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(91)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–583, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2481</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–205, § 1</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 683</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8706.</num>
<heading> Termination of insurance; assignment of ownership</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A policy purchased under this chapter shall contain a provision, approved by the Office of Personnel Management, to the effect that insurance on an employee stops on his separation from the service or 12 months after discontinuance of his pay, whichever is earlier, subject to a provision for temporary extension of life insurance coverage and for conversion to an individual policy of life insurance under conditions approved by the Office. Justices and judges of the United States described in section 8701(a)(5)(ii) and (iii) of this chapter are deemed to continue in active employment for purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of any employee who retires on an immediate annuity and has been insured under this chapter throughout—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date of the employee’s retirement, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the full period or periods of service during which the employee was entitled to be insured, if fewer than 5 years,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">life insurance, without accidental death and dismemberment insurance, may be continued, under conditions determined by the Office.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of any employee who becomes entitled to receive compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee and has been insured under this chapter throughout—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date the employee becomes entitled to compensation, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the full period or periods of service during which the employee was entitled to be insured, if fewer than 5 years,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">life insurance, without accidental death and dismemberment insurance, may be continued, under conditions determined by the Office, during the period the employee is receiving compensation and is held by the Secretary of Labor or the Secretary’s delegate to be unable to return to duty.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The amount of life insurance continued under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection shall be continued, with or without reduction, at the end of each full calendar month after the date the employee becomes 65 years of age and is retired or is receiving compensation for disease or injury, in accordance with the employee’s written election at the time eligibility to continue insurance during retirement or receipt of compensation arises, as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the employee may elect to have the deductions required by <ref>section 8707 of this title</ref> withheld from annuity or compensation, and the employee’s life insurance shall be reduced each month by 2 percent of the face value until 25 percent of the amount of life insurance in force before the first reduction remains; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in addition to any deductions which would be required if the insurance were continued as provided under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the employee may elect continuous withholdings from annuity or compensation in amounts determined by the Office, and the employee’s life insurance coverage shall be either continued without reduction or reduced each month by no more than 1 percent of its face value until no less than 50 percent of the amount of insurance in force before the first reduction remains.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If an employee elects to continue insurance under subparagraph (B) of paragraph (3) of this subsection at the time eligibility to continue insurance during retirement or receipt of compensation for disease or injury arises, the individual may later cancel that election and life insurance coverage shall continue as if the individual had originally elected coverage under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (3) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section, an employee who enters on approved leave without pay to serve as a full-time officer or employee of an organization composed primarily of employees as defined by <ref>section 8701(a) of this title</ref>, within 60 days after entering on that leave without pay, may elect to continue his insurance and arrange to pay currently into the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund, through his employing agency, both employee and agency contributions from the beginning of leave without pay. The employing agency shall forward the premium payments to the Fund. If the employee does not so elect, his insurance will continue during nonpay status and stop as provided by subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee who enters on approved leave without pay in the circumstances described in paragraph (2) may elect to have such employee’s life insurance continue (beyond the end of the 12 months of coverage provided for under subsection (a)) for an additional 12 months and arrange to pay currently into the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund, through such employee’s employing agency, both employee and agency contributions, from the beginning of that additional 12 months of coverage. The employing agency shall forward the premium payments to the Fund. If the employee does not so elect, such employee’s insurance will continue during nonpay status and stop as provided by subsection (a). An individual making an election under this subsection may cancel that election at any time, in which case such employee’s insurance will stop as provided by subsection (a) or upon receipt of notice of cancellation, whichever is later.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> This subsection applies in the case of any employee who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a member of a reserve component of the armed forces called or ordered to active duty under a call or order that does not specify a period of 30 days or less; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enters on approved leave without pay to perform active duty pursuant to such call or order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If the insurance of an employee stops because of separation from the service or suspension without pay, and the separation or suspension is thereafter officially found to have been erroneous, the employee is deemed to have been insured during the period of erroneous separation or suspension. Deductions otherwise required by section 8707 of this chapter shall not be withheld from any backpay awarded for the period of separation or suspension unless death or accidental dismemberment of the employee occurs during such period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Office, each policy purchased under this chapter shall provide that an insured employee or former employee may make an irrevocable assignment of the employee’s or former employee’s incidents of ownership in the policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A court decree of divorce, annulment, or legal separation, or the terms of a court-approved property settlement agreement incident to any court decree of divorce, annulment, or legal separation, may direct that an insured employee or former employee make an irrevocable assignment of the employee’s or former employee’s incidents of ownership in insurance under this chapter (if there is no previous assignment) to the person specified in the court order or court-approved property settlement agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> If the insurance of a former employee receiving a disability annuity under <ref>section 8337 of this title</ref> stops because of the termination of such annuity, and such annuity is thereafter restored under the second or third sentence of subsection (e) of such section, such former employee may, under regulations prescribed by the Office, elect to resume the insurance coverage which was so stopped.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The insurance of an employee under a policy purchased under section 8709 shall not be invalidated based on a finding that the employee erroneously became insured, or erroneously continued insurance upon retirement or entitlement to compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title, if such finding occurs after the erroneous insurance and applicable withholdings have been in force for 2 years during the employee’s lifetime.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 595</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(92)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 219</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–529</ref>, <date date="1972-10-21">Oct. 21, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1050</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–583, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2481</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–427, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1832</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title II</ref>, §§ 206, 208, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 351</ref>, as amended by <ref>Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–53, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-06-17">June 17, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 95</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–335, title II, § 207(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(74)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1355</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–336, § 4</ref>, <date date="1994-10-03">Oct. 3, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–205, § 2</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 683</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–311, § 5</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2951</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XI, § 1102</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 345</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8707.</num>
<heading> Employee deductions; withholding</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (c)(2), during each period in which an employee is insured under a policy purchased by the Office of Personnel Management under <ref>section 8709 of this title</ref>, there shall be withheld from the employee’s pay a share of the cost of the group life insurance and accidental death and dismemberment insurance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (c)(2), whenever life insurance continues after an employee retires on an immediate annuity or while the employee is receiving compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee, as provided in <ref>section 8706(b) of this title</ref>, deductions for insurance shall be withheld from the employee’s annuity or compensation, except that, in any case in which the insurance is continued as provided in <ref>section 8706(b)(3)(A) of this title</ref>, the deductions shall not be made for months after the calendar month in which the employee becomes 65 years of age.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, insurance shall be so continued without cost (other than as provided under section 8706(b)(3)(B)) to each employee who so retires, or commences receiving compensation, on or before <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The amount withheld from the pay, annuity, or compensation of each employee subject to insurance deductions shall be at the rate, adjusted to the nearest half-cent, of 66⅔ percent of the level cost as determined by the Office for each $1,000 of the employee’s basic insurance amount.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An employee who is subject to withholdings under this section and whose pay, annuity, or compensation is insufficient to cover such withholdings may nevertheless continue insurance if the employee arranges to pay currently into the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund, through the agency or retirement system that administers pay, annuity, or compensation, an amount equal to the withholdings that would otherwise be required under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If an agency fails to withhold the proper amount of life insurance deductions from an individual’s salary, compensation, or retirement annuity, the collection of unpaid deductions may be waived by the agency if, in the judgment of the agency, the individual is without fault and recovery would be against equity and good conscience. However, if the agency so waives the collection of unpaid deductions, the agency shall submit an amount equal to the sum of the uncollected deductions and related agency contributions required under <ref>section 8708 of this title</ref> to the Office for deposit to the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 595</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–206, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 647</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–427, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–311, § 6(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2951</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8708.</num>
<heading> Government contributions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For each period in which an employee is insured under a policy of insurance purchased by the Office of Personnel Management under <ref>section 8709 of this title</ref>, a sum equal to one-half the amount which is withheld from the pay of the employee under <ref>section 8707 of this title</ref> shall be contributed from the appropriation or fund which is used to pay him.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When an employee is paid by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer may contribute the sum required by subsection (a) of this section from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> When the employee is an elected official, the sum required by subsection (a) of this section is contributed from an appropriation or fund available for payment of other salaries of the same office or establishment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, for each period in which an employee continues life insurance after retirement or while in receipt of compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee, as provided under <ref>section 8706(b) of this title</ref>, a sum equal to one-half of the amount which is withheld from the employee’s annuity or compensation under <ref>section 8707 of this title</ref> shall be contributed by the Office from annual appropriations which are authorized to be made for that purpose and which may be made available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Contributions under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall not be made other than with respect to individuals who retire, or commence receiving compensation, after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall not be made with respect to any individual for months after the calendar month in which such individual becomes 65 years of age; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall, in the case of any individual who elects coverage under subparagraph (B) of <ref>section 8706(b)(3) of this title</ref>, be equal to the amount which would apply under this subsection if such individual had instead elected coverage under subparagraph (A) of such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The United States Postal Service shall pay the contributions required under this subsection with respect to any individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> first becomes an annuitant by reason of retirement from employment with the United States Postal Service after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> commences receiving compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title (because of disease or injury to the individual) after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>, if the position last held by the individual before commencing to receive such compensation was within the United States Postal Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 595</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–206, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 647</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–303, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-05-29">May 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 250</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 215(18)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8709.</num>
<heading> Insurance policies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Office of Personnel Management, without regard to section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41, may purchase from one or more life insurance companies a policy or policies of group life and accidental death and dismemberment insurance to provide the benefits specified by this chapter. A company must meet the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It must be licensed to transact life and accidental death and dismemberment insurance under the laws of 48 of the States and the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> It must have in effect, on the most recent December 31 for which information is available to the Office, an amount of employee group life insurance equal to at least 1 percent of the total amount of employee group life insurance in the United States in all life insurance companies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A company issuing a policy under subsection (a) of this section shall establish an administrative office under a name approved by the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Office at any time may discontinue a policy purchased from a company under subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The provisions of any contract under this chapter which relate to the nature or extent of coverage or benefits (including payments with respect to benefits) shall supersede and preempt any law of any State or political subdivision thereof, or any regulation issued thereunder, which relates to group life insurance to the extent that the law or regulation is inconsistent with the contractual provisions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section, “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and a territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–427, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8710.</num>
<heading> Reinsurance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall arrange with a company issuing a policy under this chapter for the reinsurance, under conditions approved by the Office, of portions of the total amount of insurance under the policy, determined under this section, with other life insurance companies which elect to participate in the reinsurance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Office shall determine for and in advance of a policy year which companies are eligible to participate as reinsurers and the amount of insurance under a policy which is to be allocated to the issuing company and to reinsurers. The Office shall make this determination at least every 3 years and when a participating company withdraws.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The Office shall establish a formula under which the amount of insurance retained by an issuing company after ceding reinsurance, and the amount of reinsurance ceded to each reinsurer, is in proportion to the total amount of each company’s group life insurance, excluding insurance purchased under this chapter, in force in the United States on the determination date, which is the most recent December 31 for which information is available to the Office. In determining the proportions, the portion of a company’s group life insurance in force on the determination date in excess of $100,000,000 shall be reduced by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 25 percent of the first $100,000,000 of the excess;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 50 percent of the second $100,000,000 of the excess;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> 75 percent of the third $100,000,000 of the excess; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> 95 percent of the remaining excess.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">However, the amount retained by or ceded to a company may not exceed 25 percent of the amount of the company’s total life insurance in force in the United States on the determination date.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> A fraternal benefit association which is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> licensed to transact life insurance under the laws of a State or the District of Columbia; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> engaged in issuing insurance certificates on the lives of employees of the United States exclusively;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">is eligible to act as a reinsuring company and may be allocated an amount of reinsurance equal to 25 percent of its total life insurance in force on employees of the United States on the determination date named by subsection (c) of this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> An issuing company or reinsurer is entitled, as a minimum, to be allocated an amount of insurance under the policy equal to any reduction from <date date="1953-12-31">December 31, 1953</date>, to the determination date, in the amount of the company’s group life insurance under policies issued to associations of employees of the United States. However, any increase under this subsection in the amount allocated is reduced by the amount in force on the determination date of any policy covering life insurance agreements assumed by the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Office may modify the computations under this section as necessary to carry out the intent of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 596</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8711.</num>
<heading> Basic tables of premium rates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A policy purchased under this chapter shall include, for the first policy year, basic tables of premium rates as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For group life insurance, a schedule of basic premium rates by age which the Office of Personnel Management determines to be consistent with the lowest schedule of basic premium rates generally charged for new group life insurance policies issued to large employers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For group accidental death and dismemberment insurance, a basic premium rate which the Office determines is consistent with the lowest rate generally charged for new group accidental death and dismemberment policies issued to large employers.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The schedule for group life insurance, except as otherwise provided by this section, shall be applied to the distribution by age of the amounts of group life insurance under the policy at its date of issuance to determine an average basic premium rate per $1,000 of life insurance.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The policy shall provide that the basic premium rates determined for the first policy year continue for later policy years except as readjusted for a later year based on experience under the policy. The company issuing the policy may make the readjustment on a basis that the Office determines in advance of the policy year is consistent with the general practice of life insurance companies under policies of group life and group accidental death and dismemberment insurance issued to large employers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The policy shall provide that if the Office determines that ascertaining the actual age distribution of the amounts of group life insurance in force at the date of issue of the policy or at the end of the first or any later year of insurance thereunder would not be possible except at a disproportionately high expense, the Office may approve the determination of a tentative average group life premium rate, for the first or any later policy year, instead of using the actual age distribution. The Office, on request by the company issuing the policy, shall redetermine the tentative average premium rate during any policy year, if experience indicates that the assumptions made in determining that rate were incorrect for that year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The policy shall stipulate the maximum expense and risk charges for the first policy year. The Office shall determine these charges on a basis consistent with the general level of charges made by life insurance companies under policies of group life and accidental death and dismemberment insurance issued to large employers. The maximum charges continue from year to year, except that the Office may redetermine them for any year either by agreement with the company issuing the policy or on written notice given to the company at least 1 year before the beginning of the year for which the redetermined maximum charges will be effective.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8712.</num>
<heading> Annual accounting; special contingency reserve</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A policy purchased under this chapter shall provide for an accounting to the Office of Personnel Management not later than 90 days after the end of each policy year. The accounting shall set forth, in a form approved by the Office—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amounts of premiums actually accrued under the policy from its date of issue to the end of the policy year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the total of all mortality and other claim charges incurred for that period; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amounts of the insurers’ expense and risk charges for that period.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">An excess of the total of paragraph (1) of this section over the sum of paragraphs (2) and (3) of this section shall be held by the company issuing the policy as a special contingency reserve to be used by the company only for charges under the policy. The reserve shall bear interest at a rate determined in advance of each policy year by the company and approved by the Office as being consistent with the rates generally used by the company for similar funds held under other group life insurance policies. When the Office determines that the special contingency reserve has attained an amount estimated by it to make satisfactory provision for adverse fluctuations in future charges under the policy, any further excess shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund. When a policy is discontinued, any balance remaining in the special contingency reserve after all charges have been made shall be deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the Fund. The company may make the deposit in equal monthly installments over a period of not more than 2 years.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8713.</num>
<heading> Effect of other statutes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any provision of law outside of this chapter which provides coverage or any other benefit under this chapter to any individuals who (based on their being employed by an entity other than the Government) would not otherwise be eligible for any such coverage or benefit shall not apply with respect to any individual appointed, transferred, or otherwise commencing that type of employment on or after <date date="1988-10-01">October 1, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–238, title I, § 108(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1988-01-08">Jan. 8, 1988</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1747</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8714.</num>
<heading> Employees’ Life Insurance Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The amounts withheld from employees under <ref>section 8707 of this title</ref> and the sums contributed from appropriations and funds under <ref>section 8708 of this title</ref> shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund. The Fund is available without fiscal year limitation for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> premium payments under an insurance policy purchased under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expenses incurred by the Office of Personnel Management in the administration of this chapter within the limitations that may be specified annually by appropriation acts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury may invest and reinvest any of the money in the Fund in interest-bearing obligations of the United States, and may sell these obligations for the purposes of the Fund. The interest on and the proceeds from the sale of these obligations, and the income derived from dividend or premium rate adjustments from insurers, become a part of the Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No tax, fee, or other monetary payment may be imposed or collected by any State, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or by any political subdivision or other governmental authority thereof, on, or with respect to, any premium paid under an insurance policy purchased under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not be construed to exempt any company issuing a policy of insurance under this chapter from the imposition, payment, or collection of a tax, fee, or other monetary payment on the net income or profit accruing to or realized by that company from business conducted under this chapter, if that tax, fee, or payment is applicable to a broad range of business activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–499, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2606</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8714a.</num>
<heading> Optional insurance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under the conditions, directives, and terms specified in sections 8709–8712 of this title, the Office of Personnel Management, without regard to section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41, may purchase a policy which shall make available to each insured employee equal amounts of optional life insurance and accidental death and dismemberment insurance in addition to the amounts provided in <ref>section 8704(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee who is deployed in support of a contingency operation (as that term is defined in <ref>section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>) or an employee of the Department of Defense who is designated as emergency essential under <ref>section 1580 of title 10</ref> shall be insured under the policy of insurance under this section if the employee, within 60 days after the date of notification of deployment or designation, elects to be insured under the policy of insurance. An election under this paragraph shall be effective when provided to the Office in writing, in the form prescribed by the Office, within such 60-day period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The optional life insurance and accidental death and dismemberment insurance shall be made available to each insured employee under such conditions as the Office shall prescribe and in amounts approved by the Office but not more than the greater of $10,000 or an amount which, when added to the amount provided in <ref>section 8704(a) of this title</ref>, makes the sum of his insurance equal to his annual pay.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the optional insurance on an employee stops on his separation from service or 12 months after discontinuance of his pay, whichever is earlier, subject to a provision for temporary extension of life insurance coverage and for conversion to an individual policy of life insurance under conditions approved by the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of any employee who retires on an immediate annuity and has been insured under this section throughout—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date of such retirement, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the full period or periods of service during which the employee was entitled to be insured, if less than 5 years,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the amount of optional life insurance only which has been in force throughout such period may be continued, under conditions determined by the Office.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of any employee who becomes entitled to receive compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee and has been insured under this section throughout—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date such employee becomes entitled to such compensation, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the full period or periods of service during which the employee was entitled to be insured, if less than 5 years,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the amount of optional life insurance only which has been in force throughout such period may be continued, under conditions determined by the Office, during the period the employee is receiving such compensation for disease or injury and is held by the Secretary of Labor or his delegate to be unable to return to duty.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The amount of optional life insurance continued under subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B) of this paragraph shall be reduced by 2 percent at the end of each full calendar month after the date the employee becomes 65 years of age and is retired or is receiving compensation for disease or injury. The Office shall prescribe minimum amounts, not less than 25 percent of the amount of life insurance in force before the first reduction, to which the insurance may be reduced.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (c)(1) of this section,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002187">1</ref> a justice or judge of the United States as defined by <ref>section 8701(a)(5) of this title</ref> who resigns his office without meeting the requirements of <ref>section 371(a) of title 28</ref>, United States Code, for continuation of the judicial salary shall have the right to convert regular optional life insurance coverage issued under this section during his judicial service to an individual policy of life insurance under the same conditions approved by the Office governing conversion of basic life insurance coverage for employees eligible as provided in <ref>section 8706(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During each period in which an employee has the optional insurance the full cost thereof shall be withheld from his pay. During each period in which an employee continues optional life insurance after retirement or while in receipt of compensation for work injuries, as provided in <ref>section 8706(b) of this title</ref>, the full cost thereof shall be withheld from his annuity or compensation, except that, at the end of the calendar month in which he becomes 65 years of age, the optional life insurance shall be without cost to him. Amounts so withheld shall be deposited, used, and invested as provided in <ref>section 8714 of this title</ref> and shall be reported and accounted for separately from amounts withheld and contributed under sections 8707 and 8708 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If an agency fails to withhold the proper cost of optional insurance from an individual’s salary, compensation, or retirement annuity, the collection of amounts properly due may be waived by the agency if, in the judgment of the agency, the individual is without fault and recovery would be against equity and good conscience. However, if the agency so waives the collection of any unpaid amount, the agency shall submit an amount equal to the uncollected amount to the Office for deposit to the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), an employee who is subject to withholdings under this subsection and whose pay, annuity, or compensation is insufficient to cover such withholdings may nevertheless continue optional insurance if the employee arranges to pay currently into the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund, through the agency or retirement system which administers pay, annuity, or compensation, an amount equal to the withholdings that would otherwise be required under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The cost of the optional insurance shall be determined from time to time by the Office on the basis of such age groups as it considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The amount of optional life, or life and accidental death, insurance in force on an employee at the date of his death shall be paid as provided in <ref>section 8705 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–206, title IV, § 404(1)</ref>, <date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 647</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–583, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2481</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–427, § 6</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 351</ref>, as amended by <ref>Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–335, title II, § 207(k)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–311, § 6(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2951</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title XI, § 1103(b), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4616</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8714b.</num>
<heading> Additional optional life insurance</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under the conditions, directives, and terms specified in sections 8709 through 8712 of this title, the Office of Personnel Management, without regard to section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41, may purchase a policy which shall make available to each employee insured under <ref>section 8702 of this title</ref> amounts of additional optional life insurance (without accidental death and dismemberment insurance). An employee may elect coverage under this section without regard to whether the employee has elected coverage under optional insurance available under <ref>section 8714a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee who is deployed in support of a contingency operation (as that term is defined in <ref>section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>) or an employee of the Department of Defense who is designated as emergency essential under <ref>section 1580 of title 10</ref> shall be insured under the policy of insurance under this section if the employee, within 60 days after the date of notification of deployment or designation, elects to be insured under the policy of insurance. An election under this paragraph shall be effective when provided to the Office in writing, in the form prescribed by the Office, within such 60-day period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The additional optional insurance provided under this section shall be made available to each eligible employee who has elected coverage under this section, under conditions the Office shall prescribe, in multiples, at the employee’s election, of 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 times the annual rate of basic pay payable to the employee (rounded to the next higher multiple of $1,000). An employee may reduce or stop coverage elected pursuant to this section at any time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the additional optional insurance elected by an employee pursuant to this section shall stop on separation from service or 12 months after discontinuance of his pay, whichever is earlier, subject to a provision for temporary extension of life insurance coverage and for conversion to an individual policy of life insurance under conditions approved by the Office. Justices and judges of the United States described in section 8701(a)(5)(ii) and (iii) of this chapter are deemed to continue in active employment for purposes of this chapter. A justice or judge of the United States as defined by <ref>section 8701(a)(5) of this title</ref> who resigns his office without meeting the requirements of <ref>section 371(a) of title 28</ref>, United States Code, for continuation of the judicial salary shall have the right to convert additional optional life insurance coverage issued under this section during his judicial service to an individual policy of life insurance under the same conditions approved by the Office governing conversion of basic life insurance coverage for employees eligible as provided in <ref>section 8706(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of any employee who retires on an immediate annuity or who becomes entitled to receive compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee, so much of the additional optional insurance as has been in force for not less than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date of retirement or entitlement to compensation, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the full period or periods of service during which the insurance was available to the employee, if fewer than 5 years,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">may be continued under conditions determined by the Office after retirement or while the employee is receiving compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title and is held by the Secretary of Labor (or the Secretary’s delegate) to be unable to return to duty.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The amount of additional optional insurance continued under paragraph (2) shall be continued, with or without reduction, in accordance with the employee’s written election at the time eligibility to continue insurance during retirement or receipt of compensation arises, as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The employee may elect to have withholdings cease in accordance with subsection (d), in which case—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of additional optional insurance continued under paragraph (2) shall be reduced each month by 2 percent effective at the beginning of the second calendar month after the date the employee becomes 65 years of age and is retired or is in receipt of compensation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the reduction under clause (i) shall continue for 50 months at which time the insurance shall stop.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The employee may, instead of the option under subparagraph (A), elect to have the full cost of additional optional insurance continue to be withheld from such employee’s annuity or compensation on and after the date such withholdings would otherwise cease pursuant to an election under subparagraph (A), in which case the amount of additional optional insurance continued under paragraph (2) shall not be reduced, subject to paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> An employee who does not make any election under the preceding provisions of this paragraph shall be treated as if such employee had made an election under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If an employee makes an election under paragraph (3)(B), that individual may subsequently cancel such election, in which case additional optional insurance shall be determined as if the individual had originally made an election under paragraph (3)(A).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> An employee whose additional optional insurance under this section would otherwise stop in accordance with paragraph (1) and who is not eligible to continue insurance under paragraph (2) may elect, under conditions prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, to continue all or a portion of so much of the additional optional insurance as has been in force for not less than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date of the event which would cause insurance to stop under paragraph (1); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the full period or periods of service during which the insurance was available to the employee, if fewer than 5 years,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">at group rates established for purposes of this section, in lieu of conversion to an individual policy. The amount of insurance continued under this paragraph shall be reduced by 50 percent effective at the beginning of the second calendar month after the date the employee or former employee attains age 70 and shall stop at the beginning of the second calendar month after attainment of age 80, subject to a provision for temporary extension of life insurance coverage and for conversion to an individual policy of life insurance under conditions approved by the Office. Alternatively, insurance continued under this paragraph may be reduced or stopped at any time the employee or former employee elects.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> When an employee or former employee elects to continue additional optional insurance under this paragraph following separation from service or 12 months without pay, the insured individual shall submit timely payment of the full cost thereof, plus any amount the Office determines necessary to cover associated administrative expenses, in such manner as the Office shall prescribe by regulation. Amounts required under this subparagraph shall be deposited, used, and invested as provided under section 8714 and shall be reported and accounted for together with amounts withheld under section 8714a(d).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Subject to clause (ii), no election to continue additional optional insurance may be made under this paragraph 3 years after the effective date of this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> On and after the date on which an election may not be made under clause (i), all additional optional insurance under this paragraph for former employees shall terminate, subject to a provision for temporary extension of life insurance coverage and for conversion to an individual policy of life insurance under conditions approved by the Office.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During each period in which the additional optional insurance is in force on an employee the full cost thereof shall be withheld from the employee’s pay. During each period in which an employee continues additional optional insurance after retirement or while in receipt of compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee, as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the full cost thereof shall be withheld from the former employee’s annuity or compensation, except that, if insurance is continued as provided under subsection (c)(3)(A), beginning at the end of the calendar month in which the former employee becomes 65 years of age, the additional optional life insurance shall be without cost to the former employee. Amounts so withheld (and any amounts withheld as provided in subsection (c)(3)(B)) shall be deposited, used, and invested as provided in <ref>section 8714 of this title</ref> and shall be reported and accounted for together with amounts withheld under <ref>section 8714a(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If an agency fails to withhold the proper cost of additional optional insurance from an individual’s salary, compensation, or retirement annuity, the collection of amounts properly due may be waived by the agency if, in the judgment of the agency, the individual is without fault and recovery would be against equity and good conscience. However, if the agency so waives the collection of any unpaid amount, the agency shall submit an amount equal to the uncollected amount to the Office for deposit to the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), an employee who is subject to withholdings under this subsection and whose pay, annuity, or compensation is insufficient to cover such withholdings may nevertheless continue additional optional insurance if the employee arranges to pay currently into the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund, through the agency or retirement system which administers pay, annuity, or compensation, an amount equal to the withholdings that would otherwise be required under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The cost of the additional optional insurance shall be determined from time to time by the Office on the basis of the employee’s age relative to such age groups as the Office establishes under <ref>section 8714a(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The amount of additional optional life insurance in force on an employee at the date of his death shall be paid as provided in <ref>section 8705 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–427, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1834</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title II</ref>, §§ 206, 207, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 351</ref>, as amended by <ref>Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–335, title II, § 207(k)(4)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–311</ref>, §§ 3(2), 6(3), 7(a), (c), <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2950–2953</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title XI, § 1103(c), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4617</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8714c.</num>
<heading> Optional life insurance on family members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under the conditions, directives, and terms specified in sections 8709 through 8712 of this title, the Office of Personnel Management, without regard to section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41, may purchase a policy which shall make available to each employee insured under <ref>section 8702 of this title</ref> amounts of optional life insurance (without accidental death and dismemberment insurance) on the employee’s family members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The optional life insurance on family members provided under this section shall be made available to each eligible employee who has elected coverage under this section, under conditions the Office shall prescribe, in multiples, at the employee’s election, of 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 times—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> $5,000 for a spouse; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> $2,500 for each child described under section 8701(d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An employee may reduce or stop coverage elected pursuant to this section at any time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the optional life insurance on family members shall stop at the earlier of the employee’s death, the employee’s separation from the service, or 12 months after discontinuance of pay, subject to a provision for temporary extension of life insurance coverage and for conversion to individual policies of life insurance under conditions approved by the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of any employee who retires on an immediate annuity or who becomes entitled to receive compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee and who has had in force insurance under this section for no less than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date of retirement or entitlement to compensation, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the full period or periods of service during which the insurance was available to the employee, if fewer than 5 years,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">optional life insurance on family members may be continued under the same conditions as provided in section 8714b(c)(2) through (4).</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During each period in which the optional life insurance on family members is in force the full cost thereof shall be withheld from the employee’s pay. During each period in which an employee continues optional life insurance on family members after retirement or while in receipt of compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee, as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the full cost shall be withheld from the annuity or compensation, except that, beginning at the end of the calendar month in which the former employee becomes 65 years of age, the optional life insurance on family members shall be without cost to the employee. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the full cost shall be continued after the calendar month in which the former employee becomes 65 years of age if, and for so long as, an election under this section corresponding to that described in section 8714b(c)(3)(B) remains in effect with respect to such former employee. Amounts so withheld shall be deposited, used, and invested as provided in <ref>section 8714 of this title</ref> and shall be reported and accounted for together with amounts withheld under <ref>section 8714a(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If an agency fails to withhold the proper cost of optional life insurance on family members from an individual’s salary, compensation, or retirement annuity, the collection of amounts properly due may be waived by the agency if, in the judgment of the agency, the individual is without fault and recovery would be against equity and good conscience. However, if the agency so waives the collection of any unpaid amount, the agency shall submit an amount equal to the uncollected amount to the Office for deposit to the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), an employee who is subject to withholdings under this subsection and whose pay, annuity, or compensation is insufficient to cover such withholdings may nevertheless continue optional life insurance on family members if the employee arranges to pay currently into the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund, through the agency or retirement system that administers pay, annuity, or compensation, an amount equal to the withholdings that would otherwise be required under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The cost of the optional life insurance on family members shall be determined from time to time by the Office on the basis of the employee’s age relative to such age groups as the Office establishes under <ref>section 8714a(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The amount of optional life insurance which is in force under this section on a family member of an employee or former employee on the date of the death of the family member shall be paid, on the establishment of a valid claim by the employee, to such employee or, in the event of the death of the employee before payment can be made, to the person or persons entitled to the group life insurance in force on the employee under <ref>section 8705 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–427, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1836</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title II, § 206</ref>, as amended by <ref>Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–335, title II, § 207(k)(5)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–311</ref>, §§ 6(4), 8, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2951</ref>, 2953; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3842</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8714d.</num>
<heading> Option to receive “living benefits”</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section, an individual shall be considered to be “terminally ill” if such individual has a medical prognosis that such individual’s life expectancy is 9 months or less.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations under which any individual covered by group life insurance under section 8704(a) may, if such individual is terminally ill, elect to receive a lump-sum payment equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the full amount of insurance under section 8704(a) (or portion thereof designated for this purpose under subsection (d)(4)) which would otherwise be payable under this chapter (on the establishment of a valid claim)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> computed based on a date determined under regulations of the Office (but not later than 30 days after the date on which the individual’s application for benefits under this section is approved or deemed approved under subsection (d)(3)); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assuming continued coverage under this chapter at that time;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">reduced by</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an amount necessary to assure that there is no increase in the actuarial value of the benefit paid (as determined under regulations of the Office).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> If a lump-sum payment is taken under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> no insurance under the provisions of section 8704(a) or (b) shall be payable based on the death or any loss of the individual involved, unless the lump-sum payment represents only a portion of the total benefits which could have been taken, in which case benefits under those provisions shall remain in effect, except that the basic insurance amount on which they are based—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be reduced by the percentage which the designated portion comprised relative to the total benefits which could have been taken (rounding the result to the nearest multiple of $1,000 or, if midway between multiples of $1,000, to the next higher multiple of $1,000); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall not be subject to further adjustment; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> deductions and withholdings under section 8707, and contributions under section 8708, shall be terminated with respect to such individual (or reduced in a manner consistent with the percentage reduction in the individual’s basic insurance amount, if applicable), effective with respect to any amounts which would otherwise become due on or after the date of payment under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An individual who takes a lump-sum payment under this section (whether full or partial) remains eligible for optional benefits under sections 8714a–8714c (subject to payment of the full cost of those benefits in accordance with applicable provisions of the section or sections involved, to the same extent as if no election under this section had been made).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Office’s regulations shall include provisions regarding the form and manner in which an application under this section shall be made and the procedures in accordance with which any such application shall be considered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An application shall not be considered to be complete unless it includes such information and supporting evidence as the regulations require, including certification by an appropriate medical authority as to the nature of the individual’s illness and that the individual is not expected to live more than 9 months because of that illness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In order to ascertain the reliability of any medical opinion or finding submitted as part of an application under this section, the covered individual may be required to submit to a medical examination under the direction of the agency or entity considering the application. The individual shall not be liable for the costs associated with any examination required under this subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any decision by the reviewing agency or entity with respect to an application for benefits under this section (including one relating to an individual’s medical prognosis) shall not be subject to administrative review.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An individual making an election under this section may designate that only a limited portion (expressed as a multiple of $1,000) of the total amount otherwise allowable under this section be paid pursuant to such election.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A designation under this paragraph may not be made by an individual described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 8706(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An election to receive benefits under this section shall be irrevocable, and not more than one such election may be made by any individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The regulations shall include provisions to address the question of how to apply section 8706(b)(3)(B) in the case of an electing individual who has attained 65 years of age.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–409, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8715.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction of courts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The district courts of the United States have original jurisdiction, concurrent with the United States Court of Federal Claims, of a civil action or claim against the United States founded on this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 160(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8716.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management may prescribe regulations necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The regulations of the Office may prescribe the time at which and the conditions under which an employee is eligible for coverage under this chapter. The Office, after consulting the head of the agency or other employing authority concerned, may exclude an employee on the basis of the nature and type of his employment or conditions pertaining to it, such as short-term appointment, seasonal, intermittent employment, and employment of like nature. The Office may not exclude—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an employee or group of employees solely on the basis of the hazardous nature of employment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a teacher in the employ of the Board of Education of the District of Columbia, whose pay is fixed by <ref>section 1501 of title 31</ref>, District of Columbia Code, on the basis of the fact that the teacher is serving under a temporary appointment if the teacher has been so employed by the Board for a period or periods totaling not less than two school years; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an employee who is occupying a position on a part-time career employment basis (as defined in <ref>section 3401(2) of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Agriculture shall prescribe regulations to effect the application and operation of this chapter to an individual named by <ref>section 8701(a)(8) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–437, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1058</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), (c)(2)(F), (G), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>, 1227.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>