<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 73—</num>
<heading>SUITABILITY, SECURITY, AND CONDUCT</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>REGULATION OF CONDUCT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7301.</num>
<heading> Presidential regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may prescribe regulations for the conduct of employees in the executive branch.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7302.</num>
<heading> Post-employment notification</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Not later than the effective date of the amendments made by section 1106 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2004,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002133">1</ref> or 180 days after the date of the enactment of that Act, whichever is later, the Office of Personnel Management shall, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Office of Government Ethics, promulgate regulations requiring that each Executive branch agency notify any employee of that agency who is subject to the provisions of <ref>section 207(c)(1) of title 18</ref>, as a result of the amendment to section 207(c)(2)(A)(ii) of that title by that Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The regulations shall require that notice be given before, or as part of, the action that affects the employee’s coverage under <ref>section 207(c)(1) of title 18</ref>, by virtue of the provisions of section 207(c)(2)(A)(ii) of that title, and again when employment or service in the covered position is terminated.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1125(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1639</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>EMPLOYMENT LIMITATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7311.</num>
<heading> Loyalty and striking</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An individual may not accept or hold a position in the Government of the United States or the government of the District of Columbia if he—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> advocates the overthrow of our constitutional form of government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is a member of an organization that he knows advocates the overthrow of our constitutional form of government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> participates in a strike, or asserts the right to strike, against the Government of the United States or the government of the District of Columbia; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is a member of an organization of employees of the Government of the United States or of individuals employed by the government of the District of Columbia that he knows asserts the right to strike against the Government of the United States or the government of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7312.</num>
<heading> Employment and clearance; individuals removed for national security</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Removal under <ref>section 7532 of this title</ref> does not affect the right of an individual so removed to seek or accept employment in an agency of the United States other than the agency from which removed. However, the appointment of an individual so removed may be made only after the head of the agency concerned has consulted with the Office of Personnel Management. The Office, on written request of the head of the agency or the individual so removed, may determine whether the individual is eligible for employment in an agency other than the agency from which removed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 524</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7313.</num>
<heading> Riots and civil disorders</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An individual convicted by any Federal, State, or local court of competent jurisdiction of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> inciting a riot or civil disorder;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> organizing, promoting, encouraging, or participating in a riot or civil disorder;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> aiding or abetting any person in committing any offense specified in clause (1) or (2); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any offense determined by the head of the employing agency to have been committed in furtherance of, or while participating in, a riot or civil disorder;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall, if the offense for which he is convicted is a felony, be ineligible to accept or hold any position in the Government of the United States or in the government of the District of Columbia for the five years immediately following the date upon which his conviction becomes final. Any such individual holding a position in the Government of the United States or the government of the District of Columbia on the date his conviction becomes final shall be removed from such position.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, “felony” means any offense for which imprisonment is authorized for a term exceeding one year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–351, title V, § 1001(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-06-19">June 19, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 235</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>POLITICAL ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7321.</num>
<heading> Political participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the Congress that employees should be encouraged to exercise fully, freely, and without fear of penalty or reprisal, and to the extent not expressly prohibited by law, their right to participate or to refrain from participating in the political processes of the Nation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–94, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1001</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7322.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “employee” means any individual, other than the President and the Vice President, employed or holding office in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an Executive agency other than the Government Accountability Office; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a position within the competitive service which is not in an Executive agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">but does not include a member of the uniformed services or an individual employed or holding office in the government of the District of Columbia;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “partisan political office” means any office for which any candidate is nominated or elected as representing a party any of whose candidates for Presidential elector received votes in the last preceding election at which Presidential electors were selected, but shall exclude any office or position within a political party or affiliated organization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> “political contribution”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means any gift, subscription, loan, advance, or deposit of money or anything of value, made for any political purpose;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes any contract, promise, or agreement, express or implied, whether or not legally enforceable, to make a contribution for any political purpose;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> includes any payment by any person, other than a candidate or a political party or affiliated organization, of compensation for the personal services of another person which are rendered to any candidate or political party or affiliated organization without charge for any political purpose; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> includes the provision of personal services for any political purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–94, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1001</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–230, § 3(e)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-28">Dec. 28, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1617</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7323.</num>
<heading> Political activity authorized; prohibitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the provisions of subsection (b), an employee may take an active part in political management or in political campaigns, except an employee may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> use his official authority or influence for the purpose of interfering with or affecting the result of an election;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> knowingly solicit, accept, or receive a political contribution from any person, unless such person is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a member of the same Federal labor organization as defined under <ref>section 7103(4) of this title</ref> or a Federal employee organization which as of the date of enactment of the Hatch Act Reform Amendments of 1993 had a multicandidate political committee (as defined under section 315(a)(4) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 441a(a)(4)</ref>)); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002134">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not a subordinate employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the solicitation is for a contribution to the multicandidate political committee (as defined under section 315(a)(4) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 441a(a)(4)</ref>)) <sup>1</sup> of such Federal labor organization as defined under <ref>section 7103(4) of this title</ref> or a Federal employee organization which as of the date of the enactment of the Hatch Act Reform Amendments of 1993 had a multicandidate political committee (as defined under section 315(a)(4) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 441a(a)(4)</ref>)); <sup>1</sup> or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> run for the nomination or as a candidate for election to a partisan political office; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> knowingly solicit or discourage the participation in any political activity of any person who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has an application for any compensation, grant, contract, ruling, license, permit, or certificate pending before the employing office of such employee; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is the subject of or a participant in an ongoing audit, investigation, or enforcement action being carried out by the employing office of such employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee of the Federal Election Commission (except one appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate), may not request or receive from, or give to, an employee, a Member of Congress, or an officer of a uniformed service a political contribution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> No employee described under subparagraph (B) (except one appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate), may take an active part in political management or political campaigns.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of subparagraph (A) shall apply to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> an employee of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Federal Election Commission or the Election Assistance Commission;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the Secret Service;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the Central Intelligence Agency;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> the National Security Council;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> the National Security Agency;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(VII)</num>
<content> the Defense Intelligence Agency;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(VIII)</num>
<content> the Merit Systems Protection Board;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(IX)</num>
<content> the Office of Special Counsel;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(X)</num>
<content> the Office of Criminal Investigation of the Internal Revenue Service;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(XI)</num>
<content> the Office of Investigative Programs of the United States Customs Service;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(XII)</num>
<content> the Office of Law Enforcement of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(XIII)</num>
<content> the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(XIV)</num>
<content> the Office of the Director of National Intelligence; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a person employed in a position described under section 3132(a)(4), 5372, 5372a, or 5372b of title 5, United States Code.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> No employee of the Criminal Division or National Security Division of the Department of Justice (except one appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate), may take an active part in political management or political campaigns.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “active part in political management or in a political campaign” means those acts of political management or political campaigning which were prohibited for employees of the competitive service before <date date="1940-07-19">July 19, 1940</date>, by determinations of the Civil Service Commission under the rules prescribed by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An employee retains the right to vote as he chooses and to express his opinion on political subjects and candidates.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–94, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1002</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title V, § 501(k)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3430</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1122(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2687</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(3) [title VI, § 645(a)(2)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–170; <ref>Pub. L. 107–252, title VIII, § 811(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-10-29">Oct. 29, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1079(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title V, § 506(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 249</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 931(a)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4575</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7324.</num>
<heading> Political activities on duty; prohibition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An employee may not engage in political activity—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> while the employee is on duty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in any room or building occupied in the discharge of official duties by an individual employed or holding office in the Government of the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> while wearing a uniform or official insignia identifying the office or position of the employee; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> using any vehicle owned or leased by the Government of the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee described in paragraph (2) of this subsection may engage in political activity otherwise prohibited by subsection (a) if the costs associated with that political activity are not paid for by money derived from the Treasury of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) applies to an employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the duties and responsibilities of whose position continue outside normal duty hours and while away from the normal duty post; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> who is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an employee paid from an appropriation for the Executive Office of the President; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an employee appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, whose position is located within the United States, who determines policies to be pursued by the United States in relations with foreign powers or in the nationwide administration of Federal laws.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–94, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1003</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7325.</num>
<heading> Political activity permitted; employees residing in certain municipalities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management may prescribe regulations permitting employees, without regard to the prohibitions in paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 7323(a) and paragraph (2) of <ref>section 7323(b) of this title</ref>, to take an active part in political management and political campaigns involving the municipality or other political subdivision in which they reside, to the extent the Office considers it to be in their domestic interest, when—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the municipality or political subdivision is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the District of Columbia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in Maryland or Virginia and in the immediate vicinity of the District of Columbia; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a municipality in which the majority of voters are employed by the Government of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Office determines that because of special or unusual circumstances which exist in the municipality or political subdivision it is in the domestic interest of the employees and individuals to permit that political participation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–94, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1004</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–93, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1996-01-06">Jan. 6, 1996</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 966</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–230, § 3(f)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-28">Dec. 28, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1617</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7326.</num>
<heading> Penalties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An employee or individual who violates section 7323 or 7324 shall be subject to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> disciplinary action consisting of removal, reduction in grade, debarment from Federal employment for a period not to exceed 5 years, suspension, or reprimand;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assessment of a civil penalty not to exceed $1,000; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any combination of the penalties described in paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–230, § 4</ref>, <date date="2012-12-28">Dec. 28, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1617</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1626</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>FOREIGN GIFTS AND DECORATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>[§ 7341.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(45)(B)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 208</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7342.</num>
<heading> Receipt and disposition of foreign gifts and decorations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “employee” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an employee as defined by <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref> and an officer or employee of the United States Postal Service or of the Postal Regulatory Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an expert or consultant who is under contract under <ref>section 3109 of this title</ref> with the United States or any agency, department, or establishment thereof, including, in the case of an organization performing services under such section, any individual involved in the performance of such services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an individual employed by, or occupying an office or position in, the government of a territory or possession of the United States or the government of the District of Columbia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a member of a uniformed service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the President and the Vice President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a Member of Congress as defined by <ref>section 2106 of this title</ref> (except the Vice President) and any Delegate to the Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the spouse of an individual described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) (unless such individual and his or her spouse are separated) or a dependent (within the meaning of section 152 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) of such an individual, other than a spouse or dependent who is an employee under subparagraphs (A) through (F);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “foreign government” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any unit of foreign governmental authority, including any foreign national, State, local, and municipal government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any international or multinational organization whose membership is composed of any unit of foreign government described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any agent or representative of any such unit or such organization, while acting as such;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “gift” means a tangible or intangible present (other than a decoration) tendered by, or received from, a foreign government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “decoration” means an order, device, medal, badge, insignia, emblem, or award tendered by, or received from, a foreign government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> “minimal value” means a retail value in the United States at the time of acceptance of $100 or less, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on <date date="1981-01-01">January 1, 1981</date>, and at 3 year intervals thereafter, “minimal value” shall be redefined in regulations prescribed by the Administrator of General Services, in consultation with the Secretary of State, to reflect changes in the consumer price index for the immediately preceding 3-year period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> regulations of an employing agency may define “minimal value” for its employees to be less than the value established under this paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> “employing agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of the House of Representatives, for Members and employees of the House of Representatives, except that those responsibilities specified in subsections (c)(2)(A), (e)(1), and (g)(2)(B) shall be carried out by the Clerk of the House;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate, for Senators and employees of the Senate, except that those responsibilities (other than responsibilities involving approval of the employing agency) specified in subsections (c)(2), (d), and (g)(2)(B) shall be carried out by the Secretary of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, for judges and judicial branch employees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the department, agency, office, or other entity in which an employee is employed, for other legislative branch employees and for all executive branch employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An employee may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> request or otherwise encourage the tender of a gift or decoration; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> accept a gift or decoration, other than in accordance with the provisions of subsections (c) and (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress consents to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the accepting and retaining by an employee of a gift of minimal value tendered and received as a souvenir or mark of courtesy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the accepting by an employee of a gift of more than minimal value when such gift is in the nature of an educational scholarship or medical treatment or when it appears that to refuse the gift would likely cause offense or embarrassment or otherwise adversely affect the foreign relations of the United States, except that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a tangible gift of more than minimal value is deemed to have been accepted on behalf of the United States and, upon acceptance, shall become the property of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an employee may accept gifts of travel or expenses for travel taking place entirely outside the United States (such as transportation, food, and lodging) of more than minimal value if such acceptance is appropriate, consistent with the interests of the United States, and permitted by the employing agency and any regulations which may be prescribed by the employing agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Within 60 days after accepting a tangible gift of more than minimal value (other than a gift described in paragraph (1)(B)(ii)), an employee shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> deposit the gift for disposal with his or her employing agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subject to the approval of the employing agency, deposit the gift with that agency for official use.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Within 30 days after terminating the official use of a gift under subparagraph (B), the employing agency shall forward the gift to the Administrator of General Services in accordance with subsection (e)(1) or provide for its disposal in accordance with subsection (e)(2).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> When an employee deposits a gift of more than minimal value for disposal or for official use pursuant to paragraph (2), or within 30 days after accepting travel or travel expenses as provided in paragraph (1)(B)(ii) unless such travel or travel expenses are accepted in accordance with specific instructions of his or her employing agency, the employee shall file a statement with his or her employing agency or its delegate containing the information prescribed in subsection (f) for that gift.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Congress consents to the accepting, retaining, and wearing by an employee of a decoration tendered in recognition of active field service in time of combat operations or awarded for other outstanding or unusually meritorious performance, subject to the approval of the employing agency of such employee. Without this approval, the decoration is deemed to have been accepted on behalf of the United States, shall become the property of the United States, and shall be deposited by the employee, within sixty days of acceptance, with the employing agency for official use, for forwarding to the Administrator of General Services for disposal in accordance with subsection (e)(1), or for disposal in accordance with subsection (e)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), gifts and decorations that have been deposited with an employing agency for disposal shall be (A) returned to the donor, or (B) forwarded to the Administrator of General Services for transfer, donation, or other disposal in accordance with the provisions of subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41. However, no gift or decoration that has been deposited for disposal may be sold without the approval of the Secretary of State, upon a determination that the sale will not adversely affect the foreign relations of the United States. Gifts and decorations may be sold by negotiated sale.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Gifts and decorations received by a Senator or an employee of the Senate that are deposited with the Secretary of the Senate for disposal, or are deposited for an official use which has terminated, shall be disposed of by the Commission on Arts and Antiquities of the United States Senate. Any such gift or decoration may be returned by the Commission to the donor or may be transferred or donated by the Commission, subject to such terms and conditions as it may prescribe, (A) to an agency or instrumentality of (i) the United States, (ii) a State, territory, or possession of the United States, or a political subdivision of the foregoing, or (iii) the District of Columbia, or (B) to an organization described in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 which is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code. Any such gift or decoration not disposed of as provided in the preceding sentence shall be forwarded to the Administrator of General Services for disposal in accordance with paragraph (1). If the Administrator does not dispose of such gift or decoration within one year, he shall, at the request of the Commission, return it to the Commission and the Commission may dispose of such gift or decoration in such manner as it considers proper, except that such gift or decoration may be sold only with the approval of the Secretary of State upon a determination that the sale will not adversely affect the foreign relations of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not later than January 31 of each year, each employing agency or its delegate shall compile a listing of all statements filed during the preceding year by the employees of that agency pursuant to subsection (c)(3) and shall transmit such listing to the Secretary of State who shall publish a comprehensive listing of all such statements in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Such listings shall include for each tangible gift reported—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name and position of the employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a brief description of the gift and the circumstances justifying acceptance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the identity, if known, of the foreign government and the name and position of the individual who presented the gift;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the date of acceptance of the gift;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the estimated value in the United States of the gift at the time of acceptance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> disposition or current location of the gift.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Such listings shall include for each gift of travel or travel expenses—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name and position of the employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a brief description of the gift and the circumstances justifying acceptance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the identity, if known, of the foreign government and the name and position of the individual who presented the gift.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In transmitting such listings for an element of the intelligence community, the head of such element may delete the information described in subparagraph (A) or (C) of paragraph (2) or in subparagraph (A) or (C) of paragraph (3) if the head of such element certifies in writing to the Secretary of State that the publication of such information could adversely affect United States intelligence sources or methods.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any information not provided to the Secretary of State pursuant to the authority in subparagraph (A) shall be transmitted to the Director of National Intelligence who shall keep a record of such information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In this paragraph, the term “intelligence community” has the meaning given that term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 401a(4)</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002135">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each employing agency shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purpose of this section. For all employing agencies in the executive branch, such regulations shall be prescribed pursuant to guidance provided by the Secretary of State. These regulations shall be implemented by each employing agency for its employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Each employing agency shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> report to the Attorney General cases in which there is reason to believe that an employee has violated this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establish a procedure for obtaining an appraisal, when necessary, of the value of gifts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> take any other actions necessary to carry out the purpose of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may bring a civil action in any district court of the United States against any employee who knowingly solicits or accepts a gift from a foreign government not consented to by this section or who fails to deposit or report such gift as required by this section. The court in which such action is brought may assess a penalty against such employee in any amount not to exceed the retail value of the gift improperly solicited or received plus $5,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The President shall direct all Chiefs of a United States Diplomatic Mission to inform their host governments that it is a general policy of the United States Government to prohibit United States Government employees from receiving gifts or decorations of more than minimal value.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to derogate any regulation prescribed by any employing agency which provides for more stringent limitations on the receipt of gifts and decorations by its employees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> The provisions of this section do not apply to grants and other forms of assistance to which section 108A of the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 applies.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(45)(C)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 208</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–105, title V, § 515(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 862</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–426, title VII, § 712(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1978-10-07">Oct. 7, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 994</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1295</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1079(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3696</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title VI, § 604(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–259, title III, § 361</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2701</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>MISCONDUCT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7351.</num>
<heading> Gifts to superiors</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An employee may not—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> solicit a contribution from another employee for a gift to an official superior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make a donation as a gift or give a gift to an official superior; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> accept a gift from an employee receiving less pay than himself.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An employee who violates this section shall be subject to appropriate disciplinary action by the employing agency or entity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Each supervising ethics office (as defined in section 7353(d)(1)) is authorized to issue regulations implementing this section, including regulations exempting voluntary gifts or contributions that are given or received for special occasions such as marriage or retirement or under other circumstances in which gifts are traditionally given or exchanged.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 527</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–194, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–280, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-05-04">May 4, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7352.</num>
<heading> Excessive and habitual use of intoxicants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An individual who habitually uses intoxicating beverages to excess may not be employed in the competitive service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 527</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7353.</num>
<heading> Gifts to Federal employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except as permitted by subsection (b), no Member of Congress or officer or employee of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch shall solicit or accept anything of value from a person—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> seeking official action from, doing business with, or (in the case of executive branch officers and employees) conducting activities regulated by, the individual’s employing entity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whose interests may be substantially affected by the performance or nonperformance of the individual’s official duties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each supervising ethics office is authorized to issue rules or regulations implementing the provisions of this section and providing for such reasonable exceptions as may be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), a Member, officer, or employee may accept a gift pursuant to rules or regulations established by such individual’s supervising ethics office pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> No gift may be accepted pursuant to subparagraph (A) in return for being influenced in the performance of any official act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section precludes a Member, officer, or employee from accepting gifts on behalf of the United States Government or any of its agencies in accordance with statutory authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section precludes an employee of a private sector organization, while assigned to an agency under chapter 37, from continuing to receive pay and benefits from such organization in accordance with such chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A Member of Congress or an officer or employee who violates this section shall be subject to appropriate disciplinary and other remedial action in accordance with any applicable laws, Executive orders, and rules or regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “supervising ethics office” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of the House of Representatives or the House of Representatives as a whole, for Members, officers, and employees of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate, or the Senate as a whole, for Senators, officers, and employees of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Judicial Conference of the United States for judges and judicial branch officers and employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Office of Government Ethics for all executive branch officers and employees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> in the case of legislative branch officers and employees other than those specified in subparagraphs (A) and (B), the committee referred to in either such subparagraph to which reports filed by such officers and employees under subchapter I of chapter 131 of this title are transmitted under such subchapter, except that the authority of this section may be delegated by such committee with respect to such officers and employees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “officer or employee” means an individual holding an appointive or elective position in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of Government, other than a Member of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–194, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1746</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–280, § 4(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-05-04">May 4, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 158</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–347, title II, § 209(g)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-17">Dec. 17, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2932</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(c)(9)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>DRUG ABUSE, ALCOHOL ABUSE, AND ALCOHOLISM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7361.</num>
<heading> Drug abuse</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall be responsible for developing, in cooperation with the President, with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (acting through the National Institute on Drug Abuse), and with other agencies, and in accordance with applicable provisions of this subchapter, appropriate prevention, treatment, and rehabilitation programs and services for drug abuse among employees. Such agencies are encouraged to extend, to the extent feasible, such programs and services to the families of employees and to employees who have family members who are drug abusers. Such programs and services shall make optimal use of existing governmental facilities, services, and skills.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Section 527 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002136">1</ref> of the Public Health Service Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 290ee–3</ref>), relating to confidentiality of records, and any regulations prescribed thereunder, shall apply with respect to records maintained for the purpose of carrying out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Each agency shall, with respect to any programs or services provided by such agency, submit such written reports as the Office may require in connection with any report required under <ref>section 7363 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section, the term “agency” means an Executive agency.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title VI, § 6002(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7362.</num>
<heading> Alcohol abuse and alcoholism</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall be responsible for developing, in cooperation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and with other agencies, and in accordance with applicable provisions of this subpart, appropriate prevention, treatment, and rehabilitation programs and services for alcohol abuse and alcoholism among employees. Such agencies are encouraged to extend, to the extent feasible, such programs and services to the families of alcoholic employees and to employees who have family members who are alcoholics. Such programs and services shall make optimal use of existing governmental facilities, services, and skills.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Section 523 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002137">1</ref> of the Public Health Service Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 290dd–3</ref>), relating to confidentiality of records, and any regulations prescribed thereunder, shall apply with respect to records maintained for the purpose of carrying out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Each agency shall, with respect to any programs or services provided by such agency, submit such written reports as the Office may require in connection with any report required under <ref>section 7363 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section, the term “agency” means an Executive agency.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title VI, § 6002(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7363.</num>
<heading> Reports to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall, within 6 months after the date of the enactment of the Federal Employee Substance Abuse Education and Treatment Act of 1986 and annually thereafter, submit to each House of Congress a report containing the matters described in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Each report under this section shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of any programs or services provided under section 7361 or 7362 of this title, including the costs associated with each such program or service and the source and adequacy of any funding <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002138">1</ref> such program or service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the levels of participation in each program and service provided under section 7361 or 7362 of this title, and the effectiveness of such programs and services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of the training and qualifications required of the personnel providing any program or service under section 7361 or 7362 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a description of the training given to supervisory personnel in connection with recognizing the symptoms of drug or alcohol abuse and the procedures (including those relating to confidentiality) under which individuals are referred for treatment, rehabilitation, or other assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any recommendations for legislation considered appropriate by the Office and any proposed administrative actions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> information describing any other related activities under <ref>section 7904 of this title</ref>, and any other matter which the Office considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title VI, § 6002(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>MANDATORY REMOVAL FROM EMPLOYMENT OF CONVICTED LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7371.</num>
<heading> Mandatory removal from employment of law enforcement officers convicted of felonies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this section, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “conviction notice date” means the date on which an agency that employs a law enforcement officer has notice that the officer has been convicted of a felony that is entered by a Federal or State court, regardless of whether that conviction is appealed or is subject to appeal; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “law enforcement officer” has the meaning given that term under section 8331(20) or 8401(17).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any law enforcement officer who is convicted of a felony shall be removed from employment as a law enforcement officer on the last day of the first applicable pay period following the conviction notice date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> This section does not prohibit the removal of an individual from employment as a law enforcement officer before a conviction notice date if the removal is properly effected other than under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> This section does not prohibit the employment of any individual in any position other than that of a law enforcement officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If the conviction is overturned on appeal, the removal shall be set aside retroactively to the date on which the removal occurred, with back pay under section 5596 for the period during which the removal was in effect, unless the removal was properly effected other than under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If removal is required under this section, the agency shall deliver written notice to the employee as soon as practicable, and not later than 5 calendar days after the conviction notice date. The notice shall include a description of the specific reasons for the removal, the date of removal, and the procedures made applicable under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The procedures under section 7513(b)(2), (3), and (4), (c), (d), and (e) shall apply to any removal under this section. The employee may use the procedures to contest or appeal a removal, but only with respect to whether—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the employee is a law enforcement officer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the employee was convicted of a felony; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the conviction was overturned on appeal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A removal required under this section shall occur on the date specified in subsection (b) regardless of whether the notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection and the procedures made applicable under paragraph (2) of this subsection have been provided or completed by that date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(3) [title VI, § 639(a)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–168.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>