<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 12—</num>
<heading>MERIT SYSTEMS PROTECTION BOARD, OFFICE OF SPECIAL COUNSEL, AND EMPLOYEE RIGHT OF ACTION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>MERIT SYSTEMS PROTECTION BOARD</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1201.</num>
<heading> Appointment of members of the Merit Systems Protection Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Merit Systems Protection Board is composed of 3 members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, not more than 2 of whom may be adherents of the same political party. The members of the Board shall be individuals who, by demonstrated ability, background, training, or experience are especially qualified to carry out the functions of the Board. No member of the Board may hold another office or position in the Government of the United States, except as otherwise provided by law or at the direction of the President. The Board shall have an official seal which shall be judicially noticed. The Board shall have its principal office in the District of Columbia and may have field offices in other appropriate locations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1121</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 16</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1202.</num>
<heading> Term of office; filling vacancies; removal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The term of office of each member of the Merit Systems Protection Board is 7 years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the end of a term of office of the member’s predecessor serves for the remainder of that term. Any appointment to fill a vacancy is subject to the requirements of section 1201. Any new member serving only a portion of a seven-year term in office may continue to serve until a successor is appointed and has qualified, except that such member may not continue to serve for more than one year after the date on which the term of the member would otherwise expire, unless reappointed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Any member appointed for a 7-year term may not be reappointed to any following term but may continue to serve beyond the expiration of the term until a successor is appointed and has qualified, except that such member may not continue to serve for more than one year after the date on which the term of the member would otherwise expire under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Any member may be removed by the President only for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1122</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(m) [title VI, § 620]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329–390</ref>, 1329–427; <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 17</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1203.</num>
<heading> Chairman; Vice Chairman</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President shall from time to time appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, one of the members of the Merit Systems Protection Board as the Chairman of the Board. The Chairman is the chief executive and administrative officer of the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The President shall from time to time designate one of the members of the Board as Vice Chairman of the Board. During the absence or disability of the Chairman, or when the office of Chairman is vacant, the Vice Chairman shall perform the functions vested in the Chairman.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> During the absence or disability of both the Chairman and the Vice Chairman, or when the offices of Chairman and Vice Chairman are vacant, the remaining Board member shall perform the functions vested in the Chairman.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1122</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(4)</ref>, (5), <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 17</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1204.</num>
<heading> Powers and functions of the Merit Systems Protection Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Merit Systems Protection Board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> hear, adjudicate, or provide for the hearing or adjudication, of all matters within the jurisdiction of the Board under this title, chapter 43 of title 38, or any other law, rule, or regulation, and, subject to otherwise applicable provisions of law, take final action on any such matter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> order any Federal agency or employee to comply with any order or decision issued by the Board under the authority granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection and enforce compliance with any such order;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> conduct, from time to time, special studies relating to the civil service and to other merit systems in the executive branch, and report to the President and to the Congress as to whether the public interest in a civil service free of prohibited personnel practices is being adequately protected; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> review, as provided in subsection (f), rules and regulations of the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any member of the Merit Systems Protection Board, any administrative law judge appointed by the Board under <ref>section 3105 of this title</ref>, and any employee of the Board designated by the Board may administer oaths, examine witnesses, take depositions, and receive evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Any member of the Board, any administrative law judge appointed by the Board under section 3105, and any employee of the Board designated by the Board may, with respect to any individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> issue subpoenas requiring the attendance and presentation of testimony of any such individual, and the production of documentary or other evidence from any place in the United States, any territory or possession of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or the District of Columbia; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> order the taking of depositions from, and responses to written interrogatories by, any such individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Witnesses (whether appearing voluntarily or under subpoena) shall be paid the same fee and mileage allowances which are paid subpoenaed witnesses in the courts of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In the case of contumacy or failure to obey a subpoena issued under subsection (b)(2)(A) or section 1214(b), upon application by the Board, the United States district court for the district in which the person to whom the subpoena is addressed resides or is served may issue an order requiring such person to appear at any designated place to testify or to produce documentary or other evidence. Any failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court as a contempt thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A subpoena referred to in subsection (b)(2)(A) may, in the case of any individual outside the territorial jurisdiction of any court of the United States, be served in such manner as the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure prescribe for service of a subpoena in a foreign country. To the extent that the courts of the United States can assert jurisdiction over such individual, the United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall have the same jurisdiction to take any action respecting compliance under this subsection by such individual that such court would have if such individual were personally within the jurisdiction of such court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In any proceeding under subsection (a)(1), any member of the Board may request from the Director of the Office of Personnel Management an advisory opinion concerning the interpretation of any rule, regulation, or other policy directive promulgated by the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Merit Systems Protection Board may, during an investigation by the Office of Special Counsel or during the pendency of any proceeding before the Board, issue any order which may be necessary to protect a witness or other individual from harassment, except that an agency (other than the Office of Special Counsel) may not request any such order with regard to an investigation by the Office of Special Counsel from the Board during such investigation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> An order issued under this subparagraph may be enforced in the same manner as provided for under paragraph (2) with respect to any order under subsection (a)(2).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In enforcing compliance with any order under subsection (a)(2), the Board may order that any employee charged with complying with such order, other than an employee appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall not be entitled to receive payment for service as an employee during any period that the order has not been complied with. The Board shall certify to the Comptroller General of the United States that such an order has been issued and no payment shall be made out of the Treasury of the United States for any service specified in such order.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Board shall prescribe regulations under which any employee who is aggrieved by the failure of any other employee to comply with an order of the Board may petition the Board to exercise its authority under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In carrying out any study under subsection (a)(3), the Board shall make such inquiries as may be necessary and, unless otherwise prohibited by law, shall have access to personnel records or information collected by the Office of Personnel Management and may require additional reports from other agencies as needed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> At any time after the effective date of any rule or regulation issued by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management in carrying out functions under section 1103, the Board shall review any provision of such rule or regulation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on its own motion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on the granting by the Board, in its sole discretion, of any petition for such review filed with the Board by any interested person, after consideration of the petition by the Board; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> on the filing of a written complaint by the Special Counsel requesting such review.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In reviewing any provision of any rule or regulation pursuant to this subsection, the Board shall declare such provision—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> invalid on its face, if the Board determines that such provision would, if implemented by any agency, on its face, require any employee to violate section 2302(b); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> invalidly implemented by any agency, if the Board determines that such provision, as it has been implemented by the agency through any personnel action taken by the agency or through any policy adopted by the agency in conformity with such provision, has required any employee to violate section 2302(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Director of the Office of Personnel Management, and the head of any agency implementing any provision of any rule or regulation under review pursuant to this subsection, shall have the right to participate in such review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The Board shall require any agency—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to cease compliance with any provisions of any rule or regulation which the Board declares under this subsection to be invalid on its face; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to correct any invalid implementation by the agency of any provision of any rule or regulation which the Board declares under this subsection to have been invalidly implemented by the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The Board may delegate the performance of any of its administrative functions under this title to any employee of the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The Board shall have the authority to prescribe such regulations as may be necessary for the performance of its functions. The Board shall not issue advisory opinions. All regulations of the Board shall be published in the Federal Register.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Except as provided in <ref>section 518 of title 28</ref>, relating to litigation before the Supreme Court, attorneys designated by the Chairman of the Board may appear for the Board, and represent the Board, in any civil action brought in connection with any function carried out by the Board pursuant to this title or as otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> The Chairman of the Board may appoint such personnel as may be necessary to perform the functions of the Board. Any appointment made under this subsection shall comply with the provisions of this title, except that such appointment shall not be subject to the approval or supervision of the Office of Personnel Management or the Executive Office of the President (other than approval required under section 3324 or subchapter VIII of chapter 33).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> The Board shall prepare and submit to the President, and, at the same time, to the appropriate committees of Congress, an annual budget of the expenses and other items relating to the Board which shall, as revised, be included as a separate item in the budget required to be transmitted to the Congress under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<content> The Board shall submit to the President, and, at the same time, to each House of the Congress, any legislative recommendations of the Board relating to any of its functions under this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board, or an administrative law judge or other employee of the Board designated to hear a case arising under section 1215, may require payment by the agency where the prevailing party was employed or had applied for employment at the time of the events giving rise to the case of reasonable attorney fees incurred by an employee or applicant for employment if the employee or applicant is the prevailing party and the Board, administrative law judge, or other employee (as the case may be) determines that payment by the agency is warranted in the interest of justice, including any case in which a prohibited personnel practice was engaged in by the agency or any case in which the agency’s action was clearly without merit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If an employee or applicant for employment is the prevailing party of a case arising under section 1215 and the decision is based on a finding of discrimination prohibited under <ref>section 2302(b)(1) of this title</ref>, the payment of attorney fees shall be in accordance with the standards prescribed under section 706(k) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e–5(k)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(n)</num>
<content> The Board may accept and use gifts and donations of property and services to carry out the duties of the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1122</ref>, § 1205; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1063</ref>; renumbered § 1204 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 17</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–568, title V, § 506(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–353, § 2(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3169</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–424, § 2</ref>, <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4361</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1203(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4690</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–199, title I, § 107(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1469</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. E, title V</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 217</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1205.</num>
<heading> Transmittal of information to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law or any rule, regulation or policy directive, any member of the Board, or any employee of the Board designated by the Board, may transmit to the Congress on the request of any committee or subcommittee thereof, by report, testimony, or otherwise, information and views on functions, responsibilities, or other matters relating to the Board, without review, clearance, or approval by any other administrative authority.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1131</ref>, § 1209(a); renumbered § 1205 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 18</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1206.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall submit an annual report to the President and the Congress on its activities, which shall include a description of significant actions taken by the Board to carry out its functions under this title. The report shall also review the significant actions of the Office of Personnel Management, including an analysis of whether the actions of the Office of Personnel Management are in accord with merit system principles and free from prohibited personnel practices.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1131</ref>, § 1209(b); renumbered § 1206 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 18</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 1207, 1208.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 18</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1209.</num>
<heading> Renumbered §§ 1205 and 1206]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>OFFICE OF SPECIAL COUNSEL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1211.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is established the Office of Special Counsel, which shall be headed by the Special Counsel. The Office shall have an official seal which shall be judicially noticed. The Office shall have its principal office in the District of Columbia and shall have field offices in other appropriate locations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, for a term of 5 years. The Special Counsel may continue to serve beyond the expiration of the term until a successor is appointed and has qualified, except that the Special Counsel may not continue to serve for more than one year after the date on which the term of the Special Counsel would otherwise expire under this subsection. The Special Counsel shall be an attorney who, by demonstrated ability, background, training, or experience, is especially qualified to carry out the functions of the position. A Special Counsel appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the end of a term of office of the Special Counsel’s predecessor serves for the remainder of the term. The Special Counsel may be removed by the President only for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office. The Special Counsel may not hold another office or position in the Government of the United States, except as otherwise provided by law or at the direction of the President.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 19</ref>, § 1211(a), and <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1122</ref>, § 1204; renumbered § 1211(b) and amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(6)</ref>, (12), <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 17</ref>, 19; <ref>Pub. L. 103–424, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4361</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1212.</num>
<heading> Powers and functions of the Office of Special Counsel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Office of Special Counsel shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in accordance with section 1214(a) and other applicable provisions of this subchapter, protect employees, former employees, and applicants for employment from prohibited personnel practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> receive and investigate allegations of prohibited personnel practices, and, where appropriate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> bring petitions for stays, and petitions for corrective action, under section 1214; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> file a complaint or make recommendations for disciplinary action under section 1215;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> receive, review, and, where appropriate, forward to the Attorney General or an agency head under section 1213, disclosures of violations of any law, rule, or regulation, or gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> review rules and regulations issued by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management in carrying out functions under section 1103 and, where the Special Counsel finds that any such rule or regulation would, on its face or as implemented, require the commission of a prohibited personnel practice, file a written complaint with the Board; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> investigate and, where appropriate, bring actions concerning allegations of violations of other laws within the jurisdiction of the Office of Special Counsel (as referred to in section 1216).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel and any employee of the Office of Special Counsel designated by the Special Counsel may administer oaths, examine witnesses, take depositions, and receive evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Special Counsel may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> issue subpoenas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> order the taking of depositions and order responses to written interrogatories;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">in the same manner as provided under section 1204.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of contumacy or failure to obey a subpoena issued under paragraph (2)(A), the Special Counsel may apply to the Merit Systems Protection Board to enforce the subpoena in court pursuant to section 1204(c).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A subpoena under paragraph (2)(A) may, in the case of any individual outside the territorial jurisdiction of any court of the United States, be served in the manner referred to in subsection (d) of section 1204, and the United States District Court for the District of Columbia may, with respect to any such individual, compel compliance in accordance with such subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Witnesses (whether appearing voluntarily or under subpoena) shall be paid the same fee and mileage allowances which are paid subpoenaed witnesses in the courts of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Special Counsel, in carrying out this subchapter, is authorized to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> have timely access to all records, data, reports, audits, reviews, documents, papers, recommendations, or other material available to the applicable agency that relate to an investigation, review, or inquiry conducted under—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> section 1213, 1214, 1215, or 1216 of this title; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content><ref>section 4324(a) of title 38</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> request from any agency the information or assistance that may be necessary for the Special Counsel to carry out the duties and responsibilities of the Special Counsel under this subchapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> require, during an investigation, review, or inquiry of an agency, the agency to provide to the Special Counsel any record or other information that relates to an investigation, review, or inquiry conducted under—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> section 1213, 1214, 1215, or 1216 of this title; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content><ref>section 4324(a) of title 38</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The authorization of the Special Counsel under subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to any entity that is an element of the intelligence community, as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>), unless the Special Counsel is investigating, or otherwise carrying out activities relating to the enforcement of, an action under subchapter III of chapter 73.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> An Inspector General may withhold from the Special Counsel material described in subparagraph (A) if the Inspector General determines that the material contains information derived from, or pertaining to, intelligence activities.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General or an Inspector General may withhold from the Special Counsel material described in subparagraph (A) if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<item class="indent1">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> disclosing the material could reasonably be expected to interfere with a criminal investigation or prosecution that is ongoing as of the date on which the Special Counsel submits a request for the material; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent1">
<num>(bb)</num>
<chapeau> the material—</chapeau>
<subitem class="indent2">
<num>(AA)</num>
<content> may not be disclosed pursuant to a court order; or</content>
</subitem>
<subitem class="indent2">
<num>(BB)</num>
<content> has been filed under seal under <ref>section 3730 of title 31</ref>; and</content>
</subitem>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> the Attorney General or the Inspector General, as applicable, submits to the Special Counsel a written report that describes—</chapeau>
<item class="indent2">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> the material being withheld; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent2">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> the reason that the material is being withheld.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A claim of common law privilege by an agency, or an officer or employee of an agency, shall not prevent the Special Counsel from obtaining any material described in subparagraph (A)(i) with respect to the agency.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The submission of material described in subparagraph (A)(i) by an agency to the Special Counsel may not be deemed to waive any assertion of privilege by the agency against a non-Federal entity or against an individual in any other proceeding.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> With respect to any record or other information made available to the Special Counsel by an agency under subparagraph (A), the Special Counsel may only disclose the record or information for a purpose that is in furtherance of any authority provided to the Special Counsel under this subchapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and each committee of Congress with jurisdiction over the applicable agency a report regarding any case of contumacy or failure to comply with a request submitted by the Special Counsel under paragraph (5)(A).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Special Counsel may as a matter of right intervene or otherwise participate in any proceeding before the Merit Systems Protection Board, except that the Special Counsel shall comply with the rules of the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel may not intervene in an action brought by an individual under section 1221, or in an appeal brought by an individual under section 7701, without the consent of such individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel may appoint the legal, administrative, and support personnel necessary to perform the functions of the Special Counsel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any appointment made under this subsection shall be made in accordance with the provisions of this title, except that such appointment shall not be subject to the approval or supervision of the Office of Personnel Management or the Executive Office of the President (other than approval required under section 3324 or subchapter VIII of chapter 33).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to perform the functions of the Special Counsel. Such regulations shall be published in the Federal Register.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel may not issue any advisory opinion concerning any law, rule, or regulation (other than an advisory opinion concerning chapter 15 or subchapter III of chapter 73).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel may not respond to any inquiry or disclose any information from or about any person making an allegation under section 1214(a), except in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref>, United States Code, or as required by any other applicable Federal law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding the exception under paragraph (1), the Special Counsel may not respond to any inquiry concerning an evaluation of the work performance, ability, aptitude, general qualifications, character, loyalty, or suitability for any personnel action of any person described in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> unless the consent of the individual as to whom the information pertains is obtained in advance; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> except upon request of an agency which requires such information in order to make a determination concerning an individual’s having access to the information unauthorized disclosure of which could be expected to cause exceptionally grave damage to the national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel is authorized to appear as amicus curiae in any action brought in a court of the United States related to section 2302(b)(8) or (9), or as otherwise authorized by law. In any such action, the Special Counsel is authorized to present the views of the Special Counsel with respect to compliance with section 2302(b)(8) or (9) and the impact court decisions would have on the enforcement of such provisions of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A court of the United States shall grant the application of the Special Counsel to appear in any such action for the purposes described under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> The Special Counsel shall enter into at least 1 agreement with the Inspector General of an agency under which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Inspector General shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> receive, review, and investigate allegations of prohibited personnel practices or wrongdoing filed by employees of the Office of Special Counsel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> develop a method for an employee of the Office of Special Counsel to communicate directly with the Inspector General; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the Special Counsel—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may not require an employee of the Office of Special Counsel to seek authorization or approval before directly contacting the Inspector General in accordance with the agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may reimburse the Inspector General for services provided under the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 19</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–424, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4362</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–199, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(a)</ref>, (g), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1615</ref>, 1623.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1213.</num>
<heading> Provisions relating to disclosures of violations of law, gross mismanagement, and certain other matters</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> This section applies with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> any disclosure of information by an employee, former employee, or applicant for employment which the employee, former employee, or applicant reasonably believes evidences—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a violation of any law, rule, or regulation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">if such disclosure is not specifically prohibited by law and if such information is not specifically required by Executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or the conduct of foreign affairs; and</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> any disclosure by an employee, former employee, or applicant for employment to the Special Counsel or to the Inspector General of an agency or another employee designated by the head of the agency to receive such disclosures of information which the employee, former employee, or applicant reasonably believes evidences—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a violation of any law, rule, or regulation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whenever the Special Counsel receives information of a type described in subsection (a) of this section, the Special Counsel shall review such information and, within 45 days after receiving the information, determine whether there is a substantial likelihood that the information discloses a violation of any law, rule, or regulation, or gross mismanagement, gross waste of funds, abuse of authority, or substantial and specific danger to public health and safety.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2), if the Special Counsel makes a positive determination under subsection (b) of this section, the Special Counsel shall promptly transmit the information with respect to which the determination was made to the appropriate agency head and require that the agency head—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct an investigation with respect to the information and any related matters transmitted by the Special Counsel to the agency head; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submit a written report setting forth the findings of the agency head within 60 days after the date on which the information is transmitted to the agency head or within any longer period of time agreed to in writing by the Special Counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Special Counsel may require an agency head to conduct an investigation and submit a written report under paragraph (1) only if the information was transmitted to the Special Counsel by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an employee, former employee, or applicant for employment in the agency which the information concerns; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an employee who obtained the information in connection with the performance of the employee’s duties and responsibilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Any report required under subsection (c) shall be reviewed and signed by the head of the agency and shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a summary of the information with respect to which the investigation was initiated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the conduct of the investigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a summary of any evidence obtained from the investigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a listing of any violation or apparent violation of any law, rule, or regulation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> a description of any action taken or planned as a result of the investigation, such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> changes in agency rules, regulations, or practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the restoration of any aggrieved employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> disciplinary action against any employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> referral to the Attorney General of any evidence of a criminal violation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any report required under subsection (c) or paragraph (5) of this subsection shall be submitted to the Special Counsel, and the Special Counsel shall transmit a copy to the complainant, except as provided under subsection (f) of this section. The complainant may submit comments to the Special Counsel on the agency report within 15 days of having received a copy of the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Upon receipt of any report that the head of an agency is required to submit under subsection (c), the Special Counsel shall review the report and determine whether—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the findings of the head of the agency appear reasonable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the Special Counsel requires the head of the agency to submit a supplemental report under paragraph (5), the reports submitted by the head of the agency collectively contain the information required under subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel shall transmit any report submitted to the Special Counsel by the head of an agency under subsection (c) or paragraph (5) of this subsection, any comments provided by the complainant pursuant to subsection (e)(1), and any appropriate comments or recommendations by the Special Counsel to the President and the congressional committees with jurisdiction over the agency which the disclosure involves.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Whenever the Special Counsel does not receive the report of the agency within the time prescribed in subsection (c)(2) of this section, the Special Counsel shall transmit a copy of the information which was transmitted to the agency head to the President and the congressional committees with jurisdiction over the agency which the disclosure involves together with a statement noting the failure of the head of the agency to file the required report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> If, after conducting a review of a report under paragraph (2), the Special Counsel concludes that the Special Counsel requires additional information or documentation to determine whether the report submitted by the head of an agency is reasonable and sufficient, the Special Counsel may request that the head of the agency submit a supplemental report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> containing the additional information or documentation identified by the Special Counsel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that the head of the agency shall submit to the Special Counsel within a period of time specified by the Special Counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> In any case in which evidence of a criminal violation obtained by an agency in an investigation under subsection (c) of this section is referred to the Attorney General—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the report shall not be transmitted to the complainant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the agency shall notify the Office of Personnel Management and the Office of Management and Budget of the referral.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Special Counsel receives information of a type described in subsection (a) from an individual other than an individual described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (c)(2), the Special Counsel may transmit the information to the head of the agency which the information concerns. The head of such agency shall, within a reasonable time after the information is transmitted, inform the Special Counsel in writing of what action has been or is being taken and when such action shall be completed. The Special Counsel shall inform the individual of the report of the agency head.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the Special Counsel receives information of a type described in subsection (a) from an individual described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (c)(2), but does not make a positive determination under subsection (b), the Special Counsel may transmit the information to the head of the agency which the information concerns, except that the information may not be transmitted to the head of the agency without the consent of the individual. The head of such agency shall, within a reasonable time after the information is transmitted, inform the Special Counsel in writing of what action has been or is being taken and when such action will be completed. The Special Counsel shall inform the individual of the report of the agency head.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> If the Special Counsel does not transmit the information to the head of the agency under paragraph (2), the Special Counsel shall inform the individual of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the reasons why the disclosure may not be further acted on under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other offices available for receiving disclosures, should the individual wish to pursue the matter further.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The identity of any individual who makes a disclosure described in subsection (a) may not be disclosed by the Special Counsel without such individual’s consent unless the Special Counsel determines that the disclosure of the individual’s identity is necessary because of an imminent danger to public health or safety or imminent violation of any criminal law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Except as specifically authorized under this section, the provisions of this section shall not be considered to authorize disclosure of any information by any agency or any person which is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specifically prohibited from disclosure by any other provision of law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specifically required by Executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or the conduct of foreign affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> With respect to any disclosure of information described in subsection (a) which involves foreign intelligence or counterintelligence information, if the disclosure is specifically prohibited by law or by Executive order, the Special Counsel shall transmit such information to the National Security Advisor, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 21</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–316, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3828</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–304, § 3</ref>, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2364</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1214.</num>
<heading> Investigation of prohibited personnel practices; corrective action</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel shall receive any allegation of a prohibited personnel practice and shall investigate the allegation to the extent necessary to determine whether there are reasonable grounds to believe that a prohibited personnel practice has occurred, exists, or is to be taken.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Within 15 days after the date of receiving an allegation of a prohibited personnel practice under paragraph (1), the Special Counsel shall provide written notice to the person who made the allegation that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the allegation has been received by the Special Counsel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall include the name of a person at the Office of Special Counsel who shall serve as a contact with the person making the allegation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Unless an investigation is terminated under paragraph (2), the Special Counsel shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> within 90 days after notice is provided under subparagraph (B), notify the person who made the allegation of the status of the investigation and any action taken by the Office of the Special Counsel since the filing of the allegation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> notify such person of the status of the investigation and any action taken by the Office of the Special Counsel since the last notice, at least every 60 days after notice is given under clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> notify such person of the status of the investigation and any action taken by the Special Counsel at such time as determined appropriate by the Special Counsel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> No later than 10 days before the Special Counsel terminates any investigation of a prohibited personnel practice, the Special Counsel shall provide a written status report to the person who made the allegation of the proposed findings of fact and legal conclusions. The person may submit written comments about the report to the Special Counsel. The Special Counsel shall not be required to provide a subsequent written status report under this subparagraph after the submission of such written comments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> If the Special Counsel terminates any investigation under paragraph (1), the Special Counsel shall prepare and transmit to any person on whose allegation the investigation was initiated a written statement notifying the person of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the termination of the investigation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a summary of relevant facts ascertained by the Special Counsel, including the facts that support, and the facts that do not support, the allegations of such person;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the reasons for terminating the investigation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a response to any comments submitted under paragraph (1)(D).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A written statement under subparagraph (A) may not be admissible as evidence in any judicial or administrative proceeding, without the consent of the person who received such statement under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Except in a case in which an employee, former employee, or applicant for employment has the right to appeal directly to the Merit Systems Protection Board under any law, rule, or regulation, any such employee, former employee, or applicant shall seek corrective action from the Special Counsel before seeking corrective action from the Board. An employee, former employee, or applicant for employment may seek corrective action from the Board under section 1221, if such employee, former employee, or applicant seeks corrective action for a prohibited personnel practice described in section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D) from the Special Counsel and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Special Counsel notifies such employee, former employee, or applicant that an investigation concerning such employee, former employee, or applicant has been terminated; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> no more than 60 days have elapsed since notification was provided to such employee, former employee, or applicant for employment that such investigation was terminated; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 120 days after seeking corrective action from the Special Counsel, such employee, former employee, or applicant has not been notified by the Special Counsel that the Special Counsel shall seek corrective action on behalf of such employee, former employee, or applicant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If an employee, former employee, or applicant seeks a corrective action from the Board under section 1221, pursuant to the provisions of paragraph (3)(B), the Special Counsel may continue to seek corrective action personal to such employee, former employee, or applicant only with the consent of such employee, former employee, or applicant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In addition to any authority granted under paragraph (1), the Special Counsel may, in the absence of an allegation, conduct an investigation for the purpose of determining whether there are reasonable grounds to believe that a prohibited personnel practice (or a pattern of prohibited personnel practices) has occurred, exists, or is to be taken.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, not later than 30 days after the date on which the Special Counsel receives an allegation of a prohibited personnel practice under paragraph (1), the Special Counsel may terminate an investigation of the allegation without further inquiry if the Special Counsel determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the same allegation, based on the same set of facts and circumstances, had previously been—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<item class="indent2">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> made by the individual; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent2">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> investigated by the Special Counsel; or</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> filed by the individual with the Merit Systems Protection Board;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Special Counsel does not have jurisdiction to investigate the allegation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the individual knew or should have known of the alleged prohibited personnel practice on or before the date that is 3 years before the date on which the Special Counsel received the allegation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Special Counsel terminates an investigation under subparagraph (A), the Special Counsel shall provide a written notification to the individual who submitted the allegation of a prohibited personnel practice that states the basis of the Special Counsel for terminating the investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel may request any member of the Merit Systems Protection Board to order a stay of any personnel action for 45 days if the Special Counsel determines that there are reasonable grounds to believe that the personnel action was taken, or is to be taken, as a result of a prohibited personnel practice.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Any member of the Board requested by the Special Counsel to order a stay under clause (i) shall order such stay unless the member determines that, under the facts and circumstances involved, such a stay would not be appropriate.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Unless denied under clause (ii), any stay under this subparagraph shall be granted within 3 calendar days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) after the date of the request for the stay by the Special Counsel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Board may extend the period of any stay granted under subparagraph (A) for any period which the Board considers appropriate.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If the Board lacks the number of members appointed under section 1201 required to constitute a quorum, any remaining member of the Board may, upon request by the Special Counsel, extend the period of any stay granted under subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Board shall allow any agency which is the subject of a stay to comment to the Board on any extension of stay proposed under subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> A stay may be terminated by the Board at any time, except that a stay may not be terminated by the Board—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on its own motion or on the motion of an agency, unless notice and opportunity for oral or written comments are first provided to the Special Counsel and the individual on whose behalf the stay was ordered; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on motion of the Special Counsel, unless notice and opportunity for oral or written comments are first provided to the individual on whose behalf the stay was ordered.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> If the Board grants a stay under subparagraph (A), the head of the agency employing the employee who is the subject of the action shall give priority to a request for a transfer submitted by the employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Except as provided under clause (ii), no later than 240 days after the date of receiving an allegation of a prohibited personnel practice under paragraph (1), the Special Counsel shall make a determination whether there are reasonable grounds to believe that a prohibited personnel practice has occurred, exists, or is to be taken.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If the Special Counsel is unable to make the required determination within the 240-day period specified under clause (i) and the person submitting the allegation of a prohibited personnel practice agrees to an extension of time, the determination shall be made within such additional period of time as shall be agreed upon between the Special Counsel and the person submitting the allegation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If, in connection with any investigation, the Special Counsel determines that there are reasonable grounds to believe that a prohibited personnel practice has occurred, exists, or is to be taken which requires corrective action, the Special Counsel shall report the determination together with any findings or recommendations to the Board, the agency involved and to the Office of Personnel Management, and may report such determination, findings and recommendations to the President. The Special Counsel may include in the report recommendations for corrective action to be taken.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> If, after a reasonable period of time, the agency does not act to correct the prohibited personnel practice, the Special Counsel may petition the Board for corrective action.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> If the Special Counsel finds, in consultation with the individual subject to the prohibited personnel practice, that the agency has acted to correct the prohibited personnel practice, the Special Counsel shall file such finding with the Board, together with any written comments which the individual may provide.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A determination by the Special Counsel under this paragraph shall not be cited or referred to in any proceeding under this paragraph or any other administrative or judicial proceeding for any purpose, without the consent of the person submitting the allegation of a prohibited personnel practice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever the Special Counsel petitions the Board for corrective action, the Board shall provide an opportunity for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> oral or written comments by the Special Counsel, the agency involved, and the Office of Personnel Management; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> written comments by any individual who alleges to be the subject of the prohibited personnel practice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Board shall order such corrective action as the Board considers appropriate, if the Board determines that the Special Counsel has demonstrated that a prohibited personnel practice, other than one described in section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D), has occurred, exists, or is to be taken.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisions of clause (ii), in any case involving an alleged prohibited personnel practice as described under section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D), the Board shall order such corrective action as the Board considers appropriate if the Special Counsel has demonstrated that a disclosure or protected activity described under section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D) was a contributing factor in the personnel action which was taken or is to be taken against the individual.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Corrective action under clause (i) may not be ordered if, after a finding that a protected disclosure was a contributing factor, the agency demonstrates by clear and convincing evidence that it would have taken the same personnel action in the absence of such disclosure.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Judicial review of any final order or decision of the Board under this section may be obtained by any employee, former employee, or applicant for employment adversely affected by such order or decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A petition for review under this subsection shall be filed with such court, and within such time, as provided for under section 7703(b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If, in connection with any investigation under this subchapter, the Special Counsel determines that there is reasonable cause to believe that a criminal violation has occurred, the Special Counsel shall report the determination to the Attorney General and to the head of the agency involved, and shall submit a copy of the report to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In any case in which the Special Counsel determines that there are reasonable grounds to believe that a prohibited personnel practice has occurred, exists, or is to be taken, the Special Counsel shall proceed with any investigation or proceeding unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the alleged violation has been reported to the Attorney General; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Attorney General is pursuing an investigation, in which case the Special Counsel, after consultation with the Attorney General, has discretion as to whether to proceed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> If, in connection with any investigation under this subchapter, the Special Counsel determines that there is reasonable cause to believe that any violation of any law, rule, or regulation has occurred other than one referred to in subsection (b) or (d), the Special Counsel shall report such violation to the head of the agency involved. The Special Counsel shall require, within 30 days after the receipt of the report by the agency, a certification by the head of the agency which states—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the head of the agency has personally reviewed the report; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> what action has been or is to be taken, and when the action will be completed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> During any investigation initiated under this subchapter, no disciplinary action shall be taken against any employee for any alleged prohibited activity under investigation or for any related activity without the approval of the Special Counsel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> If the Board orders corrective action under this section, such corrective action may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the individual be placed, as nearly as possible, in the position the individual would have been in had the prohibited personnel practice not occurred; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reimbursement for attorney’s fees, back pay and related benefits, medical costs incurred, travel expenses, any other reasonable and foreseeable consequential damages, and compensatory damages (including interest, reasonable expert witness fees, and costs).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Any corrective action ordered under this section to correct a prohibited personnel practice may include fees, costs, or damages reasonably incurred due to an agency investigation of the employee, if such investigation was commenced, expanded, or extended in retaliation for the disclosure or protected activity that formed the basis of the corrective action.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel may petition the Board to order corrective action, including fees, costs, or damages reasonably incurred by an employee due to an investigation of the employee by an agency, if the investigation by an agency was commenced, expanded, or extended in retaliation for a disclosure or protected activity described in section 2302(b)(8) or subparagraph (A)(i), (B), (C), or (D) of section 2302(b)(9), without regard to whether a personnel action, as defined in section 2302(a)(2)(A), is taken.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 23</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–424</ref>, §§ 3(c), (d), 8(a), <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4362</ref>, 4364; <ref>Pub. L. 112–199, title I</ref>, §§ 101(b)(1)(A), (2)(A), 104(c)(1), 107(b), 114(a), <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1465</ref>, 1468, 1469, 1472; <ref>Pub. L. 115–42, § 1</ref>, <date date="2017-06-27">June 27, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 883</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–73, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-10-26">Oct. 26, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1236</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(c)(3)(A)</ref>, (4), (f), (j), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1619</ref>, 1622, 1625.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1215.</num>
<heading> Disciplinary action</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (b), if the Special Counsel determines that disciplinary action should be taken against any employee for having—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> committed a prohibited personnel practice,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> violated the provisions of any law, rule, or regulation, or engaged in any other conduct within the jurisdiction of the Special Counsel as described in section 1216, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> knowingly and willfully refused or failed to comply with an order of the Merit Systems Protection Board,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Special Counsel shall prepare a written complaint against the employee containing the Special Counsel’s determination, together with a statement of supporting facts, and present the complaint and statement to the employee and the Board, in accordance with this subsection.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Any employee against whom a complaint has been presented to the Merit Systems Protection Board under paragraph (1) is entitled to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a reasonable time to answer orally and in writing, and to furnish affidavits and other documentary evidence in support of the answer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be represented by an attorney or other representative;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a hearing before the Board or an administrative law judge appointed under section 3105 and designated by the Board;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> have a transcript kept of any hearing under subparagraph (C); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a written decision and reasons therefor at the earliest practicable date, including a copy of any final order imposing disciplinary action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A final order of the Board may impose—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> disciplinary action consisting of removal, reduction in grade, debarment from Federal employment for a period not to exceed 5 years, suspension, or reprimand;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an assessment of a civil penalty not to exceed $1,000; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any combination of disciplinary actions described under clause (i) and an assessment described under clause (ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In any case brought under paragraph (1) in which the Board finds that an employee has committed a prohibited personnel practice under section 2302(b)(8), or 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D), the Board may impose disciplinary action if the Board finds that the activity protected under section 2302(b)(8), or 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D) was a significant motivating factor, even if other factors also motivated the decision, for the employee’s decision to take, fail to take, or threaten to take or fail to take a personnel action, unless that employee demonstrates, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the employee would have taken, failed to take, or threatened to take or fail to take the same personnel action, in the absence of such protected activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> There may be no administrative appeal from an order of the Board. An employee subject to a final order imposing disciplinary action under this subsection may obtain judicial review of the order by filing a petition therefor with such court, and within such time, as provided for under section 7703(b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In the case of any State or local officer or employee under chapter 15, the Board shall consider the case in accordance with the provisions of such chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In the case of an employee in a confidential, policy-making, policy-determining, or policy-advocating position appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate (other than an individual in the Foreign Service of the United States), the complaint and statement referred to in subsection (a)(1), together with any response of the employee, shall be presented to the President for appropriate action in lieu of being presented under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of members of the uniformed services and individuals employed by any person under contract with an agency to provide goods or services, the Special Counsel may transmit recommendations for disciplinary or other appropriate action (including the evidence on which such recommendations are based) to the head of the agency concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In any case in which the Special Counsel transmits recommendations to an agency head under paragraph (1), the agency head shall, within 60 days after receiving such recommendations, transmit a report to the Special Counsel on each recommendation and the action taken, or proposed to be taken, with respect to each such recommendation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 27</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–199, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1468</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1216.</num>
<heading> Other matters within the jurisdiction of the Office of Special Counsel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to the authority otherwise provided in this chapter, the Special Counsel shall, except as provided in subsection (b), conduct an investigation of any allegation concerning—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> political activity prohibited under subchapter III of chapter 73, relating to political activities by Federal employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> political activity prohibited under chapter 15, relating to political activities by certain State and local officers and employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> arbitrary or capricious withholding of information prohibited under section 552, except that the Special Counsel shall make no investigation of any withholding of foreign intelligence or counterintelligence information the disclosure of which is specifically prohibited by law or by Executive order;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> activities prohibited by any civil service law, rule, or regulation, including any activity relating to political intrusion in personnel decisionmaking; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> involvement by any employee in any prohibited discrimination found by any court or appropriate administrative authority to have occurred in the course of any personnel action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel shall make no investigation of any allegation of any prohibited activity referred to in subsection (a)(5), if the Special Counsel determines that the allegation may be resolved more appropriately under an administrative appeals procedure.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If the Special Counsel receives an allegation concerning any matter under paragraph (1), (3), (4), or (5) of subsection (a), the Special Counsel may investigate and seek corrective action under section 1214 and disciplinary action under section 1215 in the same way as if a prohibited personnel practice were involved.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 28</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–94, § 3</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1004</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1217.</num>
<heading> Transmittal of information to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Special Counsel or any employee of the Special Counsel designated by the Special Counsel, shall transmit to the Congress on the request of any committee or subcommittee thereof, by report, testimony, or otherwise, information and the Special Counsel’s views on functions, responsibilities, or other matters relating to the Office. Such information shall be transmitted concurrently to the President and any other appropriate agency in the executive branch.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Additional Report Required.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an allegation submitted to the Special Counsel is resolved by an agreement between an agency and an individual, the Special Counsel shall submit to Congress and each congressional committee with jurisdiction over the agency a report regarding the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any report required under paragraph (1) shall identify, with respect to an agreement described in that paragraph—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the agency that entered into the agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the position and employment location of the employee who submitted the allegation that formed the basis of the agreement, provided the information is not so specific as to be reasonably likely to identify the employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the position and employment location of any employee alleged by an employee described in subparagraph (B) to have committed a prohibited personnel practice, as defined in section 2302(a)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a description of the allegation described in subparagraph (B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> whether the agency that entered into the agreement has agreed to pursue any disciplinary action as a result of the allegation described in subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 28</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(h)(3)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1625</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1218.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Special Counsel shall submit to Congress, on an annual basis, a report regarding the activities of the Special Counsel, which shall include, for the year preceding the submission of the report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number, types, and disposition of allegations of prohibited personnel practices filed with the Special Counsel and the costs of resolving such allegations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of investigations conducted by the Special Counsel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the number of stays and disciplinary actions negotiated with agencies by the Special Counsel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the number of subpoenas issued by the Special Counsel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the number of instances in which the Special Counsel reopened an investigation after the Special Counsel had made an initial determination with respect to the investigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the actions that resulted from reopening investigations, as described in paragraph (5);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the number of instances in which the Special Counsel did not make a determination before the end of the 240-day period described in section 1214(b)(2)(A)(i) regarding whether there were reasonable grounds to believe that a prohibited personnel practice had occurred, existed, or was to be taken;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a description of the recommendations and reports made by the Special Counsel to other agencies under this subchapter and the actions taken by the agencies as a result of the recommendations or reports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> the number of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> actions initiated before the Merit Systems Protection Board, including the number of corrective action petitions and disciplinary action complaints initiated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> stays and extensions of stays obtained from the Merit Systems Protection Board;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> the number of prohibited personnel practice complaints that resulted in a favorable action for the complainant, other than a stay or an extension of a stay, organized by actions in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> complaints dealing with reprisals against whistleblowers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all other complaints;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> the number of prohibited personnel practice complaints that were resolved by an agreement between an agency and an individual, organized by agency and agency components in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> complaints dealing with reprisals against whistleblowers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all other complaints;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the number of corrective actions that the Special Counsel required an agency to take after a finding by the Special Counsel of a prohibited personnel practice, as defined in section 2302(a)(1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> the results for the Office of Special Counsel of any employee viewpoint survey conducted by the Office of Personnel Management or any other agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 29</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–424, § 3(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4363</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1623</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1219.</num>
<heading> Public information</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Special Counsel shall maintain and make available to the public—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a list of any noncriminal matters referred to the head of an agency under section 1213(c), together with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a copy of the information transmitted to the head of the agency under section 1213(c)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any report from the agency under section 1213(c)(1)(B) relating to the matter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if appropriate, not otherwise prohibited by law, and consented to by the complainant, any comments from the complainant under section 1213(e)(1) relating to the matter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the comments or recommendations of the Special Counsel under paragraph (3) or (4) of section 1213(e);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a list of matters referred to heads of agencies under section 1215(c)(2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a list of matters referred to heads of agencies under subsection (e) of section 1214, together with certifications from heads of agencies under such subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> reports from heads of agencies under section 1213(g)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Special Counsel shall take steps to ensure that any list or report made available to the public under this section does not contain any information the disclosure of which is prohibited by law or by Executive order requiring that information be kept secret in the interest of national defense or the conduct of foreign affairs.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 29</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1624</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>INDIVIDUAL RIGHT OF ACTION IN CERTAIN REPRISAL CASES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1221.</num>
<heading> Individual right of action in certain reprisal cases</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section and subsection 1214(a)(3), an employee, former employee, or applicant for employment may, with respect to any personnel action taken, or proposed to be taken, against such employee, former employee, or applicant for employment, as a result of a prohibited personnel practice described in section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D), seek corrective action from the Merit Systems Protection Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section may not be construed to prohibit any employee, former employee, or applicant for employment from seeking corrective action from the Merit Systems Protection Board before seeking corrective action from the Special Counsel, if such employee, former employee, or applicant for employment has the right to appeal directly to the Board under any law, rule, or regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any employee, former employee, or applicant for employment seeking corrective action under subsection (a) may request that the Board order a stay of the personnel action involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any stay requested under paragraph (1) shall be granted within 10 calendar days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) after the date the request is made, if the Board determines that such a stay would be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Board shall allow any agency which would be subject to a stay under this subsection to comment to the Board on such stay request.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (C), a stay granted under this subsection shall remain in effect for such period as the Board determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Board may modify or dissolve a stay under this subsection at any time, if the Board determines that such a modification or dissolution is appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> At the request of an employee, former employee, or applicant for employment seeking corrective action under subsection (a), the Board shall issue a subpoena for the attendance and testimony of any person or the production of documentary or other evidence from any person if the Board finds that the testimony or production requested is not unduly burdensome and appears reasonably calculated to lead to the discovery of admissible evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A subpoena under this subsection may be issued, and shall be enforced, in the same manner as applies in the case of subpoenas under section 1204.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2), in any case involving an alleged prohibited personnel practice as described under section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D), the Board shall order such corrective action as the Board considers appropriate if the employee, former employee, or applicant for employment has demonstrated that a disclosure or protected activity described under section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D) was a contributing factor in the personnel action which was taken or is to be taken against such employee, former employee, or applicant. The employee may demonstrate that the disclosure or protected activity was a contributing factor in the personnel action through circumstantial evidence, such as evidence that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the official taking the personnel action knew of the disclosure or protected activity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the personnel action occurred within a period of time such that a reasonable person could conclude that the disclosure or protected activity was a contributing factor in the personnel action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Corrective action under paragraph (1) may not be ordered if, after a finding that a protected disclosure was a contributing factor, the agency demonstrates by clear and convincing evidence that it would have taken the same personnel action in the absence of such disclosure.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A final order or decision shall be rendered by the Board as soon as practicable after the commencement of any proceeding under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A decision to terminate an investigation under subchapter II may not be considered in any action or other proceeding under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If, based on evidence presented to it under this section, the Merit Systems Protection Board determines that there is reason to believe that a current employee may have committed a prohibited personnel practice, the Board shall refer the matter to the Special Counsel to investigate and take appropriate action under section 1215.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> If the Board orders corrective action under this section, such corrective action may include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that the individual be placed, as nearly as possible, in the position the individual would have been in had the prohibited personnel practice not occurred; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> back pay and related benefits, medical costs incurred, travel expenses, any other reasonable and foreseeable consequential damages, and compensatory damages (including interest, reasonable expert witness fees, and costs).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Corrective action shall include attorney’s fees and costs as provided for under paragraphs (2) and (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If an employee, former employee, or applicant for employment is the prevailing party before the Merit Systems Protection Board, and the decision is based on a finding of a prohibited personnel practice, the agency involved shall be liable to the employee, former employee, or applicant for reasonable attorney’s fees and any other reasonable costs incurred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If an employee, former emloyee,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002035">1</ref> or applicant for employment is the prevailing party in an appeal from the Merit Systems Protection Board, the agency involved shall be liable to the employee, former employee, or applicant for reasonable attorney’s fees and any other reasonable costs incurred, regardless of the basis of the decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any corrective action ordered under this section to correct a prohibited personnel practice may include fees, costs, or damages reasonably incurred due to an agency investigation of the employee, if such investigation was commenced, expanded, or extended in retaliation for the disclosure or protected activity that formed the basis of the corrective action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee, former employee, or applicant for employment adversely affected or aggrieved by a final order or decision of the Board under this section may obtain judicial review of the order or decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A petition for review under this subsection shall be filed with such court, and within such time, as provided for under section 7703(b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Subsections (a) through (h) shall apply in any proceeding brought under section 7513(d) if, or to the extent that, a prohibited personnel practice as defined in section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D) is alleged.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> In determining the appealability of any case involving an allegation made by an individual under the provisions of this chapter, neither the status of an individual under any retirement system established under a Federal statute nor any election made by such individual under any such system may be taken into account.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> If the Board grants a stay under subsection (c) and the employee who is the subject of the action is in probationary status, the head of the agency employing the employee shall give priority to a request for a transfer submitted by the employee.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 29</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–424</ref>, §§ 4, 8(b), <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4363</ref>, 4365; <ref>Pub. L. 112–199, title I</ref>, §§ 101(b)(1)(A), (2)(A), 104(c)(2), 107(b), 114(b), <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1465</ref>, 1468, 1469, 1472; <ref>Pub. L. 115–73, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-10-26">Oct. 26, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1236</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(c)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1619</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1222.</num>
<heading> Availability of other remedies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in section 1221(i), nothing in this chapter or chapter 23 shall be construed to limit any right or remedy available under a provision of statute which is outside of both this chapter and chapter 23.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 31</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>