<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 23—</num>
<heading>MERIT SYSTEM PRINCIPLES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2301.</num>
<heading> Merit system principles</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> This section shall apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an Executive agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Government Publishing Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Federal personnel management should be implemented consistent with the following merit system principles:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Recruitment should be from qualified individuals from appropriate sources in an endeavor to achieve a work force from all segments of society, and selection and advancement should be determined solely on the basis of relative ability, knowledge, and skills, after fair and open competition which assures that all receive equal opportunity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> All employees and applicants for employment should receive fair and equitable treatment in all aspects of personnel management without regard to political affiliation, race, color, religion, national origin, sex, marital status, age, or handicapping condition, and with proper regard for their privacy and constitutional rights.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Equal pay should be provided for work of equal value, with appropriate consideration of both national and local rates paid by employers in the private sector, and appropriate incentives and recognition should be provided for excellence in performance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> All employees should maintain high standards of integrity, conduct, and concern for the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Federal work force should be used efficiently and effectively.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Employees should be retained on the basis of the adequacy of their performance, inadequate performance should be corrected, and employees should be separated who cannot or will not improve their performance to meet required standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Employees should be provided effective education and training in cases in which such education and training would result in better organizational and individual performance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> Employees should be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> protected against arbitrary action, personal favoritism, or coercion for partisan political purposes, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prohibited from using their official authority or influence for the purpose of interfering with or affecting the result of an election or a nomination for election.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> Employees should be protected against reprisal for the lawful disclosure of information which the employees reasonably believe evidences—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a violation of any law, rule, or regulation, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> In administering the provisions of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> with respect to any agency (as defined in <ref>section 2302(a)(2)(C) of this title</ref>), the President shall, pursuant to the authority otherwise available under this title, take any action, including the issuance of rules, regulations, or directives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with respect to any entity in the executive branch which is not such an agency or part of such an agency, the head of such entity shall, pursuant to authority otherwise available, take any action, including the issuance of rules, regulations, or directives;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">which is consistent with the provisions of this title and which the President or the head, as the case may be, determines is necessary to ensure that personnel management is based on and embodies the merit system principles.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1113</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–474, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2302.</num>
<heading> Prohibited personnel practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this title, “prohibited personnel practice” means any action described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> “personnel action” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an appointment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a promotion;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an action under chapter 75 of this title or other disciplinary or corrective action;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a detail, transfer, or reassignment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a reinstatement;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a restoration;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> a reemployment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> a performance evaluation under chapter 43 of this title or under title 38;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> a decision concerning pay, benefits, or awards, or concerning education or training if the education or training may reasonably be expected to lead to an appointment, promotion, performance evaluation, or other action described in this subparagraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> a decision to order psychiatric testing or examination;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> the implementation or enforcement of any nondisclosure policy, form, or agreement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(xii)</num>
<content> any other significant change in duties, responsibilities, or working conditions;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">with respect to an employee in, or applicant for, a covered position in an agency, and in the case of an alleged prohibited personnel practice described in subsection (b)(8), an employee or applicant for employment in a Government corporation as defined in <ref>section 9101 of title 31</ref>;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> “covered position” means, with respect to any personnel action, any position in the competitive service, a career appointee position in the Senior Executive Service, or a position in the excepted service, but does not include any position which is, prior to the personnel action—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> excepted from the competitive service because of its confidential, policy-determining, policy-making, or policy-advocating character; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> excluded from the coverage of this section by the President based on a determination by the President that it is necessary and warranted by conditions of good administration;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> “agency” means an Executive agency and the Government Publishing Office, but does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a Government corporation, except in the case of an alleged prohibited personnel practice described under subsection (b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Central Intelligence Agency, the Defense Intelligence Agency, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, the National Security Agency, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, and the National Reconnaissance Office; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> as determined by the President, any executive agency or unit thereof the principal function of which is the conduct of foreign intelligence or counterintelligence activities, provided that the determination be made prior to a personnel action; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Government Accountability Office; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> “disclosure” means a formal or informal communication or transmission, but does not include a communication concerning policy decisions that lawfully exercise discretionary authority unless the employee or applicant providing the disclosure reasonably believes that the disclosure evidences—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any violation of any law, rule, or regulation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Any employee who has authority to take, direct others to take, recommend, or approve any personnel action, shall not, with respect to such authority—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> discriminate for or against any employee or applicant for employment—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> on the basis of race, color, religion, sex, or national origin, as prohibited under section 717 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e–16</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on the basis of age, as prohibited under sections 12 and 15 of the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 631</ref>, 633a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> on the basis of sex, as prohibited under section 6(d) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 206(d)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> on the basis of handicapping condition, as prohibited under section 501 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 791</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> on the basis of marital status or political affiliation, as prohibited under any law, rule, or regulation;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> solicit or consider any recommendation or statement, oral or written, with respect to any individual who requests or is under consideration for any personnel action unless such recommendation or statement is based on the personal knowledge or records of the person furnishing it and consists of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the work performance, ability, aptitude, or general qualifications of such individual; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the character, loyalty, or suitability of such individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> coerce the political activity of any person (including the providing of any political contribution or service), or take any action against any employee or applicant for employment as a reprisal for the refusal of any person to engage in such political activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> deceive or willfully obstruct any person with respect to such person’s right to compete for employment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> influence any person to withdraw from competition for any position for the purpose of improving or injuring the prospects of any other person for employment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> grant any preference or advantage not authorized by law, rule, or regulation to any employee or applicant for employment (including defining the scope or manner of competition or the requirements for any position) for the purpose of improving or injuring the prospects of any particular person for employment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> appoint, employ, promote, advance, or advocate for appointment, employment, promotion, or advancement, in or to a civilian position any individual who is a relative (as defined in <ref>section 3110(a)(3) of this title</ref>) of such employee if such position is in the agency in which such employee is serving as a public official (as defined in <ref>section 3110(a)(2) of this title</ref>) or over which such employee exercises jurisdiction or control as such an official;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> take or fail to take, or threaten to take or fail to take, a personnel action with respect to any employee or applicant for employment because of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> any disclosure of information by an employee or applicant which the employee or applicant reasonably believes evidences—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any violation of any law, rule, or regulation, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">if such disclosure is not specifically prohibited by law and if such information is not specifically required by Executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or the conduct of foreign affairs;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> any disclosure to the Special Counsel, or to the Inspector General of an agency or another employee designated by the head of the agency to receive such disclosures, of information which the employee or applicant reasonably believes evidences—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any violation (other than a violation of this section) of any law, rule, or regulation, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> any disclosure to Congress (including any committee of Congress) by any employee of an agency or applicant for employment at an agency of information described in subparagraph (B) that is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not classified; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> if classified—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> has been classified by the head of an agency that is not an element of the intelligence community (as defined by section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>)); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> does not reveal intelligence sources and methods.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002044">1</ref></content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> take or fail to take, or threaten to take or fail to take, any personnel action against any employee or applicant for employment because of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the exercise of any appeal, complaint, or grievance right granted by any law, rule, or regulation—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> with regard to remedying a violation of paragraph (8); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> other than with regard to remedying a violation of paragraph (8);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> testifying for or otherwise lawfully assisting any individual in the exercise of any right referred to in subparagraph (A)(i) or (ii);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> cooperating with or disclosing information to the Inspector General (or any other component responsible for internal investigation or review) of an agency, or the Special Counsel, in accordance with applicable provisions of law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> refusing to obey an order that would require the individual to violate a law, rule, or regulation;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> discriminate for or against any employee or applicant for employment on the basis of conduct which does not adversely affect the performance of the employee or applicant or the performance of others; except that nothing in this paragraph shall prohibit an agency from taking into account in determining suitability or fitness any conviction of the employee or applicant for any crime under the laws of any State, of the District of Columbia, or of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> knowingly take, recommend, or approve any personnel action if the taking of such action would violate a veterans’ preference requirement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> knowingly fail to take, recommend, or approve any personnel action if the failure to take such action would violate a veterans’ preference requirement;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> take or fail to take any other personnel action if the taking of or failure to take such action violates any law, rule, or regulation implementing, or directly concerning, the merit system principles contained in <ref>section 2301 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<chapeau> implement or enforce any nondisclosure policy, form, or agreement, if such policy, form, or agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> does not contain the following statement: “These provisions are consistent with and do not supersede, conflict with, or otherwise alter the employee obligations, rights, or liabilities created by existing statute or Executive order relating to (1) classified information, (2) communications to Congress, (3) the reporting to an Inspector General or the Office of Special Counsel of a violation of any law, rule, or regulation, or mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety, or (4) any other whistleblower protection. The definitions, requirements, obligations, rights, sanctions, and liabilities created by controlling Executive orders and statutory provisions are incorporated into this agreement and are controlling.”; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prohibits or restricts an employee or applicant for employment from disclosing to Congress, the Special Counsel, the Inspector General of an agency, or any other agency component responsible for internal investigation or review any information that relates to any violation of any law, rule, or regulation, or mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety, or any other whistleblower protection; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> access the medical record of another employee or an applicant for employment as a part of, or otherwise in furtherance of, any conduct described in paragraphs (1) through (13).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">This subsection shall not be construed to authorize the withholding of information from Congress or the taking of any personnel action against an employee who discloses information to Congress. For purposes of paragraph (8), (i) any presumption relating to the performance of a duty by an employee whose conduct is the subject of a disclosure as defined under subsection (a)(2)(D) may be rebutted by substantial evidence, and (ii) a determination as to whether an employee or applicant reasonably believes that such employee or applicant has disclosed information that evidences any violation of law, rule, regulation, gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety shall be made by determining whether a disinterested observer with knowledge of the essential facts known to and readily ascertainable by the employee or applicant could reasonably conclude that the actions of the Government evidence such violations, mismanagement, waste, abuse, or danger.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the term “new employee” means an individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> appointed to a position as an employee on or after the date of enactment of this subsection; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> who has not previously served as an employee; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “whistleblower protections” means the protections against and remedies for a prohibited personnel practice described in paragraph (8) or subparagraph (A)(i), (B), (C), or (D) of paragraph (9) of subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The head of each agency shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> preventing prohibited personnel practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> complying with and enforcing applicable civil service laws, rules, and regulations and other aspects of personnel management; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> ensuring, in consultation with the Special Counsel and the Inspector General of the agency, that employees of the agency are informed of the rights and remedies available to the employees under this chapter and chapter 12, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> information with respect to whistleblower protections available to new employees during a probationary period;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the role of the Office of Special Counsel and the Merit Systems Protection Board with respect to whistleblower protections; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> the means by which, with respect to information that is otherwise required by law or Executive order to be kept classified in the interest of national defense or the conduct of foreign affairs, an employee may make a lawful disclosure of the information to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Special Counsel;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Inspector General of an agency;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> Congress (including any committee of Congress with respect to information that is not classified or, if classified, has been classified by the head of an agency that is not an element of the intelligence community and does not reveal intelligence sources and methods); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> another employee of the agency who is designated to receive such a disclosure.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The head of each agency shall ensure that the information described in paragraph (2) is provided to each new employee of the agency not later than 180 days after the date on which the new employee is appointed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The head of each agency shall make available information regarding whistleblower protections applicable to employees of the agency on the public website of the agency and on any online portal that is made available only to employees of the agency, if such portal exists.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Any employee to whom the head of an agency delegates authority for any aspect of personnel management shall, within the limits of the scope of the delegation, be responsible for the activities described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> This section shall not be construed to extinguish or lessen any effort to achieve equal employment opportunity through affirmative action or any right or remedy available to any employee or applicant for employment in the civil service under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> section 717 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 2000e–16</ref>), prohibiting discrimination on the basis of race, color, religion, sex, or national origin;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> sections 12 and 15 of the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 631</ref>, 633a), prohibiting discrimination on the basis of age;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> under section 6(d) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 206(d)</ref>), prohibiting discrimination on the basis of sex;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> section 501 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 791</ref>), prohibiting discrimination on the basis of handicapping condition; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the provisions of any law, rule, or regulation prohibiting discrimination on the basis of marital status or political affiliation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section, the term “veterans’ preference requirement” means any of the following provisions of law:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Sections 2108, 3305(b), 3309, 3310, 3311, 3312, 3313, 3314, 3315, 3316, 3317(b), 3318, 3320, 3351, 3352, 3363, 3501, 3502(b), 3504, and 4303(e) and (with respect to a preference eligible referred to in section 7511(a)(1)(B)) subchapter II of chapter 75 and section 7701.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Sections 943(c)(2) and 1784(c) of title 10.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Section 1308(b) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Section 301(c) of the Foreign Service Act of 1980.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Sections 106(f),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002045">1</ref> 7281(e), and 7802(5) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002045">1</ref> of title 38.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content><ref>Section 1005(a) of title 39</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Any other provision of law that the Director of the Office of Personnel Management designates in regulations as being a veterans’ preference requirement for the purposes of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Any regulation prescribed under subsection (b) or (c) of section 1302 and any other regulation that implements a provision of law referred to in any of the preceding subparagraphs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, no authority to order corrective action shall be available in connection with a prohibited personnel practice described in subsection (b)(11). Nothing in this paragraph shall be considered to affect any authority under section 1215 (relating to disciplinary action).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A disclosure shall not be excluded from subsection (b)(8) because—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the disclosure was made to a supervisor or to a person who participated in an activity that the employee or applicant reasonably believed to be covered by subsection (b)(8)(A)(i) and (ii);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the disclosure revealed information that had been previously disclosed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> of the employee’s or applicant’s motive for making the disclosure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the disclosure was not made in writing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the disclosure was made while the employee was off duty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the disclosure was made before the date on which the individual was appointed or applied for appointment to a position; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> of the amount of time which has passed since the occurrence of the events described in the disclosure.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a disclosure is made during the normal course of duties of an employee, the principal job function of whom is to regularly investigate and disclose wrongdoing (referred to in this paragraph as the “disclosing employee”), the disclosure shall not be excluded from subsection (b)(8) if the disclosing employee demonstrates that an employee who has the authority to take, direct other individuals to take, recommend, or approve any personnel action with respect to the disclosing employee took, failed to take, or threatened to take or fail to take a personnel action with respect to the disclosing employee in reprisal for the disclosure made by the disclosing employee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1114</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 4</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–474, § 5(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(5)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1346</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–94, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1007</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title V, § 501(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–424, § 5</ref>, <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4363</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–197, title III, § 315(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2416</ref>, <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1122(a)(1)</ref>, title XVI, § 1615(b), <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2687</ref>, 2741; <ref>Pub. L. 105–339, § 6(a)</ref>, (b), (c)(2), <date date="1998-10-31">Oct. 31, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3187</ref>, 3188; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 931(a)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4575</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–199, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a), (b)(1)(B), (2)(B), (C), 102–104(b)(1), 105, 112, <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1465–1468</ref>, 1472; <ref>Pub. L. 112–277, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2478</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. J, title II, § 238</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–40, § 2</ref>, <date date="2017-06-14">June 14, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 861</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–73, title I</ref>, §§ 103, 107(a)(1), <date date="2017-10-26">Oct. 26, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1236</ref>, 1238; <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(b)(1)(B)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1616</ref>, 1618; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LVII, § 5721</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1138</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3905</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2303.</num>
<heading> Prohibited personnel practices in the Federal Bureau of Investigation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Any employee of the Federal Bureau of Investigation who has authority to take, direct others to take, recommend, or approve any personnel action, shall not, with respect to such authority, take or fail to take a personnel action with respect to an employee in, or applicant for, a position in the Bureau as a reprisal for a disclosure of information—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> made—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an employee, to a supervisor in the direct chain of command of the employee, up to and including the head of the employing agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the Inspector General;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to the Office of Professional Responsibility of the Department of Justice;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to the Office of Professional Responsibility of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to the Inspection Division of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> as described in section 7211;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> to the Office of Special Counsel; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> to an employee designated by any officer, employee, office, or division described in subparagraphs (A) through (G) for the purpose of receiving such disclosures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> which the employee or applicant reasonably believes evidences—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any violation of any law, rule, or regulation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For the purpose of this subsection, “personnel action” means any action described in clauses (i) through (x) of <ref>section 2302(a)(2)(A) of this title</ref> with respect to an employee in, or applicant for, a position in the Bureau (other than a position of a confidential, policy-determining, policymaking, or policy-advocating character).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall prescribe regulations to ensure that such a personnel action shall not be taken against an employee of the Bureau as a reprisal for any disclosure of information described in subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The President shall provide for the enforcement of this section in a manner consistent with applicable provisions of sections 1214 and 1221 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An employee of the Federal Bureau of Investigation who makes an allegation of a reprisal under regulations promulgated under this section may appeal a final determination or corrective action order by the Bureau under those regulations to the Merit Systems Protection Board pursuant to section 1221.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If no final determination or corrective action order has been made or issued for an allegation described in paragraph (1) before the expiration of the 180-day period beginning on the date on which the allegation is received by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the employee described in that paragraph may seek corrective action directly from the Merit Systems Protection Board pursuant to section 1221.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1117</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–12, § 9(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–302, § 2</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LIII, § 5304(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3250</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2304.</num>
<heading> Prohibited personnel practices affecting the Transportation Security Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any individual holding or applying for a position within the Transportation Security Administration shall be covered by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the provisions of section 2302(b)(1), (8), and (9);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any provision of law implementing section 2302(b)(1), (8), or (9) by providing any right or remedy available to an employee or applicant for employment in the civil service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any rule or regulation prescribed under any provision of law referred to in paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any rights, apart from those described in subsection (a), to which an individual described in subsection (a) might otherwise be entitled under law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–199, title I, § 109(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1470</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2305.</num>
<heading> Responsibility of the Government Accountability Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If requested by either House of the Congress (or any committee thereof), or if considered necessary by the Comptroller General, the Government Accountability Office shall conduct audits and reviews to assure compliance with the laws, rules, and regulations governing employment in the executive branch and in the competitive service and to assess the effectiveness and soundness of Federal personnel management.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1118</ref>, § 2304; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(6)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1346</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title II, § 2181(e)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; renumbered § 2305, <ref>Pub. L. 112–199, title I, § 109(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1470</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2306.</num>
<heading> Coordination with certain other provisions of law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of this chapter, or action taken under this chapter, shall be construed to impair the authorities and responsibilities set forth in section 102 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>61 Stat. 495</ref>; <ref>50 U.S.C. 403</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002046">1</ref> the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 (<ref>63 Stat. 208</ref>; <ref>50 U.S.C. 403a</ref> and following),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002046">1</ref> the Act entitled “An Act to provide certain administrative authorities for the National Security Agency, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1959-05-29">May 29, 1959</date> (<ref>73 Stat. 63</ref>; <ref>50 U.S.C. 402</ref> note),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002046">1</ref> and the Act entitled “An Act to amend the Internal Security Act of 1950”, approved <date date="1964-03-26">March 26, 1964</date> (<ref>78 Stat. 168</ref>; <ref>50 U.S.C. 831–835</ref>).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1118</ref>, § 2305; renumbered § 2306, <ref>Pub. L. 112–199, title I, § 109(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1470</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2307.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1616</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>