<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 79—</num>
<heading>SERVICES TO EMPLOYEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7901.</num>
<heading> Health service programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The head of each agency of the Government of the United States may establish, within the limits of appropriations available, a health service program to promote and maintain the physical and mental fitness of employees under his jurisdiction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A health service program may be established by contract or otherwise, but only—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> after consultation with the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare and consideration of its recommendations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in localities where there are a sufficient number of employees to warrant providing the service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A health service program is limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> treatment of on-the-job illness and dental conditions requiring emergency attention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> preemployment and other examinations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> referral of employees to private physicians and dentists; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> preventive programs relating to health.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, on request, shall review a health service program conducted under this section and shall submit comment and recommendations to the head of the agency concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> When this section authorizes the use of the professional services of physicians, that authorization includes the use of the professional services of surgeons and osteopathic practitioners within the scope of their practice as defined by State law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The health programs conducted by the Tennessee Valley Authority are not affected by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 530</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(47)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXV, § 3548(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7902.</num>
<heading> Safety programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “employee” means an employee as defined by <ref>section 8101 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “agency” means an agency in any branch of the Government of the United States (not including the United States Postal Service), including an instrumentality wholly owned by the United States, and the government of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Labor shall carry out a safety program under <ref>section 941(b)(1) of title 33</ref> covering the employment of each employee of an agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The President may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish by Executive order a safety council composed of representatives of the agencies and of labor organizations representing employees to serve as an advisory body to the Secretary in furtherance of the safety program carried out by the Secretary under subsection (b) of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> undertake such other measures as he considers proper to prevent injuries and accidents to employees of the agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The head of each agency shall develop and support organized safety promotion to reduce accidents and injuries among employees of his agency, encourage safe practices, and eliminate work hazards and health risks.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> Each agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> keep a record of injuries and accidents to its employees whether or not they result in loss of time or in the payment or furnishing of benefits; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make such statistical or other reports on such forms as the Secretary may prescribe by regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 530</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–596, § 19(c)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1610</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–241, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-09-28">Sept. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1572</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7903.</num>
<heading> Protective clothing and equipment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Appropriations available for the procurement of supplies and material or equipment are available for the purchase and maintenance of special clothing and equipment for the protection of personnel in the performance of their assigned tasks. For the purpose of this section, “appropriations” includes funds made available by statute under <ref>section 9104 of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 531</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1063</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7904.</num>
<heading> Employee assistance programs relating to drug abuse and alcohol abuse</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The head of each Executive agency shall, in a manner consistent with guidelines prescribed under subsection (b) of this section and applicable provisions of law, establish appropriate prevention, treatment, and rehabilitation programs and services for drug abuse and alcohol abuse for employees in or under such agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management shall, after such consultations as the Office considers appropriate, prescribe guidelines for programs and services under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services, on request of the head of an Executive agency, shall review any program or service provided under this section and shall submit comments and recommendations to the head of the agency concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title VI, § 6004(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7905.</num>
<heading> Programs to encourage commuting by means other than single-occupancy motor vehicles</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “employee” means an employee as defined by section 2105, a member of a uniformed service, and a student who provides voluntary services under section 3111;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an Executive agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an entity of the legislative branch; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the judicial branch;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “entity of the legislative branch” means the House of Representatives, the Senate, the Office of the Architect of the Capitol (including the Botanic Garden), the Capitol Police, the Congressional Budget Office, the Copyright Royalty Tribunal, the Government Publishing Office, the Library of Congress, and the Office of Technology Assessment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “transit pass” means a transit pass as defined by section 132(f)(5) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The head of each agency may establish a program to encourage employees of such agency to use means other than single-occupancy motor vehicles to commute to or from work.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A program established under this section may involve such options as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> transit passes (including cash reimbursements therefor, but only if a voucher or similar item which may be exchanged only for a transit pass is not readily available for direct distribution by the agency);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> furnishing space, facilities, or services to bicyclists; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any non-monetary incentive which the agency head may otherwise offer under any other provision of law or other authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The functions of an agency head under this section shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> with respect to the judicial branch, be carried out by the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with respect to the House of Representatives, be carried out by the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> with respect to the Senate, be carried out by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The President shall designate 1 or more agencies which shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prescribe guidelines for programs under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on request, furnish information or technical advice on the design or operation of any program under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> submit to the President and the Congress, before <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, and at least every 2 years thereafter, a written report on the operation of this section, including, with respect to the period covered by the report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of agencies offering programs under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a brief description of each of the various programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the extent of employee participation in, and the costs to the Government associated with, each of the various programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an assessment of any environmental or other benefits realized as a result of programs established under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any other matter which may be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–172, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-02">Dec. 2, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1995</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XIII, § 1314(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2296</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7906.</num>
<heading> Services of post-combat case coordinators</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the terms “employee”, “agency”,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002142">1</ref> “injury”, “war-risk hazard”, and “hostile force or individual” have the meanings given those terms in section 8101; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “qualified employee” means an employee as described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of each agency shall, in a manner consistent with the guidelines prescribed under subsection (c), provide for the assignment of a post-combat case coordinator in the case of any employee of such agency who suffers an injury or disability incurred, or an illness contracted, while in the performance of such employee’s duties, as a result of a war-risk hazard or during or as a result of capture, detention, or other restraint by a hostile force or individual.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guidelines</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Office of Personnel Management shall, after such consultation as the Office considers appropriate, prescribe guidelines for the operation of this section. Under the guidelines, the responsibilities of a post-combat case coordinator shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acting as the main point of contact for qualified employees seeking administrative guidance or assistance relating to benefits under chapter 81 or 89;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assisting qualified employees in the collection of documentation or other supporting evidence for the expeditious processing of claims under chapter 81 or 89;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assisting qualified employees in connection with the receipt of prescribed medical care and the coordination of benefits under chapter 81 or 89;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> resolving problems relating to the receipt of benefits under chapter 81 or 89; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> ensuring that qualified employees are properly screened and receive appropriate treatment—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for post-traumatic stress disorder or other similar disorder stemming from combat trauma; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for suicidal or homicidal thoughts or behaviors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The services of a post-combat case coordinator shall remain available to a qualified employee until—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such employee accepts or declines a reasonable offer of employment in a position in the employee’s agency for which the employee is qualified, which is not lower than 2 grades (or pay levels) below the employee’s grade (or pay level) before the occurrence or onset of the injury, disability, or illness (as referred to in subsection (a)), and which is within the employee’s commuting area; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such employee gives written notice, in such manner as the employing agency prescribes, that those services are no longer desired or necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title XI, § 1106(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>