<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 54—</num>
<heading>HUMAN CAPITAL PERFORMANCE FUND</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5401.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this chapter is to promote, through the creation of a Human Capital Performance Fund, greater performance in the Federal Government. Monies from the Fund will be used to reward agencies’ highest performing and most valuable employees. This Fund will offer Federal managers a new tool to recognize employee performance that is critical to the achievement of agency missions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1129(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1642</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5402.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “agency” means an Executive agency under section 105, but does not include the Government Accountability Office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “employee” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an individual paid under a statutory pay system defined in section 5302(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a prevailing rate employee, as defined in section 5342(a)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a category of employees included by the Office of Personnel Management following the review of an agency plan under section 5403(b)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">but does not include—</continuation>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an individual paid at an annual rate of basic pay for a level of the Executive Schedule, under subchapter II of chapter 53, or at a rate provided for one of those levels under another provision of law;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a member of the Senior Executive Service paid under subchapter VIII of chapter 53, or an equivalent system;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an administrative law judge paid under section 5372;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a contract appeals board member paid under section 5372a;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> an administrative appeals judge paid under section 5372b; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> an individual in a position which is excepted from the competitive service because of its confidential, policy-determining, policy-making, or policy-advocating character; and</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “Office” means the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1129(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1642</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5403.</num>
<heading> Human Capital Performance Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is hereby established the Human Capital Performance Fund, to be administered by the Office for the purpose of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An agency shall submit a plan as described in section 5406 to be eligible for consideration by the Office for an allocation under this section. An allocation shall be made only upon approval by the Office of an agency’s plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> After the reduction for training required under section 5408, ninety percent of the remaining amount appropriated to the Fund may be allocated by the Office to the agencies. Of the amount to be allocated, an agency’s pro rata distribution may not exceed its pro rata share of Executive branch payroll.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If the Office does not allocate an agency’s full pro rata share, the undistributed amount remaining from that share will become available for distribution to other agencies, as provided in subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> After the reduction for training under section 5408, ten percent of the remaining amount appropriated to the Fund, as well as the amount of the pro rata share not distributed because of an agency’s failure to submit a satisfactory plan, shall be allocated among agencies with exceptionally high-quality plans.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> An agency with an exceptionally high-quality plan is eligible to receive an additional distribution in addition to its full pro rata distribution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each agency is required to provide to the Office such payroll information as the Office specifies necessary to determine the Executive branch payroll.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1129(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1642</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5404.</num>
<heading> Human capital performance payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Office may authorize an agency to provide human capital performance payments to individual employees based on exceptional performance contributing to the achievement of the agency mission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The number of employees in an agency receiving payments from the Fund, in any year, shall not be more than the number equal to 15 percent of the agency’s average total civilian full- and part-time permanent employment for the previous fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A human capital performance payment provided to an individual employee from the Fund, in any year, shall not exceed 10 percent of the employee’s rate of basic pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The aggregate of an employee’s rate of basic pay, adjusted by any locality-based comparability payments, and human capital performance pay, as defined by regulation, may not exceed the rate of basic pay for Executive Level IV in any year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any human capital performance payment provided to an employee from the Fund is in addition to any annual pay adjustment (under section 5303 or any similar provision of law) and any locality-based comparability payment that may apply.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> No monies from the Human Capital Performance Fund may be used to pay for a new position, for other performance-related payments, or for recruitment or retention incentives paid under sections 5753 and 5754.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An agency may finance initial human capital performance payments using monies from the Human Capital Performance Fund, as available.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In subsequent years, continuation of previously awarded human capital performance payments shall be financed from other agency funds available for salaries and expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1129(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1643</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5405.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office shall issue such regulations as it determines to be necessary for the administration of this chapter, including the administration of the Fund. The Office’s regulations shall include criteria governing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an agency plan under section 5406;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the allocation of monies from the Fund to agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the nature, extent, duration, and adjustment of, and approval processes for, payments to individual employees under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the relationship to this chapter of agency performance management systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> training of supervisors, managers, and other individuals involved in the process of making performance distinctions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the circumstances under which funds may be allocated by the Office to an agency in amounts below or in excess of the agency’s pro rata share.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1129(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1643</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5406.</num>
<heading> Agency plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> To be eligible for consideration by the Office for an allocation under this section, an agency shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> develop a plan that incorporates the following elements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> adherence to merit principles set forth in section 2301;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a fair, credible, and transparent employee performance appraisal system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a link between the pay-for-performance system, the employee performance appraisal system, and the agency’s strategic plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a means for ensuring employee involvement in the design and implementation of the system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> adequate training and retraining for supervisors, managers, and employees in the implementation and operation of the pay-for-performance system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a process for ensuring ongoing performance feedback and dialogue between supervisors, managers, and employees throughout the appraisal period, and setting timetables for review;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> effective safeguards to ensure that the management of the system is fair and equitable and based on employee performance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> a means for ensuring that adequate agency resources are allocated for the design, implementation, and administration of the pay-for-performance system;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> upon approval, receive an allocation of funding from the Office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make payments to individual employees in accordance with the agency’s approved plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide such information to the Office regarding payments made and use of funds received under this section as the Office may specify.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Office, in consultation with the Chief Human Capital Officers Council, shall review and approve an agency’s plan before the agency is eligible to receive an allocation of funding from the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Chief Human Capital Officers Council shall include in its annual report to Congress under section 1303(d) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 an evaluation of the formulation and implementation of agency performance management systems.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1129(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1644</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5407.</num>
<heading> Nature of payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any payment to an employee under this section shall be part of the employee’s basic pay for the purposes of subchapter III of chapter 83, and chapters 84 and 87, and for such other purposes (other than chapter 75) as the Office shall determine by regulation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1129(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5408.</num>
<heading> Appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated $500,000,000 for fiscal year 2004, and, for each subsequent fiscal year, such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter. In the first year of implementation, up to 10 percent of the amount appropriated to the Fund shall be available to participating agencies to train supervisors, managers, and other individuals involved in the appraisal process on using performance management systems to make meaningful distinctions in employee performance and on the use of the Fund.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1129(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>