<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 29—</num>
<heading>COMMISSIONS, OATHS, RECORDS, AND REPORTS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>COMMISSIONS, OATHS, AND RECORDS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2901.</num>
<heading> Commission of an officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may make out and deliver, after adjournment of the Senate, the commission of an officer whose appointment has been confirmed by the Senate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 411</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2902.</num>
<heading> Commission; where recorded</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided by subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Secretary of State shall make out and record, and affix the seal of the United States to, the commission of an officer appointed by the President. The seal of the United States may not be affixed to the commission before the commission has been signed by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The commission of an officer in the civil service or uniformed services under the control of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of a military department, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Homeland Security, or the Secretary of the Treasury shall be made out and recorded in the department in which he is to serve under the seal of that department. The departmental seal may not be affixed to the commission before the commission has been signed by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The commissions of judicial officers and United States attorneys and marshals, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and other commissions which before <date date="1888-08-08">August 8, 1888</date>, were prepared at the Department of State on the requisition of the Attorney General, shall be made out and recorded in the Department of Justice under the seal of that department and countersigned by the Attorney General. The departmental seal may not be affixed to the commission before the commission has been signed by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 411</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–183, § 2(3)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 1057</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title IX, § 902(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 566</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2903.</num>
<heading> Oath; authority to administer</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The oath of office required by <ref>section 3331 of this title</ref> may be administered by an individual authorized by the laws of the United States or local law to administer oaths in the State, District, or territory or possession of the United States where the oath is administered.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An employee of an Executive agency designated in writing by the head of the Executive agency, or the Secretary of a military department with respect to an employee of his department, may administer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the oath of office required by <ref>section 3331 of this title</ref>, incident to entrance into the executive branch; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any other oath required by law in connection with employment in the executive branch.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> An oath authorized or required under the laws of the United States may be administered by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Vice President; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an individual authorized by local law to administer oaths in the State, District, or territory or possession of the United States where the oath is administered.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 411</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2904.</num>
<heading> Oath; administered without fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employee of an Executive agency who is authorized to administer the oath of office required by <ref>section 3331 of this title</ref>, or any other oath required by law in connection with employment in the executive branch, may not charge or receive a fee or pay for administering the oath.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 412</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2905.</num>
<heading> Oath; renewal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An employee of an Executive agency or an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia who, on original appointment, subscribed to the oath of office required by <ref>section 3331 of this title</ref> is not required to renew the oath because of a change in status so long as his service is continuous in the agency in which he is employed, unless, in the opinion of the head of the Executive agency, the Secretary of a military department with respect to an employee of his department, or the Commissioners of the District of Columbia, the public interest so requires.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An individual who, on appointment as an employee of a House of Congress, subscribed to the oath of office required by <ref>section 3331 of this title</ref> is not required to renew the oath so long as his service as an employee of that House of Congress is continuous.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 412</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2906.</num>
<heading> Oath; custody</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The oath of office taken by an individual under <ref>section 3331 of this title</ref> shall be delivered by him to, and preserved by, the House of Congress, agency, or court to which the office pertains.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 412</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>REPORTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2951.</num>
<heading> Reports to the Office of Personnel Management</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may prescribe rules which shall provide, as nearly as conditions of good administration warrant, that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the appointing authority notify the Office of Personnel Management in writing of the following actions and their dates as to each individual selected for appointment in the competitive service from among those who have been examined—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appointment and residence of appointee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> separation during probation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> transfer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> resignation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> removal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Office keep records of these actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), (16), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>, 1226.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2952.</num>
<heading> Time of making annual reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except when a different time is specifically prescribed by statute, the head of each Executive department or military department shall make the annual reports, required to be submitted to Congress, at the beginning of each regular session of Congress. The reports shall cover the transactions of the preceding year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 413</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2953.</num>
<heading> Reports to Congress on additional employee requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Each report, recommendation, or other communication, of an official nature, of an Executive agency which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> relates to pending or proposed legislation which, if enacted, will entail an estimated annual expenditure of appropriated funds in excess of $1,000,000;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is submitted or transmitted to Congress or a committee thereof in compliance with law or on the initiative of the appropriate authority of the executive branch; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> officially proposes or recommends the creation or expansion, either by action of Congress or by administrative action, of a function, activity, or authority of the Executive agency to be in addition to those functions, activities, and authorities thereof existing when the report, recommendation, or other communication is so submitted or transmitted;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall contain a statement, concerning the Executive agency, for each of the first 5 fiscal years during which each additional or expanded function, activity, or authority so proposed or recommended is to be in effect, setting forth the following information—</continuation>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the estimated maximum additional—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> man-years of civilian employment, by general categories of positions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> expenditures for personal services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> expenditures for all purposes other than personal services;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">which are attributable to the function, activity, or authority and which will be required to be effected by the Executive agency in connection with the performance thereof; and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such other statement, discussion, explanation, or other information as is considered advisable by the appropriate authority of the executive branch or that is required by Congress or a committee thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Subsection (a) of this section does not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Central Intelligence Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a Government controlled corporation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Government Accountability Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2954.</num>
<heading> Information to committees of Congress on request</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An Executive agency, on request of the Committee on Government Operations of the House of Representatives, or of any seven members thereof, or on request of the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate, or any five members thereof, shall submit any information requested of it relating to any matter within the jurisdiction of the committee.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4581</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>