<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 110—</num>
<heading>ENHANCED PERSONNEL SECURITY PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 11001.</num>
<heading> Enhanced personnel security programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enhanced Personnel Security Program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director of National Intelligence shall direct each agency to implement a program to provide enhanced security review of covered individuals—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in accordance with this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> not later than the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the backlog of overdue periodic reinvestigations of covered individuals is eliminated, as determined by the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Comprehensiveness.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sources of information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The enhanced personnel security program of an agency shall integrate relevant and appropriate information from various sources, including government, publicly available, and commercial data sources, consumer reporting agencies, social media, and such other sources as determined by the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Types of information</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Information obtained and integrated from sources described in paragraph (1) may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information relating to any criminal or civil legal proceeding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> financial information relating to the covered individual, including the credit worthiness of the covered individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> publicly available information, whether electronic, printed, or other form, including relevant security or counterintelligence information about the covered individual or information that may suggest ill intent, vulnerability to blackmail, compulsive behavior, allegiance to another country, change in ideology, or that the covered individual lacks good judgment, reliability, or trustworthiness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> data maintained on any terrorist or criminal watch list maintained by any agency, State or local government, or international organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reviews of Covered Individuals.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reviews.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The enhanced personnel security program of an agency shall require that, not less than 2 times every 5 years, the head of the agency shall conduct or request the conduct of automated record checks and checks of information from sources under subsection (b) to ensure the continued eligibility of each covered individual to access classified information and hold a sensitive position unless more frequent reviews of automated record checks and checks of information from sources under subsection (b) are conducted on the covered individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of reviews</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except for a covered individual who is subject to more frequent reviews to ensure the continued eligibility of the covered individual to access classified information and hold a sensitive position, the reviews under subparagraph (A) shall consist of random or aperiodic checks of covered individuals, such that each covered individual is subject to at least 2 reviews during the 5-year period beginning on the date on which the agency implements the enhanced personnel security program of an agency, and during each 5-year period thereafter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Individual reviews</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A review of the information relating to the continued eligibility of a covered individual to access classified information and hold a sensitive position under subparagraph (A) may not be conducted until after the end of the 120-day period beginning on the date the covered individual receives the notification required under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Results</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an agency shall take appropriate action if a review under paragraph (1) finds relevant information that may affect the continued eligibility of a covered individual to access classified information and hold a sensitive position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information for covered individuals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The head of an agency shall ensure that each covered individual is adequately advised of the types of relevant security or counterintelligence information the covered individual is required to report to the head of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect the authority of an agency to determine the appropriate weight to be given to information relating to a covered individual in evaluating the continued eligibility of the covered individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of the president</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as limiting the authority of the President to direct or perpetuate periodic reinvestigations of a more comprehensive nature or to delegate the authority to direct or perpetuate such reinvestigations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect on other reviews</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Reviews conducted under paragraph (1) are in addition to investigations and reinvestigations conducted pursuant to section 3001 of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3341</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “agency” has the meaning given that term in section 3001 of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3341</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “consumer reporting agency” has the meaning given that term in section 603 of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1681a</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “covered individual” means an individual employed by an agency or a contractor of an agency who has been determined eligible for access to classified information or eligible to hold a sensitive position; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “enhanced personnel security program” means a program implemented by an agency at the direction of the Director of National Intelligence under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. M, title III, § 306(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2914</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LXVII, § 6711</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 2225</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title III, § 7327(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 1044</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>