<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 34—</num>
<heading>PART-TIME CAREER EMPLOYMENT OPPORTUNITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3401.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “agency” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an Executive agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a military department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an agency in the judicial branch;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Library of Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Botanic Garden; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> the Office of the Architect of the Capitol; but does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a Government controlled corporation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Tennessee Valley Authority;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Virgin Islands Corporation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the Federal Bureau of Investigation, Department of Justice;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the Central Intelligence Agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the National Security Agency, Department of Defense; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “part-time career employment” means part-time employment of 16 to 32 hours a week (or 32 to 64 hours during a biweekly pay period in the case of a flexible or compressed work schedule under subchapter II of chapter 61 of this title) under a schedule consisting of an equal or varied number of hours per day, whether in a position which would be part-time without regard to this section or one established to allow job-sharing or comparable arrangements, but does not include employment on a temporary or intermittent basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–437, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1056</ref>, § 3391; renumbered § 3401 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(c)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1226</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–221, § 3</ref>, <date date="1982-07-23">July 23, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–468, title VI, § 615(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2578</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(15)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1347</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXV, § 3548(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2868</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3402.</num>
<heading> Establishment of part-time career employment programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In order to promote part-time career employment opportunities in all grade levels, the head of each agency, by regulation, shall establish and maintain a program for part-time career employment within such agency. Such regulations shall provide for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the review of positions which, after such positions become vacant, may be filled on a part-time career employment basis (including the establishment of criteria to be used in identifying such positions);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> procedures and criteria to be used in connection with establishing or converting positions for part-time career employment, subject to the limitations of <ref>section 3403 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> annual goals for establishing or converting positions for part-time career employment, and a timetable setting forth interim and final deadlines for achieving such goals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a continuing review and evaluation of the part-time career employment program established under such regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> procedures for notifying the public of vacant part-time positions in such agency, utilizing facilities and funds otherwise available to such agency for the dissemination of information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The head of each agency shall provide for communication between, and coordination of the activities of, the individuals within such agency whose responsibilities relate to the part-time career employment program established within that agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Regulations established under paragraph (1) of this subsection may provide for such exceptions as may be necessary to carry out the mission of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management, by regulation, shall establish and maintain a program under which it shall, on the request of an agency, advise and assist such agency in the establishment and maintenance of its part-time career employment program under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Office shall conduct a research and demonstration program with respect to part-time career employment within the Federal Government. In particular, such program shall be directed to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determining the extent to which part-time career employment may be used in filling positions which have not traditionally been open for such employment on any extensive basis, such as supervisory, managerial, and professional positions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> determining the extent to which job-sharing arrangements may be established for various occupations and positions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> evaluating attitudes, benefits, costs, efficiency, and productivity associated with part-time career employment, as well as its various sociological effects as a mode of employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–437, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1056</ref>, § 3392; renumbered § 3402 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(c)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)(B), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1226</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3403.</num>
<heading> Limitations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An agency shall not abolish any position occupied by an employee in order to make the duties of such position available to be performed on a part-time career employment basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any person who is employed on a full-time basis in an agency shall not be required to accept part-time employment as a condition of continued employment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–437, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1057</ref>, § 3393; renumbered § 3403, <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(c)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1226</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3404.</num>
<heading> Personnel ceilings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In administering any personnel ceiling applicable to an agency (or unit therein), an employee employed by such agency on a part-time career employment basis shall be counted as a fraction which is determined by dividing 40 hours into the average number of hours of such employee’s regularly scheduled workweek. This section shall become effective on <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–437, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1057</ref>, § 3394; renumbered § 3404, <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(c)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1226</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3405.</num>
<heading> Nonapplicability</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If, on the date of enactment of this chapter, there is in effect with respect to positions within an agency a collective-bargaining agreement which establishes the number of hours of employment a week, then this chapter shall not apply to those positions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This chapter shall not require part-time career employment in positions the rate of basic pay for which is fixed at a rate equal to or greater than the minimum rate payable under section 5376.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–437, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1057</ref>, § 3395; renumbered § 3405 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(c)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)(C), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1226</ref>, 1227; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 101(b)(9)(D)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1441.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3406.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before any regulation is prescribed under this chapter, a copy of the proposed regulation shall be published in the Federal Register and an opportunity provided to interested parties to present written comment and, where practicable, oral comment. Initial regulations shall be prescribed not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–437, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1057</ref>, § 3396; renumbered § 3406 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(c)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)(C), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1226</ref>, 1227.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 3407.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title III, § 3001(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 733</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3408.</num>
<heading> Employee organization representation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If an employee organization has been accorded exclusive recognition with respect to a unit within an agency, then the employee organization shall be entitled to represent all employees within that unit employed on a part-time career employment basis.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–437, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1058</ref>, § 3398; renumbered § 3408, <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(c)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1226</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>