<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 13—</num>
<heading>SPECIAL AUTHORITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1301.</num>
<heading> Rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management shall aid the President, as he may request, in preparing the rules he prescribes under this title for the administration of the competitive service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1302.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Office of Personnel Management, subject to the rules prescribed by the President under this title for the administration of the competitive service, shall prescribe regulations for, control, supervise, and preserve the records of, examinations for the competitive service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Office shall prescribe and enforce regulations for the administration of the provisions of this title, and Executive orders issued in furtherance thereof, that implement the Congressional policy that preference shall be given to preference eligibles in certification for appointment, and in appointment, reinstatement, reemployment, and retention, in the competitive service in Executive agencies, permanent or temporary, and in the government of the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Office shall prescribe regulations for the administration of the provisions of this title that implement the Congressional policy that preference shall be given to preference eligibles in certification for appointment, and in appointment, reinstatement, reemployment, and retention, in the excepted service in Executive agencies, permanent or temporary, and in the government of the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Office may prescribe reasonable procedure and regulations for the administration of its functions under chapter 15 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1303.</num>
<heading> Investigations; reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Office of Personnel Management, Merit Systems Protection Board, and Special Counsel may investigate and report on matters concerning—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the enforcement and effect of the rules prescribed by the President under this title for the administration of the competitive service and the regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management under <ref>section 1302(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the action of an examiner, a board of examiners, and other employees concerning the execution of the provisions of this title that relate to the administration of the competitive service.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(4)</ref>, (11), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1225</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1304.</num>
<heading> Loyalty investigations; reports; revolving fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Office of Personnel Management shall conduct the investigations and issue the reports required by the following statutes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> sections 272b, 281b(e), and 290a of title 22;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>section 1874(c) of title 42</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content><ref>section 1203(e) of title 6</ref>, District of Columbia Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When an investigation under subsection (a) of this section develops data indicating that the loyalty of the individual being investigated is questionable, the Office shall refer the matter to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a full field investigation, a report of which shall be furnished to the Office for its information and appropriate action.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> When the President considers it in the national interest, he may have the investigations of a group or class, which are required by subsection (a) of this section, made by the Federal Bureau of Investigation rather than the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The investigation and report required by subsection (a) of this section shall be made by the Federal Bureau of Investigation rather than the Office for those specific positions which the Secretary of State certifies are of a high degree of importance or sensitivity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A revolving fund is available, to the Office without fiscal year limitation, for financing investigations, training, and such other functions as the Office is authorized or required to perform on a reimbursable basis, including personnel management services performed at the request of individual agencies (which would otherwise be the responsibility of such agencies), or at the request of nonappropriated fund instrumentalities, and for the cost of audits, investigations, and oversight activities, conducted by the Inspector General of the Office, of the fund and the activities financed by the fund. However, the functions which may be financed in any fiscal year by the fund are restricted to those functions which are covered by the budget estimates submitted to the Congress for that fiscal year. To the maximum extent feasible, each individual activity shall be conducted generally on an actual cost basis over a reasonable period of time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The capital of the fund consists of the aggregate of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appropriations made to provide capital for the fund, which appropriations are hereby authorized, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the sum of the fair and reasonable value of such supplies, equipment, and other assets as the Office from time to time transfers to the fund (including the amount of the unexpended balances of appropriations or funds relating to activities the financing of which is transferred to the fund) less the amount of related liabilities, the amount of unpaid obligations, and the value of accrued annual leave of employees, which are attributable to the activities the financing of which is transferred to the fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The fund shall be credited with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> advances and reimbursements from available funds of the Office or other agencies, or from other sources, for those services and supplies provided at rates estimated by the Office as adequate to recover expenses of operation (including provision for accrued annual leave of employees and depreciation of equipment); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> receipts from sales or exchanges of property, and payments for loss of or damage to property, accounted for under the fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any unobligated and unexpended balances in the fund which the Office determines to be in excess of amounts needed for activities financed by the fund shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Office shall prepare a business-type budget providing full disclosure of the results of operations for each of the functions performed by the Office and financed by the fund, and such budget shall be transmitted to the Congress and considered, in the manner prescribed by law for wholly owned Government corporations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Such budget shall include an estimate from the Inspector General of the Office of the amount required to pay the expenses to audit, investigate, and provide other oversight activities with respect to the fund and the activities financed by the fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The amount requested by the Inspector General under subparagraph (B) shall not exceed .33 percent of the total budgetary authority requested by the Office under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Comptroller General of the United States shall, as a result of his periodic reviews of the activities financed by the fund, report and make such recommendations as he deems appropriate to the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> An agency may use available appropriations to reimburse the Office or the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the cost of investigations, training, and functions performed for them under this section, or to make advances toward their cost. These advances and reimbursements shall be credited directly to the applicable appropriations of the Office or the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> This section does not affect the responsibility of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to investigate espionage, sabotage, or subversive acts.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–189, § 1</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 851</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–648, title V, § 510</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1928</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–60, title II, § 203(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-15">Aug. 15, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–412, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-03">Jan. 3, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2047</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–224, § 5(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-03-02">Mar. 2, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4581</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title II, § 2182</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title IV, § 421]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–343; <ref>Pub. L. 113–80, § 2</ref>, <date date="2014-02-12">Feb. 12, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1006</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1305.</num>
<heading> Administrative law judges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of sections 3105, 3344, 4301(2)(D), and 5372 of this title and the provisions of <ref>section 5335(a)(B) of this title</ref> that relate to administrative law judges, the Office of Personnel Management may, and for the purpose of <ref>section 7521 of this title</ref>, the Merit Systems Protection Board may investigate, prescribe regulations, appoint advisory committees as necessary, recommend legislation, subpena witnesses and records, and pay witness fees as established for the courts of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 196</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–251, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1978-03-27">Mar. 27, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 183</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VIII, § 801(a)(3)(B)(iii)</ref>, title IX, § 906(a)(12), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1221</ref>, 1225; <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(4)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1346</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title XIII, § 1302(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1306.</num>
<heading> Oaths to witnesses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Personnel Management and authorized representatives of the Director may administer oaths to witnesses in matters pending before the Office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1226</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1307.</num>
<heading> Minutes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Civil Service Commission shall keep minutes of its proceedings.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 402</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1308.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title XIII, § 1302(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3293</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>