<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 71—</num>
<heading>LABOR-MANAGEMENT RELATIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7101.</num>
<heading> Findings and purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> experience in both private and public employment indicates that the statutory protection of the right of employees to organize, bargain collectively, and participate through labor organizations of their own choosing in decisions which affect them—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> safeguards the public interest,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> contributes to the effective conduct of public business, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> facilitates and encourages the amicable settlements of disputes between employees and their employers involving conditions of employment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the public interest demands the highest standards of employee performance and the continued development and implementation of modern and progressive work practices to facilitate and improve employee performance and the efficient accomplishment of the operations of the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Therefore, labor organizations and collective bargaining in the civil service are in the public interest.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> It is the purpose of this chapter to prescribe certain rights and obligations of the employees of the Federal Government and to establish procedures which are designed to meet the special requirements and needs of the Government. The provisions of this chapter should be interpreted in a manner consistent with the requirement of an effective and efficient Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7102.</num>
<heading> Employees’ rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each employee shall have the right to form, join, or assist any labor organization, or to refrain from any such activity, freely and without fear of penalty or reprisal, and each employee shall be protected in the exercise of such right. Except as otherwise provided under this chapter, such right includes the right—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to act for a labor organization in the capacity of a representative and the right, in that capacity, to present the views of the labor organization to heads of agencies and other officials of the executive branch of the Government, the Congress, or other appropriate authorities, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to engage in collective bargaining with respect to conditions of employment through representatives chosen by employees under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7103.</num>
<heading> Definitions; application</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “person” means an individual, labor organization, or agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> “employee” means an individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> employed in an agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whose employment in an agency has ceased because of any unfair labor practice under <ref>section 7116 of this title</ref> and who has not obtained any other regular and substantially equivalent employment, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Federal Labor Relations Authority;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">but does not include—</continuation>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an alien or noncitizen of the United States who occupies a position outside the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a member of the uniformed services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a supervisor or a management official;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> an officer or employee in the Foreign Service of the United States employed in the Department of State, the International Communication Agency, the Agency for International Development, the Department of Agriculture, or the Department of Commerce; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any person who participates in a strike in violation of <ref>section 7311 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> “agency” means an Executive agency (including a nonappropriated fund instrumentality described in <ref>section 2105(c) of this title</ref> and the Veterans’ Canteen Service, Department of Veterans Affairs), the Library of Congress, the Government Publishing Office, and the Smithsonian Institution <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002132">1</ref> but does not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Government Accountability Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Central Intelligence Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the National Security Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Tennessee Valley Authority;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Federal Labor Relations Authority;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Federal Service Impasses Panel; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the United States Secret Service and the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “labor organization” means an organization composed in whole or in part of employees, in which employees participate and pay dues, and which has as a purpose the dealing with an agency concerning grievances and conditions of employment, but does not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an organization which, by its constitution, bylaws, tacit agreement among its members, or otherwise, denies membership because of race, color, creed, national origin, sex, age, preferential or nonpreferential civil service status, political affiliation, marital status, or handicapping condition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an organization which advocates the overthrow of the constitutional form of government of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an organization sponsored by an agency; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an organization which participates in the conduct of a strike against the Government or any agency thereof or imposes a duty or obligation to conduct, assist, or participate in such a strike;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “dues” means dues, fees, and assessments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “Authority” means the Federal Labor Relations Authority described in <ref>section 7104(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “Panel” means the Federal Service Impasses Panel described in <ref>section 7119(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “collective bargaining agreement” means an agreement entered into as a result of collective bargaining pursuant to the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> “grievance” means any complaint—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by any employee concerning any matter relating to the employment of the employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by any labor organization concerning any matter relating to the employment of any employee; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> by any employee, labor organization, or agency concerning—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the effect or interpretation, or a claim of breach, of a collective bargaining agreement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any claimed violation, misinterpretation, or misapplication of any law, rule, or regulation affecting conditions of employment;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> “supervisor” means an individual employed by an agency having authority in the interest of the agency to hire, direct, assign, promote, reward, transfer, furlough, layoff, recall, suspend, discipline, or remove employees, to adjust their grievances, or to effectively recommend such action, if the exercise of the authority is not merely routine or clerical in nature but requires the consistent exercise of independent judgment, except that, with respect to any unit which includes firefighters or nurses, the term “supervisor” includes only those individuals who devote a preponderance of their employment time to exercising such authority;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> “management official” means an individual employed by an agency in a position the duties and responsibilities of which require or authorize the individual to formulate, determine, or influence the policies of the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> “collective bargaining” means the performance of the mutual obligation of the representative of an agency and the exclusive representative of employees in an appropriate unit in the agency to meet at reasonable times and to consult and bargain in a good-faith effort to reach agreement with respect to the conditions of employment affecting such employees and to execute, if requested by either party, a written document incorporating any collective bargaining agreement reached, but the obligation referred to in this paragraph does not compel either party to agree to a proposal or to make a concession;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> “confidential employee” means an employee who acts in a confidential capacity with respect to an individual who formulates or effectuates management policies in the field of labor-management relations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<chapeau> “conditions of employment” means personnel policies, practices, and matters, whether established by rule, regulation, or otherwise, affecting working conditions, except that such term does not include policies, practices, and matters—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> relating to political activities prohibited under subchapter III of chapter 73 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> relating to the classification of any position; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to the extent such matters are specifically provided for by Federal statute;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<chapeau> “professional employee” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> an employee engaged in the performance of work—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> requiring knowledge of an advanced type in a field of science or learning customarily acquired by a prolonged course of specialized intellectual instruction and study in an institution of higher learning or a hospital (as distinguished from knowledge acquired by a general academic education, or from an apprenticeship, or from training in the performance of routine mental, manual, mechanical, or physical activities);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> requiring the consistent exercise of discretion and judgment in its performance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> which is predominantly intellectual and varied in character (as distinguished from routine mental, manual, mechanical, or physical work); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> which is of such character that the output produced or the result accomplished by such work cannot be standardized in relation to a given period of time; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an employee who has completed the courses of specialized intellectual instruction and study described in subparagraph (A)(i) of this paragraph and is performing related work under appropriate direction or guidance to qualify the employee as a professional employee described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<chapeau> “exclusive representative” means any labor organization which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is certified as the exclusive representative of employees in an appropriate unit pursuant to <ref>section 7111 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> was recognized by an agency immediately before the effective date of this chapter as the exclusive representative of employees in an appropriate unit—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on the basis of an election, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on any basis other than an election,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">and continues to be so recognized in accordance with the provisions of this chapter;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> “firefighter” means any employee engaged in the performance of work directly connected with the control and extinguishment of fires or the maintenance and use of firefighting apparatus and equipment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> “United States” means the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The President may issue an order excluding any agency or subdivision thereof from coverage under this chapter if the President determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the agency or subdivision has as a primary function intelligence, counterintelligence, investigative, or national security work, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the provisions of this chapter cannot be applied to that agency or subdivision in a manner consistent with national security requirements and considerations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The President may issue an order suspending any provision of this chapter with respect to any agency, installation, or activity located outside the 50 States and the District of Columbia, if the President determines that the suspension is necessary in the interest of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1192</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2314(g)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2168</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–54, § 13(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 274</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–359, title V, § 501(j)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3430</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1634(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2752</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 341(e)</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1092</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIV, § 1422(b)(1), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(4) [div. B, title I, § 139]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–235; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7104.</num>
<heading> Federal Labor Relations Authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Federal Labor Relations Authority is composed of three members, not more than 2 of whom may be adherents of the same political party. No member shall engage in any other business or employment or hold another office or position in the Government of the United States except as otherwise provided by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Members of the Authority shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and may be removed by the President only upon notice and hearing and only for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office. The President shall designate one member to serve as Chairman of the Authority. The Chairman is the chief executive and administrative officer of the Authority.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A member of the Authority shall be appointed for a term of 5 years. An individual chosen to fill a vacancy shall be appointed for the unexpired term of the member replaced. The term of any member shall not expire before the earlier of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which the member’s successor takes office, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the last day of the Congress beginning after the date on which the member’s term of office would (but for this paragraph) expire.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A vacancy in the Authority shall not impair the right of the remaining members to exercise all of the powers of the Authority.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Authority shall make an annual report to the President for transmittal to the Congress which shall include information as to the cases it has heard and the decisions it has rendered.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The General Counsel of the Authority shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, for a term of 5 years. The General Counsel may be removed at any time by the President. The General Counsel shall hold no other office or position in the Government of the United States except as provided by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The General Counsel may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> investigate alleged unfair labor practices under this chapter,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> file and prosecute complaints under this chapter, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> exercise such other powers of the Authority as the Authority may prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The General Counsel shall have direct authority over, and responsibility for, all employees in the office of General Counsel, including employees of the General Counsel in the regional offices of the Authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1196</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–224, § 3</ref>, <date date="1984-03-02">Mar. 2, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 47</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7105.</num>
<heading> Powers and duties of the Authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Authority shall provide leadership in establishing policies and guidance relating to matters under this chapter, and, except as otherwise provided, shall be responsible for carrying out the purpose of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Authority shall, to the extent provided in this chapter and in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Authority—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determine the appropriateness of units for labor organization representation under <ref>section 7112 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> supervise or conduct elections to determine whether a labor organization has been selected as an exclusive representative by a majority of the employees in an appropriate unit and otherwise administer the provisions of <ref>section 7111 of this title</ref> relating to the according of exclusive recognition to labor organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> prescribe criteria and resolve issues relating to the granting of national consultation rights under <ref>section 7113 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> prescribe criteria and resolve issues relating to determining compelling need for agency rules or regulations under <ref>section 7117(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> resolves issues relating to the duty to bargain in good faith under <ref>section 7117(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> prescribe criteria relating to the granting of consultation rights with respect to conditions of employment under <ref>section 7117(d) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> conduct hearings and resolve complaints of unfair labor practices under <ref>section 7118 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> resolve exceptions to arbitrator’s awards under <ref>section 7122 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> take such other actions as are necessary and appropriate to effectively administer the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Authority shall adopt an official seal which shall be judicially noticed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The principal office of the Authority shall be in or about the District of Columbia, but the Authority may meet and exercise any or all of its powers at any time or place. Except as otherwise expressly provided by law, the Authority may, by one or more of its members or by such agents as it may designate, make any appropriate inquiry necessary to carry out its duties wherever persons subject to this chapter are located. Any member who participates in the inquiry shall not be disqualified from later participating in a decision of the Authority in any case relating to the inquiry.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Authority shall appoint an Executive Director and such regional directors, administrative law judges under <ref>section 3105 of this title</ref>, and other individuals as it may from time to time find necessary for the proper performance of its functions. The Authority may delegate to officers and employees appointed under this subsection authority to perform such duties and make such expenditures as may be necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Authority may delegate to any regional director its authority under this chapter—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to determine whether a group of employees is an appropriate unit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to conduct investigations and to provide for hearings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to determine whether a question of representation exists and to direct an election; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to supervise or conduct secret ballot elections and certify the results thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Authority may delegate to any administrative law judge appointed under subsection (d) of this section its authority under <ref>section 7118 of this title</ref> to determine whether any person has engaged in or is engaging in an unfair labor practice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> If the Authority delegates any authority to any regional director or administrative law judge to take any action pursuant to subsection (e) of this section, the Authority may, upon application by any interested person filed within 60 days after the date of the action, review such action, but the review shall not, unless specifically ordered by the Authority, operate as a stay of action. The Authority may affirm, modify, or reverse any action reviewed under this subsection. If the Authority does not undertake to grant review of the action under this subsection within 60 days after the later of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date of the action; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the date of the filing of any application under this subsection for review of the action;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the action shall become the action of the Authority at the end of such 60-day period.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> In order to carry out its functions under this chapter, the Authority may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> hold hearings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> administer oaths, take the testimony or deposition of any person under oath, and issue subpenas as provided in <ref>section 7132 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may require an agency or a labor organization to cease and desist from violations of this chapter and require it to take any remedial action it considers appropriate to carry out the policies of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Except as provided in <ref>section 518 of title 28</ref>, relating to litigation before the Supreme Court, attorneys designated by the Authority may appear for the Authority and represent the Authority in any civil action brought in connection with any function carried out by the Authority pursuant to this title or as otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In the exercise of the functions of the Authority under this title, the Authority may request from the Director of the Office of Personnel Management an advisory opinion concerning the proper interpretation of rules, regulations, or policy directives issued by the Office of Personnel Management in connection with any matter before the Authority.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1196</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7106.</num>
<heading> Management rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to subsection (b) of this section, nothing in this chapter shall affect the authority of any management official of any agency—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to determine the mission, budget, organization, number of employees, and internal security practices of the agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in accordance with applicable laws—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to hire, assign, direct, layoff, and retain employees in the agency, or to suspend, remove, reduce in grade or pay, or take other disciplinary action against such employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to assign work, to make determinations with respect to contracting out, and to determine the personnel by which agency operations shall be conducted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to filling positions, to make selections for appointments from—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> among properly ranked and certified candidates for promotion; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any other appropriate source; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to take whatever actions may be necessary to carry out the agency mission during emergencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this section shall preclude any agency and any labor organization from negotiating—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at the election of the agency, on the numbers, types, and grades of employees or positions assigned to any organizational subdivision, work project, or tour of duty, or on the technology, methods, and means of performing work;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> procedures which management officials of the agency will observe in exercising any authority under this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> appropriate arrangements for employees adversely affected by the exercise of any authority under this section by such management officials.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1198</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>RIGHTS AND DUTIES OF AGENCIES AND LABOR ORGANIZATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7111.</num>
<heading> Exclusive recognition of labor organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An agency shall accord exclusive recognition to a labor organization if the organization has been selected as the representative, in a secret ballot election, by a majority of the employees in an appropriate unit who cast valid ballots in the election.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> If a petition is filed with the Authority—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> by any person alleging—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an appropriate unit for which there is no exclusive representative, that 30 percent of the employees in the appropriate unit wish to be represented for the purpose of collective bargaining by an exclusive representative, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an appropriate unit for which there is an exclusive representative, that 30 percent of the employees in the unit allege that the exclusive representative is no longer the representative of the majority of the employees in the unit; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by any person seeking clarification of, or an amendment to, a certification then in effect or a matter relating to representation;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Authority shall investigate the petition, and if it has reasonable cause to believe that a question of representation exists, it shall provide an opportunity for a hearing (for which a transcript shall be kept) after reasonable notice. If the Authority finds on the record of the hearing that a question of representation exists, the Authority shall supervise or conduct an election on the question by secret ballot and shall certify the results thereof. An election under this subsection shall not be conducted in any appropriate unit or in any subdivision thereof within which, in the preceding 12 calendar months, a valid election under this subsection has been held.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A labor organization which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has been designated by at least 10 percent of the employees in the unit specified in any petition filed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has submitted a valid copy of a current or recently expired collective bargaining agreement for the unit; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has submitted other evidence that it is the exclusive representative of the employees involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">may intervene with respect to a petition filed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section and shall be placed on the ballot of any election under such subsection (b) with respect to the petition.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The Authority shall determine who is eligible to vote in any election under this section and shall establish rules governing any such election, which shall include rules allowing employees eligible to vote the opportunity to choose—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> from labor organizations on the ballot, that labor organization which the employees wish to have represent them; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not to be represented by a labor organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In any election in which no choice on the ballot receives a majority of the votes cast, a runoff election shall be conducted between the two choices receiving the highest number of votes. A labor organization which receives the majority of the votes cast in an election shall be certified by the Authority as the exclusive representative.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A labor organization seeking exclusive recognition shall submit to the Authority and the agency involved a roster of its officers and representatives, a copy of its constitution and bylaws, and a statement of its objectives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> Exclusive recognition shall not be accorded to a labor organization—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if the Authority determines that the labor organization is subject to corrupt influences or influences opposed to democratic principles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of a petition filed pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(A) of this section, if there is not credible evidence that at least 30 percent of the employees in the unit specified in the petition wish to be represented for the purpose of collective bargaining by the labor organization seeking exclusive recognition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> if there is then in effect a lawful written collective bargaining agreement between the agency involved and an exclusive representative (other than the labor organization seeking exclusive recognition) covering any employees included in the unit specified in the petition, unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the collective bargaining agreement has been in effect for more than 3 years, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the petition for exclusive recognition is filed not more than 105 days and not less than 60 days before the expiration date of the collective bargaining agreement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> if the Authority has, within the previous 12 calendar months, conducted a secret ballot election for the unit described in any petition under this section and in such election a majority of the employees voting chose a labor organization for certification as the unit’s exclusive representative.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the waiving of hearings by stipulation for the purpose of a consent election in conformity with regulations and rules or decisions of the Authority.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1199</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7112.</num>
<heading> Determination of appropriate units for labor organization representation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Authority shall determine the appropriateness of any unit. The Authority shall determine in each case whether, in order to ensure employees the fullest freedom in exercising the rights guaranteed under this chapter, the appropriate unit should be established on an agency, plant, installation, functional, or other basis and shall determine any unit to be an appropriate unit only if the determination will ensure a clear and identifiable community of interest among the employees in the unit and will promote effective dealings with, and efficiency of the operations of the agency involved.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A unit shall not be determined to be appropriate under this section solely on the basis of the extent to which employees in the proposed unit have organized, nor shall a unit be determined to be appropriate if it includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> except as provided under <ref>section 7135(a)(2) of this title</ref>, any management official or supervisor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a confidential employee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an employee engaged in personnel work in other than a purely clerical capacity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an employee engaged in administering the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> both professional employees and other employees, unless a majority of the professional employees vote for inclusion in the unit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any employee engaged in intelligence, counterintelligence, investigative, or security work which directly affects national security; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> any employee primarily engaged in investigation or audit functions relating to the work of individuals employed by an agency whose duties directly affect the internal security of the agency, but only if the functions are undertaken to ensure that the duties are discharged honestly and with integrity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Any employee who is engaged in administering any provision of law relating to labor-management relations may not be represented by a labor organization—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which represents other individuals to whom such provision applies; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> which is affiliated directly or indirectly with an organization which represents other individuals to whom such provision applies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Two or more units which are in an agency and for which a labor organization is the exclusive representative may, upon petition by the agency or labor organization, be consolidated with or without an election into a single larger unit if the Authority considers the larger unit to be appropriate. The Authority shall certify the labor organization as the exclusive representative of the new larger unit.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1200</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(54)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7113.</num>
<heading> National consultation rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If, in connection with any agency, no labor organization has been accorded exclusive recognition on an agency basis, a labor organization which is the exclusive representative of a substantial number of the employees of the agency, as determined in accordance with criteria prescribed by the Authority, shall be granted national consultation rights by the agency. National consultation rights shall terminate when the labor organization no longer meets the criteria prescribed by the Authority. Any issue relating to any labor organization’s eligibility for, or continuation of, national consultation rights shall be subject to determination by the Authority.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Any labor organization having national consultation rights in connection with any agency under subsection (a) of this section shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be informed of any substantive change in conditions of employment proposed by the agency, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be permitted reasonable time to present its views and recommendations regarding the changes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If any views or recommendations are presented under paragraph (1) of this subsection to an agency by any labor organization—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the agency shall consider the views or recommendations before taking final action on any matter with respect to which the views or recommendations are presented; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the agency shall provide the labor organization a written statement of the reasons for taking the final action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the right of any agency or exclusive representative to engage in collective bargaining.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1201</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(55)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7114.</num>
<heading> Representation rights and duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A labor organization which has been accorded exclusive recognition is the exclusive representative of the employees in the unit it represents and is entitled to act for, and negotiate collective bargaining agreements covering, all employees in the unit. An exclusive representative is responsible for representing the interests of all employees in the unit it represents without discrimination and without regard to labor organization membership.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> An exclusive representative of an appropriate unit in an agency shall be given the opportunity to be represented at—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any formal discussion between one or more representatives of the agency and one or more employees in the unit or their representatives concerning any grievance or any personnel policy or practices or other general condition of employment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> any examination of an employee in the unit by a representative of the agency in connection with an investigation if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the employee reasonably believes that the examination may result in disciplinary action against the employee; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the employee requests representation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Each agency shall annually inform its employees of their rights under paragraph (2)(B) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any agency and any exclusive representative in any appropriate unit in the agency, through appropriate representatives, shall meet and negotiate in good faith for the purposes of arriving at a collective bargaining agreement. In addition, the agency and the exclusive representative may determine appropriate techniques, consistent with the provisions of <ref>section 7119 of this title</ref>, to assist in any negotiation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The rights of an exclusive representative under the provisions of this subsection shall not be construed to preclude an employee from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> being represented by an attorney or other representative, other than the exclusive representative, of the employee’s own choosing in any grievance or appeal action; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> exercising grievance or appellate rights established by law, rule, or regulation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">except in the case of grievance or appeal procedures negotiated under this chapter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The duty of an agency and an exclusive representative to negotiate in good faith under subsection (a) of this section shall include the obligation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to approach the negotiations with a sincere resolve to reach a collective bargaining agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to be represented at the negotiations by duly authorized representatives prepared to discuss and negotiate on any condition of employment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to meet at reasonable times and convenient places as frequently as may be necessary, and to avoid unnecessary delays;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an agency, to furnish to the exclusive representative involved, or its authorized representative, upon request and, to the extent not prohibited by law, data—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which is normally maintained by the agency in the regular course of business;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which is reasonably available and necessary for full and proper discussion, understanding, and negotiation of subjects within the scope of collective bargaining; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> which does not constitute guidance, advice, counsel, or training provided for management officials or supervisors, relating to collective bargaining; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> if agreement is reached, to execute on the request of any party to the negotiation a written document embodying the agreed terms, and to take such steps as are necessary to implement such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> An agreement between any agency and an exclusive representative shall be subject to approval by the head of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The head of the agency shall approve the agreement within 30 days from the date the agreement is executed if the agreement is in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and any other applicable law, rule, or regulation (unless the agency has granted an exception to the provision).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the head of the agency does not approve or disapprove the agreement within the 30-day period, the agreement shall take effect and shall be binding on the agency and the exclusive representative subject to the provisions of this chapter and any other applicable law, rule, or regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A local agreement subject to a national or other controlling agreement at a higher level shall be approved under the procedures of the controlling agreement or, if none, under regulations prescribed by the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1202</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7115.</num>
<heading> Allotments to representatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If an agency has received from an employee in an appropriate unit a written assignment which authorizes the agency to deduct from the pay of the employee amounts for the payment of regular and periodic dues of the exclusive representative of the unit, the agency shall honor the assignment and make an appropriate allotment pursuant to the assignment. Any such allotment shall be made at no cost to the exclusive representative or the employee. Except as provided under subsection (b) of this section, any such assignment may not be revoked for a period of 1 year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An allotment under subsection (a) of this section for the deduction of dues with respect to any employee shall terminate when—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the agreement between the agency and the exclusive representative involved ceases to be applicable to the employee; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the employee is suspended or expelled from membership in the exclusive representative.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, if a petition has been filed with the Authority by a labor organization alleging that 10 percent of the employees in an appropriate unit in an agency have membership in the labor organization, the Authority shall investigate the petition to determine its validity. Upon certification by the Authority of the validity of the petition, the agency shall have a duty to negotiate with the labor organization solely concerning the deduction of dues of the labor organization from the pay of the members of the labor organization who are employees in the unit and who make a voluntary allotment for such purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply in the case of any appropriate unit for which there is an exclusive representative.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any agreement under paragraph (1) of this subsection between a labor organization and an agency with respect to an appropriate unit shall be null and void upon the certification of an exclusive representative of the unit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7116.</num>
<heading> Unfair labor practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this chapter, it shall be an unfair labor practice for an agency—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to interfere with, restrain, or coerce any employee in the exercise by the employee of any right under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to encourage or discourage membership in any labor organization by discrimination in connection with hiring, tenure, promotion, or other conditions of employment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to sponsor, control, or otherwise assist any labor organization, other than to furnish, upon request, customary and routine services and facilities if the services and facilities are also furnished on an impartial basis to other labor organizations having equivalent status;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to discipline or otherwise discriminate against an employee because the employee has filed a complaint, affidavit, or petition, or has given any information or testimony under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to refuse to consult or negotiate in good faith with a labor organization as required by this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to fail or refuse to cooperate in impasse procedures and impasse decisions as required by this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to enforce any rule or regulation (other than a rule or regulation implementing <ref>section 2302 of this title</ref>) which is in conflict with any applicable collective bargaining agreement if the agreement was in effect before the date the rule or regulation was prescribed; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to otherwise fail or refuse to comply with any provision of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this chapter, it shall be an unfair labor practice for a labor organization—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to interfere with, restrain, or coerce any employee in the exercise by the employee of any right under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to cause or attempt to cause an agency to discriminate against any employee in the exercise by the employee of any right under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to coerce, discipline, fine, or attempt to coerce a member of the labor organization as punishment, reprisal, or for the purpose of hindering or impeding the member’s work performance or productivity as an employee or the discharge of the member’s duties as an employee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to discriminate against an employee with regard to the terms or conditions of membership in the labor organization on the basis of race, color, creed, national origin, sex, age, preferential or nonpreferential civil service status, political affiliation, marital status, or handicapping condition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to refuse to consult or negotiate in good faith with an agency as required by this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to fail or refuse to cooperate in impasse procedures and impasse decisions as required by this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to call, or participate in, a strike, work stoppage, or slowdown, or picketing of an agency in a labor-management dispute if such picketing interferes with an agency’s operations, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to condone any activity described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph by failing to take action to prevent or stop such activity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to otherwise fail or refuse to comply with any provision of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in paragraph (7) of this subsection shall result in any informational picketing which does not interfere with an agency’s operations being considered as an unfair labor practice.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this chapter it shall be an unfair labor practice for an exclusive representative to deny membership to any employee in the appropriate unit represented by such exclusive representative except for failure—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to meet reasonable occupational standards uniformly required for admission, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to tender dues uniformly required as a condition of acquiring and retaining membership.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">This subsection does not preclude any labor organization from enforcing discipline in accordance with procedures under its constitution or bylaws to the extent consistent with the provisions of this chapter.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Issues which can properly be raised under an appeals procedure may not be raised as unfair labor practices prohibited under this section. Except for matters wherein, under section 7121(e) and (f) of this title, an employee has an option of using the negotiated grievance procedure or an appeals procedure, issues which can be raised under a grievance procedure may, in the discretion of the aggrieved party, be raised under the grievance procedure or as an unfair labor practice under this section, but not under both procedures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> The expression of any personal view, argument, opinion or the making of any statement which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> publicizes the fact of a representational election and encourages employees to exercise their right to vote in such election,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> corrects the record with respect to any false or misleading statement made by any person, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> informs employees of the Government’s policy relating to labor-management relations and representation,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall not, if the expression contains no threat of reprisal or force or promise of benefit or was not made under coercive conditions, (A) constitute an unfair labor practice under any provision of this chapter, or (B) constitute grounds for the setting aside of any election conducted under any provisions of this chapter.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7117.</num>
<heading> Duty to bargain in good faith; compelling need; duty to consult</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the duty to bargain in good faith shall, to the extent not inconsistent with any Federal law or any Government-wide rule or regulation, extend to matters which are the subject of any rule or regulation only if the rule or regulation is not a Government-wide rule or regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The duty to bargain in good faith shall, to the extent not inconsistent with Federal law or any Government-wide rule or regulation, extend to matters which are the subject of any agency rule or regulation referred to in paragraph (3) of this subsection only if the Authority has determined under subsection (b) of this section that no compelling need (as determined under regulations prescribed by the Authority) exists for the rule or regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Paragraph (2) of the subsection applies to any rule or regulation issued by any agency or issued by any primary national subdivision of such agency, unless an exclusive representative represents an appropriate unit including not less than a majority of the employees in the issuing agency or primary national subdivision, as the case may be, to whom the rule or regulation is applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In any case of collective bargaining in which an exclusive representative alleges that no compelling need exists for any rule or regulation referred to in subsection (a)(3) of this section which is then in effect and which governs any matter at issue in such collective bargaining, the Authority shall determine under paragraph (2) of this subsection, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Authority, whether such a compelling need exists.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this section, a compelling need shall be determined not to exist for any rule or regulation only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the agency, or primary national subdivision, as the case may be, which issued the rule or regulation informs the Authority in writing that a compelling need for the rule or regulation does not exist; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Authority determines that a compelling need for a rule or regulation does not exist.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A hearing may be held, in the discretion of the Authority, before a determination is made under this subsection. If a hearing is held, it shall be expedited to the extent practicable and shall not include the General Counsel as a party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The agency, or primary national subdivision, as the case may be, which issued the rule or regulation shall be a necessary party at any hearing under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except in any case to which subsection (b) of this section applies, if an agency involved in collective bargaining with an exclusive representative alleges that the duty to bargain in good faith does not extend to any matter, the exclusive representative may appeal the allegation to the Authority in accordance with the provisions of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The exclusive representative may, on or before the 15th day after the date on which the agency first makes the allegation referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection, institute an appeal under this subsection by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> filing a petition with the Authority; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> furnishing a copy of the petition to the head of the agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> On or before the 30th day after the date of the receipt by the head of the agency of the copy of the petition under paragraph (2)(B) of this subsection, the agency shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> file with the Authority a statement—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> withdrawing the allegation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> setting forth in full its reasons supporting the allegation; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> furnish a copy of such statement to the exclusive representative.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> On or before the 15th day after the date of the receipt by the exclusive representative of a copy of a statement under paragraph (3)(B) of this subsection, the exclusive representative shall file with the Authority its response to the statement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> A hearing may be held, in the discretion of the Authority, before a determination is made under this subsection. If a hearing is held, it shall not include the General Counsel as a party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Authority shall expedite proceedings under this subsection to the extent practicable and shall issue to the exclusive representative and to the agency a written decision on the allegation and specific reasons therefor at the earliest practicable date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A labor organization which is the exclusive representative of a substantial number of employees, determined in accordance with criteria prescribed by the Authority, shall be granted consultation rights by any agency with respect to any Government-wide rule or regulation issued by the agency effecting any substantive change in any condition of employment. Such consultation rights shall terminate when the labor organization no longer meets the criteria prescribed by the Authority. Any issue relating to a labor organization’s eligibility for, or continuation of, such consultation rights shall be subject to determination by the Authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A labor organization having consultation rights under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be informed of any substantive change in conditions of employment proposed by the agency, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be permitted reasonable time to present its views and recommendations regarding the changes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> If any views or recommendations are presented under paragraph (2) of this subsection to an agency by any labor organization—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the agency shall consider the views or recommendations before taking final action on any matter with respect to which the views or recommendations are presented; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the agency shall provide the labor organization a written statement of the reasons for taking the final action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7118.</num>
<heading> Prevention of unfair labor practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If any agency or labor organization is charged by any person with having engaged in or engaging in an unfair labor practice, the General Counsel shall investigate the charge and may issue and cause to be served upon the agency or labor organization a complaint. In any case in which the General Counsel does not issue a complaint because the charge fails to state an unfair labor practice, the General Counsel shall provide the person making the charge a written statement of the reasons for not issuing a complaint.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Any complaint under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall contain a notice—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> of the charge;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that a hearing will be held before the Authority (or any member thereof or before an individual employed by the authority and designated for such purpose); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> of the time and place fixed for the hearing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The labor organization or agency involved shall have the right to file an answer to the original and any amended complaint and to appear in person or otherwise and give testimony at the time and place fixed in the complaint for the hearing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, no complaint shall be issued based on any alleged unfair labor practice which occurred more than 6 months before the filing of the charge with the Authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If the General Counsel determines that the person filing any charge was prevented from filing the charge during the 6-month period referred to in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph by reason of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any failure of the agency or labor organization against which the charge is made to perform a duty owed to the person, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any concealment which prevented discovery of the alleged unfair labor practice during the 6-month period,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the General Counsel may issue a complaint based on the charge if the charge was filed during the 6-month period beginning on the day of the discovery by the person of the alleged unfair labor practice.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The General Counsel may prescribe regulations providing for informal methods by which the alleged unfair labor practice may be resolved prior to the issuance of a complaint.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Authority (or any member thereof or any individual employed by the Authority and designated for such purpose) shall conduct a hearing on the complaint not earlier than 5 days after the date on which the complaint is served. In the discretion of the individual or individuals conducting the hearing, any person involved may be allowed to intervene in the hearing and to present testimony. Any such hearing shall, to the extent practicable, be conducted in accordance with the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of this title, except that the parties shall not be bound by rules of evidence, whether statutory, common law, or adopted by a court. A transcript shall be kept of the hearing. After such a hearing the Authority, in its discretion, may upon notice receive further evidence or hear argument.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> If the Authority (or any member thereof or any individual employed by the Authority and designated for such purpose) determines after any hearing on a complaint under paragraph (5) of this subsection that the preponderance of the evidence received demonstrates that the agency or labor organization named in the complaint has engaged in or is engaging in an unfair labor practice, then the individual or individuals conducting the hearing shall state in writing their findings of fact and shall issue and cause to be served on the agency or labor organization an order—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to cease and desist from any such unfair labor practice in which the agency or labor organization is engaged;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> requiring the parties to renegotiate a collective bargaining agreement in accordance with the order of the Authority and requiring that the agreement, as amended, be given retroactive effect;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> requiring reinstatement of an employee with backpay in accordance with <ref>section 5596 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> including any combination of the actions described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of this paragraph or such other action as will carry out the purpose of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">If any such order requires reinstatement of an employee with backpay, backpay may be required of the agency (as provided in <ref>section 5596 of this title</ref>) or of the labor organization, as the case may be, which is found to have engaged in the unfair labor practice involved.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> If the individual or individuals conducting the hearing determine that the preponderance of the evidence received fails to demonstrate that the agency or labor organization named in the complaint has engaged in or is engaging in an unfair labor practice, the individual or individuals shall state in writing their findings of fact and shall issue an order dismissing the complaint.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In connection with any matter before the Authority in any proceeding under this section, the Authority may request, in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 7105(i) of this title</ref>, from the Director of the Office of Personnel Management an advisory opinion concerning the proper interpretation of rules, regulations, or other policy directives issued by the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1207</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7119.</num>
<heading> Negotiation impasses; Federal Service Impasses Panel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service shall provide services and assistance to agencies and exclusive representatives in the resolution of negotiation impasses. The Service shall determine under what circumstances and in what manner it shall provide services and assistance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> If voluntary arrangements, including the services of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service or any other third-party mediation, fail to resolve a negotiation impasse—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> either party may request the Federal Service Impasses Panel to consider the matter, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the parties may agree to adopt a procedure for binding arbitration of the negotiation impasse, but only if the procedure is approved by the Panel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Federal Service Impasses Panel is an entity within the Authority, the function of which is to provide assistance in resolving negotiation impasses between agencies and exclusive representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Panel shall be composed of a Chairman and at least six other members, who shall be appointed by the President, solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties and functions involved, from among individuals who are familiar with Government operations and knowledgeable in labor-management relations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Of the original members of the Panel, 2 members shall be appointed for a term of 1 year, 2 members shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, and the Chairman and the remaining members shall be appointed for a term of 5 years. Thereafter each member shall be appointed for a term of 5 years, except that an individual chosen to fill a vacancy shall be appointed for the unexpired term of the member replaced. Any member of the Panel may be removed by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Panel may appoint an Executive Director and any other individuals it may from time to time find necessary for the proper performance of its duties. Each member of the Panel who is not an employee (as defined in <ref>section 2105 of this title</ref>) is entitled to pay at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the maximum annual rate of basic pay then currently paid under the General Schedule for each day he is engaged in the performance of official business of the Panel, including travel time, and is entitled to travel expenses as provided under <ref>section 5703 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Panel or its designee shall promptly investigate any impasse presented to it under subsection (b) of this section. The Panel shall consider the impasse and shall either—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> recommend to the parties procedures for the resolution of the impasse; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assist the parties in resolving the impasse through whatever methods and procedures, including factfinding and recommendations, it may consider appropriate to accomplish the purpose of this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If the parties do not arrive at a settlement after assistance by the Panel under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the Panel may—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> hold hearings;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> administer oaths, take the testimony or deposition of any person under oath, and issue subpenas as provided in <ref>section 7132 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> take whatever action is necessary and not inconsistent with this chapter to resolve the impasse.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Notice of any final action of the Panel under this section shall be promptly served upon the parties, and the action shall be binding on such parties during the term of the agreement, unless the parties agree otherwise.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7120.</num>
<heading> Standards of conduct for labor organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> An agency shall only accord recognition to a labor organization that is free from corrupt influences and influences opposed to basic democratic principles. Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, an organization is not required to prove that it is free from such influences if it is subject to governing requirements adopted by the organization or by a national or international labor organization or federation of labor organizations with which it is affiliated, or in which it participates, containing explicit and detailed provisions to which it subscribes calling for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the maintenance of democratic procedures and practices including provisions for periodic elections to be conducted subject to recognized safeguards and provisions defining and securing the right of individual members to participate in the affairs of the organization, to receive fair and equal treatment under the governing rules of the organization, and to receive fair process in disciplinary proceedings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the exclusion from office in the organization of persons affiliated with communist or other totalitarian movements and persons identified with corrupt influences;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the prohibition of business or financial interests on the part of organization officers and agents which conflict with their duty to the organization and its members; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the maintenance of fiscal integrity in the conduct of the affairs of the organization, including provisions for accounting and financial controls and regular financial reports or summaries to be made available to members.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding the fact that a labor organization has adopted or subscribed to standards of conduct as provided in subsection (a) of this section, the organization is required to furnish evidence of its freedom from corrupt influences or influences opposed to basic democratic principles if there is reasonable cause to believe that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the organization has been suspended or expelled from, or is subject to other sanction, by a parent labor organization, or federation of organizations with which it had been affiliated, because it has demonstrated an unwillingness or inability to comply with governing requirements comparable in purpose to those required by subsection (a) of this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the organization is in fact subject to influences that would preclude recognition under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A labor organization which has or seeks recognition as a representative of employees under this chapter shall file financial and other reports with the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Labor Management Relations, provide for bonding of officials and employees of the organization, and comply with trusteeship and election standards.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Assistant Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this section. Such regulations shall conform generally to the principles applied to labor organizations in the private sector. Complaints of violations of this section shall be filed with the Assistant Secretary. In any matter arising under this section, the Assistant Secretary may require a labor organization to cease and desist from violations of this section and require it to take such actions as he considers appropriate to carry out the policies of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> This chapter does not authorize participation in the management of a labor organization or acting as a representative of a labor organization by a management official, a supervisor, or a confidential employee, except as specifically provided in this chapter, or by an employee if the participation or activity would result in a conflict or apparent conflict of interest or would otherwise be incompatible with law or with the official duties of the employee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of any labor organization which by omission or commission has willfully and intentionally, with regard to any strike, work stoppage, or slowdown, violated <ref>section 7116(b)(7) of this title</ref>, the Authority shall, upon an appropriate finding by the Authority of such violation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> revoke the exclusive recognition status of the labor organization, which shall then immediately cease to be legally entitled and obligated to represent employees in the unit; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> take any other appropriate disciplinary action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>GRIEVANCES, APPEALS, AND REVIEW</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7121.</num>
<heading> Grievance procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, any collective bargaining agreement shall provide procedures for the settlement of grievances, including questions of arbitrability. Except as provided in subsections (d), (e), and (g) of this section, the procedures shall be the exclusive administrative procedures for resolving grievances which fall within its coverage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any collective bargaining agreement may exclude any matter from the application of the grievance procedures which are provided for in the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Any negotiated grievance procedure referred to in subsection (a) of this section shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be fair and simple,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for expeditious processing, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> include procedures that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assure an exclusive representative the right, in its own behalf or on behalf of any employee in the unit represented by the exclusive representative, to present and process grievances;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assure such an employee the right to present a grievance on the employee’s own behalf, and assure the exclusive representative the right to be present during the grievance proceeding; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> provide that any grievance not satisfactorily settled under the negotiated grievance procedure shall be subject to binding arbitration which may be invoked by either the exclusive representative or the agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The provisions of a negotiated grievance procedure providing for binding arbitration in accordance with paragraph (1)(C)(iii) shall, if or to the extent that an alleged prohibited personnel practice is involved, allow the arbitrator to order—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a stay of any personnel action in a manner similar to the manner described in section 1221(c) with respect to the Merit Systems Protection Board; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the taking, by an agency, of any disciplinary action identified under section 1215(a)(3) that is otherwise within the authority of such agency to take.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any employee who is the subject of any disciplinary action ordered under subparagraph (A)(ii) may appeal such action to the same extent and in the same manner as if the agency had taken the disciplinary action absent arbitration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The preceding subsections of this section shall not apply with respect to any grievance concerning—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any claimed violation of subchapter III of chapter 73 of this title (relating to prohibited political activities);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> retirement, life insurance, or health insurance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a suspension or removal under <ref>section 7532 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any examination, certification, or appointment; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the classification of any position which does not result in the reduction in grade or pay of an employee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> An aggrieved employee affected by a prohibited personnel practice under <ref>section 2302(b)(1) of this title</ref> which also falls under the coverage of the negotiated grievance procedure may raise the matter under a statutory procedure or the negotiated procedure, but not both. An employee shall be deemed to have exercised his option under this subsection to raise the matter under either a statutory procedure or the negotiated procedure at such time as the employee timely initiates an action under the applicable statutory procedure or timely files a grievance in writing, in accordance with the provisions of the parties’ negotiated procedure, whichever event occurs first. Selection of the negotiated procedure in no manner prejudices the right of an aggrieved employee to request the Merit Systems Protection Board to review the final decision pursuant to <ref>section 7702 of this title</ref> in the case of any personnel action that could have been appealed to the Board, or, where applicable, to request the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission to review a final decision in any other matter involving a complaint of discrimination of the type prohibited by any law administered by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Matters covered under sections 4303 and 7512 of this title which also fall within the coverage of the negotiated grievance procedure may, in the discretion of the aggrieved employee, be raised either under the appellate procedures of <ref>section 7701 of this title</ref> or under the negotiated grievance procedure, but not both. Similar matters which arise under other personnel systems applicable to employees covered by this chapter may, in the discretion of the aggrieved employee, be raised either under the appellate procedures, if any, applicable to those matters, or under the negotiated grievance procedure, but not both. An employee shall be deemed to have exercised his option under this subsection to raise a matter either under the applicable appellate procedures or under the negotiated grievance procedure at such time as the employee timely files a notice of appeal under the applicable appellate procedures or timely files a grievance in writing in accordance with the provisions of the parties’ negotiated grievance procedure, whichever event occurs first.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In matters covered under sections 4303 and 7512 of this title which have been raised under the negotiated grievance procedure in accordance with this section, an arbitrator shall be governed by <ref>section 7701(c)(1) of this title</ref>, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> In matters covered under sections 4303 and 7512 of this title which have been raised under the negotiated grievance procedure in accordance with this section, <ref>section 7703 of this title</ref> pertaining to judicial review shall apply to the award of an arbitrator in the same manner and under the same conditions as if the matter had been decided by the Board. In matters similar to those covered under sections 4303 and 7512 of this title which arise under other personnel systems and which an aggrieved employee has raised under the negotiated grievance procedure, judicial review of an arbitrator’s award may be obtained in the same manner and on the same basis as could be obtained of a final decision in such matters raised under applicable appellate procedures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> This subsection applies with respect to a prohibited personnel practice other than a prohibited personnel practice to which subsection (d) applies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An aggrieved employee affected by a prohibited personnel practice described in paragraph (1) may elect not more than one of the remedies described in paragraph (3) with respect thereto. For purposes of the preceding sentence, a determination as to whether a particular remedy has been elected shall be made as set forth under paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The remedies described in this paragraph are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board under section 7701.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A negotiated grievance procedure under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Procedures for seeking corrective action under subchapters II and III of chapter 12.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of this subsection, a person shall be considered to have elected—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the remedy described in paragraph (3)(A) if such person has timely filed a notice of appeal under the applicable appellate procedures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the remedy described in paragraph (3)(B) if such person has timely filed a grievance in writing, in accordance with the provisions of the parties’ negotiated procedure; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the remedy described in paragraph (3)(C) if such person has sought corrective action from the Office of Special Counsel by making an allegation under section 1214(a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Settlements and awards under this chapter shall be subject to the limitations in <ref>section 5596(b)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1211</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–424, § 9</ref>, <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4365</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title XI, § 1104(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2142</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7122.</num>
<heading> Exceptions to arbitral awards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Either party to arbitration under this chapter may file with the Authority an exception to any arbitrator’s award pursuant to the arbitration (other than an award relating to a matter described in <ref>section 7121(f) of this title</ref>). If upon review the Authority finds that the award is deficient—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> because it is contrary to any law, rule, or regulation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on other grounds similar to those applied by Federal courts in private sector labor-management relations;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Authority may take such action and make such recommendations concerning the award as it considers necessary, consistent with applicable laws, rules, or regulations.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If no exception to an arbitrator’s award is filed under subsection (a) of this section during the 30-day period beginning on the date the award is served on the party, the award shall be final and binding. An agency shall take the actions required by an arbitrator’s final award. The award may include the payment of backpay (as provided in <ref>section 5596 of this title</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1212</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–224, § 4</ref>, <date date="1984-03-02">Mar. 2, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 48</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7123.</num>
<heading> Judicial review; enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Any person aggrieved by any final order of the Authority other than an order under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content><ref>section 7122 of this title</ref> (involving an award by an arbitrator), unless the order involves an unfair labor practice under <ref>section 7118 of this title</ref>, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>section 7112 of this title</ref> (involving an appropriate unit determination),</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">may, during the 60-day period beginning on the date on which the order was issued, institute an action for judicial review of the Authority’s order in the United States court of appeals in the circuit in which the person resides or transacts business or in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Authority may petition any appropriate United States court of appeals for the enforcement of any order of the Authority and for appropriate temporary relief or restraining order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Upon the filing of a petition under subsection (a) of this section for judicial review or under subsection (b) of this section for enforcement, the Authority shall file in the court the record in the proceedings, as provided in <ref>section 2112 of title 28</ref>. Upon the filing of the petition, the court shall cause notice thereof to be served to the parties involved, and thereupon shall have jurisdiction of the proceeding and of the question determined therein and may grant any temporary relief (including a temporary restraining order) it considers just and proper, and may make and enter a decree affirming and enforcing, modifying and enforcing as so modified, or setting aside in whole or in part the order of the Authority. The filing of a petition under subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall not operate as a stay of the Authority’s order unless the court specifically orders the stay. Review of the Authority’s order shall be on the record in accordance with <ref>section 706 of this title</ref>. No objection that has not been urged before the Authority, or its designee, shall be considered by the court, unless the failure or neglect to urge the objection is excused because of extraordinary circumstances. The findings of the Authority with respect to questions of fact, if supported by substantial evidence on the record considered as a whole, shall be conclusive. If any person applies to the court for leave to adduce additional evidence and shows to the satisfaction of the court that the additional evidence is material and that there were reasonable grounds for the failure to adduce the evidence in the hearing before the Authority, or its designee, the court may order the additional evidence to be taken before the Authority, or its designee, and to be made a part of the record. The Authority may modify its findings as to the facts, or make new findings by reason of additional evidence so taken and filed. The Authority shall file its modified or new findings, which, with respect to questions of fact, if supported by substantial evidence on the record considered as a whole, shall be conclusive. The Authority shall file its recommendations, if any, for the modification or setting aside of its original order. Upon the filing of the record with the court, the jurisdiction of the court shall be exclusive and its judgment and decree shall be final, except that the judgment and decree shall be subject to review by the Supreme Court of the United States upon writ of certiorari or certification as provided in <ref>section 1254 of title 28</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Authority may, upon issuance of a complaint as provided in <ref>section 7118 of this title</ref> charging that any person has engaged in or is engaging in an unfair labor practice, petition any United States district court within any district in which the unfair labor practice in question is alleged to have occurred or in which such person resides or transacts business for appropriate temporary relief (including a restraining order). Upon the filing of the petition, the court shall cause notice thereof to be served upon the person, and thereupon shall have jurisdiction to grant any temporary relief (including a temporary restraining order) it considers just and proper. A court shall not grant any temporary relief under this section if it would interfere with the ability of the agency to carry out its essential functions or if the Authority fails to establish probable cause that an unfair labor practice is being committed.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1213</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATIVE AND OTHER PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7131.</num>
<heading> Official time</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any employee representing an exclusive representative in the negotiation of a collective bargaining agreement under this chapter shall be authorized official time for such purposes, including attendance at impasse proceeding, during the time the employee otherwise would be in a duty status. The number of employees for whom official time is authorized under this subsection shall not exceed the number of individuals designated as representing the agency for such purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any activities performed by any employee relating to the internal business of a labor organization (including the solicitation of membership, elections of labor organization officials, and collection of dues) shall be performed during the time the employee is in a non-duty status.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, the Authority shall determine whether any employee participating for, or on behalf of, a labor organization in any phase of proceedings before the Authority shall be authorized official time for such purpose during the time the employee otherwise would be in a duty status.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in the preceding subsections of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any employee representing an exclusive representative, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in connection with any other matter covered by this chapter, any employee in an appropriate unit represented by an exclusive representative,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be granted official time in any amount the agency and the exclusive representative involved agree to be reasonable, necessary, and in the public interest.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1214</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7132.</num>
<heading> Subpenas</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Any member of the Authority, the General Counsel, or the Panel, any administrative law judge appointed by the Authority under <ref>section 3105 of this title</ref>, and any employee of the Authority designated by the Authority may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> issue subpenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of documentary or other evidence from any place in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> administer oaths, take or order the taking of depositions, order responses to written interrogatories, examine witnesses, and receive evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">No subpena shall be issued under this section which requires the disclosure of intramanagement guidance, advice, counsel, or training within an agency or between an agency and the Office of Personnel Management.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In the case of contumacy or failure to obey a subpena issued under subsection (a)(1) of this section, the United States district court for the judicial district in which the person to whom the subpena is addressed resides or is served may issue an order requiring such person to appear at any designated place to testify or to produce documentary or other evidence. Any failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court as a contempt thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Witnesses (whether appearing voluntarily or under subpena) shall be paid the same fee and mileage allowances which are paid subpenaed witnesses in the courts of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1214</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7133.</num>
<heading> Compilation and publication of data</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Authority shall maintain a file of its proceedings and copies of all available agreements and arbitration decisions, and shall publish the texts of its decisions and the actions taken by the Panel under <ref>section 7119 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> All files maintained under subsection (a) of this section shall be open to inspection and reproduction in accordance with the provisions of sections 552 and 552a of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7134.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Authority, the General Counsel, the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Labor Management Relations, and the Panel shall each prescribe rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this chapter applicable to each of them, respectively. Provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of this title shall be applicable to the issuance, revision, or repeal of any such rule or regulation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7135.</num>
<heading> Continuation of existing laws, recognitions, agreements, and procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing contained in this chapter shall preclude—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the renewal or continuation of an exclusive recognition, certification of an exclusive representative, or a lawful agreement between an agency and an exclusive representative of its employees, which is entered into before the effective date of this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the renewal, continuation, or initial according of recognition for units of management officials or supervisors represented by labor organizations which historically or traditionally represent management officials or supervisors in private industry and which hold exclusive recognition for units of such officials or supervisors in any agency on the effective date of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Policies, regulations, and procedures established under and decisions issued under Executive Orders 11491, 11616, 11636, 11787, and 11838, or under any other Executive order, as in effect on the effective date of this chapter, shall remain in full force and effect until revised or revoked by the President, or unless superseded by specific provisions of this chapter or by regulations or decisions issued pursuant to this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 7151 to 7154.</num>
<heading> Transferred]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>