<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 11—</num>
<heading>ACQUISITIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1101.</num>
<heading> Acquisition directorate</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall establish an acquisition directorate to provide guidance and oversight for the implementation and management of all Coast Guard acquisition processes, programs, and projects.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mission</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The mission of the acquisition directorate is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to acquire and deliver assets and systems that increase operational readiness, enhance mission performance, and create a safe working environment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assist in the development of a workforce that is trained and qualified to further the Coast Guard’s missions and deliver the best-value products and services to the Nation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to meet the needs of customers of major acquisition programs in the most cost-effective manner practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2931</ref>, § 561; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 899(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2333</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(c)(6)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2320</ref>; renumbered § 1101, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1102.</num>
<heading> Improvements in Coast Guard acquisition management</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Project or Program Managers.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Level 1 projects</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual may not be assigned as the project or program manager for a Level 1 acquisition unless the individual holds a Level III acquisition certification as a program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Level 2 projects</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An individual may not be assigned as the project or program manager for a Level 2 acquisition unless the individual holds a Level II acquisition certification as a program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Acquisition Workforce.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall designate a sufficient number of positions to be in the Coast Guard’s acquisition workforce to perform acquisition-related functions at Coast Guard headquarters and field activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required positions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In designating positions under subsection (a), the Commandant shall include, at a minimum, positions encompassing the following competencies and functions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Program management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Systems planning, research, development, engineering, and testing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Procurement, including contracting.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Industrial and contract property management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Life-cycle logistics.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Quality control and assurance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Manufacturing and production.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Business, cost estimating, financial management, and auditing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Acquisition education, training, and career development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Construction and facilities engineering.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> Testing and evaluation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisition management headquarter activities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall also designate as positions in the acquisition workforce under paragraph (1) those acquisition-related positions located at Coast Guard headquarters units.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate expertise required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall ensure that each individual assigned to a position in the acquisition workforce has the appropriate expertise to carry out the responsibilities of that position.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Management Information System.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall establish a management information system capability to improve acquisition workforce management and reporting.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Information maintained</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Information maintained with such capability shall include the following standardized information on individuals assigned to positions in the workforce:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Qualifications, assignment history, and tenure of those individuals assigned to positions in the acquisition workforce or holding acquisition-related certifications.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Promotion rates for officers and members of the Coast Guard in the acquisition workforce.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointments to Acquisition Positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall ensure that no requirement or preference for officers or members of the Coast Guard is used in the consideration of individuals for positions in the acquisition workforce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Career Paths.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Identification of career paths</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>To establish acquisition management as a core competency of the Coast Guard, the Commandant shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> ensure that career paths for officers, members, and employees of the Coast Guard who wish to pursue careers in acquisition are identified in terms of the education, training, experience, and assignments necessary for career progression of those officers, members, and employees to the most senior positions in the acquisition workforce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> publish information on such career paths.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Promotion parity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall ensure that promotion parity is established for officers and members of the Coast Guard who have been assigned to the acquisition workforce relative to officers and members who have not been assigned to the acquisition workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2931</ref>, § 562; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–330, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 210(c)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1551</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 899(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2333</ref>; renumbered § 1102, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(10), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1103.</num>
<heading> Role of Vice Commandant in major acquisition programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Vice Commandant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall represent the customer of a major acquisition program with regard to trade-offs made among cost, schedule, technical feasibility, and performance with respect to such program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall advise the Commandant in decisions regarding the balancing of resources against priorities, and associated trade-offs referred to in paragraph (1), on behalf of the customer of a major acquisition program.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 899(b)(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2334</ref>, § 578; renumbered § 1103, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1104.</num>
<heading> Recognition of Coast Guard personnel for excellence in acquisition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall maintain a program to recognize excellent performance by individuals and teams comprised of officers, members, and employees of the Coast Guard that contributed to the long-term success of a Coast Guard acquisition project or program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The program shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specific award categories, criteria, and eligibility and manners of recognition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> procedures for the nomination by personnel of the Coast Guard of individuals and teams comprised of officers, members, and employees of the Coast Guard for recognition under the program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> procedures for the evaluation of nominations for recognition under the program by one or more panels of individuals from the Government, academia, and the private sector who have such expertise and are appointed in such manner as the Commandant shall establish for the purposes of this program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Award of Cash Bonuses</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As part of the program required by subsection (a), the Commandant, subject to the availability of appropriations, may award to any civilian employee recognized pursuant to the program a cash bonus to the extent that the performance of such individual so recognized warrants the award of such bonus.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2934</ref>, § 563; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–330, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 899(b)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2333</ref>; renumbered § 1104, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1105.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on use of lead systems integrators</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of lead systems integrator</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may not use a private sector entity as a lead systems integrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Full and open competition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall use full and open competition for any acquisition contract unless otherwise excepted in accordance with Federal acquisition laws and regulations promulgated under those laws, including the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No effect on small business act</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to supersede or otherwise affect the authorities provided by and under the Small Business Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 631</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Financial Interest in Subcontractors</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Neither an entity performing lead systems integrator functions for a Coast Guard acquisition nor a Tier 1 subcontractor for any acquisition may have a financial interest in a subcontractor below the Tier 1 subcontractor level unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the subcontractor was selected by the prime contractor through full and open competition for such procurement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the procurement was awarded by an entity performing lead systems integrator functions or a subcontractor through full and open competition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the procurement was awarded by a subcontractor through a process over which the entity performing lead systems integrator functions or a Tier 1 subcontractor exercised no control; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Commandant has determined that the procurement was awarded in a manner consistent with Federal acquisition laws and regulations promulgated under those laws, including the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2935</ref>, § 564; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–330, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 217(7)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1557</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 899(b)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2333</ref>; renumbered § 1105 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, title III, § 304(d), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>, 4245.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1106.</num>
<heading> Required contract terms</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall ensure that a contract awarded or a delivery order or task order issued for an acquisition of a capability or an asset with an expected service life of 10 or more years and with a total acquisition cost that is equal to or exceeds $10,000,000—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provides that all certifications for an end-state capability or asset under such contract, delivery order, or task order, respectively, will be conducted by the Commandant or an independent third party, and that self-certification by a contractor or subcontractor is not allowed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provides that the Commandant shall maintain the authority to establish, approve, and maintain technical requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> requires that any measurement of contractor and subcontractor performance be based on the status of all work performed, including the extent to which the work performed met all performance, cost, and schedule requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> specifies that, for the acquisition or upgrade of air, surface, or shore capabilities and assets for which compliance with TEMPEST certification is a requirement, the standard for determining such compliance will be the air, surface, or shore standard then used by the Department of the Navy for that type of capability or asset; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> for any contract awarded to acquire an Offshore Patrol Cutter, includes provisions specifying the service life, fatigue life, and days underway in general Atlantic and North Pacific Sea conditions, maximum range, and maximum speed the cutter will be built to achieve.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Prohibited Provisions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall ensure that any contract awarded or delivery order or task order issued by the Coast Guard does not include any provision allowing for equitable adjustment that is not consistent with the Federal Acquisition Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Extension of program</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A contract, contract modification, or award term extending a contract with a lead systems integrator—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may not include any minimum requirements for the purchase of a given or determinable number of specific capabilities or assets; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be reviewed by an independent third party with expertise in acquisition management, and the results of that review shall be submitted to the appropriate congressional committees at least 60 days prior to the award of the contract, contract modification, or award term.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Integrated Product Teams</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Integrated product teams, and all teams that oversee integrated product teams, shall be chaired by officers, members, or employees of the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Technical Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall maintain or designate the technical authority to establish, approve, and maintain technical requirements. Any such designation shall be made in writing and may not be delegated to the authority of the Chief Acquisition Officer established by <ref>section 308 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2936</ref>, § 565; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–330, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3533(f)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2321</ref>; renumbered § 1106 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 108(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1107.</num>
<heading> Extension of major acquisition program contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 1105(a)(2) of this title</ref> and section 2304 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002014">1</ref> of title 10, and subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Secretary may acquire additional units procured under a Coast Guard major acquisition program contract, by extension of such contract without competition, if the Director of the Cost Analysis Division of the Department of Homeland Security determines that the costs that would be saved through award of a new contract in accordance with such sections would not exceed the costs of such an award.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Number of Additional Units</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The number of additional units acquired under a contract extension under this section may not exceed the number of additional units for which such determination is made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of Costs Upon Request</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director of the Cost Analysis Division of the Department of Homeland Security shall, at the request of the Secretary, determine for purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the costs that would be saved through award of a new major acquisition program contract in accordance with section 1105(a)(2) for the acquisition of a number of additional units specified by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the costs of such award, including the costs that would be incurred due to acquisition schedule delays and asset design changes associated with such award.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Number of Extensions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract may be extended under this section more than once.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 899(b)(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2334</ref>, § 579; renumbered § 1107 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 108(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1108.</num>
<heading> Department of Defense consultation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall make arrangements as appropriate with the Secretary of Defense for support in contracting and management of Coast Guard acquisition programs. The Commandant shall also seek opportunities to make use of Department of Defense contracts, and contracts of other appropriate agencies, to obtain the best possible price for assets acquired for the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interservice Technical Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall seek to maintain a memorandum of understanding or a memorandum of agreement with the Secretary of the Navy to obtain the assistance of the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Navy for Research, Development, and Acquisition, including the Navy Systems Command, with the oversight of Coast Guard major acquisition programs. The memorandum of understanding or memorandum of agreement shall, at a minimum, provide for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the exchange of technical assistance and support that the Assistant Commandants for Acquisition, Human Resources, Engineering, and Information technology may identify;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the use, as appropriate, of Navy technical expertise; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the temporary assignment or exchange of personnel between the Coast Guard and the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Navy for Research, Development, and Acquisition, including Naval Systems Command, to facilitate the development of organic capabilities in the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Technical Requirement Approval Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief Acquisition Officer shall adopt, to the extent practicable, procedures modeled after those used by the Navy Senior Acquisition Official to approve all technical requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2937</ref>, § 566; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–330, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3534</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2322</ref>; renumbered § 1108, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1109.</num>
<heading> Undefinitized contractual actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Coast Guard may not enter into an undefinitized contractual action unless such action is directly approved by the Head of Contracting Activity of the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requests for Undefinitized Contractual Actions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any request to the Head of Contracting Activity for approval of an undefinitized contractual action shall include a description of the anticipated effect on requirements of the Coast Guard if a delay is incurred for the purposes of determining contractual terms, specifications, and price before performance is begun under the contractual action.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Undefinitized Contractual Actions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deadline for agreement on terms, specifications, and price</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A contracting officer of the Coast Guard may not enter into an undefinitized contractual action unless the contractual action provides for agreement upon contractual terms, specification, and price by the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date on which the contractor submits a qualifying proposal to definitize the contractual terms, specifications, and price; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the amount of funds obligated under the contractual action is equal to more than 50 percent of the negotiated overall ceiling price for the contractual action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation on obligations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the contracting officer for an undefinitized contractual action may not obligate under such contractual action an amount that exceeds 50 percent of the negotiated overall ceiling price until the contractual terms, specifications, and price are definitized for such contractual action.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), if a contractor submits a qualifying proposal to definitize an undefinitized contractual action before an amount that exceeds 50 percent of the negotiated overall ceiling price is obligated on such action, the contracting officer for such action may not obligate with respect to such contractual action an amount that exceeds 75 percent of the negotiated overall ceiling price until the contractual terms, specifications, and price are definitized for such contractual action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant may waive the application of this subsection with respect to a contract if the Commandant determines that the waiver is necessary to support—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a contingency operation (as that term is defined in <ref>section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operations to prevent or respond to a transportation security incident (as defined in section 70101(6) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002015">1</ref> of title 46);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an operation in response to an emergency that poses an unacceptable threat to human health or safety or to the marine environment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an operation in response to a natural disaster or major disaster or emergency designated by the President under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection does not apply to an undefinitized contractual action for the purchase of initial spares.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inclusion of Nonurgent Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Requirements for spare parts and support equipment that are not needed on an urgent basis may not be included in an undefinitized contractual action by the Coast Guard for spare parts and support equipment that are needed on an urgent basis unless the Commandant approves such inclusion as being—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> good business practice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Modification of Scope</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The scope of an undefinitized contractual action under which performance has begun may not be modified unless the Commandant approves such modification as being—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> good business practice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Allowable Profit</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall ensure that the profit allowed on an undefinitized contractual action for which the final price is negotiated after a substantial portion of the performance required is completed reflects—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the possible reduced cost risk of the contractor with respect to costs incurred during performance of the contract before the final price is negotiated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the reduced cost risk of the contractor with respect to costs incurred during performance of the remaining portion of the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Undefinitized contractual action.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “undefinitized contractual action” means a new procurement action entered into by the Coast Guard for which the contractual terms, specifications, or price are not agreed upon before performance is begun under the action.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “undefinitized contractual action” does not include contractual actions with respect to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> foreign military sales;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> purchases in an amount not in excess of the amount of the simplified acquisition threshold; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> special access programs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifying proposal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “qualifying proposal” means a proposal that contains sufficient information to enable complete and meaningful audits of the information contained in the proposal as determined by the contracting officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2938</ref>, § 567; renumbered § 1109, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1110.</num>
<heading> Elevation of disputes to the Chief Acquisition Officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, after 90 days following the elevation to the Chief Acquisition Officer of any design or other dispute regarding level 1 or level 2 acquisition, the dispute remains unresolved, the Commandant shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a detailed description of the issue and the rationale underlying the decision taken by the Chief Acquisition Officer to resolve the issue.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8501(a)(5), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4745</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1111.</num>
<heading> Acquisition workforce authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Expedited Hiring Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For the purposes of <ref>section 3304 of title 5</ref>, the Commandant may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> designate any category of acquisition positions within the Coast Guard as shortage category positions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> use the authorities in such section to recruit and appoint highly qualified persons directly to positions so designated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall include in reports under section 1102 information described in such section regarding positions designated under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reemployment Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), if an annuitant receiving an annuity from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund becomes employed in any category of acquisition positions designated by the Commandant under subsection (a), the annuity of the annuitant so employed shall continue. The annuitant so reemployed shall not be considered an employee for purposes of subchapter III of chapter 83 or chapter 84 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Election</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An annuitant retired under section 8336(d)(1) or 8414(b)(1)(A) of title 5, receiving an annuity from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund, who becomes employed in any category of acquisition positions designated by the Commandant under subsection (a) after the date of the enactment of the Elijah E. Cummings Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2020, may elect to be subject to section 8344 or 8468 of such title (as the case may be).</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An election for coverage under this subsection shall be filed not later than 90 days after the Commandant takes reasonable actions to notify an employee who may file an election.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coverage</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an employee files an election under this subsection, coverage shall be effective beginning on the first day of the first applicable pay period beginning on or after the date of the filing of the election.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Paragraph (1) shall apply to an individual who is eligible to file an election under subparagraph (A) and does not file a timely election under clause (i) of such subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8219(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4655</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>IMPROVED ACQUISITION PROCESS AND PROCEDURES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1131.</num>
<heading> Identification of major system acquisitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support mechanisms</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall develop and implement mechanisms to support the establishment of mature and stable operational requirements for all acquisitions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Mission analysis; affordability assessment</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant may not initiate a Level 1 or Level 2 acquisition project or program until the Commandant—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> completes a mission analysis that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> identifies the specific capability gaps to be addressed by the project or program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> develops a clear mission need to be addressed by the project or program; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prepares a preliminary affordability assessment for the project or program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Elements.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The mechanisms required by subsection (a) shall ensure the implementation of a formal process for the development of a mission-needs statement, concept-of-operations document, capability development plan, and resource proposal for the initial project or program funding, and shall ensure the project or program is included in the Coast Guard Capital Investment Plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Assessment of trade-offs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In conducting an affordability assessment under subsection (a)(2)(B), the Commandant shall develop and implement mechanisms to ensure that trade-offs among cost, schedule, and performance are considered in the establishment of preliminary operational requirements for development and production of new assets and capabilities for Level 1 and Level 2 acquisitions projects and programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Human Resource Capital Planning</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall develop staffing predictions, define human capital performance initiatives, and identify preliminary training needs required to implement each Level 1 and Level 2 acquisition project and program.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2941</ref>, § 571; renumbered § 1131, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1132.</num>
<heading> Acquisition</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant may not establish a Level 1 or Level 2 acquisition project or program until the Commandant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> clearly defines the operational requirements for the project or program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establishes the feasibility of alternatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> develops an acquisition project or program baseline;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> produces a life-cycle cost estimate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> assesses the relative merits of alternatives to determine a preferred solution in accordance with the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission Required Before Proceeding</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any Coast Guard Level 1 or Level 2 acquisition project or program may not begin to obtain any capability or asset or proceed beyond that phase of its development that entails approving the supporting acquisition until the Commandant submits to the appropriate congressional committees the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The key performance parameters, the key system attributes, and the operational performance attributes of the capability or asset to be acquired under the proposed acquisition project or program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A detailed list of the systems or other capabilities with which the capability or asset to be acquired is intended to be interoperable, including an explanation of the attributes of interoperability.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The anticipated acquisition project or program baseline and acquisition unit cost for the capability or asset to be acquired under the project or program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A detailed schedule for the acquisition process showing when all capability and asset acquisitions are to be completed and when all acquired capabilities and assets are to be initially and fully deployed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Analysis of Alternatives.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Coast Guard may not acquire an experimental or technically immature capability or asset or implement a Level 1 or Level 2 acquisition project or program, unless it has prepared an analysis of alternatives for the capability or asset to be acquired in the concept and technology development phase of the acquisition process for the capability or asset.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The analysis of alternatives shall be prepared by a federally funded research and development center, a qualified entity of the Department of Defense, or a similar independent third-party entity that has appropriate acquisition expertise and has no financial interest in any part of the acquisition project or program that is the subject of the analysis. At a minimum, the analysis of alternatives shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an assessment of the technical maturity of the capability or asset, and technical and other risks;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an examination of capability, interoperability, and other advantages and disadvantages;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an evaluation of whether different combinations or quantities of specific assets or capabilities could meet the Coast Guard’s overall performance needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a discussion of key assumptions and variables, and sensitivity to change in such assumptions and variables;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> when an alternative is an existing capability, asset, or prototype, an evaluation of relevant safety and performance records and costs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> a calculation of life-cycle costs including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an examination of likely research and development costs and the levels of uncertainty associated with such estimated costs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an examination of likely production and deployment costs and the levels of uncertainty associated with such estimated costs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an examination of likely operating and support costs and the levels of uncertainty associated with such estimated costs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> if they are likely to be significant, an examination of likely disposal costs and the levels of uncertainty associated with such estimated costs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> such additional measures as the Commandant or the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating determines to be necessary for appropriate evaluation of the capability or asset; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the business case for each viable alternative.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Test and Evaluation Master Plan.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For any Level 1 or Level 2 acquisition project or program the Chief Acquisition Officer must approve a test and evaluation master plan specific to the acquisition project or program for the capability, asset, or subsystems of the capability or asset and intended to minimize technical, cost, and schedule risk as early as practicable in the development of the project or program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Test and evaluation strategy</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The master plan shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> set forth an integrated test and evaluation strategy that will verify that capability-level or asset-level and subsystem-level design and development, including performance and supportability, have been sufficiently proven before the capability, asset, or subsystem of the capability or asset is approved for production; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> require that adequate developmental tests and evaluations and operational tests and evaluations established under subparagraph (A) are performed to inform production decisions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other components of the master plan</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At a minimum, the master plan shall identify—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the key performance parameters to be resolved through the integrated test and evaluation strategy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the performance data to be used to determine whether the key performance parameters have been resolved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> critical operational issues to be assessed in addition to the key performance parameters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the results during test and evaluation that will be required to demonstrate that a capability, asset, or subsystem meets performance requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> specific development test and evaluation phases and the scope of each phase;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> modeling and simulation activities to be performed, if any, and the scope of such activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> early operational assessments to be performed, if any, and the scope of such assessments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> operational test and evaluation phases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an estimate of the resources, including funds, that will be required for all test, evaluation, assessment, modeling, and simulation activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the Government entity or independent entity that will perform the test, evaluation, assessment, modeling, and simulation activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Update</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Chief Acquisition Officer must approve an updated master plan whenever there is a revision to project or program test and evaluation strategy, scope, or phasing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Coast Guard may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> proceed beyond that phase of the acquisition process that entails approving the supporting acquisition of a capability or asset before the master plan is approved by the Chief Acquisition Officer; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> award any production contract for a capability, asset, or subsystem for which a master plan is required under this subsection before the master plan is approved by the Chief Acquisition Officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Life-Cycle Cost Estimates.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall implement mechanisms to ensure the development and regular updating of life-cycle cost estimates for each acquisition with a total acquisition cost that equals or exceeds $10,000,000 and an expected service life of 10 or more years, and to ensure that these estimates are considered in decisions to develop or produce new or enhanced capabilities and assets.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Types of estimates</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For each Level 1 or Level 2 acquisition project or program, in addition to life-cycle cost estimates developed under paragraph (1), the Commandant shall require that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> life-cycle cost estimates developed under paragraph (1) be updated before—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> each milestone decision is concluded; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the project or program enters a new acquisition phase; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an independent cost estimate or independent cost assessment, as appropriate, be developed to validate life-cycle cost estimates developed under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2942</ref>, § 572; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 34</ref>; renumbered § 1132, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11210</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4012</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1133.</num>
<heading> Preliminary development and demonstration</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall ensure that developmental test and evaluation, operational test and evaluation, life-cycle cost estimates, and the development and demonstration requirements applied by this chapter to acquisition projects and programs are met to confirm that the projects or programs meet the requirements identified in the mission-analysis and affordability assessment prepared under section 1131(a)(2), the operational requirements developed under section 1132(a)(1) and the following development and demonstration objectives:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To demonstrate that the design, manufacturing, and production solution is based upon a stable, producible, and cost-effective product design.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To ensure that the product capabilities meet contract specifications, acceptable operational performance requirements, and system security requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To ensure that the product design is mature enough to commit to full production and deployment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Tests and Evaluations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall ensure that the Coast Guard conducts developmental tests and evaluations and operational tests and evaluations of a capability or asset and the subsystems of the capability or asset in accordance with the master plan prepared for the capability or asset under section 1132(d)(1).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002016">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of third parties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall ensure that the Coast Guard uses independent third parties with expertise in testing and evaluating the capabilities or assets and the subsystems of the capabilities or assets being acquired to conduct developmental tests and evaluations and operational tests and evaluations whenever the Coast Guard lacks the capability to conduct the tests and evaluations required by a master plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Communication of safety concerns</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall ensure that independent third parties and Government employees that identify safety concerns during developmental or operational tests and evaluations or through independent or Government-conducted design assessments of capabilities or assets and subsystems of capabilities or assets to be acquired by the Coast Guard communicate such concerns as soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days after the completion of the test or assessment event or activity that identified the safety concern, to the program manager for the capability or asset and the subsystems concerned and to the Chief Acquisition Officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reporting of safety concerns</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall ensure that any safety concerns that have been communicated under paragraph (3) for an acquisition program or project are reported to the appropriate congressional committees at least 90 days before the award of any contract or issuance of any delivery order or task order for low, initial, or full-rate production of the capability or asset concerned if they will remain uncorrected or unmitigated at the time such a contract is awarded or delivery order or task order is issued. The report shall include a justification for the approval of that level of production of the capability or asset before the safety concerns are corrected or mitigated. The report shall also include an explanation of the actions that will be taken to correct or mitigate the safety concerns, the date by which those actions will be taken, and the adequacy of current funding to correct or mitigate the safety concerns.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Asset already in low, initial, or full-rate production</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall ensure that if an independent third party or a Government employee identifies a safety concern with a capability or asset or any subsystems of a capability or asset not previously identified during operational test and evaluation of a capability or asset already in low, initial, or full-rate production—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Commandant, through the Assistant Commandant for Capability, shall notify the program manager and the Chief Acquisition Officer of the safety concern as soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days after the completion of the test and evaluation event or activity that identified the safety concern; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the Deputy Commandant for Mission Support shall notify the Commandant and the Deputy Commandant for Operations of the safety concern within 50 days after the notification required under subparagraph (A), and include in such notification—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an explanation of the actions that will be taken to correct or mitigate the safety concern in all capabilities or assets and subsystems of the capabilities or assets yet to be produced, and the date by which those actions will be taken;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an explanation of the actions that will be taken to correct or mitigate the safety concern in previously produced capabilities or assets and subsystems of the capabilities or assets, and the date by which those actions will be taken; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an assessment of the adequacy of current funding to correct or mitigate the safety concern in capabilities or assets and subsystems of the capabilities or assets and in previously produced capabilities or assets and subsystems.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Technical Certification.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall ensure that any Level 1 or Level 2 acquisition project or program is certified by the technical authority of the Coast Guard after review by an independent third party with capabilities in the mission area, asset, or particular asset component.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">TEMPEST testing</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> cause all electronics on all aircraft, surface, and shore capabilities and assets that require TEMPEST certification to be tested in accordance with TEMPEST standards and communications security (comsec) standards by an independent third party that is authorized by the Federal Government to perform such testing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> certify that the assets meet all applicable TEMPEST requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Cutter classification.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall cause each cutter, other than a National Security Cutter, acquired by the Coast Guard and delivered after the date of enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2010 to be classed by the American Bureau of Shipping before final acceptance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>[(B)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 210(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1551</ref>.]</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other vessels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall cause the design and construction of each National Security Cutter, other than National Security Cutters 1, 2, and 3, to be assessed by an independent third party with expertise in vessel design and construction certification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Aircraft airworthiness</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall cause all aircraft and aircraft engines acquired by the Coast Guard to be assessed for airworthiness by an independent third party with expertise in aircraft and aircraft engine certification before final acceptance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2944</ref>, § 573; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 210(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1551</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2314</ref>; renumbered § 1133 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 108(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1134.</num>
<heading> Acquisition, production, deployment, and support</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensure there is a stable and efficient production and support capability to develop an asset or capability for the Coast Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conduct follow-on testing to confirm and monitor performance and correct deficiencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> conduct acceptance tests and trials prior to the delivery of each asset or system to ensure the delivered asset or system achieves full operational capability.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> execute production contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that delivered assets and capabilities meet operational cost and schedules requirements established in the acquisition program baseline;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> validate manpower and training requirements to meet system needs to operate, maintain, support, and instruct the assets or capabilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> prepare an acquisition project or program transition plan to enter into programmatic sustainment, operations, and support.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2947</ref>, § 574; renumbered § 1134, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1135.</num>
<heading> Acquisition program baseline breach</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives as soon as possible, but not later than 30 days, after the Chief Acquisition Officer of the Coast Guard becomes aware of the breach of an acquisition program baseline for any Level 1 or Level 2 acquisition program, by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a likely cost overrun greater than 15 percent of the acquisition program baseline for that individual capability or asset or a class of capabilities or assets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a likely delay of more than 180 days in the delivery schedule for any individual capability or asset or class of capabilities or assets; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an anticipated failure for any individual capability or asset or class of capabilities or assets to satisfy any key performance threshold or parameter under the acquisition program baseline.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The report submitted under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a detailed description of the breach and an explanation of its cause;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the projected impact to performance, cost, and schedule;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an updated acquisition program baseline and the complete history of changes to the original acquisition program baseline;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the updated acquisition schedule and the complete history of changes to the original schedule;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a full life-cycle cost analysis for the capability or asset or class of capabilities or assets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a remediation plan identifying corrective actions and any resulting issues or risks; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a description of how progress in the remediation plan will be measured and monitored.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Substantial Variances in Costs or Schedule</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a likely cost overrun is greater than 20 percent or a likely delay is greater than 12 months from the costs and schedule described in the acquisition program baseline for any Level 1 or Level 2 acquisition project or program of the Coast Guard, the Commandant shall include in the report a written determination, with a supporting explanation, of whether—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the capability or asset or capability or asset class to be acquired under the project or program is essential to the accomplishment of Coast Guard missions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> there are no alternatives to such capability or asset or capability or asset class that will provide equal or greater capability in both a more cost-effective and timely manner;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the new acquisition schedule and estimates for total acquisition cost are reasonable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the management structure for the acquisition program is adequate to manage and control performance, cost, and schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to Congress With Respect to Breach of Contract</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Not later than 48 hours after the Commandant becomes aware that a major acquisition contract cannot be carried out under the terms specified in the contract, the Commandant shall provide a written notification to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of the terms of the contract that cannot be met; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assessment of whether the applicable contract officer has issued a cease and desist order to the contractor based on the breach of such terms of the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2947</ref>, § 575; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3533(g)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2321</ref>; renumbered § 1135, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8221(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4657</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1136.</num>
<heading> Acquisition approval authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as altering or diminishing in any way the statutory authority and responsibility of the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, or the Secretary’s designee, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> manage and administer department procurements, including procurements by department components, as required by section 701 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref>6 U.S.C. 341</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> manage department acquisition activities and act as the Acquisition Decision Authority with regard to the review or approval of a Coast Guard Level 1 or Level 2 acquisition project or program, as required by section 16 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002017">1</ref> of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act (<ref>41 U.S.C. 414</ref>) and related implementing regulations and directives.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2948</ref>, § 576; renumbered § 1136, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1137.</num>
<heading> Contracting for major acquisitions programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out authorities provided to the Secretary to design, construct, accept, or otherwise acquire assets and systems under section 501(d), the Secretary, acting through the Commandant or the head of an integrated program office established for a major acquisition program, may enter into contracts for a major acquisition program and 3 Polar Security Cutters in addition to those approved as part of a major acquisition program on <date date="2019-11-01">November 1, 2019</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorized Methods</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Contracts entered into under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may be block buy contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may be incrementally funded;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> may include combined purchases, also known as economic order quantity purchases, of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> materials and components; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> long lead time materials; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> as provided in <ref>section 3501 of title 10</ref>, may be multiyear contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Subject to Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any contract entered into under subsection (a) shall provide that any obligation of the United States to make a payment under the contract is subject to the availability of amounts specifically provided in advance for that purpose in subsequent appropriations Acts.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title III, § 311(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4249</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXI</ref> [LXXXI], § 8111(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2156</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PROCUREMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1151.</num>
<heading> Restriction on construction of vessels in foreign shipyards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b), no Coast Guard vessel, and no major component of the hull or superstructure of a Coast Guard vessel, may be constructed in a foreign shipyard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The President may authorize exceptions to the prohibition in subsection (a) when the President determines that it is in the national security interest of the United States to do so. The President shall transmit notice to Congress of any such determination, and no contract may be made pursuant to the exception authorized until the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date the notice of such determination is received by Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–448, § 26(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-28">Sept. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1847</ref>, § 665; renumbered § 1151, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1152.</num>
<heading> Advance procurement funding</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>With respect to any Coast Guard vessel for which amounts are appropriated and any amounts otherwise made available for vessels for the Coast Guard in any fiscal year, the Commandant may enter into a contract or place an order, in advance of a contract or order for construction of a vessel, for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> materials, parts, components, and labor for the vessel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the advance construction of parts or components for the vessel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> protection and storage of materials, parts, or components for the vessel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> production planning, design, and other related support services that reduce the overall procurement lead time of the vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Materials, Parts, and Components Manufactured in the United States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In entering into contracts and placing orders under subsection (a), the Commandant may give priority to persons that manufacture materials, parts, and components in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1551</ref>, § 577; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(c)(7)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2320</ref>; renumbered § 1152, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1153.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on overhaul, repair, and maintenance of Coast Guard vessels in foreign shipyards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Coast Guard vessel the home port of which is in the United States or Guam may not be overhauled, repaired, or maintained in a shipyard outside the United States or Guam, other than in the case of voyage repairs.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title III, § 311(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3920</ref>, § 96; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 218</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2918</ref>; renumbered § 1153, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1154.</num>
<heading> Procurement of buoy chain</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (b), the Coast Guard may not procure buoy chain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that is not manufactured in the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> substantially all of the components of which are not produced or manufactured in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Coast Guard may procure buoy chain that is not manufactured in the United States if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the price of buoy chain manufactured in the United States is unreasonable; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> emergency circumstances exist.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title XI, § 1128(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3984</ref>, § 97; renumbered § 1154, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1155.</num>
<heading> Contract termination</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before terminating a procurement or acquisition contract with a total value of more than $1,000,000, the Commandant of the Coast Guard shall notify each vendor under such contract and require the vendor to maintain all work product related to the contract until the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not less than 1 year after the date of the notification; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date the Commandant notifies the vendor that maintenance of such work product is no longer required.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Work Product Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section the term “work product”—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> means tangible and intangible items and information produced or possessed as a result of a contract referred to in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any completed end items;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any uncompleted end items; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any property in the contractor’s possession in which the United States Government has an interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Penalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A vendor that fails to maintain work product as required under subsection (a) is liable to the United States for a civil penalty of not more than $25,000 for each day on which such work product is unavailable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in paragraph (2), not later than 45 days after the end of each fiscal year the Commandant of the Coast Guard shall provide to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report detailing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all Coast Guard contracts with a total value of more than $1,000,000 that were terminated in the fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all vendors who were notified under subsection (a)(1) in the fiscal year, and the date of such notification;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> all criminal, administrative, and other investigations regarding any contract with a total value of more than $1,000,000 that were initiated by the Coast Guard in the fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> all criminal, administrative, and other investigations regarding contracts with a total value of more than $1,000,000 that were completed by the Coast Guard in the fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an estimate of costs incurred by the Coast Guard, including contract line items and termination costs, as a result of the requirements of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant is not required to provide a report under paragraph (1) for any fiscal year for which there is no responsive information as described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3523(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2315</ref>, § 657; renumbered § 1155, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1156.</num>
<heading> Limitation on unmanned aircraft systems</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>During any fiscal year for which funds are appropriated for the design or construction of an Offshore Patrol Cutter, the Commandant—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may not award a contract for design of an unmanned aircraft system for use by the Coast Guard; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> may lease, acquire, or acquire the services of an unmanned aircraft system only if such system—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has been part of a program of record of, procured by, or used by a Federal entity (or funds for research, development, test, and evaluation have been received from a Federal entity with regard to such system) before the date on which the Commandant leases, acquires, or acquires the services of the system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is leased, acquired, or utilized by the Commandant through an agreement with a Federal entity, unless such an agreement is not practicable or would be less cost-effective than an independent contract action by the Coast Guard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Small Unmanned Aircraft Exemption</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subsection (a)(2) does not apply to small unmanned aircraft.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the terms “small unmanned aircraft” and “unmanned aircraft system” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 44801 of title 49</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title III, § 304(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4244</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVIII, § 11803(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4163</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1157.</num>
<heading> Extraordinary relief</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With respect to any prime contracting entity receiving extraordinary relief pursuant to the Act entitled “An Act to authorize the making, amendment, and modification of contracts to facilitate the national defense”, approved <date date="1958-08-28">August 28, 1958</date> (<ref>Public Law 85–804</ref>; <ref>50 U.S.C. 1432</ref> et seq.) for a major acquisition, the Secretary shall not consider any further request by the prime contracting entity for extraordinary relief under such Act for such major acquisition.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to Subcontractors</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The limitation under subsection (a) shall not apply to subcontractors of a prime contracting entity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Quarterly Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not less frequently than quarterly during each fiscal year in which extraordinary relief is approved or provided to an entity under the Act referred to in subsection (a) for the acquisition of Offshore Patrol Cutters, the Commandant shall provide to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that describes in detail such relief and the compliance of the entity with the oversight measures required as a condition of receiving such relief.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8221(a)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4657</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1158.</num>
<heading> Authority to enter into transactions other than contracts and grants to procure cost-effective, advanced technology for mission-critical needs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to subsections (b) and (c), the Commandant may enter into transactions (other than contracts, cooperative agreements, and grants) to operate, test, and acquire cost-effective technology for the purpose of meeting the mission needs of the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operation, Testing, and Acquisition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Operation, testing, and acquisition of technologies under subsection (a) shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carried out in accordance with Coast Guard policies and guidance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consistent with the operational requirements of the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant may not enter into a transaction under subsection (a) with respect to a technology that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> does not comply with the cybersecurity standards of the Coast Guard; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> is sourced from an entity domiciled in the People’s Republic of China, unless the Commandant determines that the prototype or procurement of such a technology is for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> counter-UAS or surrogate testing; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> intelligence, electronic warfare, and information warfare, testing, and analysis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Education and Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall ensure that management, technical, and contracting personnel of the Coast Guard involved in the award or administration of transactions under this section are provided adequate education and training with respect to the authority under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall prescribe regulations as necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Counter-UAS Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “counter-UAS” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 44801 of title 49</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11205(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4009</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>DEFINITIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1171.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chief acquisition officer</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Chief Acquisition Officer” means the officer appointed under <ref>section 308 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Customer of a major acquisition program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “customer of a major acquisition program” means the operating field unit of the Coast Guard that will field the system or systems acquired under a major acquisition program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Level 1 acquisition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “Level 1 acquisition” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> an acquisition by the Coast Guard—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the estimated life-cycle costs of which exceed $1,000,000,000; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the estimated total acquisition costs of which exceed $300,000,000; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> any acquisition that the Chief Acquisition Officer of the Coast Guard determines to have a special interest—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> due to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the experimental or technically immature nature of the asset;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the technological complexity of the asset;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the commitment of resources; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the nature of the capability or set of capabilities to be achieved; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> because such acquisition is a joint acquisition.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Level 2 acquisition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “Level 2 acquisition” means an acquisition by the Coast Guard—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the estimated life-cycle costs of which are equal to or less than $1,000,000,000, but greater than $300,000,000; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the estimated total acquisition costs of which are equal to or less than $300,000,000, but greater than $100,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Life-cycle cost</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “life-cycle cost” means all costs for development, procurement, construction, and operations and support for a particular capability or asset, without regard to funding source or management control.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Major acquisition program</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “major acquisition program” means an ongoing acquisition undertaken by the Coast Guard with a life-cycle cost estimate greater than or equal to $300,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Project or program manager defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “project or program manager” means an individual designated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to develop, produce, and deploy a new asset to meet identified operational requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to manage cost, schedule, and performance of the acquisition, project, or program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safety concern</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “safety concern” means any hazard associated with a capability or asset or a subsystem of a capability or asset that is likely to cause serious bodily injury or death to a typical Coast Guard user in testing, maintaining, repairing, or operating the capability, asset, or subsystem or any hazard associated with the capability, asset, or subsystem that is likely to cause major damage to the capability, asset, or subsystem during the course of its normal operation by a typical Coast Guard user.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Developmental test and evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “developmental test and evaluation” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the testing of a capability or asset and the subsystems of the capability or asset to determine whether they meet all contractual performance requirements, including technical performance requirements, supportability requirements, and interoperability requirements and related specifications; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the evaluation of the results of such testing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operational test and evaluation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “operational test and evaluation” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the testing of a capability or asset and the subsystems of the capability or asset, under conditions similar to those in which the capability or asset and subsystems will actually be deployed, for the purpose of determining the effectiveness and suitability of the capability or asset and subsystems for use by typical Coast Guard users to conduct those missions for which the capability or asset and subsystems are intended to be used; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the evaluation of the results of such testing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2948</ref>, § 581; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 209(8)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 41</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 899(b)(1)(F)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2334</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2320</ref>; renumbered § 1171 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 108(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4208</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>