<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 37—</num>
<heading>COAST GUARD RESERVE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3701.</num>
<heading> Organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Coast Guard Reserve is a component of the Coast Guard. It shall be organized, administered, trained, and supplied under the direction of the Commandant.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1003</ref>, § 701; renumbered § 3701, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3702.</num>
<heading> Authorized strength</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President shall prescribe the authorized strength of the Coast Guard Reserve if not otherwise prescribed by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subject to the authorized strength of the Coast Guard Reserve, the Secretary shall determine, at least annually, the authorized strength in numbers in each grade necessary to provide for mobilization requirements. Without the consent of the member concerned, a member of the Reserve may not be reduced in grade because of the Secretary’s determination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may vary the authorized end strength of the Coast Guard Selected Reserves for a fiscal year by a number equal to not more than 3 percent of such end strength upon a determination by the Secretary that varying such authorized end strength is in the national interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Commandant may increase the authorized end strength of the Coast Guard Selected Reserves by a number equal to not more than 2 percent of such authorized end strength upon a determination by the Commandant that such increase would enhance manning and readiness in essential units or in critical specialties or ratings.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1003</ref>, § 702; renumbered § 3702, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11234</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4034</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3703.</num>
<heading> Coast Guard Reserve Boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall convene a Coast Guard Reserve Policy Board at least annually to consider, recommend, and report to the Secretary on Reserve policy matters. At least one-half of the members of the Board shall be Reserve officers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary may convene any other Reserve Board the Secretary considers necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1003</ref>, § 703; renumbered § 3703, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3704.</num>
<heading> Grades and ratings; military authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The grades and ratings in the Reserve, including cadets but not grades above rear admiral, are those prescribed by law or regulation for the Coast Guard. A member of the Reserve on active duty or inactive-duty training has the same authority, rights, and privileges in the performance of that duty as a member of the Regular Coast Guard of corresponding grade or rating.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1003</ref>, § 704; renumbered § 3704, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3705.</num>
<heading> Benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A member of the Reserve on active duty, on inactive-duty training, or engaged in authorized travel to or from that duty, is entitled to the same benefits as a member of the Navy Reserve of corresponding grade, rating, and length of service. In determining length of service for the purpose of this section, there shall be included all service for which credit is given by law to members of the Regular Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Chapter 27 of this title applies to a member of the Reserve under the same conditions and limitations as it applies to a member of the Regular Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A member of the Reserve who suffers sickness, disease, disability, or death is entitled to the same benefits as prescribed by law for a member of the Navy Reserve who suffers sickness, disease, disability, or death under similar conditions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A member of the Reserve on active duty or when retired for disability is entitled to the benefits of <ref>section 253(a) of title 42</ref>. A member of the Reserve when on active duty (other than for training) or when retired for disability is entitled to the benefits of chapter 55 of title 10.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A member of the Reserve, except an enlisted member retiring on the basis of years of active service, is entitled to the same retirement rights, benefits, and privileges as prescribed by law for a member of the Navy Reserve, and wherever a law confers authority upon the Secretary of the Navy, similar authority is given to the Secretary to be exercised with respect to the Coast Guard when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy. An enlisted member of the Reserve who retires on the basis of years of active service is entitled to the same retirement rights, benefits, and privileges as prescribed by law for an enlisted member of the Regular Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> A member of the Coast Guard Reserve not on active duty who is enrolled in an officer candidate program authorized by <ref>section 12209 of title 10</ref> leading to a commission in the Coast Guard Reserve, and is a full-time student in an accredited college curriculum leading to a bachelor’s degree may be paid a subsistence allowance for each month of the member’s academic year at the same rate as that prescribed by <ref>section 209(a) of title 37</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1003</ref>, § 705; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–417, § 1</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2085</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(e)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3235</ref>; renumbered § 3705 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(c)(3), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4241.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3706.</num>
<heading> Temporary members of the Reserve; eligibility and compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A citizen of the United States, its territories, or possessions who is a member of the Auxiliary, an officer or member of the crew of a motorboat or yacht placed at the disposal of the Coast Guard, or an individual (including a Government employee without pay other than the compensation of that individual’s civilian position) who by reason of special training and experience is considered by the Commandant to be qualified for duty, may be enrolled by the Commandant as a temporary member of the Reserve, for duty under conditions the Commandant may prescribe, including part-time and intermittent active duty with or without pay, without regard to age. The Commandant is authorized to define the powers and duties of temporary members of the Reserve, and to confer upon them, appropriate to their qualifications and experience, the same grades and ratings as provided for members of the Reserve. When performing active duty with pay as authorized by this section, temporary members of the Reserve are entitled to receive the pay and allowances of their rank, grade, or rating.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1004</ref>, § 706; renumbered § 3706, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(50), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3707.</num>
<heading> Temporary members of the Reserve; disability or death benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> If a temporary member of the Reserve is physically injured, or dies as a result of physical injury, and the injury is incurred incident to service while performing active duty, or engaged in authorized travel to or from that duty, the law authorizing compensation for employees of the United States suffering injuries while in the performance of their duties, applies, subject to this section. That law shall be administered by the Secretary of Labor to the same extent as if the member was a civil employee of the United States and was injured in the performance of that duty. For benefit computation, regardless of pay or pay status, the member is considered to have had monthly pay of the monthly equivalent of the minimum rate of basic pay in effect for grade GS–9 of the General Schedule on the date the injury is incurred.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section does not apply if the workmen’s compensation law of a State, a territory, or another jurisdiction provides coverage because of a concurrent employment status of the temporary member. When the temporary member or a dependent is entitled to a benefit under this section and also to a concurrent benefit from the United States on account of the same disability or death, the temporary member or dependent, as appropriate, shall elect which benefit to receive.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If a claim is filed under this section with the Secretary of Labor for benefits because of an alleged injury or death, the Secretary of Labor shall notify the Commandant who shall direct an investigation into the facts surrounding the alleged injury or death. The Commandant shall then certify to the Secretary of Labor whether or not the injured or deceased individual was a temporary member of the Reserve, the individual’s military status, and whether or not the injury or death was incurred incident to military service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A temporary member of the Reserve, who incurs a physical disability or contracts sickness or disease while performing a duty to which the member has been assigned by competent authority, is entitled to the same hospital treatment afforded a member of the Regular Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> In administering <ref>section 8133 of title 5</ref>, for an individual covered by this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the percentages applicable to payments under that section are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 45 percent under subsection (a)(2) of that section, where the member died fully or currently insured under title II of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.), with no additional payments for a child or children so long as the widow or widower remains eligible for payments under that subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 20 percent under subsection (a)(3) of that section, for one child, and 10 percent additional for each additional child, not to exceed a total of 75 percent, where the member died fully or currently insured under title II of the Social Security Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 25 percent under subsection (a)(4) of that section, if one parent was wholly dependent for support upon the deceased member at the time of the member’s death and the other was not dependent to any extent; 16 percent to each if both were wholly dependent; and if one was, or both were, partly dependent, a proportionate amount in the discretion of the Secretary of Labor;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> payments may not be made under subsection (a)(5) of that section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Labor shall inform the Commissioner of Social Security whenever a claim is filed and eligibility for compensation is established under subsection (a)(2) or (a)(3) of <ref>section 8133 of title 5</ref>. The Commissioner of Social Security shall then certify to the Secretary of Labor whether or not the member concerned was fully or currently insured under title II of the Social Security Act at the time of the member’s death.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1004</ref>, § 707; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–136, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 2(21)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1303</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(g)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1487</ref>; renumbered § 3707, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(51), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3708.</num>
<heading> Temporary members of the Reserve; certificate of honorable service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In recognition of the service of temporary members of the Reserve, the Secretary may upon request issue an appropriate certificate of honorable service in lieu of a certificate of disenrollment issued to any individual following disenrollment under honorable conditions from service as a temporary member. Issuance of a certificate of honorable service to any individual under this section does not entitle that individual to any rights, privileges, or benefits under any law of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1005</ref>, § 708; renumbered § 3708, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(52), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3709.</num>
<heading> Reserve student aviation pilots; Reserve aviation pilots; appointments in commissioned grade</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary an enlisted member of the Reserve may be designated as a student aviation pilot.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A member who is not a qualified aviator may not be designated as a student aviation pilot unless the member agrees in writing to serve on active duty for a period of two years after successful completion of flight training, unless sooner released. A student aviation pilot may be released from active duty or discharged at any time as provided for in the regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A student aviation pilot who is a qualified civilian aviator may be given a brief refresher course in flight training.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A student aviation pilot undergoing flight training is entitled to have uniforms and equipment provided at Government expense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, a student aviation pilot may be designated an aviation pilot upon the successful completion of flight training.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> In time of peace, an aviation pilot obligated under subsection (b) to serve on active duty for two years may serve for an additional period of not more than two years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> An aviation pilot may be released from active duty or discharged at any time as provided for in the regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> If qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, an aviation pilot may be appointed as an ensign in the Reserve.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1005</ref>, § 709; renumbered § 3709, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3710.</num>
<heading> Reserve student pre-commissioning assistance program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may provide financial assistance to an eligible enlisted member of the Coast Guard Reserve, not on active duty, for expenses of the member while the member is pursuing on a full-time basis at an institution of higher education a program of education approved by the Secretary that leads to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a baccalaureate degree in not more than 5 academic years; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a post-baccalaureate degree.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To be eligible for financial assistance under this section, an enlisted member of the Coast Guard Reserve shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be enrolled on a full-time basis in a program of education referred to in subsection (a) at any institution of higher education; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> enter into a written agreement with the Coast Guard described in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A written agreement referred to in paragraph (1)(B) is an agreement between the member and the Secretary in which the member agrees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to accept an appointment as a commissioned officer in the Coast Guard Reserve, if tendered;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to serve on active duty for up to five years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> under such terms and conditions as shall be prescribed by the Secretary, to serve in the Coast Guard Reserve until the eighth anniversary of the date of the appointment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Expenses for which financial assistance may be provided under this section are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Tuition and fees charged by the institution of higher education involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The cost of books.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of a program of education leading to a baccalaureate degree, laboratory expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Such other expenses as are deemed appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The amount of financial assistance provided to a member under this section shall be prescribed by the Secretary, but may not exceed $25,000 for any academic year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Financial assistance may be provided to a member under this section for up to 5 consecutive academic years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> A member who receives financial assistance under this section may be ordered to active duty in the Coast Guard Reserve by the Secretary to serve in a designated enlisted grade for such period as the Secretary prescribes, but not more than 4 years, if the member—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> completes the academic requirements of the program and refuses to accept an appointment as a commissioned officer in the Coast Guard Reserve when offered;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fails to complete the academic requirements of the institution of higher education involved; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> fails to maintain eligibility for an original appointment as a commissioned officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a member requests to be released from the program and the request is accepted by the Secretary, or if the member fails because of misconduct to complete the period of active duty specified, or if the member fails to fulfill any term or condition of the written agreement required to be eligible for financial assistance under this section, the financial assistance shall be terminated. The Secretary may request the member to reimburse the United States in an amount that bears the same ratio to the total costs of the education provided to that member as the unserved portion of active duty bears to the total period of active duty the member agreed to serve. The Secretary shall have the option to order such reimbursement without first ordering the member to active duty. An obligation to reimburse the United States imposed under this paragraph is a debt owed to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary may waive the service obligated under subsection (f) of a member who becomes unqualified to serve on active duty due to a circumstance not within the control of that member or who is not physically qualified for appointment and who is determined to be unqualified for service as an enlisted member of the Coast Guard Reserve due to a physical or medical condition that was not the result of the member’s own misconduct or grossly negligent conduct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A discharge in bankruptcy under title 11 that is entered less than 5 years after the termination of a written agreement entered into under subsection (b) does not discharge the individual signing the agreement from a debt arising under such agreement or under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 413(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2119</ref>, § 709a; renumbered § 3710, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3711.</num>
<heading> Appointment or wartime promotion; retention of grade upon release from active duty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A member of the Reserve on active duty, who is appointed or promoted under section 2104 or 2125 of this title, is entitled upon release from that duty to the highest grade satisfactorily held by reason of that appointment or promotion. The Secretary shall determine the highest grade satisfactorily held.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Unless otherwise entitled to a higher grade, a member recalled to active duty shall be recalled in the grade in which released under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1006</ref>, § 710; renumbered § 3711 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3712.</num>
<heading> Exclusiveness of service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No member of the Reserve, other than a temporary member, may be a member of another military organization. A temporary member of the Reserve who is a member of another military component shall, if ordered to active duty therein, be disenrolled as a temporary member of the Reserve.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1006</ref>, § 711; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–136, § 6(c)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1706</ref>; renumbered § 3712, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3713.</num>
<heading> Active duty for emergency augmentation of regular forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding another law, and for the emergency augmentation of the Regular Coast Guard forces during a, or to aid in prevention of an imminent, serious natural or manmade disaster, accident, catastrophe, act of terrorism (as defined in section 2 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref>6 U.S.C. 101</ref>)), or transportation security incident as defined in <ref>section 70101 of title 46</ref>, the Secretary may, without the consent of the member affected, order to active duty of not more than 120 days in any 2-year period an organized training unit of the Coast Guard Ready Reserve, a member thereof, or a member not assigned to a unit organized to serve as a unit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Under the circumstances of the domestic emergency involved, a reasonable time shall be allowed between the date when a Reserve member ordered to active duty under this section is alerted for that duty and the date when the member is required to enter upon that duty. Unless the Secretary determines that the nature of the domestic emergency does not allow it, this period shall be at least two days.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Active duty served under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> satisfies on a day-for-day basis all or a part of the annual active duty for training requirement of <ref>section 10147 of title 10</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> does not satisfy any part of the active duty obligation of a member whose statutory Reserve obligation is not already terminated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> entitles a member while engaged therein, or while engaged in authorized travel to or from that duty, to all rights and benefits, including pay and allowances and time creditable for pay and retirement purposes, to which the member would be entitled while performing other active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Reserve members ordered to active duty under this section shall not be counted in computing authorized strength of members on active duty or members in grade under this title or under any other law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> For purposes of calculating the duration of active duty allowed pursuant to subsection (a), each period of active duty shall begin on the first day that a member reports to active duty, including for purposes of training.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1006</ref>, § 712; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–241, § 13</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 2213</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1677(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3020</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3907</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–53, title V, § 502(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 311</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 219</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3037</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XIX, § 1913(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2687</ref>; renumbered § 3713, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3714.</num>
<heading> Enlistment of members engaged in schooling</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The initial period of active duty for training required by <ref>section 12103(d) of title 10</ref>, may be divided into two successive annual periods of not less than six weeks each, to permit the enlistment of a Reserve member without interrupting any full-time schooling in which the member is engaged.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1007</ref>, § 713; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1677(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3020</ref>; renumbered § 3714, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>PERSONNEL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3731.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Reserve officer” means a commissioned officer in the Reserve, except an officer excluded by <ref>section 3732 of this title</ref> or a commissioned warrant officer; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “discharged” means released from an appointment as a Reserve officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1007</ref>, § 720; renumbered § 3731 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3732.</num>
<heading> Applicability of this subchapter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter applies only to the Reserve; except that it does not apply to a temporary member of the Reserve.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1007</ref>, § 721; renumbered § 3732, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3733.</num>
<heading> Suspension of this subchapter in time of war or national emergency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In time of war or national emergency declared by Congress, the President may suspend the operation of this subchapter or any part hereof. If this subchapter or any part hereof is suspended by the President, prior to placing the suspended provision in operation, the President shall by regulation, in so far as practicable, adjust the grades of Reserve officers in the same manner as adjustments in grade are made for Regular officers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1007</ref>, § 722; renumbered § 3733, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3734.</num>
<heading> Effect of this subchapter on retirement and retired pay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection 3757(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002024">1</ref> of this title, nothing in this subchapter authorizes the retirement of a Reserve officer or the payment of retired, retainer, or severance pay to a Reserve officer; or affects in any manner the law relating to the retirement of, or the granting of retired or retainer pay or other benefits to a Reserve officer.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1007</ref>, § 723; renumbered § 3734 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3735.</num>
<heading> Authorized number of officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The authorized number of officers in the Reserve in an active status is 5,000. Reserve officers on an active-duty list shall not be counted as part of the authorized number of officers in the Reserve. The actual number of Reserve officers in an active status at any time shall not exceed the authorized number unless the Secretary determines that a greater number is necessary for planned mobilization requirements, or unless the excess results directly from the operation of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall make, at least once each year, a computation to determine the number of Reserve officers in an active status authorized to be serving in each grade. The number in each grade shall be computed by applying the applicable percentage to the total number of such officers serving in an active status on the date the computation is made. The number of Reserve officers in an active status below the grade of rear admiral (lower half) shall be distributed by pay grade so as not to exceed percentages of commissioned officers authorized by <ref>section 2103(b) of this title</ref>. When the actual number of Reserve officers in an active status in a particular pay grade is less than the maximum percentage authorized, the difference may be applied to the number in the next lower grade. A Reserve officer may not be reduced in rank or grade solely because of a reduction in an authorized number as provided for in this subsection, or because an excess results directly from the operation of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authorized number of Reserve Officers in an active status not on active duty in the grades of rear admiral (lower half) and rear admiral is a total of two. However, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may authorize an additional number of Reserve officers not on active duty in the grades of rear admiral (lower half) and rear admiral as necessary in order to meet planned mobilization requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deferral of Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If at the end of any fiscal year there is in effect a declaration of war or national emergency, the President may defer the effectiveness of any end-strength limitation with respect to that fiscal year prescribed by law for any military or civilian component of the Coast Guard Reserve, for a period not to exceed 6 months after the end of the war or termination of the national emergency.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1007</ref>, § 724; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–417, § 2(12)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 25(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2872</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2085</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 521</ref>; renumbered § 3735 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3736.</num>
<heading> Precedence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Reserve officers rank and take precedence in their respective grades among themselves and with officers of the same grade on the active duty promotion list and the permanent commissioned teaching staff in accordance with their dates of rank. When Reserve officers and officers on the active duty promotion list or the permanent commissioned teaching staff have the same date of rank in a grade, they take prec­edence as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other law, a Reserve officer shall not lose precedence when transferred to or from the active duty promotion list, nor shall that officer’s date of rank be changed due to the transfer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer shall, when on the active duty promotion list, be promoted in the same manner as any other officer on the active duty promotion list regardless of the length of active duty service of the Reserve officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other law, a Reserve officer shall not lose precedence by reason of promotion to the grade of rear admiral or rear admiral (lower half), if the promotion is determined in accordance with a running mate system.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall adjust the date of rank of a Reserve officer so that no changes of precedence occur.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1008</ref>, § 725; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 220(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1039</ref>; renumbered § 3736, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3737.</num>
<heading> Running mates</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall assign a running mate to each Reserve officer in an active status not on the active duty promotion list. The officer initially assigned as a running mate under this section shall be that officer on the active duty promotion list of the same grade who is next senior in precedence to the Reserve officer concerned. An officer who has twice failed of selection or who has been considered but has not been recommended for continuation under <ref>section 2150 of this title</ref> shall not be assigned as a running mate under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A Reserve officer in an active status not on the active duty promotion list shall be assigned a new running mate as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a previously assigned running mate is promoted from below the promotion zone, is removed from the active duty promotion list, suffers a loss of numbers, fails of selection, fails to qualify for promotion, or declines an appointment after being selected for promotion, the new running mate shall be that officer on the active duty promotion list, of the same grade, who is next senior to the previous running mate and who is, or may become, eligible for consideration for promotion. If the previous running mate was on a list of selectees for promotion, the new running mate shall be that officer on the active duty promotion list, of the same grade, who is on a list of selectees for promotion and who is next senior to the previous running mate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a Reserve officer suffers a loss of numbers, the new running mate shall be that officer on the active duty promotion list who, after the loss of numbers has been effected, is the running mate of the Reserve officer next senior to the Reserve officer concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If a Reserve officer is considered for promotion and fails of selection, fails to qualify for promotion, declines an appointment after being selected for promotion, or has his or her name removed from a list of selectees for promotion, and that officer’s running mate is promoted, the new running mate shall be that officer on the active duty promotion list, of the same grade, who, at the time the previous running mate was considered for promotion, was next senior to the previous running mate, was eligible for consideration for promotion, and whose name was not included on a list of selectees for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In a situation not expressly covered by this subsection, the Secretary may assign a new running mate as necessary to effect the intent of this section that inequitable changes of precedence do not occur.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer on the active duty promotion list shall, to the extent practicable and consistent with the limitations imposed by this section, be assigned as the running mate of all Reserve officers junior to the officer, who are in an active status not on the active duty promotion list, and who had a running mate in common with the officer just prior to the time the officer was placed on the active duty promotion list.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary may adjust, as necessary, the date of rank of a Reserve officer not on active duty so that the date will correspond with that of the running mate assigned to the officer in accordance with this section. If an overpayment of pay or allowances results from adjusting the date of rank, the overpayment is not subject to recoupment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1008</ref>, § 726; renumbered § 3737 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3738.</num>
<heading> Constructive credit upon initial appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, an individual, appointed as a Reserve officer, may be assigned a date of rank and precedence which reflects that individual’s experience, education, or other qualifications. For the purpose of this subchapter only, an individual appointed for the purpose of assignment or designation as a judge advocate in the Reserve shall be credited with a minimum of one year service in an active status. An individual holding a doctor of philosophy, or a comparable degree, in medicine or in a science allied to medicine as determined by the Secretary, may be credited with a minimum of three years service in an active status if appointed for an assignment comparable to that of an officer in the Navy Medical Department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1009</ref>, § 727; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1035</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title II, § 218(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 526</ref>; renumbered § 3738, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(53), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3738a.</num>
<heading> Direct commissioning authority for individuals with critical skills</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An individual with critical skills that the Commandant considers necessary for the Coast Guard to complete its missions who is not currently serving as an officer in the Coast Guard may be commissioned into the Coast Guard at a grade up to and including commander.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8205(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4648</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3739.</num>
<heading> Promotion of Reserve officers on active duty</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer on active duty, other than for training, duty on a board, or duty of a limited or temporary nature if assigned to active duty from an inactive duty status, shall not be eligible for consideration for promotion under this subchapter; but shall be considered for promotion under chapter 21 of this title. If promoted while serving on active duty the officer shall be considered as having been promoted under this subchapter and shall be an extra number in the grade to which promoted for the purpose of grade distribution as prescribed in this subchapter. Upon release from active duty the officer shall be included in the grade distribution authorized by this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, a Reserve officer who has been selected for promotion to the next higher grade under this subchapter at the time the officer reports for active duty, shall be promoted to that grade under chapter 21 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer who, at the time the officer is released from active duty, has been selected for promotion to the next higher grade under chapter 21 of this title, shall be promoted to that grade as though selected under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A failure of selection for promotion to the next higher grade occurring under this subchapter or under chapter 21 of this title shall count for all purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1009</ref>, § 728; renumbered § 3739 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(c)(2)(B), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4241.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3740.</num>
<heading> Promotion; recommendations of selection boards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided by law, a Reserve officer shall only be promoted pursuant to the recommendation of a selection board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall convene selection boards from time to time to recommend Reserve officers for promotion to the next higher grade. A board may be convened to consider officers in one or more grades.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A selection board shall, from among the names of those eligible Reserve officers submitted to it, recommend for promotion to the next higher grade:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> those officers serving in the grade of lieutenant (junior grade) or above whom it considers to be best qualified; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> those officers serving in the grade of ensign whom it considers to be fully qualified.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Before convening a selection board to recommend Reserve officers for promotion, the Secretary shall establish a promotion zone for officers serving in each grade to be considered by the board. The Secretary shall determine the number of officers in the promotion zone for officers serving in any grade from among officers who are eligible for promotion in that grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Before convening a selection board to recommend Reserve officers for promotion to a grade (other than the grade of lieutenant (junior grade)), the Secretary shall determine the maximum number of officers in that grade that the board may recommend for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall make the determination under subparagraph (A) of the maximum number that may be recommended with a view to having in an active status a sufficient number of Reserve officers in each grade to meet the needs of the Coast Guard for Reserve officers in an active status.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> In order to make the determination under subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall determine the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The number of positions needed to accomplish mission objectives that require officers in the grade to which the board will recommend officers for promotion.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The estimated number of officers needed to fill vacancies in such positions during the period in which it is anticipated that officers selected for promotion will be promoted.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The number of officers authorized by the Secretary to serve in an active status in the grade under consideration.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Any statutory limitation on the number of officers in any grade authorized to be in an active status.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Secretary may, when the needs of the Coast Guard require, authorize the consideration of officers in a grade above lieutenant (junior grade) for promotion to the next higher grade from below the promotion zone.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> When selection from below the promotion zone is authorized, the Secretary shall establish the number of officers that may be recommended for promotion from below the promotion zone. That number may not exceed the number equal to 10 percent of the maximum number of officers that the board is authorized to recommend for promotion, except that the Secretary may authorize a greater number, not to exceed 15 percent of the total number of officers that the board is authorized to recommend for promotion, if the Secretary determines that the needs of the Coast Guard so require. If the maximum number determined under this subparagraph is less than one, the board may recommend one officer for promotion from below the promotion zone.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The number of officers recommended for promotion from below the promotion zone does not increase the maximum number of officers that the board is authorized to recommend for promotion under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The law and regulations relating to the selection for promotion of a commissioned officer of the Regular Coast Guard to the grades of rear admiral (lower half) and rear admiral apply to a Reserve officer, except that to be eligible for consideration for promotion to the grade of rear admiral (lower half) an officer shall have completed at least ten years commissioned service, of which the last five years shall have been served in the Coast Guard Reserve.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The provisions of <ref>section 2117 of this title</ref> apply to boards convened under this section. The Secretary shall determine the procedure to be used by a selection board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> The report of a selection board shall be submitted to the Secretary for review and transmission to the President for approval. When an officer recommended by a board for promotion is not acceptable to the President, the President may remove the name of that officer from the report of the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The recommendations of a selection board, as approved by the President, constitute a list of selectees from which the promotions of Reserve officers shall be made. An officer on a list of selectees remains thereon until promoted unless removed by the President under <ref>section 3749 of this title</ref>. If an existing list of selectees has not been exhausted by the time a later list has been approved, all officers remaining on the older list shall be tendered appointments prior to those on the later list.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer whose name is on a list of selectees for promotion shall, unless that officer’s promotion is lawfully withheld, be tendered an appointment in the next higher grade on the date a vacancy occurs, or as soon thereafter as practicable in the grade to which the officer was selected for promotion or, if promotion was determined in accordance with a running mate system, at the same time, or as soon thereafter as practicable, as that officer’s running mate is tendered a similar appointment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1010</ref>, § 729; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–417, § 2(13)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 502(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–99; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 411(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2118</ref>; renumbered § 3740 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3741.</num>
<heading> Selection boards; appointment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A selection board shall (1) be appointed and convened by the Secretary; (2) consist of at least 50 per centum Reserve officer membership, except in the case of a flag officer selection board where, to the extent practicable, it shall consist of at least 50 per centum Reserve officer membership; (3) consist only of members, Reserve or Regular, senior in grade to any officer being considered by that board; and (4) be composed of not less than five members, which number constitutes a quorum.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A selection board serves for the length of time prescribed by the Secretary, but no board may serve longer than one year. No officer may serve on two consecutive selection boards for the same grade when the second of those boards considers an officer who was considered, but not recommended for promotion, by the first selection board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Each member of a selection board shall swear that he will, without prejudice or partiality, and having in view both the special fitness required of officers and the efficiency of the Coast Guard, perform the duties imposed upon him. Not less than a majority of the total membership of a selection board shall concur in each recommendation made by the board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> An officer eligible for consideration for promotion by a selection board may forward, through official channels, a written communication inviting the attention of the board to any matter in the officer’s record in the armed forces that, in the opinion of the officer concerned, is important to the board’s consideration. A communication forwarded under this subsection shall arrive in time to allow delivery to the board prior to its convening, and may not criticize or reflect upon the character, conduct, or motive of any officer.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1011</ref>, § 730; renumbered § 3741, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3742.</num>
<heading> Establishment of promotion zones under running mate system</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Use Running Mate System</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may by regulation implement <ref>section 3740(d)(1) of this title</ref> by requiring that the promotion zone for consideration of Reserve officers in an active status for promotion to the next higher grade be determined in accordance with a running mate system as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration for Promotion</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If promotion zones are determined as authorized under subsection (a), a Reserve officer shall, subject to the eligibility requirements of this subchapter, be placed in a promotion zone when that officer’s running mate is placed in a promotion zone and shall, in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, be considered for promotion at approximately the same time as that officer’s running mate or as soon thereafter as practicable, or in the event that promotion is not determined in accordance with a running mate system, then a Reserve officer becomes eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade at the beginning of the promotion year in which he or she completes the following amount of service computed from the date of rank in the grade in which he or she is serving:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> two years in the grade of lieutenant (junior grade);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> three years in the grade of lieutenant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> four years in the grade of lieutenant commander;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> four years in the grade of commander; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> three years in the grade of captain.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration of Officers Below the Zone</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Secretary authorizes the selection of officers for promotion from below the promotion zone in accordance with <ref>section 3740(d)(3) of this title</ref>, the number of officers to be considered from below the zone may be established through the application of the running mate system under this subchapter or otherwise as the Secretary determines to be appropriate to meet the needs of the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1011</ref>, § 731; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 502(b)(1), (2)(A)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–100; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 411(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2118</ref>; renumbered § 3742 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3743.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), a Reserve officer is eligible for consideration for promotion and for promotion under this subchapter if that officer is in an active status.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A Reserve officer who has been considered but not recommended for retention in an active status by a board convened under subsection 3752(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002025">1</ref> of this title is not eligible for consideration for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Request for Exclusion.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may provide that an officer may, upon the officer’s request and with the approval of the Commandant, be excluded from consideration by a selection board convened under <ref>section 3740(b) of this title</ref> to consider officers for promotion to the next higher grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Approval of request</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall approve a request under paragraph (1) only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the basis for the request is to allow an officer to complete a broadening assignment, advanced education, another assignment of significant value to the Coast Guard, a career progression requirement delayed by the assignment or education, or a qualifying personal or professional circumstance, as determined by the Commandant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Commandant determines the exclusion from consideration is in the best interest of the Coast Guard; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the officer has not previously failed of selection for promotion to the grade for which the officer requests the exclusion from consideration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1011</ref>, § 732; renumbered § 3743 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8202(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4643</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3744.</num>
<heading> Recommendation for promotion of an officer previously removed from an active status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Reserve officer recommended for promotion by a selection board but not promoted because of removal from an active status shall be reconsidered by a selection board after returning to an active status and if selected shall be placed on a recommended list of selectees for promotion. A Reserve officer to whom this section applies is not considered to have failed of selection when eliminated from a list of selectees for promotion solely as a result of being removed from an active status.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1012</ref>, § 733; renumbered § 3744, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3745.</num>
<heading> Qualifications for promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer shall not be promoted to a higher grade unless the officer has been found to be physically qualified and the character of the officer’s service subsequent to the convening of the selection board which recommended the officer for promotion has been verified as satisfactory.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) of this section does not exclude from promotion a Reserve officer physically disqualified by a medical board for duty at sea or in the field, if the disqualification results from wounds received in the line of duty, and those wounds do not incapacitate the officer for other duties in the grade to which the officer is to be promoted.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1012</ref>, § 734; renumbered § 3745, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3746.</num>
<heading> Promotion; acceptance; oath of office</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer who has been appointed under this subchapter is considered to have accepted the appointment unless delivery thereof cannot be effected.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer who has served continuously since taking the oath of office prescribed in <ref>section 3331 of title 5</ref>, is not required to take a new oath of office upon appointment in a higher grade.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1012</ref>, § 735; renumbered § 3746, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3747.</num>
<heading> Date of rank upon promotion; entitlement to pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When a Reserve officer is promoted to the next higher grade under this subchapter, the date of rank shall be the date of appointment in that grade, unless the promotion was determined in accordance with a running mate system, in which event the same date of rank shall be assigned as that assigned to the officer’s running mate. A Reserve officer so promoted shall be allowed the pay and allowances of the higher grade for duty performed from the date of the officer’s appointment thereto.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to subsection (c), if promotion of an inactive duty promotion list officer to the grade of rear admiral or rear admiral (lower half) is determined in accordance with a running mate system, a reserve officer, if acceptable to the President and the Senate, shall be promoted to the next higher grade no later than the date the officer’s running mate is promoted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this section, the date of appointment shall be that date when promotion authority is exercised by the Secretary. However, the Secretary may adjust the date of appointment—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if a delay in the finding required under <ref>section 3745(a) of this title</ref> is beyond the control of the officer and the officer is otherwise qualified for promotion; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for any other reason that equity requires.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1012</ref>, § 736; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–417, § 2(14)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–225, title II, § 203(4)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-12">Dec. 12, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 411(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2118</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 220(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1039</ref>; renumbered § 3747 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3748.</num>
<heading> Type of promotion; temporary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law, if a Reserve officer is promoted when the officer’s running mate is promoted and the promotion of the running mate is on a temporary basis, the promotion of the Reserve officer is also on a temporary basis. If subsequently the running mate is reverted to a lower grade, other than for reasons of discipline, incompetence, or at the running mate’s request, the Reserve officer shall likewise revert to the same lower grade with corresponding precedence.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1012</ref>, § 737; renumbered § 3748, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3749.</num>
<heading> Effect of removal by the President or failure of consent of the Senate</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President may, for cause, remove the name of any officer from a list of selectees established under <ref>section 3740 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If the Senate, where required, does not consent to the appointment of an officer whose name is on a list of selectees established under <ref>section 3740 of this title</ref>, that officer’s name shall be removed from the list.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An officer whose name is removed from a list of selectees under subsection (a) or (b) continues to be eligible for consideration for promotion. If selected for promotion by the next selection board and promoted, that officer shall be assigned the date of rank and precedence that would have been assigned if the officer’s name had not been previously removed. However, if the officer is not selected by the next selection board, or if the officer’s name is again removed from the list of selectees, the officer shall be considered for all purposes as having twice failed of selection for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1013</ref>, § 738; renumbered § 3749 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3750.</num>
<heading> Failure of selection for promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer, other than one serving in the grade of captain, who is, or is senior to, the junior officer in the promotion zone established for the officer’s grade, fails of selection if not selected for promotion by the selection board that considered the officer, or if having been selected for promotion by the board, the officer’s name is thereafter removed from the report of the board by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer is not considered to have failed of selection if the officer was not considered by a selection board because of administrative error. If that officer is selected by the next appropriate selection board after the error is discovered, and is promoted, the same date of rank and precedence shall be assigned that would have been assigned if the officer had been recommended for promotion by the selection board that originally would have considered the officer but for the error.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1013</ref>, § 739; renumbered § 3750, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3751.</num>
<heading> Failure of selection and removal from an active status</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may remove from an active status a Reserve officer who has twice failed of selection to the next higher grade; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall remove from an active status a Reserve officer serving in the grade of captain who has completed thirty years of total commissioned service and whose name is not carried on an approved list of selectees for promotion to the grade of rear admiral (lower half).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer who has twice failed of selection to the next higher grade and who is not removed from an active status under subsection (a)(1) of this section shall be retained for the period prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to <ref>section 12646 of title 10</ref>, a Reserve officer who is removed from an active status under subsection (a) of this section shall be given an opportunity to transfer to the Retired Reserve, if qualified, but unless so transferred shall, in the discretion of the Secretary, be transferred to the inactive status list or discharged as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if removed from an active status under subsection (a)(1) of this section, on June 30 next following the approval date of the board report by virtue of which the officer’s second failure of selection occurs; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if removed from an active status under subsection (a)(2) of this section, on June 30 next following the date on which the officer completes thirty years of total commissioned service as computed under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> For the purpose of this section, the total commissioned service of an officer who has served continuously in the Reserve following appointment in the grade of ensign shall be computed from the date on which that appointment to the Reserve was accepted. A Reserve officer initially appointed in a grade above ensign is considered to have the actual total commissioned service performed in a grade above commissioned warrant officer or the same total commissioned service as an officer of the Regular Coast Guard who has served continuously from an original appointment as ensign, who has not lost numbers or precedence, and who is, or was, junior to the Reserve officer, whichever is greater.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1013</ref>, § 740; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–417, § 2(15)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1677(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3020</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 217(14)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1558</ref>; renumbered § 3751, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3752.</num>
<heading> Retention boards; removal from an active status to provide a flow of promotion</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, whenever the Secretary determines that it is necessary to reduce the number of Reserve officers in an active status in any grade to provide a steady flow of promotion, or that there is an excessive number of Reserve officers in an active status in any grade, the Secretary may appoint and convene a retention board to consider all of the Reserve officers in that grade in an active status who have 18 years or more of service for retirement, except those officers who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are on extended active duty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> are on a list of selectees for promotion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> will complete 30 years total commissioned service by June 30th following the date that the retention board is convened; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> have reached age 59 by the date on which the retention board is convened.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The retention board shall select and recommend a specified number of the officers under consideration for retention in an active status.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> This board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, consist of at least 50 per centum Reserve officers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consist only of officers who are senior in rank to any officers being considered by that board; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, consist of officers who have not served on the last previous retention board which considered officers of the same grade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Subject to <ref>section 12646 of title 10</ref>, a Reserve officer who is not recommended for retention in an active status under this section shall be given an opportunity to transfer to the Retired Reserve, if qualified, but unless so transferred shall, in the discretion of the Secretary, be transferred to the inactive status list or discharged on June 30 next following the date on which the report of the retention board is approved.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The provisions of <ref>section 2117 of this title</ref> shall, to the extent that they are not inconsistent with this subchapter, apply to boards convened under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1014</ref>, § 741; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–225, title II, § 203(5)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-12">Dec. 12, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1911</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2420</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1677(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3020</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(e)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 501</ref>; renumbered § 3752 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3753.</num>
<heading> Maximum ages for retention in an active status</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer, if qualified, shall be transferred to the Retired Reserve on the day the officer becomes 60 years of age unless on active duty. If not qualified for retirement, a Reserve officer shall be discharged effective upon the day the officer becomes 60 years of age unless on active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A Reserve officer on active duty shall, if qualified, be retired effective upon the day the officer become 62 years of age. If not qualified for retirement, a Reserve officer on active duty shall be discharged effective upon the day the officer becomes 62 years of age.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary may authorize the retention of a Reserve rear admiral or rear admiral (lower half) in an active status not longer than the day on which the officer concerned becomes 64 years of age.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, “active duty” does not include active duty for training, duty on a board, or duty of a limited or temporary nature if assigned to active duty from an inactive duty status.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1014</ref>, § 742; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–417, § 2(16)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1035</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 209(13)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 41</ref>; renumbered § 3753, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3754.</num>
<heading> Rear admiral and rear admiral (lower half); maximum service in grade</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Unless retained in or removed from an active status under any other law, a reserve rear admiral or rear admiral (lower half) shall be retired on July 1 of the promotion year immediately following the promotion year in which that officer completes 4 years of service after the appointment of the officer to rear admiral (lower half).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if promotion of inactive duty promotion list officers to the grade of rear admiral is not determined in accordance with a running mate system, a Reserve officer serving in an active status in the grade of rear admiral (lower half) shall be promoted to the grade of rear admiral, if acceptable to the President and the Senate, on the date the officer has served 2 years in an active status in grade of rear admiral (lower half), or in the case of a vacancy occurring prior to having served 2 years in an active status, on the date the vacancy occurs, if the officer served at least 1 year in an active status in the grade of rear admiral (lower half).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1015</ref>, § 743; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–417, § 2(17)(A)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(c)(1)</ref>, (3)(A), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 220(d)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1039</ref>; renumbered § 3754, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3755.</num>
<heading> Appointment of a former Navy or Coast Guard officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A former officer of the Regular Navy or Coast Guard who applies for a Reserve commission within one year of resigning the officer’s Regular commission, and who is appointed in the same grade previously held in the Regular Navy or Coast Guard, shall be given the same date of rank in that grade as that previously assigned to the officer while a member of the Regular Navy or Coast Guard.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1015</ref>, § 744; renumbered § 3755, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3756.</num>
<heading> Grade on entry upon active duty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A Reserve officer ordered to active duty or active duty for training shall be ordered in the grade held; except that the Secretary may authorize a higher grade.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1015</ref>, § 745; renumbered § 3756, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3757.</num>
<heading> Recall of a retired officer; grade upon release</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When an officer in the Retired Reserve or an officer on a Reserve retired list is recalled to active duty, that officer shall be recalled in a manner similar to the recall of a Regular retired officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An officer in the Retired Reserve or an officer on a Reserve retired list recalled to active duty shall upon release therefrom be advanced in the Retired Reserve or on the Reserve retired list to the highest grade held on active duty, if: (1) appointed to a higher grade while on that duty, and (2) the officer’s performance has been satisfactory in the higher grade.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1015</ref>, § 746; renumbered § 3757, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>