<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5—</num>
<heading>FUNCTIONS AND POWERS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL POWERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Secretary; general powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purpose of executing the duties and functions of the Coast Guard the Secretary may within the limits of appropriations made therefor:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> establish, change the limits of, consolidate, discontinue, and re-establish Coast Guard districts;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> arrange with the Secretaries of the Army, Navy and Air Force to assign members of the Coast Guard to any school maintained by the Army, Navy, and Air Force, for instruction and training, including aviation schools;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> construct, or cause to be constructed, Coast Guard shore establishments;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> design or cause to be designed, cause to be constructed, accept as gift, or otherwise acquire vessels, aircraft, and systems, and subject to applicable regulations under subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41 dispose of them;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> acquire land or interests in land, including acceptance of gifts thereof, where required for the purpose of carrying out any project or purpose for which an appropriation has been made;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> exchange land or interests in land in part or in full payment for such other land or interests in land as may be necessary or desirable, the balance of such part payment to be defrayable in accordance with other provisions of this section;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> exercise any of the powers vested by this title in the Commandant in any case in which the Secretary deems it appropriate; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> do any and all things necessary to carry out the purposes of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 503</ref>, § 92; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654</ref>, §§ 1(32), 2(9), 3(3), <ref>65 Stat. 702</ref>, 707, 708; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 2(4)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(D)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3847</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3533(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2321</ref>; renumbered § 501 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, title III, § 311(a), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>, 4248.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Delegation of powers by the Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to confer or impose upon the Commandant any of the rights, privileges, powers, or duties, in respect to the administration of the Coast Guard, vested in or imposed upon the Secretary by this title or other provisions of law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 544</ref>, § 631; <ref>Pub. L. 94–546, § 1(33)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2521</ref>; renumbered § 502, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the authority conferred by other provisions of this title the Secretary may promulgate such regulations and orders as he deems appropriate to carry out the provisions of this title or any other law applicable to the Coast Guard.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 545</ref>, § 633; renumbered § 503, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Commandant; general powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purpose of executing the duties and functions of the Coast Guard the Commandant may:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> maintain water, land, and air patrols, and ice-breaking facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish and prescribe the purpose of, change the location of, consolidate, discontinue, re-establish, maintain, operate, and repair Coast Guard shore establishments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> assign vessels, aircraft, vehicles, aids to navigation, equipment, appliances, and supplies to Coast Guard districts and shore establishments, and transfer any of the foregoing from one district or shore establishment to another;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conduct experiments and investigate, or cause to be investigated, plans, devices, and inventions relating to the performance of any Coast Guard function, including research, development, test, or evaluation related to intelligence systems and capabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> conduct any investigations or studies that may be of assistance to the Coast Guard in the performance of any of its powers, duties, or functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> collect, publish, and distribute information concerning Coast Guard operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> conduct or make available to personnel of the Coast Guard, and to eligible spouses as defined under section 2904, such specialized training and courses of instruction, including correspondence courses and the textbooks, manuals, and other materials required as part of such training or course of instruction, as may be necessary or desirable for the good of the service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> design or cause to be designed, cause to be constructed, accept as gift, or otherwise acquire patrol boats and other small craft, equip, operate, maintain, supply, and repair such patrol boats, other small craft, aircraft, and vehicles, and subject to applicable regulations under subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41 dispose of them;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> acquire, accept as gift, maintain, repair, and discontinue aids to navigation, appliances, equipment, and supplies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> equip, operate, maintain, supply, and repair Coast Guard districts and shore establishments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> establish, equip, operate, and maintain shops, depots, and yards for the manufacture and construction of aids to navigation, equipment, apparatus, vessels, vehicles, and aircraft not normally or economically obtainable from private contractors, and for the maintenance and repair of any property used by the Coast Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> accept and utilize, in times of emergency in order to save life or protect property, such voluntary services as may be offered to the Coast Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> rent or lease, under such terms and conditions as are deemed advisable, for a period not exceeding five years, such real property under the control of the Coast Guard as may not be required for immediate use by the Coast Guard, the monies received from any such rental or lease, less amount of expenses incurred (exclusive of governmental personal services), to be deposited in the fund established under section 2946;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> grant, under such terms and conditions as are deemed advisable, permits, licenses, easements, and rights-of-way over, across, in, and upon lands under the control of the Coast Guard when in the public interest and without substantially injuring the interests of the United States in the property thereby affected;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> establish, install, abandon, re-establish, reroute, operate, maintain, repair, purchase, or lease such telephone and telegraph lines and cables, together with all facilities, apparatus, equipment, structures, appurtenances, accessories, and supplies used or useful in connection with the installation, operation, maintenance, or repair of such lines and cables, including telephones in residences leased or owned by the Government of the United States when appropriate to assure efficient response to extraordinary operational contingencies of a limited duration, and acquire such real property rights of way, easements, or attachment privileges as may be required for the installation, operation, and maintenance of such lines, cables, and equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> establish, install, abandon, reestablish, change the location of, operate, maintain, and repair radio transmitting and receiving stations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> provide medical and dental care for personnel entitled thereto by law or regulation, including care in private facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> accept, under terms and conditions the Commandant establishes, the service of an individual ordered to perform community service under the order of a Federal, State, or municipal court;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<chapeau> notwithstanding any other law, enter into cooperative agreements with States, local governments, non-governmental organizations, and individuals, to accept and utilize voluntary services for the maintenance and improvement of natural and historic resources on, or to benefit natural and historic research on, Coast Guard facilities, subject to the requirement that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the cooperative agreements shall each provide for the parties to contribute funds or services on a matching basis to defray the costs of such programs, projects, and activities under the agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an individual providing voluntary services under this subsection shall not be considered a Federal employee except for purposes of chapter 81 of title 5, United States Code, with respect to compensation for work-related injuries, and chapter 171 of title 28, United States Code, with respect to tort claims;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> enter into cooperative agreements with other Government agencies and the National Academy of Sciences;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> require that any member of the Coast Guard or Coast Guard Reserve (including a cadet or an applicant for appointment or enlistment to any of the foregoing and any member of a uniformed service who is assigned to the Coast Guard) request that all information contained in the National Driver Register pertaining to the individual, as described in <ref>section 30304(a) of title 49</ref>, be made available to the Commandant under <ref>section 30305(b)(7) of title 49</ref>, may receive that information, and upon receipt, shall make the information available to the individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> provide for the honorary recognition of individuals and organizations that significantly contribute to Coast Guard programs, missions, or operations, including State and local governments and commercial and nonprofit organizations, and pay for, using any appropriations or funds available to the Coast Guard, plaques, medals, trophies, badges, and similar items to acknowledge such contribution (including reasonable expenses of ceremony and presentation);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> rent or lease, under such terms and conditions as are considered by the Secretary to be advisable, commercial vehicles to transport the next of kin of eligible retired Coast Guard military personnel to attend funeral services of the service member at a national cemetery;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<content> after informing the Secretary, make such recommendations to the Congress relating to the Coast Guard as the Commandant considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<content> enter into cooperative agreements, contracts, and other agreements with Federal entities and other public or private entities, including academic entities, to develop a positioning, navigation, and timing system to provide redundant capability in the event Global Positioning System signals are disrupted, which may consist of an enhanced LORAN system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<content> develop data workflows and processes for the leveraging of mission-relevant data by the Coast Guard to enhance operational effectiveness and efficiency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (a)(13), a lease described in paragraph (2) of this subsection may be for a term of up to 20 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A lease referred to in paragraph (1) is a lease—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to the United States Coast Guard Academy Alumni Association for the construction of an Alumni Center on the grounds of the United States Coast Guard Academy; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to an entity with which the Commandant has a cooperative agreement under section 4(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002001">1</ref> of the Ports and Waterways Safety Act, and for which a term longer than 5 years is necessary to carry out the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Marine Safety Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In exercising the Commandant’s duties and responsibilities with regard to marine safety, the individual with the highest rank who meets the experience qualifications set forth in section 305(a)(3) shall serve as the principal advisor to the Commandant regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the operation, regulation, inspection, identification, manning, and measurement of vessels, including plan approval and the application of load lines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> approval of materials, equipment, appliances, and associated equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the reporting and investigation of marine casualties and accidents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the licensing, certification, documentation, protection and relief of merchant mariners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> suspension and revocation of licenses and certificates;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> enforcement of manning requirements, citizenship requirements, control of log books;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> documentation and numbering of vessels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> State boating safety programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> commercial instruments and maritime liens;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the administration of bridge safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> administration of the navigation rules;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> the prevention of pollution from vessels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> ports and waterways safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> waterways management; including regulation for regattas and marine parades;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> aids to navigation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> other duties and powers of the Secretary related to marine safety and stewardship.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Authority Not Affected</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Nothing in subsection (c) affects—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the authority of Coast Guard officers and members to enforce marine safety regulations using authority under <ref>section 522 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the exercise of authority under <ref>section 527 of this title</ref> and the provisions of law codified at sections 191 through 195 of title 50 on the date of enactment of this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operation and Maintenance of Coast Guard Assets and Facilities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All authority, including programmatic budget authority, for the operation and maintenance of Coast Guard vessels, aircraft, systems, aids to navigation, infrastructure, and other assets or facilities shall be allocated to and vested in the Coast Guard and the department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Leasing of Tidelands and Submerged Lands.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may lease under subsection (a)(13) submerged lands and tidelands under the control of the Coast Guard without regard to the limitation under that subsection with respect to lease duration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant may lease submerged lands and tidelands under paragraph (1) only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the lease is for cash exclusively;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the lease amount is equal to the fair market value of the use of the leased submerged lands or tidelands for the period during which such lands are leased, as determined by the Commandant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the lease does not provide authority to or commit the Coast Guard to use or support any improvements to such submerged lands and tidelands, or obtain goods and services from the lessee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> proceeds from the lease are deposited in the Coast Guard Housing Fund established under section 2946.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 504</ref>, § 93; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 2</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654</ref>, §§ 1(33), 2(10), 4(1), <ref>65 Stat. 702</ref>, 707, 709; <ref>Pub. L. 94–546, § 1(9)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2519</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–136, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–276, § 143</ref>, <date date="1982-10-02">Oct. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1199</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 2(4)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–322, title I, § 115(c)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1586</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–241, § 7</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 2212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title II, § 202</ref>, title III, § 316, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2420</ref>, 2426; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 207(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title II</ref>, §§ 202, 203, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3414</ref>, 3415; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II</ref>, §§ 201, 217, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1031</ref>, 1038; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–259, title IV, § 442(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2733</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title V, § 523</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2958</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3847</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II</ref>, §§ 206(a), 207, 208(a), 209, 214(c), 222(1), <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3025</ref>, 3026, 3034, 3038; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 209(4)</ref>, title VI, § 610(b), <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 40</ref>, 85; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3533(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2321</ref>; renumbered § 504 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 105(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>, 4240; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4747</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11229</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4029</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 505.</num>
<heading> Functions and powers vested in the Commandant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All powers and functions conferred upon the Coast Guard, or the Commandant, by or pursuant to this title or any other law shall, unless otherwise specifically stated, be executed by the Commandant subject to the general supervision of the Secretary. In order to execute the powers and functions vested in him, the Commandant may assign personnel of the Coast Guard to duty in the District of Columbia, elsewhere in the United States, in any territory of the United States, and in any foreign country, but such personnel shall not be assigned to duties in any foreign country without the consent of the government of that country; assign to such personnel such duties and authority as he deems necessary; and issue rules, orders, and instructions, not inconsistent with law, relating to the organization, internal administration, and personnel of the Coast Guard.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 545</ref>, § 632; renumbered § 505, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 506.</num>
<heading> Prospective payment of funds necessary to provide medical care</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prospective Payment Required</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In lieu of the reimbursement required under <ref>section 1085 of title 10</ref>, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall make a prospective payment to the Secretary of Defense of an amount that represents the actuarial valuation of treatment or care—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the Department of Defense shall provide to members of the Coast Guard, former members of the Coast Guard, and dependents of such members and former members (other than former members and dependents of former members who are a Medicare-eligible beneficiary or for whom the payment for treatment or care is made from the Medicare-Eligible Retiree Health Care Fund as established under chapter 56 of title 10) at facilities under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense or a military department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for which a reimbursement would otherwise be made under section 1085.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Amount</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The amount of the prospective payment under subsection (a) shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of treatment or care to be provided to members of the Coast Guard and their dependents, derived from amounts appropriated for the operations and support of the Coast Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of treatment or care to be provided former members of the Coast Guard and their dependents, derived from amounts appropriated for retired pay;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> determined under procedures established by the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> paid during the fiscal year in which treatment or care is provided; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> subject to adjustment or reconciliation as the Secretaries determine appropriate during or promptly after such fiscal year in cases in which the prospective payment is determined excessive or insufficient based on the services actually provided.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Prospective Payment When Service in Navy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No prospective payment shall be made under this section for any period during which the Coast Guard operates as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to TRICARE</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section shall not be construed to require a payment for, or the prospective payment of an amount that represents the value of, treatment or care provided under any TRICARE program.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VII, § 722(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2228</ref>, § 520; renumbered § 506, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8513(a)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4760</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 507.</num>
<heading> Appointment of judges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may appoint civilian employees of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating as appellate military judges, available for assignment to the Coast Guard Court of Criminal Appeals as provided for in <ref>section 866(a) of title 10</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2909</ref>, § 153; renumbered § 507, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 508.</num>
<heading> Coast Guard health-care professionals; licensure portability</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law regarding the licensure of health-care providers, a health-care professional described in subsection (b) may practice the health profession or professions of the health-care professional at any location in any State, the District of Columbia, or a Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, regardless of where such health-care professional or the patient is located, if the practice is within the scope of the authorized Federal duties of such health-care professional.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Described Individuals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A health-care professional described in this subsection is an individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a member of the Coast Guard;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a civilian employee of the Coast Guard;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a member of the Public Health Service who is assigned to the Coast Guard; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other health-care professional credentialed and privileged at a Federal health-care institution or location specially designated by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has a current license to practice medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or another health profession; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is performing authorized duties for the Coast Guard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the terms “license” and “health-care professional” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 1094(e) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title III, § 305(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 509.</num>
<heading> Space-available travel on Coast Guard aircraft</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Establishment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may establish a program to provide transportation on Coast Guard aircraft on a space-available basis to the categories of eligible individuals described in subsection (c) (in this section referred to as the “program”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy development</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the program is established, the Commandant shall develop a policy for the operation of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Operation of Program.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall operate the program in a budget-neutral manner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), no additional funds may be used, or flight hours performed, for the purpose of providing transportation under the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">De minimis expenditures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may make de minimis expenditures of resources required for the administrative aspects of the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement not required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Eligible individuals described in subsection (c) shall not be required to reimburse the Coast Guard for travel provided under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Categories of Eligible Individuals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subsection (d), the categories of eligible individuals described in this subsection are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Members of the armed forces on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Members of the Selected Reserve who hold a valid Uniformed Services Identification and Privilege Card.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Retired members of a regular or reserve component of the armed forces, including retired members of reserve components who, but for being under the eligibility age applicable under <ref>section 12731 of title 10</ref>, would be eligible for retired pay under chapter 1223 of title 10.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (f), veterans with a permanent service-connected disability rated as total.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such categories of dependents of individuals described in paragraphs (1) through (3) as the Commandant shall specify in the policy under subsection (a)(2), under such conditions and circumstances as the Commandant shall specify in such policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Such other categories of individuals as the Commandant considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In operating the program, the Commandant shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the sole discretion of the Commandant, establish an order of priority for transportation for categories of eligible individuals that is based on considerations of military necessity, humanitarian concerns, and enhancement of morale;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> give priority in consideration of transportation to the demands of members of the armed forces in the regular components and in the reserve components on active duty and to the need to provide such members, and their dependents, a means of respite from such demands; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> implement policies aimed at ensuring cost control (as required under subsection (b)) and the safety, security, and efficient processing of travelers, including limiting the benefit under the program to 1 or more categories of otherwise eligible individuals, as the Commandant considers necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transportation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1), in establishing space-available transportation priorities under the program, the Commandant shall provide transportation for an individual described in paragraph (2), and a single dependent of the individual if needed to accompany the individual, at a priority level in the same category as the priority level for an unaccompanied dependent over the age of 18 years traveling on environmental and morale leave.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Individuals covered</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to paragraph (3), paragraph (1) applies with respect to an individual described in subsection (c)(3) who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> resides in or is located in a Commonwealth or possession of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is referred by a military or civilian primary care provider located in that Commonwealth or possession to a specialty care provider for services to be provided outside of such Commonwealth or possession.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application to certain retired individuals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If an individual described in subsection (c)(3) is a retired member of a reserve component who is ineligible for retired pay under chapter 1223 of title 10 by reason of being under the eligibility age applicable under <ref>section 12731 of title 10</ref>, paragraph (1) applies to the individual only if the individual is also enrolled in the TRICARE program for certain members of the Retired Reserve authorized under <ref>section 1076e of title 10</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The priority for space-available transportation required by this subsection applies with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the travel from the Commonwealth or possession of the United States to receive the specialty care services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the return travel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Primary care provider and specialty care provider defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the terms “primary care provider” and “specialty care provider” refer to a medical or dental professional who provides health care services under chapter 55 of title 10.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Travel.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Travel may not be provided under this section to a veteran eligible for travel pursuant to paragraph (4) of subsection (c) in priority over any member eligible for travel under paragraph (1) of that subsection or any dependent of such a member eligible for travel under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subsection (c)(4) may not be construed as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> affecting or in any way imposing on the Coast Guard, any armed force, or any commercial entity with which the Coast Guard or an armed force contracts, an obligation or expectation that the Coast Guard or such armed force will retrofit or alter, in any way, military aircraft or commercial aircraft, or related equipment or facilities, used or leased by the Coast Guard or such armed force to accommodate passengers provided travel under such authority on account of disability; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> preempting the authority of an aircraft commander to determine who boards the aircraft and any other matters in connection with safe operation of the aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application of Section</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The authority to provide transportation under the program is in addition to any other authority under law to provide transportation on Coast Guard aircraft on a space-available basis.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11231(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4030</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 510.</num>
<heading> Conveyance of Coast Guard vessels for public purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On request by the Commandant, the Administrator of the General Services Administration may transfer ownership of a Coast Guard vessel or aircraft to an eligible entity for educational, cultural, historical, charitable, recreational, or other public purposes if such transfer is authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions of Conveyance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The General Services Administration may not convey a vessel or aircraft to an eligible entity as authorized by law unless the eligible entity agrees—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide the documentation needed by the General Services Administration to process a request for aircraft or vessels as if the request were being processed under section 102.37.225 of title 41, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the Don Young Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2022;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to comply with the special terms, conditions, and restrictions imposed on aircraft and vessels under section 102.37.460 of such title, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the Don Young Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2022;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to make the vessel available to the United States Government if it is needed for use by the Commandant in time of war or a national emergency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to hold the United States Government harmless for any claims arising from exposure to hazardous materials, including asbestos and polychlorinated biphenyls, that occurs after conveyance of the vessel, except for claims arising from use of the vessel by the United States Government under paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other Obligations Unaffected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section amends or affects any obligation of the Coast Guard or any other person under the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 2601</ref> et seq.) or any other law regarding use or disposal of hazardous materials including asbestos and polychlorinated biphenyls.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible Entity Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “eligible entity” means a State or local government, nonprofit corporation, educational agency, community development organization, or other entity that agrees to comply with the conditions established under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11258(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4057</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>LIFE SAVING AND LAW ENFORCEMENT AUTHORITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 521.</num>
<heading> Saving life and property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In order to render aid to distressed individuals, vessels, and aircraft on and under the high seas and on and under the waters over which the United States has jurisdiction and in order to render aid to individuals and property imperiled by flood, the Coast Guard may:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> perform any and all acts necessary to rescue and aid individuals and protect and save property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> take charge of and protect all property saved from marine or aircraft disasters, or floods, at which the Coast Guard is present, until such property is claimed by individuals legally authorized to receive it or until otherwise disposed of in accordance with law or applicable regulations, and care for bodies of those who may have perished in such catastrophes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> furnish clothing, food, lodging, medicines, and other necessary supplies and services to individuals succored by the Coast Guard; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> destroy or tow into port sunken or floating dangers to navigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), the Coast Guard may render aid to individuals and protect and save property at any time and at any place at which Coast Guard facilities and personnel are available and can be effectively utilized.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Commandant shall make full use of all available and qualified resources, including the Coast Guard Auxiliary and individuals licensed by the Secretary pursuant to <ref>section 8904(b) of title 46</ref>, United States Code, in rendering aid under this subsection in nonemergency cases.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> An individual who knowingly and willfully communicates a false distress message to the Coast Guard or causes the Coast Guard to attempt to save lives and property when no help is needed is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> guilty of a class D felony;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> subject to a civil penalty of not more than $10,000; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> liable for all costs the Coast Guard incurs as a result of the individual’s action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall establish a helicopter rescue swimming program for the purpose of training selected Coast Guard personnel in rescue swimming skills, which may include rescue diver training.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> An individual who knowingly and willfully operates a device with the intention of interfering with the broadcast or reception of a radio, microwave, or other signal (including a signal from a global positioning system) transmitted, retransmitted, or augmented by the Coast Guard for the purpose of maritime safety is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> guilty of a class E felony; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> subject to a civil penalty of not more than $1,000 per day for each violation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 501</ref>, § 88; <ref>Pub. L. 91–278, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-12">June 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 304</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–448, § 30(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-28">Sept. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1849</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–595, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2989</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 213(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3915</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1543</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 205(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3025</ref>; renumbered § 521, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(4), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 522.</num>
<heading> Law enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Coast Guard may make inquiries, examinations, inspections, searches, seizures, and arrests upon the high seas and waters over which the United States has jurisdiction, for the prevention, detection, and suppression of violations of laws of the United States. For such purposes, commissioned, warrant, and petty officers may at any time go on board of any vessel subject to the jurisdiction, or to the operation of any law, of the United States, address inquiries to those on board, examine the ship’s documents and papers, and examine, inspect, and search the vessel and use all necessary force to compel compliance. When from such inquiries, examination, inspection, or search it appears that a breach of the laws of the United States rendering an individual liable to arrest is being, or has been committed, by any individual, such individual shall be arrested or, if escaping to shore, shall be immediately pursued and arrested on shore, or other lawful and appropriate action shall be taken; or, if it shall appear that a breach of the laws of the United States has been committed so as to render such vessel, or the merchandise, or any part thereof, on board of, or brought into the United States by, such vessel, liable to forfeiture, or so as to render such vessel liable to a fine or penalty and if necessary to secure such fine or penalty, such vessel or such merchandise, or both, shall be seized.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The officers of the Coast Guard insofar as they are engaged, pursuant to the authority contained in this section, in enforcing any law of the United States shall:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be deemed to be acting as agents of the particular executive department or independent establishment charged with the administration of the particular law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be subject to all the rules and regulations promulgated by such department or independent establishment with respect to the enforcement of that law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The provisions of this section are in addition to any powers conferred by law upon such officers, and not in limitation of any powers conferred by law upon such officers, or any other officers of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 502</ref>, § 89; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 1</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 406</ref>; renumbered § 522, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(5), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 523.</num>
<heading> Enforcement authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to guidelines approved by the Secretary, members of the Coast Guard, in the performance of official duties, may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> carry a firearm; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> while at a facility (as defined in <ref>section 70101 of title 46</ref>)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> make an arrest without warrant for any offense against the United States committed in their presence; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> seize property as otherwise provided by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2912</ref>, § 99; renumbered § 523, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 524.</num>
<heading> Enforcement of coastwise trade laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Officers and members of the Coast Guard are authorized to enforce chapter 551 of title 46. The Secretary shall establish a program for these officers and members to enforce that chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 216(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2917</ref>, § 100; renumbered § 524, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 525.</num>
<heading> Special agents of the Coast Guard Investigative Service law enforcement authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A special agent of the Coast Guard Investigative Service designated under subsection (b) has the following authority:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To carry firearms.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To execute and serve any warrant or other process issued under the authority of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> To make arrests without warrant for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any offense against the United States committed in the agent’s presence; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if the agent has probable cause to believe that the individual to be arrested has committed or is committing the felony.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authorities provided in paragraph (1) shall be exercised only in the enforcement of statutes for which the Coast Guard has law enforcement authority, or in exigent circumstances.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Commandant may designate to have the authority provided under subsection (a) any special agent of the Coast Guard Investigative Service whose duties include conducting, supervising, or coordinating investigation of criminal activity in programs and operations of the United States Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The authority provided under subsection (a) shall be exercised in accordance with guidelines prescribed by the Commandant and approved by the Attorney General and any other applicable guidelines prescribed by the Secretary or the Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–448, § 10(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-28">Sept. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1842</ref>, § 95; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–383, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3415</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 217(2)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1557</ref>; renumbered § 525, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(6), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 526.</num>
<heading> Stopping vessels; indemnity for firing at or into vessel</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever any vessel liable to seizure or examination does not stop on being ordered to do so or on being pursued by an authorized vessel or authorized aircraft which has displayed the ensign, pennant, or other identifying insignia prescribed for an authorized vessel or authorized aircraft, the individual in command or in charge of the authorized vessel or authorized aircraft may, subject to paragraph (2), fire at or into the vessel which does not stop.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Before firing at or into a vessel as authorized in paragraph (1), the individual in command or in charge of the authorized vessel or authorized aircraft shall fire a gun as a warning signal, except that the prior firing of a gun as a warning signal is not required if that individual determines that the firing of a warning signal would unreasonably endanger individuals or property in the vicinity of the vessel to be stopped.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The individual in command of an authorized vessel or authorized aircraft and all individuals acting under that individual’s direction shall be indemnified from any penalties or actions for damages for firing at or into a vessel pursuant to subsection (a). If any individual is killed or wounded by the firing, and the individual in command of the authorized vessel or authorized aircraft or any individual acting pursuant to their orders is prosecuted or arrested therefor, they shall be forthwith admitted to bail.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A vessel or aircraft is an authorized vessel or authorized aircraft for purposes of this section if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> it is a Coast Guard vessel or aircraft;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> it is a surface naval vessel or military aircraft on which one or more members of the Coast Guard are assigned pursuant to <ref>section 379 of title 10</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">1</ref> or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> it is any other vessel or aircraft on government noncommercial service when—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the vessel or aircraft is under the tactical control of the Coast Guard; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> at least one member of the Coast Guard is assigned and conducting a Coast Guard mission on the vessel or aircraft.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 546</ref>, § 637; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7401(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4483</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1022</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 746</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 205(a)</ref>–(c), (e)(1), <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1032</ref>, 1033; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 213(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2915</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 209(9)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 41</ref>; renumbered § 526, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(7), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 527.</num>
<heading> Safety of vessels of the Armed Forces</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary may control the anchorage and movement of any vessel in the navigable waters of the United States to ensure the safety or security of any vessel of the Armed Forces in those waters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If the Secretary does not exercise the authority in subsection (a) of this section and immediate action is required, the senior officer present in command may control the anchorage or movement of any vessel in the navigable waters of the United States to ensure the safety and security of any vessel of the Armed Forces under the officer’s command.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If a person violates, or a vessel is operated in violation of, this section or a regulation or order issued under this section, the person or vessel is subject to the enforcement provisions in section 13 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">1</ref> of the Ports and Waterways Safety Act (<ref>33 U.S.C. 1232</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> As used in this section “navigable waters of the United States” includes all waters of the territorial sea of the United States as described in Presidential Proclamation No. 5928 of <date date="1988-12-27">December 27, 1988</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this title, the term “vessel of the Armed Forces” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any vessel owned or operated by the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, other than a time- or voyage-chartered vessel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any vessel owned and operated by the Department of Transportation that is designated by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating as a vessel equivalent to a vessel described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 503</ref>, § 91; <ref>Pub. L. 99–640, § 10(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3549</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 519</ref>; renumbered § 527 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, title III, § 318(a), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>, 4251.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 528.</num>
<heading> Protecting against unmanned aircraft</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of section 210G(k)(3)(C)(iv) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, the missions authorized to be performed by the United States Coast Guard shall be those related to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> functions of the U.S. Coast Guard relating to security or protection of facilities and assets assessed to be high-risk and a potential target for unlawful unmanned aircraft activity, including the security and protection of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a facility, including a facility that is under the administrative control of the Commandant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> a vessel (whether moored or underway) or an aircraft, including a vessel or aircraft—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> that is operated by the Coast Guard, or that the Coast Guard is assisting or escorting; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> that is directly involved in a mission of the Coast Guard pertaining to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> assisting or escorting a vessel of the Department of Defense;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> assisting or escorting a vessel of national security significance, a high interest vessel, a high capacity passenger vessel, or a high value unit, as those terms are defined by the Secretary;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content><ref>section 527(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> assistance in protecting the President or the Vice President (or other officer next in order of succession to the Office of the President) pursuant to the Presidential Protection Assistance Act of 1976 (<ref>18 U.S.C. 3056</ref> note);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> protection of a National Special Security Event and Special Event Assessment Rating events;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> air defense of the United States, including air sovereignty, ground-based air defense, and the National Capital Region integrated air defense system; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VII)</num>
<content> a search and rescue operation; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> missions directed by the Secretary pursuant to 210G(k)(3)(C)(iii) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref> of the Homeland Security Act of 2002.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. H, § 1603(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3529</ref>, § 104; renumbered § 528 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 105(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>AIDS TO NAVIGATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 541.</num>
<heading> Aids to navigation authorized</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In order to aid navigation and to prevent disasters, collisions, and wrecks of vessels and aircraft, the Coast Guard may establish, maintain, and operate:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> aids to maritime navigation required to serve the needs of the armed forces or of the commerce of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> aids to air navigation required to serve the needs of the armed forces of the United States peculiar to warfare and primarily of military concern as determined by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of any department within the Department of Defense and as required by any of those officials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> electronic aids to navigation systems (a) required to serve the needs of the armed forces of the United States peculiar to warfare and primarily of military concern as determined by the Secretary of Defense or any department within the Department of Defense; or (b) required to serve the needs of the maritime commerce of the United States; or (c) required to serve the needs of the air commerce of the United States as requested by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">These aids to navigation other than electronic aids to navigation systems shall be established and operated only within the United States, the waters above the Continental Shelf, the territories and possessions of the United States, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and beyond the territorial jurisdiction of the United States at places where naval or military bases of the United States are or may be located. The Coast Guard may establish, maintain, and operate aids to maritime navigation under paragraph (1) of this section by contract with any person, public body, or instrumentality.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of pierhead beacons, the Commandant may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> acquire, by donation or purchase in behalf of the United States, the right to use and occupy sites for pierhead beacons; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> properly mark all pierheads belonging to the United States situated on the northern and northwestern lakes, whenever the Commandant is duly notified by the department charged with the construction or repair of pierheads that the construction or repair of any such pierheads has been completed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 500</ref>, § 81; <ref>June 22, 1951, ch. 150</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 89</ref>; <ref>Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 30</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1237</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–726, title XIV, § 1404</ref>, <date date="1958-08-23">Aug. 23, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 808</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–662, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-10-14">Oct. 14, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 912</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–546, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2519</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–322, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1582</ref>; renumbered § 541, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8509(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4755</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 542.</num>
<heading> Unauthorized aids to maritime navigation; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person, or public body, or instrumentality, excluding the armed services, shall establish, erect, or maintain any aid to maritime navigation in or adjacent to the waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, its territories or possessions, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, or on the high seas if that person, or public body, or instrumentality is subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, without first obtaining authority to do so from the Coast Guard in accordance with applicable regulations. Whoever violates the provisions of this section or any of the regulations issued by the Secretary in accordance herewith shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and shall be fined not more than $1,500 for each offense. Each day during which such violation continues shall be considered as a new offense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 500</ref>, § 83; <ref>Pub. L. 93–283, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1974-05-14">May 14, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 139</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 205(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3025</ref>; renumbered § 542, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 543.</num>
<heading> Interference with aids to navigation; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person, or public body, or instrumentality, excluding the armed forces, to remove, change the location of, obstruct, wilfully damage, make fast to, or interfere with any aid to navigation established, installed, operated, or maintained by the Coast Guard pursuant to <ref>section 541 of this title</ref>, or with any aid to navigation lawfully maintained under authority granted by the Coast Guard pursuant to <ref>section 542 of this title</ref>, or to anchor any vessel in any of the navigable waters of the United States so as to obstruct or interfere with range lights maintained therein. Whoever violates the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and shall be fined not more than $1,500 for each offense. Each day during which such violation shall continue shall be considered as a new offense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 500</ref>, § 84; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 205(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3025</ref>; renumbered § 543 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 105(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 544.</num>
<heading> Aids to maritime navigation; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe and enforce necessary and reasonable rules and regulations, for the protection of maritime navigation, relative to the establishment, maintenance, and operation of lights and other signals on fixed and floating structures in or over waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and in the high seas for structures owned or operated by persons subject to the jurisdiction of the United States. Any owner or operator of such a structure, excluding an agency of the United States, who violates any of the rules or regulations prescribed hereunder, commits a misdemeanor and shall be punished, upon conviction thereof, by a fine of not exceeding $1,500 for each day which such violation continues.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 501</ref>, § 85; <ref>June 4, 1956, ch. 351, § 1</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 226</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–283, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1974-05-14">May 14, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 139</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 205(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3025</ref>; renumbered § 544, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 545.</num>
<heading> Marking of obstructions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may mark for the protection of navigation any sunken vessel or other obstruction existing on the navigable waters or waters above the continental shelf of the United States in such manner and for so long as, in his judgment, the needs of maritime navigation require. The owner of such an obstruction shall be liable to the United States for the cost of such marking until such time as the obstruction is removed or its abandonment legally established or until such earlier time as the Secretary may determine. All moneys received by the United States from the owners of obstructions, in accordance with this section, shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts. This section shall not be construed so as to relieve the owner of any such obstruction from the duty and responsibility suitably to mark the same and remove it as required by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 501</ref>, § 86; <ref>Pub. L. 89–191</ref>, <date date="1965-09-17">Sept. 17, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 822</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–283, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1974-05-14">May 14, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 139</ref>; renumbered § 545, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 546.</num>
<heading> Deposit of damage payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever an aid to navigation or other property belonging to the Coast Guard is damaged or destroyed by a private person, and such private person or his agent shall pay to the satisfaction of the proper official of the Coast Guard for the cost of repair or replacement of such property, the Commandant may accept and deposit such payments, through proper officers of the Fiscal Service, Treasury Department, in special deposit accounts in the Treasury, for payment therefrom to the person or persons repairing or replacing the damaged property and refundment of amounts collected in excess of the cost of the repairs or replacements concerned. In the event that repair or replacement of the damaged property is effected by the Coast Guard, the appropriations bearing the cost thereof and current at the time collection is made shall be reimbursed from the special deposit account.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 547</ref>, § 642; renumbered § 546, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 547.</num>
<heading> Rewards for apprehension of persons interfering with aids to navigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Coast Guard may offer and pay rewards for the apprehension and conviction, or for information helpful therein, of persons found interfering in violation of law with aids to navigation maintained by the Coast Guard; or for information leading to the discovery of missing Coast Guard property or to recovery thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 547</ref>, § 643; renumbered § 547, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 548.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref></num>
<heading> Prohibition against officers and employees being interested in contracts for materials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No officer, enlisted member, or civilian member of the Coast Guard in any manner connected with the construction, operation, or maintenance of lighthouses, shall be interested, either directly or indirectly, in any contract for labor, materials, or supplies for the construction, operation, or maintenance of lighthouses, or in any patent, plan, or mode of construction or illumination, or in any article of supply for the construction, operation, or maintenance of lighthouses.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8509(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4756</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 549.</num>
<heading> Lighthouse and other sites; necessity and sufficiency of cession by State of jurisdiction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No lighthouse, beacon, public pier, or landmark, shall be built or erected on any site until cession of jurisdiction over the same has been made to the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purposes of subsection (a), a cession by a State of jurisdiction over a place selected as the site of a lighthouse, or other structure or work referred to in subsection (a), shall be deemed sufficient if the cession contains a reservation that process issued under authority of such State may continue to be served within such place.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If no reservation of service described in subsection (b) is contained in a cession, all process may be served and executed within the place ceded, in the same manner as if no cession had been made.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8509(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4756</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 550.</num>
<heading> Marking pierheads in certain lakes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall properly mark all pierheads belonging to the United States situated on the northern and northwestern lakes, whenever he is duly notified by the department charged with the construction or repair of pierheads that the construction or repair of any such pierhead has been completed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8509(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4756</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 548.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002006">1</ref></num>
<heading> Marking anchorage grounds by Commandant of the Coast Guard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall provide, establish, and maintain, out of the annual appropriations for the Coast Guard, buoys or other suitable marks for marking anchorage grounds for vessels in waters of the United States, when such anchorage grounds have been defined and established by proper authority in accordance with the laws of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVIII, § 11808(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4166</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 561.</num>
<heading> Icebreaking in polar regions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procurement Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may enter into one or more contracts for the procurement of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Polar Security Cutters approved as part of a major acquisition program as of <date date="2019-11-01">November 1, 2019</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 3 additional Polar Security Cutters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Condition for out-year contract payments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A contract entered into under paragraph (1) shall provide that any obligation of the United States to make a payment under the contract during a fiscal year after fiscal year 2019 is subject to the availability of appropriations or funds for that purpose for such later fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Planning</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall facilitate planning for the design, procurement, maintenance, deployment, and operation of icebreakers as needed to support the statutory missions of the Coast Guard in the polar regions by allocating all funds to support icebreaking operations in such regions, except for recurring incremental costs associated with specific projects, to the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall preclude the Secretary from seeking reimbursement for operation and maintenance costs of the <i>Polar Star</i>, <i>Healy</i>, or any other Polar Security Cutter from other Federal agencies and entities, including foreign countries, that benefit from the use of those vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Restriction.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant may not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> transfer, relinquish ownership of, dismantle, or recycle the <i>Polar Sea</i> or <i>Polar Star</i>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> change the current homeport of the <i>Polar Sea</i> or <i>Polar Star</i>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> expend any funds—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for any expenses directly or indirectly associated with the decommissioning of the <i>Polar Sea</i> or <i>Polar Star</i>, including expenses for dock use or other goods and services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for any personnel expenses directly or indirectly associated with the decommissioning of the <i>Polar Sea</i> or <i>Polar Star</i>, including expenses for a decommissioning officer;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> for any expenses associated with a decommissioning ceremony for the <i>Polar Sea</i> or <i>Polar Star</i>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> to appoint a decommissioning officer to be affiliated with the <i>Polar Sea</i> or <i>Polar Star</i>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> to place the <i>Polar Sea</i> or <i>Polar Star</i> in inactive status.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This subsection shall cease to have effect on <date date="2022-09-30">September 30, 2022</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may not expend amounts appropriated for the Coast Guard for any of fiscal years 2015 through 2024, for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> design activities related to a capability of a Polar Security Cutter that is based solely on an operational requirement of a Federal department or agency other than the Coast Guard, except for amounts appropriated for design activities for a fiscal year before fiscal year 2016; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> long-lead-time materials, production, or postdelivery activities related to such a capability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other amounts</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Amounts made available to the Secretary under an agreement with a Federal department or agency other than the Coast Guard and expended on a capability of a Polar Security Cutter that is based solely on an operational requirement of such Federal department or agency shall not be treated as amounts expended by the Secretary for purposes of the limitation under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enhanced Maintenance Program for the </inline>Polar Star.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Commandant shall conduct an enhanced maintenance program on the Polar Star <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002007">1</ref> to extend the service life of such vessel until at least <date date="2025-12-31">December 31, 2025</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may use funds made available pursuant to section 4902(1)(A), to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Polar sea</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “<i>Polar Sea</i>” means Coast Guard Cutter <i>Polar Sea</i> (WAGB 11).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Polar star</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “<i>Polar Star</i>” means Coast Guard Cutter <i>Polar Star</i> (WAGB 10).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Healy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “<i>Healy</i>” means Coast Guard Cutter <i>Healy</i> (WAGB 20).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3060</ref>, § 87; renumbered § 561, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXI</ref> [LXXXI], § 8111(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4637</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 562.</num>
<heading> Appeals and waivers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except for the Commandant, any individual adjudicating an appeal or waiver of a decision regarding marine safety, including inspection or manning and threats to the environment, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be a qualified specialist with the training, experience, and qualifications in marine safety to effectively judge the facts and circumstances involved in the appeal and make a judgment regarding the merits of the appeal; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> have a senior staff member who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> meets the requirements of paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> actively advises the individual adjudicating the appeal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> concurs in writing on the decision on appeal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title V, § 524(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2958</ref>, § 102; renumbered § 101, <ref>Pub. L. 111–330, § 1(6)(A)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3569</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2320</ref>; renumbered § 562, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 563.</num>
<heading> Notification of certain determinations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>At least 90 days prior to making a final determination that a waterway, or a portion thereof, is navigable for purposes of the jurisdiction of the Coast Guard, the Commandant shall provide notification regarding the proposed determination to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Governor of each State in which such waterway, or portion thereof, is located;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the public; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Content Requirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each notification provided under subsection (a) to an entity specified in paragraph (3) of that subsection shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an analysis of whether vessels operating on the waterway, or portion thereof, subject to the proposed determination are subject to inspection or similar regulation by State or local officials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an analysis of whether operators of commercial vessels on such waterway, or portion thereof, are subject to licensing or similar regulation by State or local officials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an estimate of the annual costs that the Coast Guard may incur in conducting operations on such waterway, or portion thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 210(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3027</ref>, § 103; renumbered § 563, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 564.</num>
<heading> Administration of sexual assault forensic examination kits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Sexual Assault Forensic Exam Procedure.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Before embarking on any prescheduled voyage, a Coast Guard vessel shall have in place a written operating procedure that ensures that an embarked victim of sexual assault shall have access to a sexual assault forensic examination—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as soon as possible after the victim requests an examination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that is treated with the same level of urgency as emergency medical care.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The written operating procedure required by paragraph (1),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">1</ref> shall, at a minimum, account for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the health, safety, and privacy of a victim of sexual assault;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the proximity of ashore or afloat medical facilities, including coordination as necessary with the Department of Defense, including other military departments (as defined in <ref>section 101 of title 10</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the availability of aeromedical evacuation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the operational capabilities of the vessel concerned;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the qualifications of medical personnel onboard;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> coordination with law enforcement and the preservation of evidence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the means of accessing a sexual assault forensic examination and medical care with a restricted report of sexual assault;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the availability of nonprescription pregnancy prophylactics; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> other unique military considerations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11272(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4066</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>