<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 41—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS FOR COAST GUARD RESERVE AND AUXILIARY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4101.</num>
<heading> Flags; pennants; uniforms and insignia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may prescribe one or more suitable distinguishing flags, pennants, or other identifying insignia to be displayed by the motorboats, yachts, aircraft, and radio stations owned by members of the Auxiliary and one or more suitable insignia which may be worn by members of the Reserve or the Auxiliary, and may prescribe one or more suitable uniforms which may be worn by members of the Auxiliary. Such flags, pennants, uniforms, and insignia may be furnished by the Coast Guard at actual cost, and the proceeds received therefor shall be credited to current appropriations from which purchase of these articles is authorized.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 557</ref>, § 891; renumbered § 4101, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 120(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4102.</num>
<heading> Penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever, without proper authority, flies from any building, aircraft, motorboat, yacht, or other vessel, any flag or pennant or displays any identifying insignia or wears any uniform or insignia of the Reserve or the Auxiliary shall be fined not more than $500.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 557</ref>, § 892; renumbered § 4102, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 120(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4103.</num>
<heading> Limitation on rights of members of the Auxiliary and temporary members of the Reserve</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Auxiliary and temporary members of the Reserve shall be entitled only to such rights, privileges, and benefits as are specifically set forth for them in this title or as may be specifically provided for them in any other Act of Congress. Any Act of Congress which grants rights, privileges, or benefits generally to military personnel, or among others, to personnel of the Coast Guard and the Coast Guard Reserve, without specifically granting such rights, privileges, or benefits to members of the Auxiliary or temporary members of the Reserve, shall not be deemed applicable to members of the Auxiliary or to temporary members of the Reserve.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 557</ref>, § 893; renumbered § 4103, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 120(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4104.</num>
<heading> Availability of facilities and appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The services and facilities of and appropriations for the Coast Guard shall be available to effectuate the purposes of the Reserve and the Auxiliary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 557</ref>, § 894; renumbered § 4104, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 120(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>