<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 25—</num>
<heading>PERSONNEL; GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2501.</num>
<heading> Grade on retirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Commissioned Officers.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A commissioned officer who is retired under any provision of this title, shall be retired from active service with the highest grade held by the commissioned officer for not less than six months while on active duty in which, as determined by the Secretary, the commissioned officer’s performance of duty was satisfactory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditional determination</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>When a commissioned officer is under investigation for alleged misconduct at the time of retirement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary may conditionally determine the highest grade of satisfactory service of the commissioned officer pending completion of the investigation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the grade under subparagraph (A) is subject to resolution under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Warrant Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any warrant officer who is retired under any provision of section 580, 1263, 1293, or 1305 of title 10, shall be retired from active service with the highest commissioned grade above chief warrant officer, W–4, held by the warrant officer for not less than six months on active duty in which, as determined by the Secretary, the warrant officer’s performance of duty was satisfactory.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Retirement in Lower Grade.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Misconduct in lower grade</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a commissioned officer whom the Secretary determines committed misconduct in a lower grade, the Secretary may determine the commissioned officer has not served satisfactorily in any grade equal to or higher than that lower grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adverse findings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A determination of the retired grade of a commissioned officer shall be resolved following a conditional determination under subsection (a)(2) if the investigation of or personnel action against the commissioned officer results in adverse findings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recalculation of retired pay</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the retired grade of a commissioned officer is reduced pursuant to this subsection, the retired pay of the commissioned officer shall be recalculated under chapter 71 of title 10, and any modification of the retired pay of the commissioned officer shall go into effect on the effective date of the reduction in retired grade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Finality of Retired Grade Determinations.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a determination of the retired grade of a commissioned officer under this section is administratively final on the day the commissioned officer is retired, and may not be reopened.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reopening determinations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A determination of the retired grade of a commissioned officer may be reopened if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the retirement or retired grade of the commissioned officer was procured by fraud;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> substantial evidence comes to light after the retirement that could have led to a lower retired grade under this section and such evidence was not known by competent authority at the time of retirement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a mistake of law or calculation was made in the determination of the retired grade;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in the case of a retired grade following a conditional determination under subsection (a)(2), the investigation of or personnel action against the commissioned officer results in adverse findings; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, that good cause exists to reopen the determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If a determination of the retired grade of a commissioned officer is reopened under paragraph (2), the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall notify the commissioned officer of the reopening; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may not make an adverse determination on the retired grade of the commissioned officer until the commissioned officer has had a reasonable opportunity to respond regarding the basis of the reopening.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recalculation of retired pay</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the retired grade of a commissioned officer is reduced through the reopening of the commissioned officer’s retired grade under paragraph (2), the retired pay of the commissioned officer shall be recalculated under chapter 71 of title 10, and any modification of the retired pay of the commissioned officer shall go into effect on the effective date of the reduction in retired grade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to Commissioned Warrant Officers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section, including subsection (b), shall not apply to commissioned warrant officers.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 88–130, § 1(10)(C)</ref>, <date date="1963-09-24">Sept. 24, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 190</ref>, § 334; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–444, § 1(19)</ref>, <date date="1966-06-09">June 9, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 196</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 205(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1125(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1505</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 541(f)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2766</ref>; renumbered § 2501, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8201(c), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4641</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2502.</num>
<heading> Retirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Every commissioned officer, warrant officer, or enlisted member who is retired under any provisions of this title shall be retired with the permanent grade or rate held at the time of retirement, unless entitled to retire with a higher grade or rate under any provision of this title or any other law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Where an officer is entitled, under any provision of law, to retire with one grade higher than the grade in which serving at the time of retirement, the next higher grade in the case of captain shall be rear admiral (lower half), and the next higher grade in the case of commissioned warrant officer shall be lieutenant (junior grade).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 524</ref>, § 421; <ref>Pub. L. 97–417, § 2(10)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2086</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 205(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 700</ref>; renumbered § 2502, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2503.</num>
<heading> Status of recalled personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All retired personnel when recalled to active duty shall serve in the grade or rate in which they were serving at the time of retirement.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 524</ref>, § 422; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 205(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 700</ref>; renumbered § 2503, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2504.</num>
<heading> Computation of retired pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The retired pay of a member who first became a member of a uniformed service (as defined in <ref>section 101 of title 10</ref>) before <date date="1980-09-08">September 8, 1980</date>, is determined by multiplying—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the basic pay of the member’s retired grade or rate, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all permanent additions thereto including longevity credit to which the member was entitled at the time of retirement; by</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the retired pay multiplier determined under <ref>section 1409 of title 10</ref> for the number of years of service that may be credited to the member under section 1405 of such title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In the case of an officer who served as Commandant, retired pay under paragraph (1) shall be computed at the highest rate of basic pay applicable to the officer while so serving.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the case of an enlisted member who served as the master chief petty officer of the Coast Guard, retired pay under paragraph (1) shall be computed at the highest rate of basic pay to which the member was entitled while so serving, if that basic pay is greater than the basic pay of the grade or rate to which the member is otherwise entitled at the time of retirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In the case of an officer whose retired pay is computed on the pay of a grade for which basic pay is not based upon years of service, retired pay under paragraph (1) shall be computed on the basis of the number of years of service for which the officer would be entitled to credit in the computation of pay on the active list had the officer been serving in the grade of captain at the time of retirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The retired pay of a member who first became a member of a uniformed service (as defined in <ref>section 101 of title 10</ref>) on or after <date date="1980-09-08">September 8, 1980</date>, is determined by multiplying—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the retired pay base determined under <ref>section 1407 of title 10</ref>; by</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the retired pay multiplier determined under <ref>section 1409 of title 10</ref> for the number of years of service that may be credited to the member under section 1405 of such title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In computing for the purpose of subsection (a) or (b) the number of years of service that may be credited to a member under <ref>section 1405 of title 10</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each full month of service that is in addition to the number of full years of service creditable to the member shall be counted as <sup>1</sup>⁄<sub>12</sub> of a year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any remaining fractional part of a month shall be disregarded.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Retired pay computed under this section, if not a multiple of $1, shall be rounded to the next lower multiple of $1.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In addition to amounts computed pursuant to subsections (a) through (c) of this section, a full TSP member (as defined in <ref>section 8440e(a) of title 5</ref>) of the Coast Guard is entitled to continuation pay pursuant to <ref>section 356 of title 37</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 525</ref>, § 423; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 23</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–422, § 11(b)</ref>, <date date="1958-05-20">May 20, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 132</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–132, § 5(i)</ref>, <date date="1963-10-02">Oct. 2, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 214</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–455, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-10-02">Oct. 2, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 761</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–342, title VIII, § 813(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-08">Sept. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1109</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 2(12)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–94, title IX</ref>, §§ 922(b), 923(d), <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 642</ref>, 643; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 699</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. F, title II, § 225</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 616</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(c)(13)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2320</ref>; renumbered § 2504, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2505.</num>
<heading> Limitations on retirement and retired pay</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The provisions of any section of this title shall not be construed so as to prevent any member from being placed on the retired list with the highest grade or rate and the highest retired pay to which the member may be entitled under the provisions of any other section of this title or under any other law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In no case may the retired pay of a member exceed 75 percent of (1) the sum of the active-duty pay and all permanent additions thereto (including longevity credit to which the member is entitled) of the grade or rate on which the member’s pay is computed, or (2) the retired pay base determined under <ref>section 1407 of title 10</ref>, as appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 525</ref>, § 424; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 205(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 700</ref>; renumbered § 2505, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2506.</num>
<heading> Suspension of payment of retired pay of members who are absent from the United States to avoid prosecution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under procedures prescribed by the Secretary, the Secretary may suspend the payment of the retired pay of a member or former member during periods in which the member willfully remains outside the United States to avoid criminal prosecution or civil liability. The procedures shall address the types of criminal offenses and civil proceedings for which the procedures may be used, including the offenses specified in <ref>section 8312 of title 5</ref>, and the manner by which a member, upon the return of the member to the United States, may obtain retired pay withheld during the member’s absence.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 444(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2132</ref>, § 424a; renumbered § 2506, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2507.</num>
<heading> Board for Correction of Military Records deadline</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deadline for Completion of Action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall complete processing of an application for correction of military records under <ref>section 1552 of title 10</ref> by not later than 10 months after the date the Secretary receives the completed application.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Remedies Deemed Exhausted</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Ten months after a complete application for correction of military records is received by the Board for Correction of Military Records of the Coast Guard, administrative remedies are deemed to have been exhausted, and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if the Board has rendered a recommended decision, its recommendation shall be final agency action and not subject to further review or approval within the department in which the Coast Guard is operating; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> if the Board has not rendered a recommended decision, agency action is deemed to have been unreasonably delayed or withheld and the applicant is entitled to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an order under <ref>section 706(1) of title 5</ref>, directing final action be taken within 30 days from the date the order is entered; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> from amounts appropriated to the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, the costs of obtaining the order, including a reasonable attorney’s fee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 209(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3914</ref>, § 425; renumbered § 2507, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2508.</num>
<heading> Emergency leave retention authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A duty assignment for an active duty member of the Coast Guard in support of a declaration of a major disaster or emergency by the President under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.) or in response to a spill of national significance shall be treated, for the purpose of <ref>section 701(e) of title 10</ref>, as a duty assignment in support of a contingency operation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Spill of national significance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “spill of national significance” means a discharge of oil or a hazardous substance that is declared by the Commandant to be a spill of national significance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Discharge</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “discharge” has the meaning given that term in section 1001 of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 (<ref>33 U.S.C. 2701</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 207(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2912</ref>, § 426; renumbered § 2508, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 631(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2631</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2509.</num>
<heading> Prohibition of certain involuntary administrative separations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary may not authorize the involuntary administrative separation of a covered individual based on a determination that the covered individual is unsuitable for deployment or other assignment due to a medical condition of the covered individual considered by a Physical Evaluation Board during an evaluation of the covered individual that resulted in the covered individual being determined to be fit for duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reevaluation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may require a Physical Evaluation Board to reevaluate any covered individual if the Secretary determines there is reason to believe that a medical condition of the covered individual considered by a Physical Evaluation Board during an evaluation of the covered individual renders the covered individual unsuitable for continued duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retirements and separations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A covered individual who is determined, based on a reevaluation under paragraph (1), to be unfit to perform the duties of the covered individual’s office, grade, rank, or rating may be retired or separated for physical disability under chapter 61 of title 10.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Individual Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “covered individual” means any member of the Coast Guard who has been determined by a Physical Evaluation Board, pursuant to a physical evaluation by that board, to be fit for duty.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 209(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1549</ref>, § 427; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 209(6)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 41</ref>; renumbered § 2509, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2510.</num>
<heading> Sea service letters</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary shall provide a sea service letter to a member or former member of the Coast Guard who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> accumulated sea service on a vessel of the Armed Forces (as such term is defined in section 527(e)); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> requests such letter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 30 days after receiving a request for a sea service letter from a member or former member of the Coast Guard under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide such letter to such member or former member if such member or former member satisfies the requirement under subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 305(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3044</ref>, § 428; renumbered § 2510 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, title III, § 318(c), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>, 4252.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2511.</num>
<heading> Investigations of flag officers and Senior Executive Service employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In conducting an investigation into an allegation of misconduct by a flag officer or member of the Senior Executive Service serving in the Coast Guard, the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct the investigation in a manner consistent with Department of Defense policies for such an investigation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consult with the Inspector General of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 220(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 48</ref>, § 430; renumbered § 2511, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2512.</num>
<heading> Leave policies for the Coast Guard</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in subsection (b), not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary of the Navy promulgates a new rule, policy, or memorandum pursuant to <ref>section 704 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, with respect to leave associated with the birth or adoption of a child, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall promulgate a similar rule, policy, or memorandum that provides leave to officers and enlisted members of the Coast Guard that is equal in duration and compensation to that provided by the Secretary of the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leave Associated With Birth or Adoption of Child</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding subsection (a), sections 701 and 704 of title 10, or any other provision of law, all officers and enlisted members of the Coast Guard shall be authorized leave associated with the birth or adoption of a child during the 1-year period immediately following such birth or adoption and, at the discretion of the Commanding Officer, such officer or enlisted member shall be permitted—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to take such leave in increments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to use flexible work schedules (pursuant to a program established by the Secretary in accordance with chapter 61 of title 5).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 222(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 49</ref>, § 431; renumbered § 2512 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, title III, § 315(a), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>, 4250.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2513.</num>
<heading> Computation of length of service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In computing length of service of officers and enlisted personnel for any purpose all creditable service in the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, Space Force, Coast Guard, Revenue Cutter Service, and Life Saving Service shall be included in addition to any other creditable service authorized by any other law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 531</ref>, § 467; renumbered § 2513, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 927(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3831</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2514.</num>
<heading> Career flexibility to enhance retention of members</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Programs Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may carry out a program under which members of the Coast Guard may be inactivated from active duty in order to meet personal or professional needs and returned to active duty at the end of such period of inactivation from active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Period of Inactivation From Active Duty; Effect of Inactivation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The period of inactivation from active duty under a program under this section of a member participating in the program shall be such period as the Commandant shall specify in the agreement of the member under subsection (c), except that such period may not exceed 3 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion from years of service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any service by a Reserve officer while participating in a program under this section shall be excluded from computation of the total years of service of that officer pursuant to <ref>section 14706(a) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion from retirement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any period of participation of a member in a program under this section shall not count toward—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> eligibility for retirement or transfer to the Ready Reserve under either chapter 841 or 1223 of title 10; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> computation of retired or retainer pay under chapter 71 or 1223 of title 10.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each member of the Coast Guard who participates in a program under this section shall enter into a written agreement with the Commandant under which that member shall agree as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To accept an appointment or enlist, as applicable, and serve in the Coast Guard Ready Reserve during the period of the inactivation of the member from active duty under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To undergo during the period of the inactivation of the member from active duty under the program such inactive service training as the Commandant shall require in order to ensure that the member retains proficiency, at a level determined by the Commandant to be sufficient, in the military skills, professional qualifications, and physical readiness of the member during the inactivation of the member from active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Following completion of the period of the inactivation of the member from active duty under the program, to serve 2 months as a member of the Coast Guard on active duty for each month of the period of the inactivation of the member from active duty under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions of Release</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall prescribe regulations specifying the guidelines regarding the conditions of release that must be considered and addressed in the agreement required by subsection (c). At a minimum, the Commandant shall prescribe the procedures and standards to be used to instruct a member on the obligations to be assumed by the member under paragraph (2) of such subsection while the member is released from active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Order to Active Duty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Commandant, a member of the Coast Guard participating in a program under this section may, in the discretion of the Commandant, be required to terminate participation in the program and be ordered to active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Pay and Allowances.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basic pay</inline>.—</heading>
<content>During each month of participation in a program under this section, a member who participates in the program shall be paid basic pay in an amount equal to two-thirtieths of the amount of monthly basic pay to which the member would otherwise be entitled under <ref>section 204 of title 37</ref> as a member of the uniformed services on active duty in the grade and years of service of the member when the member commences participation in the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special or incentive pay or bonus.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member who participates in such a program shall not, while participating in the program, be paid any special or incentive pay or bonus to which the member is otherwise entitled under an agreement under chapter 5 of title 37 that is in force when the member commences participation in the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Not treated as failure to perform services</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The inactivation from active duty of a member participating in a program shall not be treated as a failure of the member to perform any period of service required of the member in connection with an agreement for a special or incentive pay or bonus under chapter 5 of title 37 that is in force when the member commences participation in the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Return to active duty.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Special or incentive pay or bonus</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subparagraph (B), upon the return of a member to active duty after completion by the member of participation in a program—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any agreement entered into by the member under chapter 5 of title 37 for the payment of a special or incentive pay or bonus that was in force when the member commenced participation in the program shall be revived, with the term of such agreement after revival being the period of the agreement remaining to run when the member commenced participation in the program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any special or incentive pay or bonus shall be payable to the member in accordance with the terms of the agreement concerned for the term specified in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any special or incentive pay or bonus otherwise covered by such subparagraph with respect to a member if, at the time of the return of the member to active duty as described in that subparagraph—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> such pay or bonus is no longer authorized by law; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the member does not satisfy eligibility criteria for such pay or bonus as in effect at the time of the return of the member to active duty.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pay or bonus ceases being authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subparagraph (A) shall cease to apply to any special or incentive pay or bonus otherwise covered by such subparagraph with respect to a member if, during the term of the revived agreement of the member under subparagraph (A)(i), such pay or bonus ceases being authorized by law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Repayment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member who is ineligible for payment of a special or incentive pay or bonus otherwise covered by this paragraph by reason of subparagraph (B)(i)(II) shall be subject to the requirements for repayment of such pay or bonus in accordance with the terms of the applicable agreement of the member under chapter 5 of title 37.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Required service is additional</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any service required of a member under an agreement covered by this paragraph after the member returns to active duty as described in subparagraph (A) shall be in addition to any service required of the member under an agreement under subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Travel and transportation allowance.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to subparagraph (B), a member who participates in a program is entitled, while participating in the program, to the travel and transportation allowances authorized by section 474 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002022">1</ref> of title 37 for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> travel performed from the residence of the member, at the time of release from active duty to participate in the program, to the location in the United States designated by the member as the member’s residence during the period of participation in the program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> travel performed to the residence of the member upon return to active duty at the end of the participation of the member in the program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Single residence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An allowance is payable under this paragraph only with respect to travel of a member to and from a single residence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leave balance</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member who participates in a program is entitled to carry forward the leave balance existing as of the day on which the member begins participation and accumulated in accordance with <ref>section 701 of title 10</ref>, but not to exceed 60 days.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Promotion.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Officers.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An officer participating in a program under this section shall not, while participating in the program, be eligible for consideration for promotion under chapter 21 or 37 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Return to duty</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Upon the return of an officer to active duty after completion by the officer of participation in a program—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Commandant may adjust the date of rank of the officer in such manner as the Commandant may prescribe in regulations for purposes of this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the officer shall be eligible for consideration for promotion when officers of the same grade and seniority are eligible for consideration for promotion.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enlisted members</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An enlisted member participating in a program under this section shall not be eligible for consideration for advancement during the period that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> begins on the date of the inactivation of the member from active duty under the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ends at such time after the return of the member to active duty under the program that the member is treatable as eligible for promotion by reason of time in grade and such other requirements as the Commandant shall prescribe in regulations for purposes of the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continued Entitlements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A member participating in a program under this section shall, while participating in the program, be treated as a member of the Armed Forces on active duty for a period of more than 30 days for purposes of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the entitlement of the member and of the dependents of the member to medical and dental care under the provisions of chapter 55 of title 10; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> retirement or separation for physical disability under the provisions of chapter 61 of title 10 and chapters 21 and 23 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8204(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2515.</num>
<heading> Calculation of active service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any service described, including service described prior to the date of enactment of the Don Young Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2022, in writing, including by electronic communication, by a representative of the Coast Guard Personnel Service Center as service that counts toward total active service for regular retirement under section 2152 or section 2306 shall be considered by the President as active service for purposes of applying section 2152 or section 2306 with respect to the determination of the retirement qualification for any officer or enlisted member to whom a description was provided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11242(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4040</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2516.</num>
<heading> Members asserting post-traumatic stress disorder or traumatic brain injury</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Medical Examination Required.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall ensure that a member of the Coast Guard who has performed Coast Guard operations or has been sexually assaulted during the preceding 2-year period, and who is diagnosed by an appropriate licensed or certified healthcare professional as experiencing post-traumatic stress disorder or traumatic brain injury or who otherwise alleges, based on the service of the member or based on such sexual assault, the influence of such a condition, receives a medical examination to evaluate a diagnosis of post-traumatic stress disorder or traumatic brain injury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restriction on administrative separation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A member described in paragraph (1) shall not be administratively separated under conditions other than honorable, including an administrative separation in lieu of a court-martial, until the results of the medical examination have been reviewed by appropriate authorities responsible for evaluating, reviewing, and approving the separation case, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Post-traumatic stress disorder</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In a case involving post-traumatic stress disorder under this subsection, a medical examination shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> performed by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a board-certified or board-eligible psychiatrist; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a licensed doctorate-level psychologist; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> performed under the close supervision of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a board-certified or board-eligible psychiatrist; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a licensed doctorate-level psychologist, a doctorate-level mental health provider, a psychiatry resident, or a clinical or counseling psychologist who has completed a 1-year internship or residency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Traumatic brain injury</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In a case involving traumatic brain injury under this subsection, a medical examination shall be performed by a physiatrist, psychiatrist, neurosurgeon, or neurologist.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purpose of Medical Examination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The medical examination required under subsection (a) shall assess whether the effects of mental or neurocognitive disorders, including post-traumatic stress disorder and traumatic brain injury, constitute matters in extenuation that relate to the basis for administrative separation under conditions other than honorable or the overall characterization of the service of the member as other than honorable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to Proceedings Under Uniform Code of Military Justice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The medical examination and procedures required by this section do not apply to courts-martial or other proceedings conducted pursuant to the Uniform Code of Military Justice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coast Guard Operations Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Coast Guard operations” has the meaning given that term in section 888(a) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref>6 U.S.C. 468(a)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXIV, § 11410(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4116</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ADVISORY BOARD ON WOMEN IN THE COAST GUARD</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2521.</num>
<heading> Advisory Board on Women in the Coast Guard</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall establish within the Coast Guard an Advisory Board on Women in the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Advisory Board established under subsection (a) shall be composed of such number of members as the Commandant considers appropriate, selected by the Commandant through a public selection process from among applicants for membership on the Board. The members of the Board shall, to the extent practicable, represent the diversity of the Coast Guard. The members of the Committee shall include an equal number of each of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Active duty officers of the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Active duty enlisted members of the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Members of the Coast Guard Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Retired members of the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Advisory Board established under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall advise the Commandant on improvements to the recruitment, retention, wellbeing, and success of women serving in the Coast Guard and attending the Coast Guard Academy, including recommendations for the report on gender diversity in the Coast Guard required by section 5109 of chapter 51 of title 14;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may submit to the Commandant recommendations in connection with its duties under this subsection, including recommendations to implement the advice described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may brief Congress on its duties under this subsection, including the advice described in paragraph (1) and any recommendations described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8215(c)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4651</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>[SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>REPEALED]</heading>
<section>
<num>[§§ 2531 to 2534.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVIII, § 11808(a)(18)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4166</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>