<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 9—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>REAL AND PERSONAL PROPERTY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 901.</num>
<heading> Disposal of certain material</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Commandant subject to applicable regulations under subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41 may dispose of, with or without charge, to the Coast Guard Auxiliary, including any incorporated unit thereof, to the sea-scout service of the Boy Scouts of America, and to any public body or private organization not organized for profit having an interest therein for historical or other special reasons, such obsolete or other material as may not be needed for the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Commandant may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, sell apparatus or equipment manufactured by or in use in the Coast Guard, which is not readily procurable in the open market. The money received from such sale shall be deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the current appropriation from which purchase of similar apparatus or equipment is authorized.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Commandant may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide for the sale of recyclable materials that the Coast Guard holds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide for the operation of recycling programs at Coast Guard installations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> designate Coast Guard installations that have qualified recycling programs for the purposes of subsection (d)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Recyclable materials shall be sold in accordance with sections 541–555 of title 40, except that the Commandant may conduct sales of materials for which the proceeds of sale will not exceed $5,000 under regulations prescribed by the Commandant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Proceeds from the sale of recyclable materials at a Coast Guard installation shall be credited to funds available for operations and maintenance at that installation in amounts sufficient to cover operations, maintenance, recycling equipment, and overhead costs for processing recyclable materials at the installation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If, after funds are credited, a balance remains available to a Coast Guard installation and the installation has a qualified recycling program, not more than 50 percent of that balance may be used at the installation for projects for pollution abatement, energy conservation, and occupational safety and health activities. The cost of the project may not be greater than 50 percent of the amount permissible for a minor construction project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The remaining balance available to a Coast Guard installation may be transferred to the Coast Guard Morale, Welfare, and Recreation Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If the balance available to the Coast Guard installation under this section at the end of a fiscal year is in excess of $200,000, the amount of that excess shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury as offsetting receipts of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating and ascribed to Coast Guard activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 547</ref>, § 641; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 2(11)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 707</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 2(4)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title V, § 5202</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5071</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title IV, § 408</ref>, title XI, § 1119, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3925</ref>, 3973; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3847</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 209(10)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 41</ref>; renumbered § 901, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 902.</num>
<heading> Employment of draftsmen and engineers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Coast Guard may employ temporarily, at the seat of government, draftsmen and engineers for the preparation of plans and specifications for vessels, lighthouses, aids to navigation, and other projects for the Coast Guard that may be authorized or appropriated for by Congress, to be paid from the appropriations applicable to such projects.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 550</ref>, § 653; renumbered § 902, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 903.</num>
<heading> Use of certain appropriated funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Funds appropriated to or for the use of the Coast Guard for procurement, construction, and improvement of facilities and for research and development shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary may use any funds appropriated to or for the use of the Coast Guard for other construction purposes to restore, repair, or replace facilities that have been damaged or destroyed, including acquisition of sites.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may use any funds appropriated to or for the use of the Coast Guard for other construction purposes to acquire, construct, convert, extend, and install at Coast Guard installations and facilities, needed permanent or temporary public works, including the preparation of sites and the furnishing of appurtenances, utilities, and equipment, but excluding the construction of family quarters, costing  not  more  than  $200,000  for  any  one project.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Minor Construction and Improvement.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the reporting requirements set forth in paragraph (2), each fiscal year the Secretary may expend from amounts made available for the operations and support of the Coast Guard not more than $1,500,000 for minor construction and improvement projects at any location.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than the date on which the President submits to Congress a budget under <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref> each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report describing each project carried out under paragraph (1), in the most recently concluded fiscal year, for which the amount expended under such paragraph for such project was more than $1,000,000. If no such project was carried out during a fiscal year, no report under this paragraph shall be required with respect to that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 88–45, § 2</ref>, <date date="1963-06-21">June 21, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 68</ref>, § 656; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–283, § 1(9)</ref>, <date date="1974-05-14">May 14, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 140</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 212(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1552</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 221(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3038</ref>; renumbered § 903, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8513(a)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4760</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 904.</num>
<heading> Local hire</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other law, each contract awarded by the Coast Guard for construction or services to be performed in whole or in part in a State that has an unemployment rate in excess of the national average rate of unemployment (as determined by the Secretary of Labor) shall include a provision requiring the contractor to employ, for the purpose of performing that portion of the contract in that State, individuals who are local residents and who, in the case of any craft or trade, possess or would be able to acquire promptly the necessary skills. The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may waive the requirements of this subsection in the interest of national security or economic efficiency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Local Resident Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As used in this section, “local resident” means a resident of, or an individual who commutes daily to, a State described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–225, title II, § 206(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-12">Dec. 12, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1912</ref>, § 666; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 217(10)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1558</ref>; renumbered § 904, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 905.</num>
<heading> Procurement authority for family housing</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to acquire, subject to the availability of appropriations sufficient to cover its full obligations, real property or interests therein by purchase, lease for a term not to exceed 5 years, or otherwise, for use as Coast Guard family housing units, including the acquisition of condominium units, which may include the obligation to pay maintenance, repair, and other condominium-related fees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to dispose of by sale, lease, or otherwise, any real property or interest therein used for Coast Guard family housing units for adequate consideration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this section, a multiyear contract is a contract to lease Coast Guard family housing units for at least one, but not more than 5, fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may enter into multiyear contracts under subsection (a) of this section whenever the Coast Guard finds that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the use of a contract will promote the efficiency of the Coast Guard family housing program and will result in reduced total costs under the contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there are realistic estimates of both the cost of the contract and the anticipated cost avoidance through the use of a multiyear contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A multiyear contract authorized under subsection (a) of this section shall contain cancellation and termination provisions to the extent necessary to protect the best interests of the United States, and may include consideration of both recurring and nonrecurring costs. The contract may provide for a cancellation payment to be made. Amounts that were originally obligated for the cost of the contract may be used for cancellation or termination costs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2423</ref>, § 670; renumbered § 905, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 906.</num>
<heading> Air Station Cape Cod Improvements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may expend funds for the repair, improvement, restoration, or replacement of those federally or nonfederally owned support buildings, including appurtenances, which are on leased or permitted real property constituting Coast Guard Air Station Cape Cod, located on Massachusetts Military Reservation, Cape Cod, Massachusetts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2423</ref>, § 671; renumbered § 906, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 907.</num>
<heading> Long-term lease of special purpose facilities</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized, subject to the availability of appropriations, to enter into lease agreements to acquire real property or interests therein for a term not to exceed 20 years, inclusive of any automatic renewal clauses, for special purpose facilities, including, aids to navigation (hereafter in this section referred to as “ATON”) sites, vessel traffic service (hereafter in this section referred to as “VTS”) sensor sites, or National Distress System (hereafter in this section referred to as “NDS”) high level antenna sites. These lease agreements shall include cancellation and termination provisions to the extent necessary to protect the best interests of the United States. Cancellation payment provisions may include consideration of both recurring and nonrecurring costs associated with the real property interests under the contract. These lease agreements may provide for a cancellation payment to be made. Amounts that were originally obligated for the cost of the contract may be used for cancellation or termination costs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, the term “special purpose facilities” means any facilities used to carry out Coast Guard aviation, maritime, or navigation missions other than general purpose office and storage space facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of ATON, VTS, or NDS sites, the Secretary may enter into multiyear lease agreements under subsection (a) of this section whenever the Secretary finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the use of such a lease agreement will promote the efficiency of the ATON, VTS, or NDS programs and will result in reduced total costs under the agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the minimum need for the real property or interest therein to be leased is expected to remain substantially unchanged during the contemplated lease period; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the estimates of both the cost of the lease and the anticipated cost avoidance through the use of a multiyear lease are realistic.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–206, title III, § 304(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2424</ref>, § 672; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 746(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3943</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 212(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1036</ref>; renumbered § 907, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 908.</num>
<heading> Long-term lease authority for lighthouse property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Commandant may lease to non-Federal entities, including private individuals, lighthouse property under the administrative control of the Coast Guard for terms not to exceed 30 years. Consideration for the use and occupancy of lighthouse property leased under this section, and for the value of any utilities and services furnished to a lessee of such property by the Commandant, may consist, in whole or in part, of non-pecuniary remuneration including the improvement, alteration, restoration, rehabilitation, repair, and maintenance of the leased premises by the lessee. <ref>Section 1302 of title 40</ref> shall not apply to leases issued by the Commandant under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Amounts received from leases made under this section, less expenses incurred, shall be deposited in the fund established under section 2946.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 417(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2122</ref>, § 672a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 208(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3026</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV</ref>, §§ 3531(c)(4), 3533(e), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2320</ref>, 2321; renumbered § 908 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 107(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 909.</num>
<heading> Small boat station rescue capability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that each Coast Guard small boat station (including a seasonally operated station) maintains, within the area of responsibility for the station, at least 1 vessel that is fully capable of performing offshore rescue operations, taking into consideration prevailing weather, marine conditions, and depositional geologic features such as sand bars.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title III, § 309(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3919</ref>, § 673; renumbered § 674, <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 405(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2115</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(a)</ref>, (f)(1), <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>, 2316; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 217(12)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1558</ref>; renumbered § 909, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 910.</num>
<heading> Small boat station closures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Closures</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may not close a Coast Guard multimission small boat station or subunit unless the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> remaining search and rescue capabilities maintain the safety of the maritime public in the area of the station or subunit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> regional or local prevailing weather and marine conditions, including water temperature or unusual tide and current conditions, do not require continued operation of the station or subunit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Coast Guard search and rescue standards related to search and rescue response times are met; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provides an opportunity for public comment and for public meetings in the area of the station or subunit with regard to the decision to close the station or subunit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operational Flexibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may implement any management efficiencies within the small boat station system, such as modifying the operational posture of units or reallocating resources as necessary to ensure the safety of the maritime public nationwide. No stations or subunits may be closed under this subsection except in accordance with subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title III, § 309(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3919</ref>, § 674; renumbered § 675, <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 405(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2115</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 217(13)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1558</ref>; renumbered § 910, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 911.</num>
<heading> Search and rescue center standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall establish, implement, and maintain the minimum standards necessary for the safe operation of all Coast Guard search and rescue center facilities, including with respect to the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The lighting, acoustics, and temperature in the facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The number of individuals on a shift in the facility assigned search and rescue responsibilities (including communications), which may be adjusted based on seasonal workload.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The length of time an individual may serve on watch to minimize fatigue, based on the best scientific information available.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The scheduling of individuals having search and rescue responsibilities to minimize fatigue of the individual when on duty in the facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The workload of each individual engaged in search and rescue responsibilities in the facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Stress management for the individuals assigned search and rescue responsibilities in the facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The design of equipment and facilities to minimize fatigue and enhance search and rescue operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The acquisition and maintenance of interim search and rescue command center communications equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Any other requirements that the Secretary believes will increase the safe operation of the search and rescue centers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading>
<content>It is the sense of the Congress that the Secretary should establish, implement, and maintain minimum standards necessary to ensure that an individual on duty or watch in a Coast Guard search and rescue command center facility does not work more than 12 hours in a 24-hour period, except in an emergency or unforeseen circumstances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purposes of this section, the term “search and rescue center facility” means a Coast Guard shore facility that maintains a search and rescue mission coordination and communications watch.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 405(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2115</ref>, § 676; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–207, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-27">July 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2251</ref>; renumbered § 911, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 912.</num>
<heading> Air facility closures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Closures.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Beginning on <date date="2018-01-01">January 1, 2018</date>, the Secretary may not close a Coast Guard air facility, except as specified by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determinations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Secretary may not propose closing or terminating operations at a Coast Guard air facility unless the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> remaining search and rescue capabilities maintain the safety of the maritime public in the area of the air facility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> regional or local prevailing weather and marine conditions, including water temperatures or unusual tide and current conditions, do not require continued operation of the air facility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Coast Guard search and rescue standards related to search and response times are met.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Public notice and comment.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Prior to closing an air facility, the Secretary shall provide opportunities for public comment, including the convening of public meetings in communities in the area of responsibility of the air facility with regard to the proposed closure or cessation of operations at the air facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Prior to convening a public meeting under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall notify each congressional office representing any portion of the area of responsibility of the air station that is the subject to such public meeting of the schedule and location of such public meeting.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice to congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Prior to closure, cessation of operations, or any significant reduction in personnel and use of a Coast Guard air facility that is in operation on or after <date date="2017-12-31">December 31, 2017</date>, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> submit to the Congress a proposal for such closure, cessation, or reduction in operations along with the budget of the President submitted to Congress under <ref>section 1105(a) of title 31</ref> that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a discussion of the determination made by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a report summarizing the public comments received by the Secretary under paragraph (3) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002013">1</ref></content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 7 days after the date a proposal for an air facility is submitted pursuant to subparagraph (A), provide written notice of such proposal to each of the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Each member of the House of Representatives who represents a district in which the air facility is located.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Each member of the Senate who represents a State in which the air facility is located.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Each member of the House of Representatives who represents a district in which assets of the air facility conduct search and rescue operations.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Each member of the Senate who represents a State in which assets of the air facility conduct search and rescue operations.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> The Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> The Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Congressional review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may not close, cease operations, or significantly reduce personnel and use of a Coast Guard air facility for which a written notice is provided under paragraph (4)(A) until a period of 18 months beginning on the date on which such notice is provided has elapsed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Operational Flexibility</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may implement any reasonable management efficiencies within the air station and air facility network, such as modifying the operational posture of units or reallocating resources as necessary to ensure the safety of the maritime public nationwide.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 38</ref>, § 676a; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3503(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2775</ref>; renumbered § 912 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, title III, § 319, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>, 4252.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 913.</num>
<heading> Turnkey selection procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority to Use</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may use one-step turnkey selection procedures for the purpose of entering into contracts for construction projects.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “one-step turnkey selection procedures” means procedures used for the selection of a contractor on the basis of price and other evaluation criteria to perform, in accordance with the provisions of a firm fixed-price contract, both the design and construction of a facility using performance specifications supplied by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “construction” includes the construction, procurement, development, conversion, or extension of any facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “facility” means a building, structure, or other improvement to real property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 521</ref>, § 677; renumbered § 913, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 914.</num>
<heading> Disposition of infrastructure related to E–LORAN</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commandant may dismantle or dispose of any real or personal property under the administrative control of the Coast Guard and used for the LORAN–C system.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restriction</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No action described in subsection (a) may be taken unless and until—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Commandant notifies the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of Defense in writing of the proposed dismantling or disposal of a LORAN–C system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a period of 90 calendar days expires following the day on which the notice has been submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Receipt of Notification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, not later than 90 calendar days of receipt of the written notification under subsection (b), the Secretary of Transportation or the Secretary of Defense notifies the Commandant, in writing, of a determination under <ref>section 312(d) of title 49</ref> that the property is required to provide a positioning, navigation, and timing system to provide redundant capability in the event the Global Positioning System signals are disrupted, the Commandant shall transfer the property to the Department of Transportation without any consideration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification Expiration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If, at the end of the 90 calendar day period no notification under subsection (b) has been received, the Commandant shall notify the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Appropriations in the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate that the period in subsection (b)(2) has expired, and may proceed with the dismantling and disposal of the personal property, and disposing of the real property in accordance with <ref>section 2945 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The prohibition on actions in subsection (b) does not apply to actions necessary for the safety of human life.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title VI, § 610(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 83</ref>, § 681; renumbered § 914, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8216, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4653</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11211</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4012</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 931.</num>
<heading> Oaths required for boards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The members of a retiring board, selection board, examining board, and any other board authorized to be assembled pursuant to this title shall be sworn to discharge their duties honestly and impartially, the oath to be administered to the members by the President or other presiding officer of the board, and to him by the junior member or recorder.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 545</ref>, § 635; renumbered § 931, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 932.</num>
<heading> Administration of oaths</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Such commissioned and warrant officers of the Coast Guard as may be designated by the Commandant may, pursuant to rules prescribed by the Commandant, exercise the general powers of a notary public in the administration of oaths for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> execution, acknowledgment, and attestation of instruments and papers, oaths of allegiance in connection with recruiting, oaths in connection with courts and boards, and all other notarial acts in connection with the proper execution of Coast Guard functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> execution, acknowledgment, and attestation of instruments and papers, and all other notarial acts in time of war or national emergency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> execution, acknowledgment, and attestation of instruments and papers, and all other notarial acts in Alaska and places beyond the continental limits of the United States where the Coast Guard is serving.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> No fee of any character shall be charged by any commissioned or warrant officer for performing notarial acts. The signature and indication of grade of any commissioned or warrant officer performing any notarial act shall be prima facie evidence of his authority.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 545</ref>, § 636; renumbered § 932, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 933.</num>
<heading> Coast Guard ensigns and pennants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Vessels and aircraft authorized by the Secretary shall be distinguished from other vessels and aircraft by an ensign, pennant, or other identifying insignia of such design as prescribed by the Secretary. Such ensign, pennant, or other identifying insignia shall be displayed in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> No vessel or aircraft without authority shall carry, hoist, or display any ensign, pennant, or other identifying insignia prescribed for, or intended to resemble, any ensign, pennant, or other identifying insignia prescribed for Coast Guard vessels or aircraft. An individual violating this subsection shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned for not more than two years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 546</ref>, § 638; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 213(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2915</ref>; renumbered § 933, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(9), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 934.</num>
<heading> Penalty for unauthorized use of words “Coast Guard”</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No individual, association, partnership, or corporation shall, without authority of the Commandant, use the combination of letters “USCG” or “USCGR”, the words “Coast Guard,” “United States Coast Guard,” “Coast Guard Reserve,” “United States Coast Guard Reserve,” “Coast Guard Auxiliary,” “United States Coast Guard Auxiliary,” “Lighthouse Service,” “Life Saving Service,” or any combination or variation of such letters or words alone or with other letters or words, as the name under which he or it shall do business, for the purpose of trade, or by way of advertisement to induce the effect of leading the public to believe that any such individual, association, partnership, or corporation has any connection with the Coast Guard. No individual, association, partnership, or corporation shall falsely advertise, or otherwise represent falsely by any device whatsoever, that any project or business in which he or it is engaged, or product which he or it manufactures, deals in, or sells, has been in any way endorsed, authorized, or approved by the Coast Guard. Every person violating this section shall be fined not more than $10,000, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 546</ref>, § 639; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 30</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 408</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 205(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3025</ref>; renumbered § 934, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 935.</num>
<heading> Coast Guard band recordings for commercial sale</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Coast Guard band may produce recordings for commercial sale.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Amounts received as proceeds from the sale of any such recordings may be credited to applicable appropriations of the Coast Guard for expenses of the Coast Guard band.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations governing the accounting of such proceeds.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title III, § 327(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1532</ref>, § 640; renumbered § 935, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 936.</num>
<heading> Confidentiality of medical quality assurance records; qualified immunity for participants</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “medical quality assurance program” means any activity carried out by or for the Coast Guard to assess the quality of medical care, including activities conducted by individuals, military medical or dental treatment facility committees, or other review bodies responsible for quality assurance, credentials, infection control, patient care assessment (including treatment procedures, blood, drugs, and therapeutics) medical records, health resources management review and identification and prevention of medical or dental incidents and risks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “medical quality assurance record” means the proceedings, records, minutes, and reports that emanate from quality assurance program activities described in paragraph (1) and are produced or compiled by the Coast Guard as part of a medical quality assurance program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “health care provider” means any military or civilian health care professional who, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, is granted clinical practice privileges to provide health care services in a military medical or dental treatment facility or who is licensed or certified to perform health care services by a governmental board or agency or professional health care society or organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Medical quality assurance records created by or for the Coast Guard as part of a medical quality assurance program are confidential and privileged. The records may not be disclosed to any person or entity except as provided in subsection (d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Medical quality assurance records are not subject to discovery and may not be admitted into evidence in any judicial or administrative proceeding, except as provided in subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in this section, an individual who reviews or creates medical quality assurance records for the Coast Guard or who participates in any proceeding that reviews or creates the records may not testify in any judicial or administrative proceeding with respect to the records or with respect to any finding, recommendation, evaluation, opinion, or action taken by that person in connection with the records.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2), a medical quality assurance record may be disclosed, and an individual referred to in subsection (c) may testify in connection with a record only as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To a Federal executive agency or private organization, if necessary to license, accredit, or monitor Coast Guard health care facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To an administrative or judicial proceeding commenced by a present or former Coast Guard or Coast Guard assigned Public Health Service health care provider concerning the termination, suspension, or limitation of clinical privileges of the health care provider.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To a governmental board or agency or to a professional health care society or organization, if necessary to perform licensing, or privileging, or to monitor professional standards for a health care provider who is or was a member or an employee of the Coast Guard or the Public Health Service assigned to the Coast Guard.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> To a hospital, medical center, or other institution that provides health care services, if necessary to assess the professional qualifications of any health care provider who is or was a member or employee of the Coast Guard or the Public Health Service assigned to the Coast Guard and who has applied for or been granted authority or employment to provide health care services in or on behalf of the institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> To an officer, member, employee, or contractor of the Coast Guard or the Public Health Service assigned to the Coast Guard if for official purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> To a criminal or civil law enforcement agency or instrumentality charged under applicable law with the protection of the public health or safety, if a qualified representative of the agency or instrumentality makes a written request that the record or testimony be provided for a purpose authorized by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> In an administrative or judicial proceeding commenced by a criminal or civil law enforcement agency or instrumentality referred to in subparagraph (F), but only with respect to the subject of the proceeding.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except in a quality assurance action, the identity of any individual receiving health care services from the Coast Guard or the identity of any other individual associated with the agency for the purposes of a medical quality assurance program that is disclosed in a medical quality assurance record shall be deleted from that record or document before any disclosure of the record is made outside the Coast Guard. This requirement does not apply to the release of information under <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Except as provided in this section, a person having possession of or access to a record or testimony described by this section may not disclose the contents of the record or testimony.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Medical quality assurance records may not be made available to any person under <ref>section 552 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> An individual who participates in or provides information to an individual that reviews or creates medical quality assurance records is not civilly liable for participating or providing the information if the participation or provision of information was in good faith based on prevailing professional standards at the time the medical quality assurance program activity took place.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<chapeau> Nothing in this section shall be construed as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> authority to withhold from any person aggregate statistical information regarding the results of Coast Guard medical quality assurance programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> authority to withhold any medical quality assurance record from a committee of either House of Congress, any joint committee of Congress, or the Government Accountability Office if the record pertains to any matter within their respective jurisdictions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> limiting access to the information in a record created and maintained outside a medical quality assurance program, including a patient’s medical records, on the grounds that the information was presented during meetings of a review body that are part of a medical quality assurance program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this section, an individual who willfully discloses a medical quality assurance record knowing that the record is a medical quality assurance record, is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $3,000 in the case of a first offense and not more than $20,000 in the case of a subsequent offense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title V, § 5203(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5072</ref>, § 645; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 746(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3943</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; renumbered § 936, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 937.</num>
<heading> Admiralty claims against the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may consider, ascertain, adjust, determine, compromise, or settle, and pay in an amount not more than $425,000, an admiralty claim against the United States for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> damage caused by a vessel in the Coast Guard service or by other property under the jurisdiction of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> compensation for towage and salvage services, including contract salvage, rendered to a vessel in the Coast Guard service or to other property under the jurisdiction of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> damage caused by a maritime tort committed by an agent or employee of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating or by property under the jurisdiction of that Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Upon acceptance of payment by the claimant, the settlement or compromise of a claim under this section is final and conclusive notwithstanding any other law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If a claim under this section is settled or compromised for more than $100,000, the Secretary shall certify it to Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 548</ref>, § 646; <ref>Pub. L. 86–533, § 1(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-29">June 29, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–417, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-08-29">Aug. 29, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 655</ref>; renumbered § 937, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8212(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4649</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 938.</num>
<heading> Claims for damage to property of the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may consider, ascertain, adjust, determine, compromise, or settle claims for damage cognizable in admiralty in a district court of the United States and all claims for damage caused by a vessel or floating object, to property of the United States under the jurisdiction of the Coast Guard or property for which the Coast Guard may have assumed, by contract or otherwise, any obligation to respond for damage thereto. The Secretary is further authorized to receive in payment of any such claim the amount due the United States pursuant to determination, compromise, or settlement as herein authorized and, upon acceptance of such payment but not until then, such determination, settlement, or compromise of such claim shall be final and conclusive for all purposes, any law to the contrary notwithstanding. All such payments shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts. The Secretary is further authorized to execute on behalf of the United States and to deliver in exchange for such payment a full release of such claim. This section, as respects the determination, compromise, settlement, and payment of claims, shall be supplementary to, and not in lieu of, all other provisions of law authorizing the determination, compromise, or settlement of claims for damage to property hereinabove described. No settlement or compromise where there is involved a payment in the net amount of over $425,000 is authorized by this section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 549</ref>, § 647; <ref>Pub. L. 86–533, § 1(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-29">June 29, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–546, § 1(34)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 17(b)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2868</ref>; renumbered § 938, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8212(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 939.</num>
<heading> Accounting for industrial work</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may prescribe regulations governing accounting for industrial work, including charges for overhead for civilian labor and for maintenance of industrial plant and equipment, performed at the Coast Guard Yard or such similar Coast Guard industrial establishments as he may designate. Any orders placed for such industrial work shall be covered by a transfer or advance of funds to cover the estimated cost thereof, and shall be credited to such accounts as may be necessary and established by the Secretary to carry out the provisions of this section. Accounts so established shall be available for materials, supplies, or equipment, and civilian labor, including overhead and maintenance, required in performing the work ordered. Upon completion of an order an adjustment will be made to make the amount transferred or advanced equal to the actual cost as computed in accordance with the accounting regulations prescribed by the Secretary or in accordance with subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Incentive Contracts.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The parties to an order for industrial work to be performed by the Coast Guard Yard or a Coast Guard industrial establishment designated under subsection (a) may enter into an order or a cost-plus-incentive-fee order in accordance with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If such parties enter into such an order or a cost-plus-incentive-fee order, an agreed-upon amount of any adjustment described in subsection (a) may be distributed as an incentive to the wage-grade industrial employees who complete the order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Before entering into such an order or cost-plus-incentive-fee order such parties must agree that the wage-grade employees of the Coast Guard Yard or Coast Guard industrial establishment will take action to improve the delivery schedule or technical performance agreed to in the order for industrial work to which such parties initially agreed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the industrial workforce of the Coast Guard Yard or Coast Guard industrial establishment satisfies the performance target established in such an order or cost-plus-incentive-fee order—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the adjustment to be made pursuant to subsection (a) shall be reduced by an agreed-upon amount and distributed to such wage-grade industrial employees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the remainder of the adjustment shall be credited to the appropriation for such order current at that time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 549</ref>, § 648; renumbered § 939 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, title III, § 307, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>, 4247.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 940.</num>
<heading> Supplies and equipment from stock</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Supplies and equipment for special work of the Coast Guard may be furnished from general stock and the applicable appropriation reimbursed therefor from the respective appropriations for such special work.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 550</ref>, § 649; renumbered § 940, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 941.</num>
<heading> Coast Guard Supply Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A Coast Guard Supply Fund is authorized. The Secretary may prescribe regulations for designating the classification of materials to be stocked. In these regulations, whenever the fund is extended to include items not previously stocked, or spare parts obtained as part of a procurement under a different account of major items such as vessels or aircraft, whether or not such parts were previously stocked, the Secretary may authorize an increase in the existing capital of the fund by the value of such usable materials transferred thereto from Coast Guard inventories carried in other accounts. Except for the materials so transferred, the fund shall be charged with the cost of materials purchased or otherwise acquired. The fund shall be credited with the value of materials consumed, issued for use, sold, or otherwise disposed of, such values to be determined on a basis that will approximately cover the cost thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Obligations may, without regard to fiscal year limitations, be incurred against anticipated reimbursement to the Coast Guard Supply Fund in such amount and for such period, as the Secretary, with approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, may determine to be necessary to maintain stock levels consistently with planned operations for the next year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 550</ref>, § 650; <ref>Aug. 7, 1956, ch. 1023, § 1(a)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 1077</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–278, § 1(13)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-12">June 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 306</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–546, § 1(35)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–376, § 5</ref>, <date date="1980-10-03">Oct. 3, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1509</ref>; renumbered § 941, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 942.</num>
<heading> Public and commercial vessels and other watercraft; sale of fuel, supplies, and services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary under such regulations as he may prescribe, may sell to public and commercial vessels and other watercraft, such fuel, supplies and furnish such services as may be required to meet the necessities of the vessel or watercraft if such vessel or watercraft is unable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to procure the fuel, supplies, or services from other sources at its present location; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to proceed to the nearest port where they may be obtained without endangering the safety of the ship, the health and comfort of its personnel, or the safe condition of the property carried aboard.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Sales under this section shall be at such prices as the Secretary considers reasonable. Payment will be made on a cash basis or on such other basis as will reasonably assure prompt payment. Amounts received from such a sale shall, unless otherwise directed by another provision of law, be credited to the current appropriation concerned and are available for the same purposes as that appropriation.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 86–159, § 1</ref>, <date date="1959-08-14">Aug. 14, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 357</ref>, § 654; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–444, § 1(22)</ref>, <date date="1966-06-09">June 9, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 197</ref>; renumbered § 942, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 943.</num>
<heading> Arms and ammunition; immunity from taxation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax on the sale or transfer of firearms, pistols, revolvers, shells, or cartridges may be imposed on such articles when bought with funds appropriated for the Coast Guard.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 87–526, § 1(6)</ref>, <date date="1962-07-10">July 10, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 142</ref>, § 655; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–546, § 1(37)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2522</ref>; renumbered § 943, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 944.</num>
<heading> Confidential investigative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than $250,000 each fiscal year appropriated for the operations and support of the Coast Guard shall be available for investigative expenses of a confidential character, to be expended on the approval or authority of the Commandant and payment to be made on the Commandant’s certificate of necessity for confidential purposes, and the Commandant’s determination shall be final and conclusive upon the accounting officers of the Government.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–283, § 1(10)</ref>, <date date="1974-05-14">May 14, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 140</ref>, § 658; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 221</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1040</ref>; renumbered § 944 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, title III, § 308, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>, 4248; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8513(a)(3), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4760</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 945.</num>
<heading> Assistance to film producers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, when the Secretary determines that it is appropriate, and that it will not interfere with Coast Guard missions, the Secretary may conduct operations with Coast Guard vessels, aircraft, facilities, or personnel, in such a way as to give assistance to film producers. As used in this section, “film producers” includes commercial or noncommercial producers of material for cinema, television, or videotape.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall keep account of costs incurred as a result of providing assistance to film producers, not including costs which would otherwise be incurred in Coast Guard operations or training, or shall estimate such costs in advance, and such costs shall be paid to the Secretary by the film producers who request such assistance, on terms determined by the Secretary. The Secretary may waive costs not exceeding $200 for one production, and may waive other costs related to noncommercial productions which the Secretary determines to be in the public interest. The Secretary shall reimburse the amounts collected under this section to the Coast Guard appropriation account under which the costs were incurred.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–448, § 29(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-28">Sept. 28, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1849</ref>, § 659; renumbered § 945, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 946.</num>
<heading> User fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A fee or charge for a service or thing of value provided by the Coast Guard shall be prescribed as provided in <ref>section 9701 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Amounts collected by the Secretary for a service or thing of value provided by the Coast Guard shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury as proprietary receipts of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating and ascribed to Coast Guard activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In addition to the collection of fees and charges established under this section, the Secretary may recover from the person liable for the fee or charge the costs of collecting delinquent payments of the fee or charge, and enforcement costs associated with delinquent payments of the fees and charges.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary may employ any Federal, State, or local agency or instrumentality, or any private enterprise or business, to collect a fee or charge established under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A private enterprise or business employed by the Secretary to collect fees or charges—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be subject to reasonable terms and conditions agreed to by the Secretary and the enterprise or business;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall provide appropriate accounting to the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> may not institute litigation as part of that collection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In addition to the collection of fees and charges established under this section, in the provision of a service or thing of value by the Coast Guard the Secretary may accept in-kind transportation, travel, and subsistence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The value of in-kind transportation, travel, and subsistence accepted under this paragraph may not exceed applicable per diem rates set forth in regulations prescribed under <ref>section 464 of title 37</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall account for the agency’s costs of collecting a fee or charge as a reimbursable expense, subject to the availability of appropriations, and the costs shall be credited to the account from which expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> Before January 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a verification of each activity for which a fee or charge is collected under any law stating—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount collected in the prior fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that the amount spent on that activity in that fiscal year is not less than the amount collected; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount expected to be collected under any law in the current fiscal year for each activity for which a fee or charge is expected to be collected.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> In this section the term “costs of collecting a fee or charge” includes the reasonable administrative, accounting, personnel, contract, equipment, supply, training, and travel expenses of calculating, assessing, collecting, enforcing, reviewing, adjusting, and reporting on a fee or charge.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5102(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1926</ref>, § 664; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–225, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1989-12-12">Dec. 12, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1914</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 408(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1033</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 311(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3048</ref>; renumbered § 946, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 947.</num>
<heading> Vessel construction bonding requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary or the Commandant may require bid, payment, performance, payment and performance, or completion bonds or other financial instruments from contractors for construction, alteration, repair, or maintenance of Coast Guard vessels if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the bond is required by law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary or Commandant determines after investigation that the amount of the bond in excess of 20 percent of the value of the base contract quantity excluding options, would not prevent a responsible bidder or offeror from competing for award of the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–595, title III, § 306(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2985</ref>, § 667; renumbered § 947, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 948.</num>
<heading> Contracts for medical care for retirees, dependents, and survivors: alternative delivery of health care</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may contract for the delivery of health care to which covered beneficiaries are entitled under chapter 55 of title 10. The Secretary may enter into a contract under this section with any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Health maintenance organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Preferred provider organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Individual providers, individual medical facilities, or insurers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Consortiums of these providers, facilities, or insurers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A contract entered into under this section may provide for the delivery of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> selected health care services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> total health care services for selected covered beneficiaries; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> total health care services for all covered beneficiaries who reside in a geographic area designated by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary may prescribe a premium, deductible, copayment, or other change for health care provided under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–595, title III, § 319(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2989</ref>, § 668; renumbered § 948, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 949.</num>
<heading> Telephone installation and charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, amounts appropriated to the Department of Homeland Security are available to install, repair, and maintain telephone wiring in residences owned or leased by the United States Government and, if necessary for national defense purposes in other private residences.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–587, title V, § 5204(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 5074</ref>, § 669; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; renumbered § 949, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 950.</num>
<heading> Designation, powers, and accountability of deputy disbursing officials</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Subject to paragraph (3), a disbursing official of the Coast Guard may designate a deputy disbursing official—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to make payments as the agent of the disbursing official;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to sign checks drawn on disbursing accounts of the Secretary of the Treasury; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to carry out other duties required under law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The penalties for misconduct that apply to a disbursing official apply to a deputy disbursing official designated under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A disbursing official may make a designation under paragraph (1) only with the approval of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a disbursing official of the Coast Guard dies, becomes disabled, or is separated from office, a deputy disbursing official may continue the accounts and payments in the name of the former disbursing official until the last day of the second month after the month in which the death, disability, or separation occurs. The accounts and payments shall be allowed, audited, and settled as provided by law. The Secretary of the Treasury shall honor checks signed in the name of the former disbursing official in the same way as if the former disbursing official had continued in office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The deputy disbursing official, and not the former disbursing official or the estate of the former disbursing official, is liable for the actions of the deputy disbursing official under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), this section does not apply to the Coast Guard when <ref>section 2773 of title 10</ref> applies to the Coast Guard by reason of the operation of the Coast Guard as a service in the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A designation of a deputy disbursing official under subsection (a) that is made while the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy continues in effect for purposes of <ref>section 2773 of title 10</ref> while the Coast Guard operates as a service in the Navy unless and until the designation is terminated by the disbursing official who made the designation or an official authorized to approve such a designation under subsection (a)(3) of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1009(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2634</ref>, § 673; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 217(11)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1558</ref>; renumbered § 950, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 951.</num>
<heading> Aircraft accident investigations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the Commandant conducts an accident investigation of an accident involving an aircraft under the jurisdiction of the Commandant, the records and report of the investigation shall be treated in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Public Disclosure of Certain Accident Investigation Information.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraph (2), the Commandant, upon request, shall publicly disclose unclassified tapes, scientific reports, and other factual information pertinent to an aircraft accident investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall only disclose information requested pursuant to paragraph (1) if the Commandant determines—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that such tapes, reports, or other information would be included within and releasable with the final accident investigation report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> that release of such tapes, reports, or other information—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> would not undermine the ability of accident or safety investigators to continue to conduct the investigation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> would not compromise national security.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Restriction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A disclosure under paragraph (1) may not be made by or through officials with responsibility for, or who are conducting, a safety investigation with respect to the accident.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Opinions Regarding Causation of Accident</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Following an aircraft accident referred to in subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if the evidence surrounding the accident is sufficient for the investigators who conduct the accident investigation to come to an opinion as to the cause or causes of the accident, the final report of the accident investigation shall set forth the opinion of the investigators as to the cause or causes of the accident; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the evidence surrounding the accident is not sufficient for the investigators to come to an opinion as to the cause or causes of the accident, the final report of the accident investigation shall include a description of those factors, if any, that, in the opinion of the investigators, substantially contributed to or caused the accident.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Information in Civil or Criminal Proceedings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of any civil or criminal proceeding arising from an aircraft accident referred to in subsection (a), any opinion of the accident investigators as to the cause of, or the factors contributing to, the accident set forth in the accident investigation report may not be considered as evidence in such proceeding, nor may such report be considered an admission of liability by the United States or by any person referred to in such report.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “accident investigation” means any form of investigation by Coast Guard personnel of an aircraft accident referred to in subsection (a), other than a safety investigation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “safety investigation” means an investigation by Coast Guard personnel of an aircraft accident referred to in subsection (a) that is conducted solely to determine the cause of the accident and to obtain information that may prevent the occurrence of similar accidents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1553</ref>, § 678; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(c)(5)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2320</ref>; renumbered § 951, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 952.</num>
<heading> Construction of Coast Guard vessels and assignment of vessel projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The assignment of Coast Guard vessel conversion, alteration, and repair projects shall be based on economic and military considerations and may not be restricted by a requirement that certain parts of Coast Guard shipwork be assigned to a particular type of shipyard or geographical area or by a similar requirement.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title III, § 310(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 953.</num>
<heading> Support for Coast Guard Academy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Contracts and cooperative agreements.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may enter contract and cooperative agreements with 1 or more qualified organizations for the purpose of supporting the athletic programs of the Coast Guard Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 3201(e) of title 10</ref>, the Commandant may enter into such contracts and cooperative agreements on a sole source basis pursuant to <ref>section 3204(a) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Acquisitions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding chapter 63 of title 31, a cooperative agreement under this section may be used to acquire property or services for the direct benefit or use of the Coast Guard Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Financial controls.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Before entering into a contract or cooperative agreement under paragraph (1), the Commandant shall ensure that the contract or agreement includes appropriate financial controls to account for the resources of the Coast Guard Academy and the qualified organization concerned in accordance with accepted accounting principles.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any such contract or cooperative agreement shall contain a provision that allows the Commandant to review, as the Commandant considers necessary, the financial accounts of the qualified organization to determine whether the operations of the qualified organization—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are consistent with the terms of the contract or cooperative agreement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> would compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the Department of Homeland Security.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Leases</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For the purpose of supporting the athletic programs of the Coast Guard Academy, the Commandant may, consistent with section 504(a)(13), rent or lease real property located at the Coast Guard Academy to a qualified organization, except that proceeds from such a lease shall be retained and expended in accordance with subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Support Services.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent required by a contract or cooperative agreement under subsection (a), the Commandant may provide support services to a qualified organization while the qualified organization conducts support activities at the Coast Guard Academy only if the Commandant determines that the provision of such services is essential for the support of the athletic programs of the Coast Guard Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No liability of the united states</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Support services may only be provided without any liability of the United States to a qualified organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Support services defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this subsection, the term “support services” includes utilities, office furnishings and equipment, communications services, records staging and archiving, audio and video support, and security systems, in conjunction with the leasing or licensing of property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transfers From Nonappropriated Fund Operation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Commandant may, subject to the acceptance of the qualified organization concerned, transfer to the qualified organization all title to and ownership of the assets and liabilities of the Coast Guard nonappropriated fund instrumentality, the function of which includes providing support for the athletic programs of the Coast Guard Academy, including bank accounts and financial reserves in the accounts of such fund instrumentality, equipment, supplies, and other personal property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may not transfer under paragraph (1) any interest in real property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Acceptance of Support From Qualified Organization.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, the Commandant may accept from a qualified organization funds, supplies, and services for the support of the athletic programs of the Coast Guard Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Employees of qualified organization</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, employees or personnel of the qualified organization may not be considered to be employees of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Funds received from ncaa</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may accept funds from the National Collegiate Athletic Association to support the athletic programs of the Coast Guard Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall ensure that contributions under this subsection and expenditure of funds pursuant to subsection (f) do not—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Coast Guard, any employee of the Coast Guard, or any member of the armed forces (as such term is defined in <ref>section 101(a) of title 10</ref>) to carry out any responsibility or duty in a fair and objective manner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the Coast Guard, or any individual involved in such a program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Trademarks and Service Marks.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Licensing, marketing, and sponsorship agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An agreement under subsection (a) may, consistent with <ref>section 2260 of title 10</ref> (other than subsection (d) of such section), authorize a qualified organization to enter into licensing, marketing, and sponsorship agreements relating to trademarks and service marks identifying the Coast Guard Academy, subject to the approval of the Commandant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A licensing, marketing, or sponsorship agreement may not be entered into under paragraph (1) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such agreement would reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Coast Guard, any employee of the Coast Guard, or any member of the armed forces to carry out any responsibility or duty in a fair and objective manner; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Commandant determines that the use of the trademark or service mark would compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the Coast Guard or any individual involved in such a program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Retention and Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds received by the Commandant under this section may be retained for use to support the athletic programs of the Coast Guard Academy and shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The authority provided in this section with respect to a qualified organization is available only so long as the qualified organization continues—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to operate in accordance with this section, the law of the State of Connecticut, and the constitution and bylaws of the qualified organization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to operate exclusively to support the athletic programs of the Coast Guard Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualified Organization Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “qualified organization” means an organization—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that operates as an organization under subsection (c)(3) of section 501 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under subsection (a) of that section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for which authorization under sections 1033(a) and 1589(a) of title 10 may be provided; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> established by the Coast Guard Academy Alumni Association solely for the purpose of supporting Coast Guard athletics.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11250(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4049</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 954.</num>
<heading> Mixed-funded athletic and recreational extracurricular programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a Coast Guard Academy mixed-funded athletic or recreational extracurricular program, the Commandant may designate funds appropriated to the Coast Guard and available for that program to be treated as nonappropriated funds and expended for that program in accordance with laws applicable to the expenditure of nonappropriated funds. Appropriated funds so designated shall be considered to be nonappropriated funds for all purposes and shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Covered Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “Coast Guard Academy mixed-funded athletic or recreational extracurricular program” means an athletic or recreational extracurricular program of the Coast Guard Academy to which each of the following applies:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The program is not considered a morale, welfare, or recreation program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The program is supported through appropriated funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The program is supported by a nonappropriated fund instrumentality.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The program is not a private organization and is not operated by a private organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11250(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4051</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>