<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 23—</num>
<heading>PERSONNEL; ENLISTED</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2301.</num>
<heading> Recruiting campaigns</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall initiate and carry forward an intensified voluntary enlistment campaign to obtain the required personnel strengths.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 7(a)</ref>, <ref>70A Stat. 620</ref>, § 350; renumbered § 2301, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2302.</num>
<heading> Enlistments; term, grade</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the Commandant may enlist persons for the duration of their minority or a period of at least two years but not more than six years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall prescribe the grades or ratings for persons enlisting in the Regular Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 520</ref>, § 351; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 16</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, §§ 8(a), 53, <ref>70A Stat. 620</ref>, 679; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(F)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1032</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3533(h)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2321</ref>; renumbered § 2302, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2303.</num>
<heading> Promotion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Enlisted members shall be advanced in rating by the Commandant under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 520</ref>, § 352; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(C)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; renumbered § 2303, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2304.</num>
<heading> Compulsory retirement at age of sixty-two</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any enlisted member who has reached the age of sixty-two shall be retired from active service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 520</ref>, § 353; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 205(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 700</ref>; renumbered § 2304, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2305.</num>
<heading> Voluntary retirement after thirty years’ service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any enlisted member who has completed thirty years’ service may, upon his own application, in the discretion of the Commandant, be retired from active service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 521</ref>, § 354; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 205(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 700</ref>; renumbered § 2305, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2306.</num>
<heading> Voluntary retirement after twenty years’ service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any enlisted member who has completed twenty years’ service may, upon his own application, in the discretion of the Commandant, be retired from active service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 521</ref>, § 355; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 205(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 700</ref>; renumbered § 2306, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2307.</num>
<heading> Retirement of enlisted members: increase in retired pay</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An enlisted member voluntarily or involuntarily retired after twenty years of service who was cited for extraordinary heroism in the line of duty shall be entitled to an increase in retired pay. The retired pay shall be increased by 10 percent of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the active-duty pay and permanent additions thereto of the grade or rating with which retired when the member’s retired pay is computed under <ref>section 2504(a) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the member’s retired pay base under <ref>section 1407 of title 10</ref>, when a member’s retired pay is computed under <ref>section 2504(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 521</ref>, § 357; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 17</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–114, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1963-09-06">Sept. 6, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 144</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 205(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–241, § 6</ref>, <date date="1991-12-19">Dec. 19, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 2210</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 215(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 45</ref>, 46; renumbered § 2307 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 113(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2308.</num>
<heading> Recall to active duty during war or national emergency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In times of war or national emergency, the Commandant may order any enlisted member on the retired list to active duty.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 522</ref>, § 359; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 18</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; renumbered § 2308, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2309.</num>
<heading> Recall to active duty with consent of member</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any enlisted member on the retired list may, with his consent, be assigned to such duties as he may be able to perform, except that no enlisted member on the retired list who has reached the age of sixty-two years shall be recalled in time of peace.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 522</ref>, § 360; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 19</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, (4)(B)(i), <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; renumbered § 2309, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2310.</num>
<heading> Relief of retired enlisted member promoted while on active duty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any enlisted member on the retired list recalled to active duty who during such active duty is advanced to a higher grade or rating under a permanent or temporary appointment or promotion shall, upon relief from active duty be advanced on the retired list to the highest grade or rating held while on active duty. In case the appointment or promotion was temporary the advancement on the retired list shall be made only to such grade or rating in which the member served satisfactorily on active duty.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 522</ref>, § 361; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 20</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, (G), (4)(C)(i), <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; renumbered § 2310, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2311.</num>
<heading> Retirement in cases where higher grade or rating has been held</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any enlisted member who is retired under any provision of section 2304, 2305, 2306, or 2307 of this title shall be retired from active service with the highest grade or rating held by him while on active duty in which, as determined by the Secretary, his performance of duty was satisfactory, but not lower than his permanent grade or rating.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 522</ref>, § 362; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 21</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 2(9)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 205(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1986-07-01">July 1, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 700</ref>; renumbered § 2311 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 113(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2312.</num>
<heading> Extension of enlistments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the term of enlistment of any enlisted member may, by voluntary written agreement, be extended and re-extended for a period not exceeding six full years from the date of expiration of the then-existing term of enlistment, and subsequent to such date an enlisted member who so extends his term of enlistment shall receive the same pay and allowances in all respects as though regularly discharged and reenlisted immediately upon expiration of his term of enlistment. However, the total of all such extensions of an enlistment may not exceed six years. No such extension shall operate to deprive the enlisted member concerned, upon discharge at the termination thereof, of any right, privilege, or benefit to which he would have been entitled if his term of enlistment had not been so extended.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 523</ref>, § 365; <ref>Pub. L. 86–474, § 1(18)</ref>, <date date="1960-05-14">May 14, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 146</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; renumbered § 2312, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2313.</num>
<heading> Retention beyond term of enlistment in case of disability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any enlisted member of the Coast Guard in the active service whose term of enlistment expires while he is suffering disease or injury incident to service and not due to misconduct, and who is in need of medical care or hospitalization, may, with his consent, be retained in such service beyond the expiration of his term of enlistment. Any such enlisted member shall be entitled to receive at Government expense medical care or hospitalization and his pay and allowances, including credit for longevity, until he shall have recovered to such extent as would enable him to meet the physical requirements for reenlistment, or until it shall have been ascertained by competent authority of the Coast Guard that the disease or injury is of a character that recovery to such an extent would be impossible. Any enlisted member whose enlistment is so extended shall be subject to forfeitures in the same manner and to the same extent as if his term of enlistment had not expired. Nothing contained in this section shall prevent any enlisted member from being held in the service without his consent under <ref>section 2314 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 523</ref>, § 366; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; renumbered § 2313 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 113(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2314.</num>
<heading> Detention beyond term of enlistment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, an enlisted member may be detained in the Coast Guard beyond the term of his enlistment:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> until the first arrival of the vessel on which he is serving at its permanent station, or at a port in a State of the United States or in the District of Columbia; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if attached to a shore station beyond the continental limits of the United States or in Alaska, until his first arrival at a port in any State of the United States or in the District of Columbia where his reenlistment or discharge may be effected, or until he can be discharged or reenlisted at his station beyond the continental limits of the United States or in Alaska, whichever is earlier, but in no event to exceed three months; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> during a period of war or national emergency as proclaimed by the President, and, in the interest of national defense, for a period not to exceed six months after the end of the war or the termination of the emergency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> for a period of not exceeding thirty days in other cases whether or not specifically covered by this section, when essential to the public interests, and the determination that such detention is essential to the public interests, made in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary, shall be final and conclusive.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any member detained in the Coast Guard as provided in this section shall be entitled to receive pay and allowances and benefits under the same conditions as though his enlistment period had not expired, and shall be subject in all respects to the laws and regulations for the government of the Coast Guard until his discharge therefrom. Enlisted members detained under the provisions of clause (1) shall be entitled to the pay and allowances provided for enlisted personnel of the Navy detained under similar circumstances.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 523</ref>, § 367; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 22</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref>July 24, 1956, ch. 692</ref>, §§ 2(4), 3, <ref>70 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557</ref>, §§ 15(a)(3)(A), (C), 17(b)(4), <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>, 2868; renumbered § 2314, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2315.</num>
<heading> Inclusion of certain conditions in enlistment contract</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The enlistment contract shall contain the substance of sections 2312 to 2314,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002021">1</ref> inclusive, of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 524</ref>, § 369; renumbered § 2315 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 113(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2316.</num>
<heading> Discharge within three months before expiration of enlistment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, any enlisted member may be discharged at any time within three months before the expiration of his term of enlistment or extended enlistment without prejudice to any right, privilege, or benefit that he would have received, except pay and allowances for the unexpired period not served, or to which he would thereafter become entitled, had he served his full term of enlistment or extended enlistment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>June 8, 1955, ch. 136, § 2</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 88</ref>, § 370; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2865</ref>; renumbered § 2316, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2317.</num>
<heading> Aviation cadets; procurement; transfer</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The grade of aviation cadet is established as a special enlisted grade in the Coast Guard. Under such regulations as the Secretary prescribes, citizens in civil life may be enlisted as, and enlisted members of the Coast Guard with their consent may be designated as, aviation cadets.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except in time of war or national emergency declared by Congress, not less than 20 percent of the aviation cadets procured in each fiscal year shall be procured from qualified enlisted members of the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> No individuals may be enlisted or designated as an aviation cadet unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the individual agrees in writing that, upon successful completion of the course of training as an aviation cadet, the individual will accept a commission as an ensign in the Coast Guard Reserve and will serve on active duty as such for at least three years, unless sooner released; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if under twenty-one years of age, the individual has the consent of the individual’s parent or guardian to the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Under such regulations as the Secretary prescribes, an aviation cadet may be transferred to another enlisted grade or rating in the Coast Guard, released from active duty, or discharged.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–444, § 1(20)</ref>, <date date="1966-06-09">June 9, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 196</ref>, § 371; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 2(11)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2864</ref>; renumbered § 2317, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(20), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2318.</num>
<heading> Aviation cadets; benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref>section 402(c) of title 37</ref>, aviation cadets or their beneficiaries are entitled to the same allowances, pensions, gratuities, and other benefits as are provided for enlisted members in pay grade E–4. While on active duty, an aviation cadet is entitled to uniforms, clothing, and equipment at the expense of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–444, § 1(20)</ref>, <date date="1966-06-09">June 9, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 197</ref>, § 372; renumbered § 2318, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2319.</num>
<heading> Critical skill training bonus</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary may provide a bonus, not to exceed $20,000, to an enlisted member who completes training in a skill designated as critical, if at least four years of obligated active service remain on the member’s enlistment at the time the training is completed. A bonus under this section may be paid in a single lump sum or in periodic installments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If an enlisted member voluntarily or because of misconduct does not complete the member’s term of obligated active service, the Secretary may require the member to repay the United States, on a pro rata basis, all sums paid under this section. The Secretary may charge interest on the amount repaid at a rate, to be determined quarterly, equal to 150 percent of the average of the yields on the 91-day Treasury bills auctioned during the calendar quarter preceding the date on which the amount to be repaid is determined.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1032</ref>, § 374; renumbered § 2319, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>