<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 29—</num>
<heading>COAST GUARD FAMILY SUPPORT, CHILD CARE, AND HOUSING</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>COAST GUARD FAMILIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2901.</num>
<heading> Work-life policies and programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commandant is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to establish an office for the purpose of developing, promulgating, and coordinating policies, programs, and activities related to the families of Coast Guard members;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to implement and oversee policies, programs, and activities described in paragraph (1) as the Commandant considers necessary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to perform such other duties as the Commandant considers necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3029</ref>, § 531; renumbered § 2901, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2902.</num>
<heading> Surveys of Coast Guard families</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant, in order to determine the effectiveness of Federal policies, programs, and activities related to the families of Coast Guard members, may survey—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any Coast Guard member;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any retired Coast Guard member;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the immediate family of any Coast Guard member or retired Coast Guard member; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any survivor of a deceased Coast Guard member.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Voluntary Participation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Participation in any survey conducted under subsection (a) shall be voluntary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal Recordkeeping</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each individual surveyed under subsection (a) shall be considered an employee of the United States for purposes of <ref>section 3502(3)(A)(i) of title 44</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3029</ref>, § 532; renumbered § 2902, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(47), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2903.</num>
<heading> Reimbursement for adoption expenses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authorization To Reimburse</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall carry out a program under which a member of the Coast Guard may be reimbursed, as provided in this section, for qualifying adoption expenses incurred by the member in the adoption of a child under 18 years of age.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adoptions Covered</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An adoption for which expenses may be reimbursed under this section includes an adoption by a single individual, an infant adoption, an intercountry adoption, and an adoption of a child with special needs (as defined in section 473(c) of the Social Security Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 673(c)</ref>)).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Benefits Paid After Adoption Is Final</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Benefits paid under this section in the case of an adoption may be paid only after the adoption is final.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Other Benefits</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A benefit may not be paid under this section for any expense paid to or for a member of the Coast Guard under any other adoption benefits program administered by the Federal Government or under any such program administered by a State or local government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not more than $2,000 may be paid under this section to a member of the Coast Guard, or to two such members who are spouses of each other, for expenses incurred in the adoption of a child.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not more than $5,000 may be paid under this section to a member of the Coast Guard, or to two such members who are spouses of each other, for adoptions by such member (or members) in any calendar year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “qualifying adoption expenses” means reasonable and necessary expenses that are directly related to the legal adoption of a child under 18 years of age, but only if such adoption is arranged by a qualified adoption agency. Such term does not include any expense incurred—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by an adopting parent for travel; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in connection with an adoption arranged in violation of Federal, State, or local law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “reasonable and necessary expenses” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> public and private agency fees, including adoption fees charged by an agency in a foreign country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> placement fees, including fees charged adoptive parents for counseling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> legal fees (including court costs) in connection with services that are unavailable to a member of the Coast Guard under section 1044 or 1044a of title 10; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> medical expenses, including hospital expenses of the biological mother of the child to be adopted and of a newborn infant to be adopted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “qualified adoption agency” means any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A State or local government agency which has responsibility under State or local law for child placement through adoption.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A nonprofit, voluntary adoption agency which is authorized by State or local law to place children for adoption.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any other source authorized by a State to provide adoption placement if the adoption is supervised by a court under State or local law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VI, § 651(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1386</ref>, § 514; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1054(g)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VI, § 652(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2582</ref>; renumbered § 541, <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3033</ref>; renumbered § 2903, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(48), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2904.</num>
<heading> Education and training opportunities for Coast Guard spouses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Tuition Assistance</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant may provide, subject to the availability of appropriations, tuition assistance to an eligible spouse to facilitate the acquisition of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> education and training required for a degree or credential at an accredited college, university, or technical school in the United States that expands employment and portable career opportunities for the spouse; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> education prerequisites and a professional license or credential required, by a government or government-sanctioned licensing body, for an occupation that expands employment and portable career opportunities for the spouse.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Eligible spouse.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “eligible spouse” means the spouse of a member of the Coast Guard who is serving on active duty and includes a spouse who receives transitional compensation under <ref>section 1059 of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “eligible spouse” does not include an individual who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is married to, but legally separated from, a member of the Coast Guard under a court order or statute of any State or territorial possession of the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is eligible for tuition assistance as a member of the Armed Forces.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Portable career</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “portable career” includes an occupation that requires education, training, or both that results in a credential that is recognized by an industry, profession, or specific type of business.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3030</ref>, § 542; renumbered § 2904, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(49), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2905.</num>
<heading> Youth sponsorship initiatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant is authorized to establish, within any Coast Guard unit, an initiative to help integrate into new surroundings the dependent children of members of the Coast Guard who received permanent change of station orders.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Description of Initiative</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An initiative established under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide for the involvement of a dependent child of a member of the Coast Guard in the dependent child’s new Coast Guard community; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> primarily focus on preteen and teenaged children.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out an initiative under subsection (a), the Commandant may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide to a dependent child of a member of the Coast Guard information on youth programs and activities available in the dependent child’s new Coast Guard community; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enter into agreements with nonprofit entities to provide youth programs and activities to such child.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3030</ref>, § 543; renumbered § 2905, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2906.</num>
<heading> Dependent school children</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary may provide, out of funds appropriated to or for the use of the Coast Guard, for the primary and secondary schooling of dependents of Coast Guard personnel stationed outside the continental United States at costs for any given area not in excess of those of the Department of Defense for the same area, when it is determined by the Secretary that the schools, if any, available in the locality are unable to provide adequately for the education of those dependents.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whenever the Secretary, under such regulations as he may prescribe, determines that schools located in the same area in which a Coast Guard facility is located are not accessible by public means of transportation on a regular basis, he may provide, out of funds appropriated to or for the use of the Coast Guard, for the transportation of dependents of Coast Guard personnel between the schools serving the area and the Coast Guard facility.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–278, § 1(14)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-12">June 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 306</ref>, § 657; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–430, § 5</ref>, <date date="1974-10-01">Oct. 1, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1182</ref>; renumbered § 544 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(b)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3033</ref>; renumbered § 2906, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COAST GUARD CHILD CARE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2921.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter, the following definitions apply:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Child abuse and neglect</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “child abuse and neglect” has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5101</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Child development center employee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “child development center employee” means a civilian employee of the Coast Guard who is employed to work in a Coast Guard child development center without regard to whether the employee is paid from appropriated or nonappropriated funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coast guard child development center</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “Coast Guard child development center” means a facility on Coast Guard property or on property under the jurisdiction of the commander of a Coast Guard unit at which child care services are provided for members of the Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competitive service position</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term “competitive service position” means a position in the competitive service (as defined in <ref>section 2102 of title 5</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Family home daycare</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The term “family home daycare” means home-based child care services provided for a member of the Coast Guard by an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is certified by the Commandant as qualified to provide home-based child care services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provides home-based child care services on a regular basis in exchange for monetary compensation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3031</ref>, § 551; renumbered § 2921, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2922.</num>
<heading> Child development services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Commandant may make child development services available, in such priority as the Commandant considers to be appropriate and consistent with readiness and resources and in the best interests of dependents of members and civilian employees of the Coast Guard, for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> members and civilian employees of the Coast Guard;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> surviving dependents of service members who have died on active duty, if such dependents were beneficiaries of a Coast Guard child development service at the time of the death of such members;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> members of the armed forces (as defined in <ref>section 101(a) of title 10</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Federal civilian employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Child development service benefits provided under the authority of this section shall be in addition to benefits provided under other laws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Commandant is authorized to use appropriated funds available to the Coast Guard to provide child development services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Commandant is authorized to establish, by regulations, fees to be charged parents for the attendance of children at Coast Guard child development centers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Fees to be charged, pursuant to subparagraph (A), shall be based on family income and whether a family is participating in an initiative established under section 2925(b), except that the Commandant may, on a case-by-base basis, establish fees at lower rates if such rates would not be competitive with rates at local child development centers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Commandant is authorized to collect and expend fees, established pursuant to this subparagraph, and such fees shall, without further appropriation, remain available until expended for the purpose of providing services, including the compensation of employees and the purchase of consumable and disposable items, at Coast Guard child development centers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> In the case of an active duty member with two or more children attending a Coast Guard child development center, the Commandant may modify the fees to be charged for attendance for the second and any subsequent child of such member by an amount that is 15 percent less than the amount of the fee otherwise chargeable for the attendance of the first such child enrolled at the center, or another fee as the Commandant determines appropriate, consistent with multiple children.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Commandant is authorized to use appropriated funds available to the Coast Guard to provide assistance to family home daycare providers so that family home daycare services can be provided to uniformed service members and civilian employees of the Coast Guard at a cost comparable to the cost of services provided by Coast Guard child development centers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To the maximum extent practicable, the Commandant shall ensure that, in a location in which Coast Guard family child care centers (as such term is defined in section 8239 of the Elijah E. Cummings Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2020) are necessary to meet the demand for child care for qualified families (as such term is defined in such section), not fewer than two housing units are maintained in accordance with safety inspection standards so as to accommodate family child care providers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to implement this section. The regulations shall establish fees to be charged for child development services provided under this section which take into consideration total family income.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3906</ref>, § 515; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 222</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2920</ref>; renumbered § 552 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3033</ref>; renumbered § 2922 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 117(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>, 4240; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8235, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXIV</ref>, §§ 11401(a), 11402, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4106</ref>, 4109.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2923.</num>
<heading> Child development center standards and inspections</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall require each Coast Guard child development center to meet standards of operation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that the Commandant considers appropriate to ensure the health, safety, and welfare of the children and employees at the center; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> necessary for accreditation by an appropriate national early childhood programs accrediting entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Inspections.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not less than twice annually, the Commandant shall ensure that each Coast Guard child development center is subject to an unannounced inspection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for inspections</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Of the biannual inspections under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 1 shall be carried out by a representative of the Coast Guard installation served by the Coast Guard child development center concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 1 shall be carried out by a representative of the Coast Guard child development services work-life programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">National Reporting.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant shall maintain and publicize a means by which an individual can report, with respect to a Coast Guard child development center or a family home daycare—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> any suspected violation of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> standards established under subsection (a); or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any other applicable law or standard;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> suspected child abuse or neglect; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other deficiency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Anonymous reporting</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall ensure that an individual making a report pursuant to paragraph (1) may do so anonymously if so desired by the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Procedures</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall establish procedures for investigating reports made pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3031</ref>, § 553; renumbered § 2923, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8237(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXIV, § 11401(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2924.</num>
<heading> Child development center employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Training.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall establish a training program for Coast Guard child development center employees and satisfactory completion of the training program shall be a condition of employment for each employee of a Coast Guard child development center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timing for new hires</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall require each employee of a Coast Guard child development center to complete the training program established under paragraph (1) not later than 6 months after the date on which the employee is hired.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Minimum requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The training program established under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, instruction with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> early childhood development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> activities and disciplinary techniques appropriate to children of different ages;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> child abuse and neglect prevention and detection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> cardiopulmonary resuscitation and other emergency medical procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of department of defense programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may use Department of Defense training programs, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, for purposes of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Training and Curriculum Specialists.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specialist required</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall require that at least 1 employee at each Coast Guard child development center be a specialist in training and curriculum development with appropriate credentials and experience.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The duties of the specialist described in paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> special teaching activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> daily oversight and instruction of other child care employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> daily assistance in the preparation of lesson plans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> assisting with child abuse and neglect prevention and detection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> advising the director of the center on the performance of the other child care employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Competitive service</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each specialist described in paragraph (1) shall be an employee in a competitive service position.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3032</ref>, § 554; renumbered § 2924, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2925.</num>
<heading> Parent partnerships with child development centers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Parent Boards.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Formation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant shall require that there be formed at each Coast Guard child development center a board of parents, to be composed of parents of children attending the center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Functions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each board of parents formed under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> meet periodically with the staff of the center at which the board is formed and the commander of the unit served by the center, for the purpose of discussing problems and concerns; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be responsible, together with the staff of the center, for coordinating any parent participation initiative established under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chapter </inline>10<inline class="small-caps"> of title </inline>5.—</heading>
<content>Chapter 10 of title 5 does not apply to a board of parents formed under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Parent Participation Initiative</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant is authorized to establish a parent participation initiative at each Coast Guard child development center to encourage and facilitate parent participation in educational and related activities at the center.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3032</ref>, § 555; renumbered § 2925, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(60)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4312</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2926.</num>
<heading> Family child care providers</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not less frequently than quarterly, the Commandant shall ensure that each family child care provider is subject to inspection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for Inspections</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Of the quarterly inspections under subsection (a) each year—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 3 inspections shall be carried out by a representative of the Coast Guard installation served by the family child care provider concerned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 1 inspection shall be carried out by a representative of the Coast Guard child development services work-life programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII</ref> [LXXXII], § 8237(b)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4665</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2927.</num>
<heading> Child care subsidy program</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Commandant may operate a child care subsidy program to provide financial assistance to eligible providers that provide child care services or youth program services to members of the Coast Guard, members of the Coast Guard with dependents who are participating in the child care subsidy program, and any other individual the Commandant considers appropriate, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> providing such financial assistance—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is in the best interests of the Coast Guard; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> enables supplementation or expansion of the provision of Coast Guard child care services, while not supplanting or replacing Coast Guard child care services; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Commandant ensures, to the extent practicable, that the eligible provider is able to comply, and does comply, with the regulations, policies, and standards applicable to Coast Guard child care services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible providers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A provider of child care services or youth program services is eligible for financial assistance under this section if the provider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is licensed to provide such services under applicable State and local law or meets all applicable State and local health and safety requirements if licensure is not required;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is either—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002023">1</ref> a family home daycare; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> is <sup>1</sup> a provider of family child care services that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> otherwise provides federally funded or federally sponsored child development services;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> provides such services in a child development center owned and operated by a private, not-for-profit organization;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> provides a before-school or after-school child care program in a public school facility;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> conducts an otherwise federally funded or federally sponsored school-age child care or youth services program; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> conducts a school-age child care or youth services program operated by a not-for-profit organization; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is a provider of another category of child care services or youth program services the Commandant considers appropriate for meeting the needs of members or civilian employees of the Coast Guard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Financial assistance for in-home child care.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commandant may provide financial assistance to members of the Coast Guard who pay for services provided by in-home child care providers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In carrying out such program, the Commandant shall establish a policy and procedures to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> support the needs of families who request services provided by in-home childcare providers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide the appropriate amount of financial assistance to provide to families described in paragraph, that is at minimum consistent with the program authorized in subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> ensure the appropriate qualifications for such in-home child care provider, which shall at minimum—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> take into consideration qualifications for available in-home child care providers in the private sector; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> ensure that the qualifications the Commandant determines appropriate under this paragraph are comparable to the qualifications for a provider of child care services in a Coast Guard child development center or family home day care.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Direct Payment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In carrying out a child care subsidy program under subsection (a)(1), subject to paragraph (3), the Commandant shall provide financial assistance under the program to an eligible member or individual the Commandant considers appropriate by direct payment to such eligible member or individual through monthly pay, direct deposit, or other direct form of payment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commandant shall establish a policy to provide direct payment as described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Eligible provider funding continuation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>With the approval of an eligible member or an individual the Commandant considers appropriate, which shall include the written consent of such member or individual, the Commandant may continue to provide financial assistance under the child care subsidy program directly to an eligible provider on behalf of such member or individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to affect any preexisting reimbursement arrangement between the Coast Guard and a qualified provider.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXIV, § 11401(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4106</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>HOUSING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2941.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “construct” means to build, renovate, or improve military family housing and military unaccompanied housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “construction” means building, renovating, or improving military family housing and military unaccompanied housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “military unaccompanied housing” means military housing intended to be occupied by members of the armed forces serving a tour of duty unaccompanied by dependents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “United States” includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, and the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3909</ref>, § 680; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 207(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1034</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 221(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2919</ref>; renumbered § 2941, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2942.</num>
<heading> General authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to any other authority providing for the acquisition or construction of military family housing or military unaccompanied housing, the Secretary may acquire or construct the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Military family housing on or near Coast Guard installations within the United States and its territories and possessions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Military unaccompanied housing on or near such Coast Guard installations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Appropriations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No appropriation shall be made to acquire or construct military family housing or military unaccompanied housing under this chapter if that acquisition or construction has not been approved by resolutions adopted by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3909</ref>, § 681; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2113</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 221(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2919</ref>; renumbered § 2942, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2943.</num>
<heading> Leasing and hiring of quarters; rental of in­adequate housing</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary is authorized to lease hous­ing facilities at or near Coast Guard installations, wherever located, for assignment as public quarters to military personnel and their dependents, if any, without rental charge upon a determination by the Secretary, or his designee, that there is a lack of adequate housing facilities at or near such Coast Guard installations. The Secretary is also authorized to lease housing facilities for assignment as public quarters, without rental charge, to military personnel who are on sea duty or duty at remote offshore Coast Guard stations and who do not have dependents. Such authority shall be effective in any fiscal year only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in appropriation Acts. When any such lease involves housing facilities in a foreign country, the lease may be made on a multiyear basis for a period not to exceed five years, and, in accordance with local custom and practice, advance payment may be made for the lease. Such public housing facilities may be leased on an individual or multiple-unit basis. Expenditures for the rental of such housing facilities may not exceed the average authorized for the Department of Defense in any year except where the Secretary finds that the average is so low as to prevent rental of necessary housing facilities in some areas, in which event he is authorized to reallocate existing funds to high-cost areas so that rental expenditures in such areas exceed the average authorized for the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary is authorized, subject to regulations approved by the President—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to designate as rental housing such housing as he may determine to be inadequate as public quarters; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to lease inadequate housing to members of the Coast Guard for occupancy by them and their dependents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Where sufficient quarters are not possessed by the United States, the Commandant may hire quarters for personnel, including personnel on sea duty at such times as they may be deprived of their quarters on board ship due to repairs or other conditions which may render them uninhabitable. Such accommodations shall not be available for occupancy by the dependents of such personnel.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 532</ref>, § 475; <ref>Pub. L. 91–278, § 1(11)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-12">June 12, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 305</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–343, § 4</ref>, <date date="1972-07-10">July 10, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–65, § 5</ref>, <date date="1973-07-09">July 9, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–406, § 4</ref>, <date date="1976-09-10">Sept. 10, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1236</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–478</ref>, <date date="1976-10-11">Oct. 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2077</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–546, § 1(30)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–376, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-10-03">Oct. 3, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–470, title I, § 112(d)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2240</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–136, § 7</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1706</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–295, § 2(11)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–322, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1582</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title VI, § 632(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1105</ref>; renumbered § 2943, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2944.</num>
<heading> Retired service members and dependents serving on advisory committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A committee that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> advises or assists the Coast Guard with respect to a function that affects a member of the Coast Guard or a dependent of such a member; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> includes in its membership a retired Coast Guard member or a dependent of such a retired member;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall not be considered an advisory committee under chapter 10 of title 5 solely because of such membership.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 218(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3036</ref>, § 680; renumbered § 2944, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(61)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4312</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2945.</num>
<heading> Conveyance of real property</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Conveyance Authorized</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may convey, at fair market value, real property, owned or under the administrative control of the Coast Guard, for the purpose of expending the proceeds from such conveyance to acquire and construct military family housing and military unaccompanied housing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Terms and Conditions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The conveyance of real property under this section shall be by sale, for cash. The Secretary shall deposit the proceeds from the sale in the Coast Guard Housing Fund established under <ref>section 2946 of this title</ref>, for the purpose of expending such proceeds to acquire and construct military family housing and military unaccompanied housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The conveyance of real property under this section shall not diminish the mission capacity of the Coast Guard, but further the mission support capability of the Coast Guard with regard to military family housing or military unaccompanied housing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Environmental Law</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This section does not affect or limit the application of or obligation to comply with any environmental law, including section 120(h) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3911</ref>, § 685; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–400, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1675</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1299</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 221(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2919</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3847</ref>; renumbered § 2945 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 117(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2946.</num>
<heading> Coast Guard Housing Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is hereby established on the books of the Treasury an account to be known as the Coast Guard Housing Fund (in this section referred to as the “Fund”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Credits to Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>There shall be credited to the Fund the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Amounts authorized for and appropriated to that Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (e), any amounts that the Secretary transfers, in such amounts as provided in appropriation Acts, to that Fund from amounts authorized and appropriated to the Department of Homeland Security or Coast Guard for the acquisition or construction of military family housing or military unaccompanied housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Proceeds from the conveyance of property under <ref>section 2945 of this title</ref> for the purpose of carrying out activities under this chapter with respect to military family housing and military unaccompanied housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Monies received under section 504(a)(13).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Amounts received under section 908(b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Use of Amounts in Fund</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In such amounts as provided in appropriations Acts, and except as provided in subsection (d), the Secretary may use amounts in the Coast Guard Housing Fund to carry out activities under this chapter with respect to military family housing and military unaccompanied housing, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the planning, execution, and administration of the conveyance of real property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all necessary expenses, including expenses for environmental compliance and restoration, to prepare real property for conveyance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the conveyance of real property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Amounts made available under this subsection shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Obligations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary may not incur an obligation under a contract or other agreements entered into under this chapter in excess of the unobligated balance, at the time the contract is entered into, of the Fund required to be used to satisfy the obligation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notification Required for Transfers</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A transfer of appropriated amounts to the Fund under subsection (b)(2) of this section may be made only after the end of a 30-day period beginning on the date the Secretary submits written notice of, and justification for, the transfer to the appropriate committees of Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3912</ref>, § 687; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 402(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2114</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 207(d)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1034</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 221(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2919</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–330, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3569</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 208(c)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3026</ref>; renumbered § 2946 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 117(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2947.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress, concurrent with the budget submitted pursuant to <ref>section 1105 of title 31</ref>, a report identifying the contracts or agreements for the conveyance of properties pursuant to this chapter executed during the prior calendar year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–324, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3913</ref>, § 688; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–281, title II, § 221(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2920</ref>; renumbered § 2947, <ref>Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>