<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 21—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COURTS AND JUDGES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 451.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this title:</p>
<p class="indent0">The term “court of the United States” includes the Supreme Court of the United States, courts of appeals, district courts constituted by chapter 5 of this title, including the Court of International Trade and any court created by Act of Congress the judges of which are entitled to hold office during good behavior.</p>
<p class="indent0">The terms “district court” and “district court of the United States” mean the courts constituted by chapter 5 of this title.</p>
<p class="indent0">The term “judge of the United States” includes judges of the courts of appeals, district courts, Court of International Trade and any court created by Act of Congress, the judges of which are entitled to hold office during good behavior.</p>
<p class="indent0">The term “justice of the United States” includes the Chief Justice of the United States and the associate justices of the Supreme Court.</p>
<p class="indent0">The terms “district” and “judicial district” means the districts enumerated in Chapter 5 of this title.</p>
<p class="indent0">The term “department” means one of the executive departments enumerated in <ref>section 1 of Title 5</ref>, unless the context shows that such term was intended to describe the executive, legislative, or judicial branches of the government.</p>
<p class="indent0">The term “agency” includes any department, independent establishment, commission, administration, authority, board or bureau of the United States or any corporation in which the United States has a proprietary interest, unless the context shows that such term was intended to be used in a more limited sense.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 907</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–3, § 10</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–571, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-09-12">Sept. 12, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–417, title V, § 501(10)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1742</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 29</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 452.</num>
<heading> Courts always open; powers unrestricted by expiration of sessions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All courts of the United States shall be deemed always open for the purpose of filing proper papers, issuing and returning process, and making motions and orders.</p>
<p class="indent0">The continued existence or expiration of a session of a court in no way affects the power of the court to do any act or take any proceeding.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 907</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–139, § 2</ref>, <date date="1963-10-16">Oct. 16, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 453.</num>
<heading> Oaths of justices and judges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each justice or judge of the United States shall take the following oath or affirmation before performing the duties of his office: “I, ___ ___, do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I will administer justice without respect to persons, and do equal right to the poor and to the rich, and that I will faithfully and impartially discharge and perform all the duties incumbent upon me as ___ under the Constitution and laws of the United States. So help me God.”</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 907</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 454.</num>
<heading> Practice of law by justices and judges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any justice or judge appointed under the authority of the United States who engages in the practice of law is guilty of a high misdemeanor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 908</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 455.</num>
<heading> Disqualification of justice, judge, or magistrate judge</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any justice, judge, or magistrate judge of the United States shall disqualify himself in any proceeding in which his impartiality might reasonably be questioned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> He shall also disqualify himself in the following circumstances:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Where he has a personal bias or prejudice concerning a party, or personal knowledge of disputed evidentiary facts concerning the proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Where in private practice he served as lawyer in the matter in controversy, or a lawyer with whom he previously practiced law served during such association as a lawyer concerning the matter, or the judge or such lawyer has been a material witness concerning it;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Where he has served in governmental employment and in such capacity participated as counsel, adviser or material witness concerning the proceeding or expressed an opinion concerning the merits of the particular case in controversy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> He knows that he, individually or as a fiduciary, or his spouse or minor child residing in his household, has a financial interest in the subject matter in controversy or in a party to the proceeding, or any other interest that could be substantially affected by the outcome of the proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> He or his spouse, or a person within the third degree of relationship to either of them, or the spouse of such a person:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Is a party to the proceeding, or an officer, director, or trustee of a party;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Is acting as a lawyer in the proceeding;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Is known by the judge to have an interest that could be substantially affected by the outcome of the proceeding;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Is to the judge’s knowledge likely to be a material witness in the proceeding.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A judge should inform himself about his personal and fiduciary financial interests, and make a reasonable effort to inform himself about the personal financial interests of his spouse and minor children residing in his household.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this section the following words or phrases shall have the meaning indicated:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “proceeding” includes pretrial, trial, appellate review, or other stages of litigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the degree of relationship is calculated according to the civil law system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “fiduciary” includes such relationships as executor, administrator, trustee, and guardian;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> “financial interest” means ownership of a legal or equitable interest, however small, or a relationship as director, adviser, or other active participant in the affairs of a party, except that:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Ownership in a mutual or common investment fund that holds securities is not a “financial interest” in such securities unless the judge participates in the management of the fund;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> An office in an educational, religious, charitable, fraternal, or civic organization is not a “financial interest” in securities held by the organization;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The proprietary interest of a policyholder in a mutual insurance company, of a depositor in a mutual savings association, or a similar proprietary interest, is a “financial interest” in the organization only if the outcome of the proceeding could substantially affect the value of the interest;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Ownership of government securities is a “financial interest” in the issuer only if the outcome of the proceeding could substantially affect the value of the securities.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> No justice, judge, or magistrate judge shall accept from the parties to the proceeding a waiver of any ground for disqualification enumerated in subsection (b). Where the ground for disqualification arises only under subsection (a), waiver may be accepted provided it is preceded by a full disclosure on the record of the basis for disqualification.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this section, if any justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge to whom a matter has been assigned would be disqualified, after substantial judicial time has been devoted to the matter, because of the appearance or discovery, after the matter was assigned to him or her, that he or she individually or as a fiduciary, or his or her spouse or minor child residing in his or her household, has a financial interest in a party (other than an interest that could be substantially affected by the outcome), disqualification is not required if the justice, judge, magistrate judge, bankruptcy judge, spouse or minor child, as the case may be, divests himself or herself of the interest that provides the grounds for the disqualification.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–512, § 1</ref>, <date date="1974-12-05">Dec. 5, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1609</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title X, § 1007</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4667</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 456.</num>
<heading> Traveling expenses of justices and judges; official duty stations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall pay each justice or judge of the United States, and each retired justice or judge recalled or designated and assigned to active duty, while attending court or transacting official business at a place other than his official duty station for any continuous period of less than thirty calendar days (1) all necessary transportation expenses certified by the justice or judge; and (2) payments for subsistence expenses at rates or in amounts which the Director establishes, in accordance with regulations which the Director shall prescribe with the approval of the Judicial Conference of the United States and after considering the rates or amounts set by the Administrator of General Services and the President pursuant to <ref>section 5702 of title 5</ref>. The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall also pay each justice or judge of the United States, and each retired justice or judge recalled or designated and assigned to active duty, while attending court or transacting official business under an assignment authorized under chapter 13 of this title which exceeds in duration a continuous period of thirty calendar days, all necessary transportation expenses and actual and necessary expenses of subsistence actually incurred, notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 5702 of title 5</ref>, in accordance with regulations which the Director shall prescribe with the approval of the Judicial Conference of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The official duty station of the Chief Justice of the United States, the Justices of the Supreme Court of the United States, and the judges of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, and the United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall be the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The official duty station of the judges of the United States Court of International Trade shall be New York City.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The official duty station of each district judge shall be that place where a district court holds regular sessions at or near which the judge performs a substantial portion of his judicial work, which is nearest the place where he maintains his actual abode in which he customarily lives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The official duty station of a circuit judge shall be that place where a circuit or district court holds regular sessions at or near which the judge performs a substantial portion of his judicial work, or that place where the Director provides chambers to the judge where he performs a substantial portion of his judicial work, which is nearest the place where he maintains his actual abode in which he customarily lives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> The official duty station of a retired judge shall be established in accordance with <ref>section 374 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Each circuit or district judge whose official duty station is not fixed expressly by this section shall notify the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts in writing of his actual abode and official duty station upon his appointment and from time to time thereafter as his official duty station may change.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref>Aug. 8, 1953, ch. 376</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 488</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–138</ref>, <date date="1959-08-07">Aug. 7, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–417, title V, § 501(11)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1742</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 115(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 30</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–234, title I, § 107(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-01-02">Jan. 2, 1986</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1759</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 457.</num>
<heading> Records; obsolete papers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The records of district courts and of courts of appeals shall be kept at one or more of the places where court is held. Such places shall be designated by the respective courts except when otherwise directed by the judicial council of the circuit.</p>
<p class="indent0">Papers of any court established by Act of Congress which have become obsolete and are no longer necessary or useful, may be disposed of with the approval of the court concerned in the manner provided by sections 366–380 of Title 44 and in accordance with the rules of the Judicial Conference of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title II, § 216</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2661</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 458.</num>
<heading> Relative of justice or judge ineligible to appointment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No person shall be appointed to or employed in any office or duty in any court who is related by affinity or consanguinity within the degree of first cousin to any justice or judge of such court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> With respect to the appointment of a judge of a court exercising judicial power under article III of the United States Constitution (other than the Supreme Court), subsection (b) shall apply in lieu of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> “same court” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a district court, the court of a single judicial district; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a court of appeals, the court of appeals of a single circuit; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> “member”—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> means an active judge or a judge retired in senior status under section 371(b); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall not include a retired judge, except as described under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No person may be appointed to the position of judge of a court exercising judicial power under article III of the United States Constitution (other than the Supreme Court) who is related by affinity or consanguinity within the degree of first cousin to any judge who is a member of the same court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–300, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 459.</num>
<heading> Administration of oaths and acknowledgments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each justice or judge of the United States may administer oaths and affirmations and take acknowledgments.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 908</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 460.</num>
<heading> Application to other courts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Sections 452 through 459 and section 462 of this chapter shall also apply to the United States Court of Federal Claims, to each court created by Act of Congress in a territory which is invested with any jurisdiction of a district court of the United States, and to the judges thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The official duty station of each judge referred to in subsection (a) which is not otherwise established by law shall be that place where the court holds regular sessions at or near which the judge performs a substantial portion of his judicial work, which is nearest the place where he maintains his actual abode in which he customarily lives.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 43(a)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–508, § 12(e)</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 348</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title II, § 217(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 115(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 461.</num>
<heading> Adjustments in certain salaries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), effective at the beginning of the first applicable pay period commencing on or after the first day of the month in which an adjustment takes effect under <ref>section 5303 of title 5</ref> in the rates of pay under the General Schedule (except as provided in subsection (b)), each salary rate which is subject to adjustment under this section shall be adjusted by an amount, rounded to the nearest multiple of $100 (or if midway between multiples of $100, to the next higher multiple of $100) equal to the percentage of such salary rate which corresponds to the most recent percentage change in the ECI (relative to the date described in the next sentence), as determined under section 704(a)(1) of the Ethics Reform Act of 1989. The appropriate date under this sentence is the first day of the fiscal year in which such adjustment in the rates of pay under the General Schedule takes effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In no event shall the percentage adjustment taking effect under paragraph (1) in any calendar year (before rounding), in any salary rate, exceed the percentage adjustment taking effect in such calendar year under <ref>section 5303 of title 5</ref> in the rates of pay under the General Schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subsection (a) shall not apply to the extent it would reduce the salary of any individual whose compensation may not, under section 1 of article III of the Constitution of the United States, be diminished during such individual’s continuance in office.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–82, title II, § 205(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 422</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–194, title VII, § 704(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1769</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 101(b)(4)(J)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1440; <ref>Pub. L. 103–356, title I, § 101(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 3411</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 462.</num>
<heading> Court accommodations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Sessions of courts of the United States (except the Supreme Court) shall be held only at places where the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts provides accommodations, or where suitable accommodations are furnished without cost to the judicial branch.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall provide accommodations, including chambers and courtrooms, only at places where regular sessions of court are authorized by law to be held, but only if the judicial council of the appropriate circuit has approved the accommodations as necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The limitations and restrictions contained in subsection (b) of this section shall not prevent the Director from furnishing chambers to circuit judges at places within the circuit other than where regular sessions of court are authorized by law to be held, when the judicial council of the circuit approves.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall provide permanent accommodations for the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit and for the United States Court of Federal Claims only at the District of Columbia. However, each such court may hold regular and special sessions at other places utilizing the accommodations which the Director provides to other courts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall provide accommodations for probation officers, pretrial service officers, and Federal Public Defender Organizations at such places as may be approved by the judicial council of the appropriate circuit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Upon the request of the Director, the Administrator of General Services is authorized and directed to provide the accommodations the Director requests, and to close accommodations which the Director recommends for closure with the approval of the Judicial Conference of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 115(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 31</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title X, § 1015</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4669</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 463.</num>
<heading> Expenses of litigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever a Chief Justice, justice, judge, officer, or employee of any United States court is sued in his official capacity, or is otherwise required to defend acts taken or omissions made in his official capacity, and the services of an attorney for the Government are not reasonably available pursuant to chapter 31 of this title, the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts may pay the costs of his defense. The Director shall prescribe regulations for such payments subject to the approval of the Judicial Conference of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 116(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 32</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>