<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1—</num>
<heading>SUPREME COURT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1.</num>
<heading> Number of justices; quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Supreme Court of the United States shall consist of a Chief Justice of the United States and eight associate justices, any six of whom shall constitute a quorum.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2.</num>
<heading> Terms of court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Supreme Court shall hold at the seat of government a term of court commencing on the first Monday in October of each year and may hold such adjourned or special terms as may be necessary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3.</num>
<heading> Vacancy in office of Chief Justice; disability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Chief Justice is unable to perform the duties of his office or the office is vacant, his powers and duties shall devolve upon the associate justice next in precedence who is able to act, until such disability is removed or another Chief Justice is appointed and duly qualified.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4.</num>
<heading> Precedence of associate justices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Associate justices shall have precedence according to the seniority of their commissions. Justices whose commissions bear the same date shall have precedence according to seniority in age.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5.</num>
<heading> Salaries of justices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Justice and each associate justice shall each receive a salary at annual rates determined under section 225 of the Federal Salary Act of 1967 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 351–361</ref>), as adjusted by <ref>section 461 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 870</ref>; <ref>Mar. 2, 1955, ch. 9, § 1(a)</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–426, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–82, title II, § 205(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6.</num>
<heading> Records of former court of appeals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The records and proceedings of the court of appeals, appointed previous to the adoption of the Constitution, shall be kept until deposited with the National Archives of the United States in the office of the clerk of the Supreme Court, who shall furnish copies thereof to any person requiring and paying for them, in the manner provided by law for giving copies of the records and proceedings of the Supreme Court. Such copies shall have the same faith and credit as proceedings of the Supreme Court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 870</ref>; <ref>Oct. 25, 1951, ch. 562, § 4(7)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 640</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>