<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 178—</num>
<heading>PROFESSIONAL AND AMATEUR SPORTS PROTECTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “amateur sports organization” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a person or governmental entity that sponsors, organizes, schedules, or conducts a competitive game in which one or more amateur athletes participate, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a league or association of persons or governmental entities described in subparagraph (A),</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “governmental entity” means a State, a political subdivision of a State, or an entity or organization, including an entity or organization described in section 4(5) of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 2703(5)</ref>), that has governmental authority within the territorial boundaries of the United States, including on lands described in section 4(4) of such Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 2703(4)</ref>),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “professional sports organization” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a person or governmental entity that sponsors, organizes, schedules, or conducts a competitive game in which one or more professional athletes participate, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a league or association of persons or governmental entities described in subparagraph (A),</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “person” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 1 of title 1</ref>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “State” means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Palau, or any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–559, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4227</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3702.</num>
<heading> Unlawful sports gambling</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a governmental entity to sponsor, operate, advertise, promote, license, or authorize by law or compact, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a person to sponsor, operate, advertise, or promote, pursuant to the law or compact of a governmental entity,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">a lottery, sweepstakes, or other betting, gambling, or wagering scheme based, directly or indirectly (through the use of geographical references or otherwise), on one or more competitive games in which amateur or professional athletes participate, or are intended to participate, or on one or more performances of such athletes in such games.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–559, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4228</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3703.</num>
<heading> Injunctions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A civil action to enjoin a violation of section 3702 may be commenced in an appropriate district court of the United States by the Attorney General of the United States, or by a professional sports organization or amateur sports organization whose competitive game is alleged to be the basis of such violation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–559, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4228</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3704.</num>
<heading> Applicability</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Section 3702 shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a lottery, sweepstakes, or other betting, gambling, or wagering scheme in operation in a State or other governmental entity, to the extent that the scheme was conducted by that State or other governmental entity at any time during the period beginning <date date="1976-01-01">January 1, 1976</date>, and ending <date date="1990-08-31">August 31, 1990</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a lottery, sweepstakes, or other betting, gambling, or wagering scheme in operation in a State or other governmental entity where both—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such scheme was authorized by a statute as in effect on <date date="1991-10-02">October 2, 1991</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a scheme described in section 3702 (other than one based on parimutuel animal racing or jai-alai games) actually was conducted in that State or other governmental entity at any time during the period beginning <date date="1989-09-01">September 1, 1989</date>, and ending <date date="1991-10-02">October 2, 1991</date>, pursuant to the law of that State or other governmental entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> a betting, gambling, or wagering scheme, other than a lottery described in paragraph (1), conducted exclusively in casinos located in a municipality, but only to the extent that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such scheme or a similar scheme was authorized, not later than one year after the effective date of this chapter, to be operated in that municipality; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any commercial casino gaming scheme was in operation in such municipality throughout the 10-year period ending on such effective date pursuant to a comprehensive system of State regulation authorized by that State’s constitution and applicable solely to such municipality; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> parimutuel animal racing or jai-alai games.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (a), section 3702 shall apply on lands described in section 4(4) of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 2703(4)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 102–559, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4228</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>