<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 115—</num>
<heading>EVIDENCE; DOCUMENTARY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1731.</num>
<heading> Handwriting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The admitted or proved handwriting of any person shall be admissible, for purposes of comparison, to determine genuineness of other handwriting attributed to such person.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1732.</num>
<heading> Record made in regular course of business; photographic copies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any business, institution, member of a profession or calling, or any department or agency of government, in the regular course of business or activity has kept or recorded any memorandum, writing, entry, print, representation or combination thereof, of any act, transaction, occurrence, or event, and in the regular course of business has caused any or all of the same to be recorded, copied, or reproduced by any photographic, photostatic, microfilm, micro-card, miniature photographic, or other process which accurately reproduces or forms a durable medium for so reproducing the original, the original may be destroyed in the regular course of business unless its preservation is required by law. Such reproduction, when satisfactorily identified, is as admissible in evidence as the original itself in any judicial or administrative proceeding whether the original is in existence or not and an enlargement or facsimile of such reproduction is likewise admissible in evidence if the original reproduction is in existence and available for inspection under direction of court. The introduction of a reproduced record, enlargement, or facsimile does not preclude admission of the original. This subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002085">1</ref> shall not be construed to exclude from evidence any document or copy thereof which is otherwise admissible under the rules of evidence.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 945</ref>; <ref>Aug. 28, 1951, ch. 351</ref>, §§ 1, 3, <ref>65 Stat. 205</ref>, 206; <ref>Pub. L. 87–183</ref>, <date date="1961-08-30">Aug. 30, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–595, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1733.</num>
<heading> Government records and papers; copies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Books or records of account or minutes of proceedings of any department or agency of the United States shall be admissible to prove the act, transaction or occurrence as a memorandum of which the same were made or kept.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Properly authenticated copies or transcripts of any books, records, papers or documents of any department or agency of the United States shall be admitted in evidence equally with the originals thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> This section does not apply to cases, actions, and proceedings to which the Federal Rules of Evidence apply.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 946</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–595, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1734.</num>
<heading> Court record lost or destroyed, generally</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A lost or destroyed record of any proceeding in any court of the United States may be supplied on application of any interested party not at fault, by substituting a copy certified by the clerk of any court in which an authentic copy is lodged.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Where a certified copy is not available, any interested person not at fault may file in such court a verified application for an order establishing the lost or destroyed record.<p class="indent0">Every other interested person shall be served personally with a copy of the application and with notice of hearing on a day stated, not less than sixty days after service. Service may be made on any nonresident of the district anywhere within the jurisdiction of the United States or in any foreign country.</p>
<p class="indent0">Proof of service in a foreign country shall be certified by a minister or consul of the United States in such country, under his official seal.</p>
<p class="indent0">If, after the hearing, the court is satisfied that the statements contained in the application are true, it shall enter an order reciting the substance and effect of the lost or destroyed record. Such order, subject to intervening rights of third persons, shall have the same effect as the original record.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 946</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1735.</num>
<heading> Court record lost or destroyed where United States interested</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> When the record of any case or matter in any court of the United States to which the United States is a party, is lost or destroyed, a certified copy of any official paper of a United States attorney, United States marshal or clerk or other certifying or recording officer of any such court, made pursuant to law, on file in any department or agency of the United States and relating to such case or matter, shall, on being filed in the court to which it relates, have the same effect as an original paper filed in such court. If the copy so filed discloses the date and amount of a judgment or decree and the names of the parties thereto, the court may enforce the judgment or decree as though the original record had not been lost or destroyed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whenever the United States is interested in any lost or destroyed records or files of a court of the United States, the clerk of such court and the United States attorney for the district shall take the steps necessary to restore such records or files, under the direction of the judges of such court.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 946</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1736.</num>
<heading> Congressional Journals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Extracts from the Journals of the Senate and the House of Representatives, and from the Executive Journal of the Senate when the injunction of secrecy is removed, certified by the Secretary of the Senate or the Clerk of the House of Representatives shall be received in evidence with the same effect as the originals would have.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 947</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1737.</num>
<heading> Copy of officer’s bond</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person to whose custody the bond of any officer of the United States has been committed shall, on proper request and payment of the fee allowed by any Act of Congress, furnish certified copies thereof, which shall be prima facie evidence in any court of the execution, filing and contents of the bond.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 947</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1738.</num>
<heading> State and Territorial statutes and judicial proceedings; full faith and credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Acts of the legislature of any State, Territory, or Possession of the United States, or copies thereof, shall be authenticated by affixing the seal of such State, Territory or Possession thereto.</p>
<p class="indent0">The records and judicial proceedings of any court of any such State, Territory or Possession, or copies thereof, shall be proved or admitted in other courts within the United States and its Territories and Possessions by the attestation of the clerk and seal of the court annexed, if a seal exists, together with a certificate of a judge of the court that the said attestation is in proper form.</p>
<p class="indent0">Such Acts, records and judicial proceedings or copies thereof, so authenticated, shall have the same full faith and credit in every court within the United States and its Territories and Possessions as they have by law or usage in the courts of such State, Territory or Possession from which they are taken.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 947</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1738A.</num>
<heading> Full faith and credit given to child custody determinations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The appropriate authorities of every State shall enforce according to its terms, and shall not modify except as provided in subsections (f), (g), and (h) of this section, any custody determination or visitation determination made consistently with the provisions of this section by a court of another State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “child” means a person under the age of eighteen;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “contestant” means a person, including a parent or grandparent, who claims a right to custody or visitation of a child;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “custody determination” means a judgment, decree, or other order of a court providing for the custody of a child, and includes permanent and temporary orders, and initial orders and modifications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “home State” means the State in which, immediately preceding the time involved, the child lived with his parents, a parent, or a person acting as parent, for at least six consecutive months, and in the case of a child less than six months old, the State in which the child lived from birth with any of such persons. Periods of temporary absence of any of such persons are counted as part of the six-month or other period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “modification” and “modify” refer to a custody or visitation determination which modifies, replaces, supersedes, or otherwise is made subsequent to, a prior custody or visitation determination concerning the same child, whether made by the same court or not;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “person acting as a parent” means a person, other than a parent, who has physical custody of a child and who has either been awarded custody by a court or claims a right to custody;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “physical custody” means actual possession and control of a child;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or a territory or possession of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> “visitation determination” means a judgment, decree, or other order of a court providing for the visitation of a child and includes permanent and temporary orders and initial orders and modifications.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A child custody or visitation determination made by a court of a State is consistent with the provisions of this section only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such court has jurisdiction under the law of such State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> one of the following conditions is met:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such State (i) is the home State of the child on the date of the commencement of the proceeding, or (ii) had been the child’s home State within six months before the date of the commencement of the proceeding and the child is absent from such State because of his removal or retention by a contestant or for other reasons, and a contestant continues to live in such State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> it appears that no other State would have jurisdiction under subparagraph (A), and (ii) it is in the best interest of the child that a court of such State assume jurisdiction because (I) the child and his parents, or the child and at least one contestant, have a significant connection with such State other than mere physical presence in such State, and (II) there is available in such State substantial evidence concerning the child’s present or future care, protection, training, and personal relationships;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the child is physically present in such State and (i) the child has been abandoned, or (ii) it is necessary in an emergency to protect the child because the child, a sibling, or parent of the child has been subjected to or threatened with mistreatment or abuse;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> it appears that no other State would have jurisdiction under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (E), or another State has declined to exercise jurisdiction on the ground that the State whose jurisdiction is in issue is the more appropriate forum to determine the custody or visitation of the child, and (ii) it is in the best interest of the child that such court assume jurisdiction; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the court has continuing jurisdiction pursuant to subsection (d) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The jurisdiction of a court of a State which has made a child custody or visitation determination consistently with the provisions of this section continues as long as the requirement of subsection (c)(1) of this section continues to be met and such State remains the residence of the child or of any contestant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Before a child custody or visitation determination is made, reasonable notice and opportunity to be heard shall be given to the contestants, any parent whose parental rights have not been previously terminated and any person who has physical custody of a child.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> A court of a State may modify a determination of the custody of the same child made by a court of another State, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> it has jurisdiction to make such a child custody determination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the court of the other State no longer has jurisdiction, or it has declined to exercise such jurisdiction to modify such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> A court of a State shall not exercise jurisdiction in any proceeding for a custody or visitation determination commenced during the pendency of a proceeding in a court of another State where such court of that other State is exercising jurisdiction consistently with the provisions of this section to make a custody or visitation determination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> A court of a State may not modify a visitation determination made by a court of another State unless the court of the other State no longer has jurisdiction to modify such determination or has declined to exercise jurisdiction to modify such determination.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–611, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-28">Dec. 28, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3569</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–374, § 1</ref>, <date date="1998-11-12">Nov. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3383</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. B, title III, § 1303(d)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1512</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1738B.</num>
<heading> Full faith and credit for child support orders</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General Rule</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The appropriate authorities of each State—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall enforce according to its terms a child support order made consistently with this section by a court of another State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall not seek or make a modification of such an order except in accordance with subsections (e), (f), and (i).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “child” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a person under 18 years of age; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a person 18 or more years of age with respect to whom a child support order has been issued pursuant to the laws of a State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “child’s State” means the State in which a child resides.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “child’s home State” means the State in which a child lived with a parent or a person acting as parent for at least 6 consecutive months immediately preceding the time of filing of a petition or comparable pleading for support and, if a child is less than 6 months old, the State in which the child lived from birth with any of them. A period of temporary absence of any of them is counted as part of the 6-month period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “child support” means a payment of money, continuing support, or arrearages or the provision of a benefit (including payment of health insurance, child care, and educational expenses) for the support of a child.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> The term “child support order”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means a judgment, decree, or order of a court requiring the payment of child support in periodic amounts or in a lump sum; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a permanent or temporary order; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an initial order or a modification of an order.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> The term “contestant” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a person (including a parent) who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> claims a right to receive child support;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is a party to a proceeding that may result in the issuance of a child support order; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is under a child support order; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a State or political subdivision of a State to which the right to obtain child support has been assigned.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “court” means a court or administrative agency of a State that is authorized by State law to establish the amount of child support payable by a contestant or make a modification of a child support order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “modification” means a change in a child support order that affects the amount, scope, or duration of the order and modifies, replaces, supersedes, or otherwise is made subsequent to the child support order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the territories and possessions of the United States, and Indian country (as defined in <ref>section 1151 of title 18</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements of Child Support Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A child support order made by a court of a State is made consistently with this section if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a court that makes the order, pursuant to the laws of the State in which the court is located and subsections (e), (f), and (g)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has subject matter jurisdiction to hear the matter and enter such an order; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has personal jurisdiction over the contestants; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reasonable notice and opportunity to be heard is given to the contestants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuing Jurisdiction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A court of a State that has made a child support order consistently with this section has continuing, exclusive jurisdiction over the order if the State is the child’s State or the residence of any individual contestant or the parties have consented in a record or open court that the tribunal of the State may continue to exercise jurisdiction to modify its order, unless the court of another State, acting in accordance with subsections (e) and (f), has made a modification of the order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority To Modify Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A court of a State may modify a child support order issued by a court of another State if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the court has jurisdiction to make such a child support order pursuant to subsection (i); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the court of the other State no longer has continuing, exclusive jurisdiction of the child support order because that State no longer is the child’s State or the residence of any individual contestant and the parties have not consented in a record or open court that the tribunal of the other State may continue to exercise jurisdiction to modify its order; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> each individual contestant has filed written consent with the State of continuing, exclusive jurisdiction for a court of another State to modify the order and assume continuing, exclusive jurisdiction over the order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Recognition of Child Support Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If 1 or more child support orders have been issued with regard to an obligor and a child, a court shall apply the following rules in determining which order to recognize for purposes of continuing, exclusive jurisdiction and enforcement:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If only 1 court has issued a child support order, the order of that court must be recognized.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If 2 or more courts have issued child support orders for the same obligor and child, and only 1 of the courts would have continuing, exclusive jurisdiction under this section, the order of that court must be recognized.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If 2 or more courts have issued child support orders for the same obligor and child, and more than 1 of the courts would have continuing, exclusive jurisdiction under this section, an order issued by a court in the current home State of the child must be recognized, but if an order has not been issued in the current home State of the child, the order most recently issued must be recognized.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If 2 or more courts have issued child support orders for the same obligor and child, and none of the courts would have continuing, exclusive jurisdiction under this section, a court having jurisdiction over the parties shall issue a child support order, which must be recognized.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The court that has issued an order recognized under this subsection is the court having continuing, exclusive jurisdiction under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enforcement of Modified Orders</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A court of a State that no longer has continuing, exclusive jurisdiction of a child support order may enforce the order with respect to nonmodifiable obligations and unsatisfied obligations that accrued before the date on which a modification of the order is made under subsections (e) and (f).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Choice of Law.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In a proceeding to establish, modify, or enforce a child support order, the forum State’s law shall apply except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Law of state of issuance of order</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In interpreting a child support order including the duration of current payments and other obligations of support, a court shall apply the law of the State of the court that issued the order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Period of limitation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In an action to enforce arrears under a child support order, a court shall apply the statute of limitation of the forum State or the State of the court that issued the order, whichever statute provides the longer period of limitation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Registration for Modification</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If there is no individual contestant or child residing in the issuing State, the party or support enforcement agency seeking to modify, or to modify and enforce, a child support order issued in another State shall register that order in a State with jurisdiction over the nonmovant for the purpose of modification.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 103–383, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4064</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title III, § 322</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2221</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–33, title V, § 5554</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 636</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–183, title III, § 301(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-09-29">Sept. 29, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1738C.</num>
<heading> Certain acts, records, and proceedings and the effect thereof</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>No person acting under color of State law may deny—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> full faith and credit to any public act, record, or judicial proceeding of any other State pertaining to a marriage between 2 individuals, on the basis of the sex, race, ethnicity, or national origin of those individuals; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a right or claim arising from such a marriage on the basis that such marriage would not be recognized under the law of that State on the basis of the sex, race, ethnicity, or national origin of those individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enforcement by Attorney General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General may bring a civil action in the appropriate United States district court against any person who violates subsection (a) for declaratory and injunctive relief.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Private Right of Action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any person who is harmed by a violation of subsection (a) may bring a civil action in the appropriate United States district court against the person who violated such subsection for declaratory and injunctive relief.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">State Defined</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “State” has the meaning given such term under <ref>section 7 of title 1</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–228, § 4</ref>, <date date="2022-12-13">Dec. 13, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2305</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1739.</num>
<heading> State and Territorial nonjudicial records; full faith and credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All nonjudicial records or books kept in any public office of any State, Territory, or Possession of the United States, or copies thereof, shall be proved or admitted in any court or office in any other State, Territory, or Possession by the attestation of the custodian of such records or books, and the seal of his office annexed, if there be a seal, together with a certificate of a judge of a court of record of the county, parish, or district in which such office may be kept, or of the Governor, or secretary of state, the chancellor or keeper of the great seal, of the State, Territory, or Possession that the said attestation is in due form and by the proper officers.</p>
<p class="indent0">If the certificate is given by a judge, it shall be further authenticated by the clerk or prothonotary of the court, who shall certify, under his hand and the seal of his office, that such judge is duly commissioned and qualified; or, if given by such Governor, secretary, chancellor, or keeper of the great seal, it shall be under the great seal of the State, Territory, or Possession in which it is made.</p>
<p class="indent0">Such records or books, or copies thereof, so authenticated, shall have the same full faith and credit in every court and office within the United States and its Territories and Possessions as they have by law or usage in the courts or offices of the State, Territory, or Possession from which they are taken.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 947</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1740.</num>
<heading> Copies of consular papers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Copies of all official documents and papers in the office of any consul or vice consul of the United States, and of all official entries in the books or records of any such office, authenticated by the consul or vice consul, shall be admissible equally with the originals.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 947</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1741.</num>
<heading> Foreign official documents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An official record or document of a foreign country may be evidenced by a copy, summary, or excerpt authenticated as provided in the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 948</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 92(b)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 103</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–619, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-03">Oct. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1742.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 88–619, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-03">Oct. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 996</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1743.</num>
<heading> Demand on postmaster</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The certificate of the Postmaster General or the Government Accountability Office of the mailing to a postmaster of a statement of his account and that payment of the balance stated has not been received shall be sufficient evidence of a demand notwithstanding any allowances or credits subsequently made. A copy of such statement shall be attached to the certificate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 948</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1744.</num>
<heading> Copies of United States Patent and Trademark Office documents, generally</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Copies of letters patent or of any records, books, papers, or drawings belonging to the United States Patent and Trademark Office and relating to patents, authenticated under the seal of the United States Patent and Trademark Office and certified by the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office, or by another officer of the United States Patent and Trademark Office authorized to do so by the Director, shall be admissible in evidence with the same effect as the originals.</p>
<p class="indent0">Any person making application and paying the required fee may obtain such certified copies.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 948</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 92(c)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 103</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(b)(15)(B), (C)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–584.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1745.</num>
<heading> Copies of foreign patent documents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Copies of the specifications and drawings of foreign letters patent, or applications for foreign letters patent, and copies of excerpts of the official journals and other official publications of foreign patent offices belonging to the United States Patent and Trademark Office, certified in the manner provided by <ref>section 1744 of this title</ref> are prima facie evidence of their contents and of the dates indicated on their face.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 948</ref>, § 1746; renumbered § 1745, <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 92(e)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 103</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–619, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-03">Oct. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 996</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(b)(16)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–585.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1746.</num>
<heading> Unsworn declarations under penalty of per­jury</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Wherever, under any law of the United States or under any rule, regulation, order, or requirement made pursuant to law, any matter is required or permitted to be supported, evidenced, established, or proved by the sworn declaration, verification, certificate, statement, oath, or affidavit, in writing of the person making the same (other than a deposition, or an oath of office, or an oath required to be taken before a specified official other than a notary public), such matter may, with like force and effect, be supported, evidenced, established, or proved by the unsworn declaration, certificate, verification, or statement, in writing of such person which is subscribed by him, as true under penalty of perjury, and dated, in substantially the following form:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If executed without the United States: “I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury under the laws of the United States of America that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date).<p class="rightIndent1 firstIndent0 smallCaps">(Signature)”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If executed within the United States, its territories, possessions, or commonwealths: “I declare (or certify, verify, or state) under penalty of perjury that the foregoing is true and correct. Executed on (date).<p class="rightIndent1 firstIndent0 smallCaps">(Signature)”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–550, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2534</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>