<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 45—</num>
<heading>SUPREME COURT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 671.</num>
<heading> Clerk</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Supreme Court may appoint and fix the compensation of a clerk and one or more deputy clerks. The clerk shall be subject to removal by the Court. Deputy clerks shall be subject to removal by the clerk with the approval of the Court or the Chief Justice of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(b)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 206(c)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 203</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The clerk may appoint and fix the compensation of necessary assistants and messengers with the approval of the Chief Justice of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The clerk shall pay into the Treasury all fees, costs, and other moneys collected by him. He shall make annual returns thereof to the Court under regulations prescribed by it.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–279, § 1</ref>, <date date="1964-03-10">Mar. 10, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 158</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 206(c)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 672.</num>
<heading> Marshal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Supreme Court may appoint a marshal, who shall be subject to removal by the Court, and may fix his compensation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The marshal may, with the approval of the Chief Justice of the United States, appoint and fix the compensation of necessary assistants and other employees to attend the Court, and necessary custodial employees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The marshal shall:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Attend the Court at its sessions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Serve and execute all process and orders issued by the Court or a member thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Take charge of all property of the United States used by the Court or its members;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Disburse funds appropriated for work upon the Supreme Court building and grounds under the jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol upon certified vouchers submitted by the Architect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Disburse funds appropriated for the purchase of books, pamphlets, periodicals and other publications, and for their repair, binding, and rebinding, upon vouchers certified by the librarian of the Court;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Pay the salaries of the Chief Justice, associate justices, and all officers and employees of the Court and disburse other funds appropriated for disbursement, under the direction of the Chief Justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Pay the expenses of printing briefs and travel expenses of attorneys in behalf of persons whose motions to appear in forma pauperis in the Supreme Court have been approved and when counsel have been appointed by the Supreme Court, upon vouchers certified by the clerk of the Court;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Oversee the Supreme Court Police.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 918</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–279, § 2</ref>, <date date="1964-03-10">Mar. 10, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 158</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–390, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-12-29">Dec. 29, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1958</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 673.</num>
<heading> Reporter</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Supreme Court may appoint and fix the compensation of a reporter of its decisions who shall be subject to removal by the Court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The reporter may appoint and fix the compensation of necessary professional and clerical assistants and other employees, with the approval of the Court or the Chief Justice of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The reporter shall, under the direction of the Court or the Chief Justice, prepare the decisions of the Court for publication in bound volumes and advance copies in pamphlet installments.<p class="indent0">The reporter shall determine the quality and size of the paper, type, format, proofs and binding subject to the approval of the Court or the Chief Justice.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 919</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 674.</num>
<heading> Librarian</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Supreme Court may appoint a librarian, whose salary it shall fix, and who shall be subject to removal by the Court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The librarian shall, with the approval of the Chief Justice, appoint necessary assistants and fix their compensation and make rules governing the use of the library.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> He shall select and acquire by purchase, gift, bequest, or exchange, such books, pamphlets, periodicals, microfilm and other processed copy as may be required by the Court for its official use and for the reasonable needs of its bar.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The librarian shall certify to the marshal for payment vouchers covering expenditures for the purchase of such books and other material, and for binding, rebinding and repairing the same.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 919</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 206(d)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 675.</num>
<heading> Law clerks and secretaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Justice of the United States, and the associate justices of the Supreme Court may appoint law clerks and secretaries whose salaries shall be fixed by the Court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 919</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 676.</num>
<heading> Printing and binding</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The printing and binding for the Supreme Court, including the printing and binding of individual copies, advance pamphlet installments, and bound volumes, of its decisions, whether requisitioned or ordered by the Court or any of its officers or by any other office or agency, and whether paid for by, or charged to the appropriation for, the Court or any other office or agency, shall be done by the printer or printers whom the Court or the Chief Justice of the United States may select, unless it shall otherwise order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Whenever advance pamphlet installments and bound volumes of the Court’s decisions are printed by a private printer, an adequate number of copies for distribution in accordance with the requirements of <ref>section 411 of this title</ref> and for sale to the public shall be provided and made available for these purposes in such manner and at such prices as may be determined from time to time by the Supreme Court or the Chief Justice of the United States, in lieu of compliance by the Director of the Government Publishing Office and the Superintendent of Documents with the requirements of sections 411 and 412 of this title with respect to such copies. Pending distribution or sale, such copies shall be the property of the United States and shall be held in the custody of the marshal or such other person, organization, or agency, as the Supreme Court or the Chief Justice of the United States may designate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 919</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 74</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 100</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 45</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 677.</num>
<heading> Counselor to the Chief Justice</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Chief Justice of the United States may appoint a Counselor who shall serve at the pleasure of the Chief Justice and shall perform such duties as may be assigned to him by the Chief Justice. The salary payable to the Counselor shall be fixed by the Chief Justice at a rate which shall not exceed the salary payable to the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts. The Counselor may elect to bring himself within the same retirement program available to the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, as provided by <ref>section 611 of this title</ref>, by filing a written election with the Chief Justice within the time and in the manner prescribed by section 611.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Counselor, with the approval of the Chief Justice, may appoint and fix the compensation of necessary employees. The Counselor and his employees shall be deemed employees of the Supreme Court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding <ref>section 1342 of title 31</ref>, the Counselor, with the approval of the Chief Justice, may accept voluntary personal services to assist with public and visitor programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No person may volunteer personal services under this subsection unless the person has first agreed, in writing, to waive any claim against the United States arising out of or in connection with such services, other than a claim under chapter 81 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> No person volunteering personal services under this subsection shall be considered an employee of the United States for any purpose other than for purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> chapter 81 of title 5; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> chapter 171 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In the administration of this subsection, the Counselor shall ensure that the acceptance of personal services shall not result in the reduction of pay or displacement of any employee of the Supreme Court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The Counselor, with the approval of the Chief Justice, shall establish a retention and recruitment program that is consistent with section 908 of the Emergency Supplemental Act, 2002 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 1926</ref>) for Supreme Court Police officers and other critical employees who agree in writing to remain employed with the Supreme Court for a period of service of not less than two years.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–238, § 1</ref>, <date date="1972-03-01">Mar. 1, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 46</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–233, § 1</ref>, <date date="1998-08-13">Aug. 13, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–402, § 1(b)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4254</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. E, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>