<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 153—</num>
<heading>HABEAS CORPUS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2241.</num>
<heading> Power to grant writ</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Writs of habeas corpus may be granted by the Supreme Court, any justice thereof, the district courts and any circuit judge within their respective jurisdictions. The order of a circuit judge shall be entered in the records of the district court of the district wherein the restraint complained of is had.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Supreme Court, any justice thereof, and any circuit judge may decline to entertain an application for a writ of habeas corpus and may transfer the application for hearing and determination to the district court having jurisdiction to entertain it.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The writ of habeas corpus shall not extend to a prisoner unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> He is in custody under or by color of the authority of the United States or is committed for trial before some court thereof; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> He is in custody for an act done or omitted in pursuance of an Act of Congress, or an order, process, judgment or decree of a court or judge of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> He is in custody in violation of the Constitution or laws or treaties of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> He, being a citizen of a foreign state and domiciled therein is in custody for an act done or omitted under any alleged right, title, authority, privilege, protection, or exemption claimed under the commission, order or sanction of any foreign state, or under color thereof, the validity and effect of which depend upon the law of nations; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> It is necessary to bring him into court to testify or for trial.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Where an application for a writ of habeas corpus is made by a person in custody under the judgment and sentence of a State court of a State which contains two or more Federal judicial districts, the application may be filed in the district court for the district wherein such person is in custody or in the district court for the district within which the State court was held which convicted and sentenced him and each of such district courts shall have concurrent jurisdiction to entertain the application. The district court for the district wherein such an application is filed in the exercise of its discretion and in furtherance of justice may transfer the application to the other district court for hearing and determination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No court, justice, or judge shall have jurisdiction to hear or consider an application for a writ of habeas corpus filed by or on behalf of an alien detained by the United States who has been determined by the United States to have been properly detained as an enemy combatant or is awaiting such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 1005(e) of the Detainee Treatment Act of 2005 (<ref>10 U.S.C. 801</ref> note), no court, justice, or judge shall have jurisdiction to hear or consider any other action against the United States or its agents relating to any aspect of the detention, transfer, treatment, trial, or conditions of confinement of an alien who is or was detained by the United States and has been determined by the United States to have been properly detained as an enemy combatant or is awaiting such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 964</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 112</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–590</ref>, <date date="1966-09-19">Sept. 19, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 811</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–148, div. A, title X, § 1005(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-30">Dec. 30, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XIV, § 1405(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3477</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–366, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2635</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1063(f)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 323</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2242.</num>
<heading> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Application for a writ of habeas corpus shall be in writing signed and verified by the person for whose relief it is intended or by someone acting in his behalf.</p>
<p class="indent0">It shall allege the facts concerning the applicant’s commitment or detention, the name of the person who has custody over him and by virtue of what claim or authority, if known.</p>
<p class="indent0">It may be amended or supplemented as provided in the rules of procedure applicable to civil actions.</p>
<p class="indent0">If addressed to the Supreme Court, a justice thereof or a circuit judge it shall state the reasons for not making application to the district court of the district in which the applicant is held.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2243.</num>
<heading> Issuance of writ; return; hearing; decision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A court, justice or judge entertaining an application for a writ of habeas corpus shall forthwith award the writ or issue an order directing the respondent to show cause why the writ should not be granted, unless it appears from the application that the applicant or person detained is not entitled thereto.</p>
<p class="indent0">The writ, or order to show cause shall be directed to the person having custody of the person detained. It shall be returned within three days unless for good cause additional time, not exceeding twenty days, is allowed.</p>
<p class="indent0">The person to whom the writ or order is directed shall make a return certifying the true cause of the detention.</p>
<p class="indent0">When the writ or order is returned a day shall be set for hearing, not more than five days after the return unless for good cause additional time is allowed.</p>
<p class="indent0">Unless the application for the writ and the return present only issues of law the person to whom the writ is directed shall be required to produce at the hearing the body of the person detained.</p>
<p class="indent0">The applicant or the person detained may, under oath, deny any of the facts set forth in the return or allege any other material facts.</p>
<p class="indent0">The return and all suggestions made against it may be amended, by leave of court, before or after being filed.</p>
<p class="indent0">The court shall summarily hear and determine the facts, and dispose of the matter as law and justice require.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2244.</num>
<heading> Finality of determination</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> No circuit or district judge shall be required to entertain an application for a writ of habeas corpus to inquire into the detention of a person pursuant to a judgment of a court of the United States if it appears that the legality of such detention has been determined by a judge or court of the United States on a prior application for a writ of habeas corpus, except as provided in section 2255.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A claim presented in a second or successive habeas corpus application under section 2254 that was presented in a prior application shall be dismissed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A claim presented in a second or successive habeas corpus application under section 2254 that was not presented in a prior application shall be dismissed unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the applicant shows that the claim relies on a new rule of constitutional law, made retroactive to cases on collateral review by the Supreme Court, that was previously unavailable; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the factual predicate for the claim could not have been discovered previously through the exercise of due diligence; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the facts underlying the claim, if proven and viewed in light of the evidence as a whole, would be sufficient to establish by clear and convincing evidence that, but for constitutional error, no reasonable factfinder would have found the applicant guilty of the underlying offense.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Before a second or successive application permitted by this section is filed in the district court, the applicant shall move in the appropriate court of appeals for an order authorizing the district court to consider the application.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A motion in the court of appeals for an order authorizing the district court to consider a second or successive application shall be determined by a three-judge panel of the court of appeals.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The court of appeals may authorize the filing of a second or successive application only if it determines that the application makes a prima facie showing that the application satisfies the requirements of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The court of appeals shall grant or deny the authorization to file a second or successive application not later than 30 days after the filing of the motion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The grant or denial of an authorization by a court of appeals to file a second or successive application shall not be appealable and shall not be the subject of a petition for rehearing or for a writ of certiorari.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A district court shall dismiss any claim presented in a second or successive application that the court of appeals has authorized to be filed unless the applicant shows that the claim satisfies the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In a habeas corpus proceeding brought in behalf of a person in custody pursuant to the judgment of a State court, a prior judgment of the Supreme Court of the United States on an appeal or review by a writ of certiorari at the instance of the prisoner of the decision of such State court, shall be conclusive as to all issues of fact or law with respect to an asserted denial of a Federal right which constitutes ground for discharge in a habeas corpus proceeding, actually adjudicated by the Supreme Court therein, unless the applicant for the writ of habeas corpus shall plead and the court shall find the existence of a material and controlling fact which did not appear in the record of the proceeding in the Supreme Court and the court shall further find that the applicant for the writ of habeas corpus could not have caused such fact to appear in such record by the exercise of reasonable diligence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A 1-year period of limitation shall apply to an application for a writ of habeas corpus by a person in custody pursuant to the judgment of a State court. The limitation period shall run from the latest of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date on which the judgment became final by the conclusion of direct review or the expiration of the time for seeking such review;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the impediment to filing an application created by State action in violation of the Constitution or laws of the United States is removed, if the applicant was prevented from filing by such State action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the date on which the constitutional right asserted was initially recognized by the Supreme Court, if the right has been newly recognized by the Supreme Court and made retroactively applicable to cases on collateral review; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the date on which the factual predicate of the claim or claims presented could have been discovered through the exercise of due diligence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The time during which a properly filed application for State post-conviction or other collateral review with respect to the pertinent judgment or claim is pending shall not be counted toward any period of limitation under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 965</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–711, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1104</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title I</ref>, §§ 101, 106, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1217</ref>, 1220.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2245.</num>
<heading> Certificate of trial judge admissible in evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the hearing of an application for a writ of habeas corpus to inquire into the legality of the detention of a person pursuant to a judgment the certificate of the judge who presided at the trial resulting in the judgment, setting forth the facts occurring at the trial, shall be admissible in evidence. Copies of the certificate shall be filed with the court in which the application is pending and in the court in which the trial took place.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2246.</num>
<heading> Evidence; depositions; affidavits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On application for a writ of habeas corpus, evidence may be taken orally or by deposition, or, in the discretion of the judge, by affidavit. If affidavits are admitted any party shall have the right to propound written interrogatories to the affiants, or to file answering affidavits.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2247.</num>
<heading> Documentary evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On application for a writ of habeas corpus documentary evidence, transcripts of proceedings upon arraignment, plea and sentence and a transcript of the oral testimony introduced on any previous similar application by or in behalf of the same petitioner, shall be admissible in evidence.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2248.</num>
<heading> Return or answer; conclusiveness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The allegations of a return to the writ of habeas corpus or of an answer to an order to show cause in a habeas corpus proceeding, if not traversed, shall be accepted as true except to the extent that the judge finds from the evidence that they are not true.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2249.</num>
<heading> Certified copies of indictment, plea and judgment; duty of respondent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On application for a writ of habeas corpus to inquire into the detention of any person pursuant to a judgment of a court of the United States, the respondent shall promptly file with the court certified copies of the indictment, plea of petitioner and the judgment, or such of them as may be material to the questions raised, if the petitioner fails to attach them to his petition, and same shall be attached to the return to the writ, or to the answer to the order to show cause.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2250.</num>
<heading> Indigent petitioner entitled to documents without cost</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If on any application for a writ of habeas corpus an order has been made permitting the petitioner to prosecute the application in forma pauperis, the clerk of any court of the United States shall furnish to the petitioner without cost certified copies of such documents or parts of the record on file in his office as may be required by order of the judge before whom the application is pending.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2251.</num>
<heading> Stay of State court proceedings</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Pending matters</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A justice or judge of the United States before whom a habeas corpus proceeding is pending, may, before final judgment or after final judgment of discharge, or pending appeal, stay any proceeding against the person detained in any State court or by or under the authority of any State for any matter involved in the habeas corpus proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Matter not pending</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this section, a habeas corpus proceeding is not pending until the application is filed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Application for appointment of counsel</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a State prisoner sentenced to death applies for appointment of counsel pursuant to <ref>section 3599(a)(2) of title 18</ref> in a court that would have jurisdiction to entertain a habeas corpus application regarding that sentence, that court may stay execution of the sentence of death, but such stay shall terminate not later than 90 days after counsel is appointed or the application for appointment of counsel is withdrawn or denied.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Further Proceedings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After the granting of such a stay, any such proceeding in any State court or by or under the authority of any State shall be void. If no stay is granted, any such proceeding shall be as valid as if no habeas corpus proceedings or appeal were pending.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 966</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title V, § 507(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 251</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2252.</num>
<heading> Notice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Prior to the hearing of a habeas corpus proceeding in behalf of a person in custody of State officers or by virtue of State laws notice shall be served on the attorney general or other appropriate officer of such State as the justice or judge at the time of issuing the writ shall direct.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 967</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2253.</num>
<heading> Appeal</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In a habeas corpus proceeding or a proceeding under section 2255 before a district judge, the final order shall be subject to review, on appeal, by the court of appeals for the circuit in which the proceeding is held.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> There shall be no right of appeal from a final order in a proceeding to test the validity of a warrant to remove to another district or place for commitment or trial a person charged with a criminal offense against the United States, or to test the validity of such person’s detention pending removal proceedings.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Unless a circuit justice or judge issues a certificate of appealability, an appeal may not be taken to the court of appeals from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the final order in a habeas corpus proceeding in which the detention complained of arises out of process issued by a State court; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the final order in a proceeding under section 2255.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A certificate of appealability may issue under paragraph (1) only if the applicant has made a substantial showing of the denial of a constitutional right.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The certificate of appealability under paragraph (1) shall indicate which specific issue or issues satisfy the showing required by paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 967</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 113</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 105</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 52</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1217</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2254.</num>
<heading> State custody; remedies in Federal courts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Supreme Court, a Justice thereof, a circuit judge, or a district court shall entertain an application for a writ of habeas corpus in behalf of a person in custody pursuant to the judgment of a State court only on the ground that he is in custody in violation of the Constitution or laws or treaties of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> An application for a writ of habeas corpus on behalf of a person in custody pursuant to the judgment of a State court shall not be granted unless it appears that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the applicant has exhausted the remedies available in the courts of the State; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> there is an absence of available State corrective process; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> circumstances exist that render such process ineffective to protect the rights of the applicant.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An application for a writ of habeas corpus may be denied on the merits, notwithstanding the failure of the applicant to exhaust the remedies available in the courts of the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A State shall not be deemed to have waived the exhaustion requirement or be estopped from reliance upon the requirement unless the State, through counsel, expressly waives the requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> An applicant shall not be deemed to have exhausted the remedies available in the courts of the State, within the meaning of this section, if he has the right under the law of the State to raise, by any available procedure, the question presented.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> An application for a writ of habeas corpus on behalf of a person in custody pursuant to the judgment of a State court shall not be granted with respect to any claim that was adjudicated on the merits in State court proceedings unless the adjudication of the claim—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> resulted in a decision that was contrary to, or involved an unreasonable application of, clearly established Federal law, as determined by the Supreme Court of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> resulted in a decision that was based on an unreasonable determination of the facts in light of the evidence presented in the State court proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In a proceeding instituted by an application for a writ of habeas corpus by a person in custody pursuant to the judgment of a State court, a determination of a factual issue made by a State court shall be presumed to be correct. The applicant shall have the burden of rebutting the presumption of correctness by clear and convincing evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> If the applicant has failed to develop the factual basis of a claim in State court proceedings, the court shall not hold an evidentiary hearing on the claim unless the applicant shows that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the claim relies on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a new rule of constitutional law, made retroactive to cases on collateral review by the Supreme Court, that was previously unavailable; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a factual predicate that could not have been previously discovered through the exercise of due diligence; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the facts underlying the claim would be sufficient to establish by clear and convincing evidence that but for constitutional error, no reasonable factfinder would have found the applicant guilty of the underlying offense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> If the applicant challenges the sufficiency of the evidence adduced in such State court proceeding to support the State court’s determination of a factual issue made therein, the applicant, if able, shall produce that part of the record pertinent to a determination of the sufficiency of the evidence to support such determination. If the applicant, because of indigency or other reason is unable to produce such part of the record, then the State shall produce such part of the record and the Federal court shall direct the State to do so by order directed to an appropriate State official. If the State cannot provide such pertinent part of the record, then the court shall determine under the existing facts and circumstances what weight shall be given to the State court’s factual determination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> A copy of the official records of the State court, duly certified by the clerk of such court to be a true and correct copy of a finding, judicial opinion, or other reliable written indicia showing such a factual determination by the State court shall be admissible in the Federal court proceeding.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Except as provided in section 408 of the Controlled Substances Act, in all proceedings brought under this section, and any subsequent proceedings on review, the court may appoint counsel for an applicant who is or becomes financially unable to afford counsel, except as provided by a rule promulgated by the Supreme Court pursuant to statutory authority. Appointment of counsel under this section shall be governed by <ref>section 3006A of title 18</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The ineffectiveness or incompetence of counsel during Federal or State collateral post-conviction proceedings shall not be a ground for relief in a proceeding arising under section 2254.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 967</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–711, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1218</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2255.</num>
<heading> Federal custody; remedies on motion attacking sentence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A prisoner in custody under sentence of a court established by Act of Congress claiming the right to be released upon the ground that the sentence was imposed in violation of the Constitution or laws of the United States, or that the court was without jurisdiction to impose such sentence, or that the sentence was in excess of the maximum authorized by law, or is otherwise subject to collateral attack, may move the court which imposed the sentence to vacate, set aside or correct the sentence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Unless the motion and the files and records of the case conclusively show that the prisoner is entitled to no relief, the court shall cause notice thereof to be served upon the United States attorney, grant a prompt hearing thereon, determine the issues and make findings of fact and conclusions of law with respect thereto. If the court finds that the judgment was rendered without jurisdiction, or that the sentence imposed was not authorized by law or otherwise open to collateral attack, or that there has been such a denial or infringement of the constitutional rights of the prisoner as to render the judgment vulnerable to collateral attack, the court shall vacate and set the judgment aside and shall discharge the prisoner or resentence him or grant a new trial or correct the sentence as may appear appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A court may entertain and determine such motion without requiring the production of the prisoner at the hearing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> An appeal may be taken to the court of appeals from the order entered on the motion as from a final judgment on application for a writ of habeas corpus.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> An application for a writ of habeas corpus in behalf of a prisoner who is authorized to apply for relief by motion pursuant to this section, shall not be entertained if it appears that the applicant has failed to apply for relief, by motion, to the court which sentenced him, or that such court has denied him relief, unless it also appears that the remedy by motion is inadequate or ineffective to test the legality of his detention.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> A 1-year period of limitation shall apply to a motion under this section. The limitation period shall run from the latest of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which the judgment of conviction becomes final;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the date on which the impediment to making a motion created by governmental action in violation of the Constitution or laws of the United States is removed, if the movant was prevented from making a motion by such governmental action;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the date on which the right asserted was initially recognized by the Supreme Court, if that right has been newly recognized by the Supreme Court and made retroactively applicable to cases on collateral review; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the date on which the facts supporting the claim or claims presented could have been discovered through the exercise of due diligence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> Except as provided in section 408 of the Controlled Substances Act, in all proceedings brought under this section, and any subsequent proceedings on review, the court may appoint counsel, except as provided by a rule promulgated by the Supreme Court pursuant to statutory authority. Appointment of counsel under this section shall be governed by <ref>section 3006A of title 18</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<chapeau> A second or successive motion must be certified as provided in section 2244 by a panel of the appropriate court of appeals to contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> newly discovered evidence that, if proven and viewed in light of the evidence as a whole, would be sufficient to establish by clear and convincing evidence that no reasonable factfinder would have found the movant guilty of the offense; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a new rule of constitutional law, made retroactive to cases on collateral review by the Supreme Court, that was previously unavailable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 967</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 114</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1220</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–177, title V, § 511</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2545</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2256.</num>
<heading> Omitted]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>