<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>CONFERENCES AND COUNCILS OF JUDGES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 331.</num>
<heading> Judicial Conference of the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Justice of the United States shall summon annually the chief judge of each judicial circuit, the chief judge of the Court of International Trade, and a district judge from each judicial circuit to a conference at such time and place in the United States as he may designate. He shall preside at such conference which shall be known as the Judicial Conference of the United States. Special sessions of the Conference may be called by the Chief Justice at such times and places as he may designate.</p>
<p class="indent0">The district judge to be summoned from each judicial circuit shall be chosen by the circuit and district judges of the circuit and shall serve as a member of the Judicial Conference of the United States for a term of not less than 3 successive years nor more than 5 successive years, as established by majority vote of all circuit and district judges of the circuit. A district judge serving as a member of the Judicial Conference may be either a judge in regular active service or a judge retired from regular active service under <ref>section 371(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p class="indent0">If the chief judge of any circuit, the chief judge of the Court of International Trade, or the district judge chosen by the judges of the circuit is unable to attend, the Chief Justice may summon any other circuit or district judge from such circuit or any other judge of the Court of International Trade, as the case may be. Every judge summoned shall attend and, unless excused by the Chief Justice, shall remain throughout the sessions of the conference and advise as to the needs of his circuit or court and as to any matters in respect of which the administration of justice in the courts of the United States may be improved.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Conference shall make a comprehensive survey of the condition of business in the courts of the United States and prepare plans for assignment of judges to or from circuits or districts where necessary. It shall also submit suggestions and recommendations to the various courts to promote uniformity of management procedures and the expeditious conduct of court business. The Conference is authorized to exercise the authority provided in chapter 16 of this title as the Conference, or through a standing committee. If the Conference elects to establish a standing committee, it shall be appointed by the Chief Justice and all petitions for review shall be reviewed by that committee. The Conference or the standing committee may hold hearings, take sworn testimony, issue subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum, and make necessary and appropriate orders in the exercise of its authority. Subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum shall be issued by the clerk of the Supreme Court or by the clerk of any court of appeals, at the direction of the Chief Justice or his designee and under the seal of the court, and shall be served in the manner provided in rule 45(c) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure for subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum issued on behalf of the United States or an officer or any agency thereof. The Conference may also prescribe and modify rules for the exercise of the authority provided in chapter 16 of this title. All judicial officers and employees of the United States shall promptly carry into effect all orders of the Judicial Conference or the standing committee established pursuant to this section.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Conference shall also carry on a continuous study of the operation and effect of the general rules of practice and procedure now or hereafter in use as prescribed by the Supreme Court for the other courts of the United States pursuant to law. Such changes in and additions to those rules as the Conference may deem desirable to promote simplicity in procedure, fairness in administration, the just determination of litigation, and the elimination of unjustifiable expense and delay shall be recommended by the Conference from time to time to the Supreme Court for its consideration and adoption, modification or rejection, in accordance with law.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Judicial Conference shall review rules prescribed under <ref>section 2071 of this title</ref> by the courts, other than the Supreme Court and the district courts, for consistency with Federal law. The Judicial Conference may modify or abrogate any such rule so reviewed found inconsistent in the course of such a review.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall, upon request of the Chief Justice, report to such Conference on matters relating to the business of the several courts of the United States, with particular reference to cases to which the United States is a party.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Justice shall submit to Congress an annual report of the proceedings of the Judicial Conference and its recommendations for legislation.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Judicial Conference shall consult with the Director of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002015">1</ref> United States Marshals Service on a continuing basis regarding the security requirements for the judicial branch of the United States Government, to ensure that the views of the Judicial Conference regarding the security requirements for the judicial branch of the Federal Government are taken into account when determining staffing levels, setting priorities for programs regarding judicial security, and allocating judicial security resources. In this paragraph, the term “judicial security” includes the security of buildings housing the judiciary, the personal security of judicial officers, the assessment of threats made to judicial officers, and the protection of all other judicial personnel. The United States Marshals Service retains final authority regarding security requirements for the judicial branch of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 902</ref>; <ref>July 9, 1956, ch. 517, § 1(d)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–202</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 476</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–513</ref>, <date date="1958-07-11">July 11, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–253</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1961-09-19">Sept. 19, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 521</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2660</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–458, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-10-15">Oct. 15, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2040</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 29</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–466, § 1</ref>, <date date="1986-10-14">Oct. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1190</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IV, § 402(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4650</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–317, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3857</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11043(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1855</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–177, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2534</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 332.</num>
<heading> Judicial councils of circuits</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The chief judge of each judicial circuit shall call, at least twice in each year and at such places as he or she may designate, a meeting of the judicial council of the circuit, consisting of the chief judge of the circuit, who shall preside, and an equal number of circuit judges and district judges of the circuit, as such number is determined by majority vote of all such judges of the circuit in regular active service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Members of the council shall serve for terms established by a majority vote of all judges of the circuit in regular active service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Except for the chief judge of the circuit, either judges in regular active service or judges retired from regular active service under <ref>section 371(b) of this title</ref> may serve as members of the council. Service as a member of a judicial council by a judge retired from regular active service under section 371(b) may not be considered for meeting the requirements of section 371(f)(1)(A), (B), or (C).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002016">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> No more than one district judge from any one district shall serve simultaneously on the council, unless at least one district judge from each district within the circuit is already serving as a member of the council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In the event of the death, resignation, retirement under section 371(a) or 372(a) of this title, or disability of a member of the council, a replacement member shall be designated to serve the remainder of the unexpired term by the chief judge of the circuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Each member of the council shall attend each council meeting unless excused by the chief judge of the circuit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The council shall be known as the Judicial Council of the circuit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The chief judge shall submit to the council the semiannual reports of the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts. The council shall take such action thereon as may be necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each judicial council shall make all necessary and appropriate orders for the effective and expeditious administration of justice within its circuit. Any general order relating to practice and procedure shall be made or amended only after giving appropriate public notice and an opportunity for comment. Any such order so relating shall take effect upon the date specified by such judicial council. Copies of such orders so relating shall be furnished to the Judicial Conference and the Administrative Office of the United States Courts and be made available to the public. Each council is authorized to hold hearings, to take sworn testimony, and to issue subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum. Subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum shall be issued by the clerk of the court of appeals, at the direction of the chief judge of the circuit or his designee and under the seal of the court, and shall be served in the manner provided in rule 45(c) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure for subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum issued on behalf of the United States or an officer or agency thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> All judicial officers and employees of the circuit shall promptly carry into effect all orders of the judicial council. In the case of failure to comply with an order made under this subsection or a subpoena issued under chapter 16 of this title, a judicial council or a special committee appointed under <ref>section 353 of this title</ref> may institute a contempt proceeding in any district court in which the judicial officer or employee of the circuit who fails to comply with the order made under this subsection shall be ordered to show cause before the court why he or she should not be held in contempt of court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Unless an impediment to the administration of justice is involved, regular business of the courts need not be referred to the council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Each judicial council shall periodically review the rules which are prescribed under <ref>section 2071 of this title</ref> by district courts within its circuit for consistency with rules prescribed under <ref>section 2072 of this title</ref>. Each council may modify or abrogate any such rule found inconsistent in the course of such a review.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<chapeau> The judicial council of each circuit may appoint a circuit executive. In appointing a circuit executive, the judicial council shall take into account experience in administrative and executive positions, familiarity with court procedures, and special training. The circuit executive shall exercise such administrative powers and perform such duties as may be delegated to him by the circuit council. The duties delegated to the circuit executive of each circuit may include but need not be limited to:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Exercising administrative control of all nonjudicial activities of the court of appeals of the circuit in which he is appointed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Administering the personnel system of the court of appeals of the circuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Administering the budget of the court of appeals of the circuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Maintaining a modern accounting system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Establishing and maintaining property control records and undertaking a space management program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Conducting studies relating to the business and administration of the courts within the circuit and preparing appropriate recommendations and reports to the chief judge, the circuit council, and the Judicial Conference.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Collecting, compiling, and analyzing statistical data with a view to the preparation and presentation of reports based on such data as may be directed by the chief judge, the circuit council, and the Administrative Office of the United States Courts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Representing the circuit as its liaison to the courts of the various States in which the circuit is located, the marshal’s office, State and local bar associations, civic groups, news media, and other private and public groups having a reasonable interest in the administration of the circuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Arranging and attending meetings of the judges of the circuit and of the circuit council, including preparing the agenda and serving as secretary in all such meetings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Preparing an annual report to the circuit and to the Administrative Office of the United States Courts for the preceding calendar year, including recommendations for more expeditious disposition of the business of the circuit.<p class="indent0">All duties delegated to the circuit executive shall be subject to the general supervision of the chief judge of the circuit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each circuit executive shall be paid at a salary to be established by the Judicial Conference of the United States not to exceed the annual rate of level IV of the Executive Schedule pay rates under <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The circuit executive shall serve at the pleasure of the judicial council of the circuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The circuit executive may appoint, with the approval of the council, necessary employees in such number as may be approved by the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The circuit executive and his staff shall be deemed to be officers and employees of the judicial branch of the United States Government within the meaning of subchapter III of chapter 83 (relating to civil service retirement), chapter 87 (relating to Federal employees’ life insurance program), and chapter 89 (relating to Federal employees’ health benefits program) of title 5, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> No later than January 31 of each year, each judicial council shall submit a report to the Administrative Office of the United States Courts on the number and nature of orders entered under this section during the preceding calendar year that relate to judicial misconduct or disability.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit may appoint a circuit executive, who shall serve at the pleasure of the court. In appointing a circuit executive, the court shall take into account experience in administrative and executive positions, familiarity with court procedures, and special training. The circuit executive shall exercise such administrative powers and perform such duties as may be delegated by the court. The duties delegated to the circuit executive may include the duties specified in subsection (e) of this section, insofar as such duties are applicable to the Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The circuit executive shall be paid the salary for circuit executives established under subsection (f) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The circuit executive may appoint, with the approval of the court, necessary employees in such number as may be approved by the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The circuit executive and staff shall be deemed to be officers and employees of the United States within the meaning of the statutes specified in subsection (f)(4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The court may appoint either a circuit executive under this subsection or a clerk under <ref>section 711 of this title</ref>, but not both, or may appoint a combined circuit executive/clerk who shall be paid the salary of a circuit executive.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–176, § 3</ref>, <date date="1963-11-13">Nov. 13, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 331</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–647</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1907</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–458, § 2(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="1980-10-15">Oct. 15, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2035</ref>, 2036; <ref>Pub. L. 100–459, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2213</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IV, § 403(a)(2)</ref>, (b), title X, §§ 1018, 1020(a)(1), <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4651</ref>, 4670, 4671; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III</ref>, §§ 323, 325(b)(1), title IV, § 403, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5120</ref>, 5121, 5124; <ref>Pub. L. 102–198, § 1</ref>, <date date="1991-12-09">Dec. 9, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1623</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–317, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3851</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–518, title II, § 205</ref>, title III, § 306, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2414</ref>, 2418; <ref>Pub. L. 106–553, § 1(a)(2) [title III, § 306]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2762</ref>, 2762A–85; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11043(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1855</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 333.</num>
<heading> Judicial conferences of circuits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chief judge of each circuit may summon biennially, and may summon annually, the circuit, district, magistrate, and bankruptcy judges of the circuit, in active service, to a conference at a time and place that he designates, for the purpose of considering the business of the courts and advising means of improving the administration of justice within such circuit. He may preside at such conference, which shall be known as the Judicial Conference of the circuit. The judges of the District Court of Guam, the District Court of the Virgin Islands, and the District Court of the Northern Mariana Islands may also be summoned biennially, and may be summoned annually, to the conferences of their respective circuits.</p>
<p class="indent0">Every judge summoned may attend.</p>
<p class="indent0">The court of appeals for each circuit shall provide by its rules for representation and active participation at such conference by members of the bar of such circuit.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 903</ref>; <ref>Dec. 29, 1950, ch. 1185</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 1128</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 38</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 723</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–508, § 12(e)</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 348</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101[(a)]</ref> [title III, § 305], <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1321</ref>, 1321–36; renumbered title I, <ref>Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1327</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–406, § 9</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 334.</num>
<heading> Institutes and joint councils on sentencing</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In the interest of uniformity in sentencing procedures, there is hereby authorized to be established under the auspices of the Judicial Conference of the United States, institutes and joint councils on sentencing. The Attorney General and/or the chief judge of each circuit may at any time request, through the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, the Judicial Conference to convene such institutes and joint councils for the purpose of studying, discussing, and formulating the objectives, policies, standards, and criteria for sentencing those convicted of crimes and offenses in the courts of the United States. The agenda of the institutes and joint councils may include but shall not be limited to: (1) The development of standards for the content and utilization of presentence reports; (2) the establishment of factors to be used in selecting cases for special study and observation in prescribed diagnostic clinics; (3) the determination of the importance of psychiatric, emotional, sociological and physiological factors involved in crime and their bearing upon sentences; (4) the discussion of special sentencing problems in unusual cases such as treason, violation of public trust, subversion, or involving abnormal sex behavior, addiction to drugs or alcohol, and mental or physical handicaps; (5) the formulation of sentencing principles and criteria which will assist in promoting the equitable administration of the criminal laws of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> After the Judicial Conference has approved the time, place, participants, agenda, and other arrangements for such institutes and joint councils, the chief judge of each circuit is authorized to invite the attendance of district judges under conditions which he thinks proper and which will not unduly delay the work of the courts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Attorney General is authorized to select and direct the attendance at such institutes and meetings of United States attorneys and other officials of the Department of Justice and may invite the participation of other interested Federal officers. He may also invite specialists in sentencing methods, criminologists, psychiatrists, penologists, and others to participate in the proceedings.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The expenses of attendance of judges shall be paid from applicable appropriations for the judiciary of the United States. The expenses connected with the preparation of the plans and agenda for the conference and for the travel and other expenses incident to the attendance of officials and other participants invited by the Attorney General shall be paid from applicable appropriations of the Department of Justice.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–752, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-08-25">Aug. 25, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 335.</num>
<heading> Judicial Conference of the Court of International Trade</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The chief judge of the Court of International Trade is authorized to summon annually the judges of such court to a judicial conference, at a time and place that such chief judge designates, for the purpose of considering the business of such court and improvements in the administration of justice in such court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Court of International Trade shall provide by its rules for representation and active participation at such conference by members of the bar.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–466, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-14">Oct. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1190</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>