<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 131—</num>
<heading>RULES OF COURTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2071.</num>
<heading> Rule-making power generally</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Supreme Court and all courts established by Act of Congress may from time to time prescribe rules for the conduct of their business. Such rules shall be consistent with Acts of Congress and rules of practice and procedure prescribed under <ref>section 2072 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any rule prescribed by a court, other than the Supreme Court, under subsection (a) shall be prescribed only after giving appropriate public notice and an opportunity for comment. Such rule shall take effect upon the date specified by the prescribing court and shall have such effect on pending proceedings as the prescribing court may order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A rule of a district court prescribed under subsection (a) shall remain in effect unless modified or abrogated by the judicial council of the relevant circuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any other rule prescribed by a court other than the Supreme Court under subsection (a) shall remain in effect unless modified or abrogated by the Judicial Conference.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Copies of rules prescribed under subsection (a) by a district court shall be furnished to the judicial council, and copies of all rules prescribed by a court other than the Supreme Court under subsection (a) shall be furnished to the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts and made available to the public.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If the prescribing court determines that there is an immediate need for a rule, such court may proceed under this section without public notice and opportunity for comment, but such court shall promptly thereafter afford such notice and opportunity for comment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> No rule may be prescribed by a district court other than under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 961</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 102</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 104</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IV, § 403(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4650</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2072.</num>
<heading> Rules of procedure and evidence; power to prescribe</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Supreme Court shall have the power to prescribe general rules of practice and procedure and rules of evidence for cases in the United States district courts (including proceedings before magistrate judges thereof) and courts of appeals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Such rules shall not abridge, enlarge or modify any substantive right. All laws in conflict with such rules shall be of no further force or effect after such rules have taken effect.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Such rules may define when a ruling of a district court is final for the purposes of appeal under <ref>section 1291 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4648</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III</ref>, §§ 315, 321, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5115</ref>, 5117.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2073.</num>
<heading> Rules of procedure and evidence; method of prescribing</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Judicial Conference shall prescribe and publish the procedures for the consideration of proposed rules under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Judicial Conference may authorize the appointment of committees to assist the Conference by recommending rules to be prescribed under sections 2072 and 2075 of this title. Each such committee shall consist of members of the bench and the professional bar, and trial and appellate judges.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Judicial Conference shall authorize the appointment of a standing committee on rules of practice, procedure, and evidence under subsection (a) of this section. Such standing committee shall review each recommendation of any other committees so appointed and recommend to the Judicial Conference rules of practice, procedure, and evidence and such changes in rules proposed by a committee appointed under subsection (a)(2) of this section as may be necessary to maintain consistency and otherwise promote the interest of justice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each meeting for the transaction of business under this chapter by any committee appointed under this section shall be open to the public, except when the committee so meeting, in open session and with a majority present, determines that it is in the public interest that all or part of the remainder of the meeting on that day shall be closed to the public, and states the reason for so closing the meeting. Minutes of each meeting for the transaction of business under this chapter shall be maintained by the committee and made available to the public, except that any portion of such minutes, relating to a closed meeting and made available to the public, may contain such deletions as may be necessary to avoid frustrating the purposes of closing the meeting.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any meeting for the transaction of business under this chapter, by a committee appointed under this section, shall be preceded by sufficient notice to enable all interested persons to attend.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In making a recommendation under this section or under section 2072 or 2075, the body making that recommendation shall provide a proposed rule, an explanatory note on the rule, and a written report explaining the body’s action, including any minority or other separate views.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Failure to comply with this section does not invalidate a rule prescribed under section 2072 or 2075 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4649</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title I, § 104(e)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2074.</num>
<heading> Rules of procedure and evidence; submission to Congress; effective date</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Supreme Court shall transmit to the Congress not later than May 1 of the year in which a rule prescribed under section 2072 is to become effective a copy of the proposed rule. Such rule shall take effect no earlier than December 1 of the year in which such rule is so transmitted unless otherwise provided by law. The Supreme Court may fix the extent such rule shall apply to proceedings then pending, except that the Supreme Court shall not require the application of such rule to further proceedings then pending to the extent that, in the opinion of the court in which such proceedings are pending, the application of such rule in such proceedings would not be feasible or would work injustice, in which event the former rule applies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any such rule creating, abolishing, or modifying an evidentiary privilege shall have no force or effect unless approved by Act of Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4649</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2075.</num>
<heading> Bankruptcy rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Supreme Court shall have the power to prescribe by general rules, the forms of process, writs, pleadings, and motions, and the practice and procedure in cases under title 11.</p>
<p class="indent0">Such rules shall not abridge, enlarge, or modify any substantive right.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Supreme Court shall transmit to Congress not later than May 1 of the year in which a rule prescribed under this section is to become effective a copy of the proposed rule. The rule shall take effect no earlier than December 1 of the year in which it is transmitted to Congress unless otherwise provided by law.</p>
<p class="indent0">The bankruptcy rules promulgated under this section shall prescribe a form for the statement required under <ref>section 707(b)(2)(C) of title 11</ref> and may provide general rules on the content of such statement.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 88–623, § 1</ref>, <date date="1964-10-03">Oct. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1001</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title II, § 247</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2672</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–394, title I, § 104(f)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4110</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–8, title XII, § 1232</ref>, <date date="2005-04-20">Apr. 20, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 202</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 2076.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IV, § 401(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4650</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2077.</num>
<heading> Publication of rules; advisory committees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The rules for the conduct of the business of each court of appeals, including the operating procedures of such court, shall be published. Each court of appeals shall print or cause to be printed necessary copies of the rules. The Judicial Conference shall prescribe the fees for sales of copies under <ref>section 1913 of this title</ref>, but the Judicial Conference may provide for free distribution of copies to members of the bar of each court and to other interested persons.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each court, except the Supreme Court, that is authorized to prescribe rules of the conduct of such court’s business under <ref>section 2071 of this title</ref> shall appoint an advisory committee for the study of the rules of practice and internal operating procedures of such court and, in the case of an advisory committee appointed by a court of appeals, of the rules of the judicial council of the circuit. The advisory committee shall make recommendations to the court concerning such rules and procedures. Members of the committee shall serve without compensation, but the Director may pay travel and transportation expenses in accordance with <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 54</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IV, § 401(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4650</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>