<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 125—</num>
<heading>PENDING ACTIONS AND JUDGMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1961.</num>
<heading> Interest</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Interest shall be allowed on any money judgment in a civil case recovered in a district court. Execution therefor may be levied by the marshal, in any case where, by the law of the State in which such court is held, execution may be levied for interest on judgments recovered in the courts of the State. Such interest shall be calculated from the date of the entry of the judgment, at a rate equal to the weekly average 1-year constant maturity Treasury yield, as published by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, for the calendar week preceding.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002093">1</ref> the date of the judgment. The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall distribute notice of that rate and any changes in it to all Federal judges.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Interest shall be computed daily to the date of payment except as provided in <ref>section 2516(b) of this title</ref> and <ref>section 1304(b) of title 31</ref>, and shall be compounded annually.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> This section shall not apply in any judgment of any court with respect to any internal revenue tax case. Interest shall be allowed in such cases at the underpayment rate or overpayment rate (whichever is appropriate) established under section 6621 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, interest shall be allowed on all final judgments against the United States in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal circuit,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002094">2</ref> at the rate provided in subsection (a) and as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Interest shall be allowed, computed, and paid on judgments of the United States Court of Federal Claims only as provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection or in any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> This section shall not be construed to affect the interest on any judgment of any court not specified in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 957</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 55</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(m)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1062</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–452, § 2(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2478</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, title XV, § 1511(c)(17), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>, 2745; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(7) [title III, § 307(d)(1)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–636.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962.</num>
<heading> Lien</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every judgment rendered by a district court within a State shall be a lien on the property located in such State in the same manner, to the same extent and under the same conditions as a judgment of a court of general jurisdiction in such State, and shall cease to be a lien in the same manner and time. This section does not apply to judgments entered in favor of the United States. Whenever the law of any State requires a judgment of a State court to be registered, recorded, docketed or indexed, or any other act to be done, in a particular manner, or in a certain office or county or parish before such lien attaches, such requirements shall apply only if the law of such State authorizes the judgment of a court of the United States to be registered, recorded, docketed, indexed or otherwise conformed to rules and requirements relating to judgments of the courts of the State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 958</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXVI, § 3627</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1963.</num>
<heading> Registration of judgments for enforcement in other districts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A judgment in an action for the recovery of money or property entered in any court of appeals, district court, bankruptcy court, or in the Court of International Trade may be registered by filing a certified copy of the judgment in any other district or, with respect to the Court of International Trade, in any judicial district, when the judgment has become final by appeal or expiration of the time for appeal or when ordered by the court that entered the judgment for good cause shown. Such a judgment entered in favor of the United States may be so registered any time after judgment is entered. A judgment so registered shall have the same effect as a judgment of the district court of the district where registered and may be enforced in like manner.</p>
<p class="indent0">A certified copy of the satisfaction of any judgment in whole or in part may be registered in like manner in any district in which the judgment is a lien.</p>
<p class="indent0">The procedure prescribed under this section is in addition to other procedures provided by law for the enforcement of judgments.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 958</ref>; <ref>Aug. 23, 1954, ch. 837</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–508, § 12</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title X, § 1002(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4664</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXVI, § 3628</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4965</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–317, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3849</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1963A.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title X, § 1002(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4664</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1964.</num>
<heading> Constructive notice of pending actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where the law of a State requires a notice of an action concerning real property pending in a court of the State to be registered, recorded, docketed, or indexed in a particular manner, or in a certain office or county or parish in order to give constructive notice of the action as it relates to the real property, and such law authorizes a notice of an action concerning real property pending in a United States district court to be registered, recorded, docketed, or indexed in the same manner, or in the same place, those requirements of the State law must be complied with in order to give constructive notice of such an action pending in a United States district court as it relates to real property in such State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–689, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-20">Aug. 20, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 683</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>