<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 117—</num>
<heading>EVIDENCE; DEPOSITIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1781.</num>
<heading> Transmittal of letter rogatory or request</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Department of State has power, directly, or through suitable channels—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to receive a letter rogatory issued, or request made, by a foreign or international tribunal, to transmit it to the tribunal, officer, or agency in the United States to whom it is addressed, and to receive and return it after execution; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to receive a letter rogatory issued, or request made, by a tribunal in the United States, to transmit it to the foreign or international tribunal, officer, or agency to whom it is addressed, and to receive and return it after execution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> This section does not preclude—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the transmittal of a letter rogatory or request directly from a foreign or international tribunal to the tribunal, officer, or agency in the United States to whom it is addressed and its return in the same manner; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the transmittal of a letter rogatory or request directly from a tribunal in the United States to the foreign or international tribunal, officer, or agency to whom it is addressed and its return in the same manner.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 948</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–619, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-03">Oct. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1782.</num>
<heading> Assistance to foreign and international tribunals and to litigants before such tribunals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The district court of the district in which a person resides or is found may order him to give his testimony or statement or to produce a document or other thing for use in a proceeding in a foreign or international tribunal, including criminal investigations conducted before formal accusation. The order may be made pursuant to a letter rogatory issued, or request made, by a foreign or international tribunal or upon the application of any interested person and may direct that the testimony or statement be given, or the document or other thing be produced, before a person appointed by the court. By virtue of his appointment, the person appointed has power to administer any necessary oath and take the testimony or statement. The order may prescribe the practice and procedure, which may be in whole or part the practice and procedure of the foreign country or the international tribunal, for taking the testimony or statement or producing the document or other thing. To the extent that the order does not prescribe otherwise, the testimony or statement shall be taken, and the document or other thing produced, in accordance with the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.<p class="indent0">A person may not be compelled to give his testimony or statement or to produce a document or other thing in violation of any legally applicable privilege.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This chapter does not preclude a person within the United States from voluntarily giving his testimony or statement, or producing a document or other thing, for use in a proceeding in a foreign or international tribunal before any person and in any manner acceptable to him.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 949</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 93</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 103</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–619, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-03">Oct. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 997</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XIII, § 1342(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 486</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1783.</num>
<heading> Subpoena of person in foreign country</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A court of the United States may order the issuance of a subpoena requiring the appearance as a witness before it, or before a person or body designated by it, of a national or resident of the United States who is in a foreign country, or requiring the production of a specified document or other thing by him, if the court finds that particular testimony or the production of the document or other thing by him is necessary in the interest of justice, and, in other than a criminal action or proceeding, if the court finds, in addition, that it is not possible to obtain his testimony in admissible form without his personal appearance or to obtain the production of the document or other thing in any other manner.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The subpoena shall designate the time and place for the appearance or for the production of the document or other thing. Service of the subpoena and any order to show cause, rule, judgment, or decree authorized by this section or by <ref>section 1784 of this title</ref> shall be effected in accordance with the provisions of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure relating to service of process on a person in a foreign country. The person serving the subpoena shall tender to the person to whom the subpoena is addressed his estimated necessary travel and attendance expenses, the amount of which shall be determined by the court and stated in the order directing the issuance of the subpoena.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–619, § 10(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-03">Oct. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 997</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1784.</num>
<heading> Contempt</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The court of the United States which has issued a subpoena served in a foreign country may order the person who has failed to appear or who has failed to produce a document or other thing as directed therein to show cause before it at a designated time why he should not be punished for contempt.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The court, in the order to show cause, may direct that any of the person’s property within the United States be levied upon or seized, in the manner provided by law or court rules governing levy or seizure under execution, and held to satisfy any judgment that may be rendered against him pursuant to subsection (d) of this section if adequate security, in such amount as the court may direct in the order, be given for any damage that he might suffer should he not be found in contempt. Security under this subsection may not be required of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A copy of the order to show cause shall be served on the person in accordance with <ref>section 1783(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> On the return day of the order to show cause or any later day to which the hearing may be continued, proof shall be taken. If the person is found in contempt, the court, notwithstanding any limitation upon its power generally to punish for contempt, may fine him not more than $100,000 and direct that the fine and costs of the proceedings be satisfied by a sale of the property levied upon or seized, conducted upon the notice required and in the manner provided for sales upon execution.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–619, § 11</ref>, <date date="1964-10-03">Oct. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 998</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1785.</num>
<heading> Subpoenas in multiparty, multiforum actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the jurisdiction of the district court is based in whole or in part upon <ref>section 1369 of this title</ref>, a subpoena for attendance at a hearing or trial may, if authorized by the court upon motion for good cause shown, and upon such terms and conditions as the court may impose, be served at any place within the United States, or anywhere outside the United States if otherwise permitted by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11020(b)(4)(B)(i)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1828</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>