<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 157—</num>
<heading>SURFACE TRANSPORTATION BOARD ORDERS; ENFORCEMENT AND REVIEW</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2321.</num>
<heading> Judicial review of Board’s orders and decisions; procedure generally; process</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided by an Act of Congress, a proceeding to enjoin or suspend, in whole or in part, a rule, regulation, or order of the Surface Transportation Board shall be brought in the court of appeals as provided by and in the manner prescribed in chapter 158 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The procedure in the district courts in actions to enforce, in whole or in part, any order of the Surface Transportation Board other than for payment of money or the collection of fines, penalties, and forfeitures, shall be as provided in this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The orders, writs, and process of the district courts may, in the cases specified in subsection (b) and in enforcement actions and actions to collect civil penalties under subtitle IV of title 49, run, be served and be returnable anywhere in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 969</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 115</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–584, § 5</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1917</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–473, § 2(a)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-17">Oct. 17, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1465</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 305(c)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2322.</num>
<heading> United States as party</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All actions specified in <ref>section 2321 of this title</ref> shall be brought by or against the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 969</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2323.</num>
<heading> Duties of Attorney General; intervenors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall represent the Government in the actions specified in <ref>section 2321 of this title</ref> and in enforcement actions and actions to collect civil penalties under subtitle IV of title 49.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Surface Transportation Board and any party or parties in interest to the proceeding before the Board, in which an order or requirement is made, may appear as parties of their own motion and as of right, and be represented by their counsel, in any action involving the validity of such order or requirement or any part thereof, and the interest of such party.</p>
<p class="indent0">Communities, associations, corporations, firms, and individuals interested in the controversy or question before the Board, or in any action commenced under the aforesaid sections may intervene in said action at any time after commencement thereof.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall not dispose of or discontinue said action or proceeding over the objection of such party or intervenor, who may prosecute, defend, or continue said action or proceeding unaffected by the action or nonaction of the Attorney General therein.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 970</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 116</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 105</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–584, § 6</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1917</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–473, § 2(a)(3)(C)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-17">Oct. 17, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1465</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 305(c)(1)(C)</ref>, (D), <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 2324, 2325.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 93–584, § 7</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1918</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>