<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 119—</num>
<heading>EVIDENCE; WITNESSES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1821.</num>
<heading> Per diem and mileage generally; subsistence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided by law, a witness in attendance at any court of the United States, or before a United States Magistrate Judge, or before any person authorized to take his deposition pursuant to any rule or order of a court of the United States, shall be paid the fees and allowances provided by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the term “court of the United States” includes, in addition to the courts listed in <ref>section 451 of this title</ref>, any court created by Act of Congress in a territory which is invested with any jurisdiction of a district court of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> A witness shall be paid an attendance fee of $40 per day for each day’s attendance. A witness shall also be paid the attendance fee for the time necessarily occupied in going to and returning from the place of attendance at the beginning and end of such attendance or at any time during such attendance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A witness who travels by common carrier shall be paid for the actual expenses of travel on the basis of the means of transportation reasonably utilized and the distance necessarily traveled to and from such witness’s residence by the shortest practical route in going to and returning from the place of attendance. Such a witness shall utilize a common carrier at the most economical rate reasonably available. A receipt or other evidence of actual cost shall be furnished.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A travel allowance equal to the mileage allowance which the Administrator of General Services has prescribed, pursuant to <ref>section 5704 of title 5</ref>, for official travel of employees of the Federal Government shall be paid to each witness who travels by privately owned vehicle. Computation of mileage under this paragraph shall be made on the basis of a uniformed table of distances adopted by the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Toll charges for toll roads, bridges, tunnels, and ferries, taxicab fares between places of lodging and carrier terminals, and parking fees (upon presentation of a valid parking receipt), shall be paid in full to a witness incurring such expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> All normal travel expenses within and outside the judicial district shall be taxable as costs pursuant to <ref>section 1920 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A subsistence allowance shall be paid to a witness when an overnight stay is required at the place of attendance because such place is so far removed from the residence of such witness as to prohibit return thereto from day to day.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A subsistence allowance for a witness shall be paid in an amount not to exceed the maximum per diem allowance prescribed by the Administrator of General Services, pursuant to <ref>section 5702(a) of title 5</ref>, for official travel in the area of attendance by employees of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A subsistence allowance for a witness attending in an area designated by the Administrator of General Services as a high-cost area shall be paid in an amount not to exceed the maximum actual subsistence allowance prescribed by the Administrator, pursuant to section 5702(c)(B) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002086">1</ref> of title 5, for official travel in such area by employees of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> When a witness is detained pursuant to <ref>section 3144 of title 18</ref> for want of security for his appearance, he shall be entitled for each day of detention when not in attendance at court, in addition to his subsistence, to the daily attendance fee provided by subsection (b) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> An alien who has been paroled into the United States for prosecution, pursuant to section 212(d)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1182(d)(5)</ref>), or an alien who either has admitted belonging to a class of aliens who are deportable or has been determined pursuant to section 240 of such Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1252(b)</ref>) <sup>1</sup> to be deportable, shall be ineligible to receive the fees or allowances provided by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Any witness who is incarcerated at the time that his or her testimony is given (except for a witness to whom the provisions of <ref>section 3144 of title 18</ref> apply) may not receive fees or allowances under this section, regardless of whether such a witness is incarcerated at the time he or she makes a claim for fees or allowances under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 950</ref>; <ref>May 10, 1949, ch. 96</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 65</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 94</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 103</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 51(a)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 45</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1242</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 826</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 798</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–274, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="1968-03-27">Mar. 27, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 62</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–535, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2033</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III</ref>, §§ 314(a), 321, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5115</ref>, 5117; <ref>Pub. L. 102–417, § 2(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1992-10-14">Oct. 14, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 308(g)(5)(E)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009–623</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1822.</num>
<heading> Competency of interested persons; share of penalties payable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person interested in a share of any fine, penalty or forfeiture incurred under any Act of Congress, may be examined as a witness in any proceeding for the recovery of such fine, penalty or forfeiture by any party thereto. Such examination shall not deprive the witness of his share.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 950</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1823.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 91–563, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-19">Dec. 19, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1478</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1824.</num>
<heading> Mileage fees under summons as both witness and juror</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No constructive or double mileage fees shall be allowed by reason of any person being summoned both as a witness and a juror.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 951</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1825.</num>
<heading> Payment of fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> In any case in which the United States or an officer or agency of the United States is a party, the Attorney General shall pay all fees of witnesses on the certificate of the United States attorney or assistant United States attorney, and in the proceedings before a United States magistrate judge, on the certificate of such magistrate judge, except that any fees of defense witnesses, other than experts, appearing pursuant to subpoenas issued upon approval of the court, shall be paid by the Attorney General—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on the certificate of a Federal public defender or assistant Federal public defender, in a criminal case in which the defendant is represented by such Federal public defender or assistant Federal public defender, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on the certificate of the clerk of the court upon the affidavit of such witnesses’ attendance given by other counsel appointed pursuant to <ref>section 3006A of title 18</ref>, in a criminal case in which a defendant is represented by such other counsel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In proceedings in forma pauperis for a writ of habeas corpus, and in proceedings in forma pauperis under <ref>section 2255 of this title</ref>, the Attorney General shall pay, on the certificate of the district judge, all fees of witnesses for the party authorized to proceed in forma pauperis, except that any fees of witnesses for such party, other than experts, appearing pursuant to subpoenas issued upon approval of the court, shall be paid by the Attorney General—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on the certificate of a Federal public defender or assistant Federal public defender, in any such proceedings in which a party is represented by such Federal public defender or assistant Federal public defender, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> on the certificate of the clerk of the court upon the affidavit of such witnesses’ attendance given by other counsel appointed pursuant to <ref>section 3006A of title 18</ref>, in any such proceedings in which a party is represented by such other counsel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Fees and mileage need not be tendered to a witness upon service of a subpoena issued on behalf of the United States or an officer or agency of the United States, upon service of a subpoena issued on behalf of a defendant represented by a Federal public defender, assistant Federal public defender, or other attorney appointed pursuant to <ref>section 3006A of title 18</ref>, or upon service of a subpoena issued on behalf of a party authorized to proceed in forma pauperis, if the payment of such fees and mileage is to be made by the Attorney General under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 951</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–162</ref>, <date date="1965-09-02">Sept. 2, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 618</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–651, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3645</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. B, title II, § 220</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1826.</num>
<heading> Recalcitrant witnesses</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever a witness in any proceeding before or ancillary to any court or grand jury of the United States refuses without just cause shown to comply with an order of the court to testify or provide other information, including any book, paper, document, record, recording or other material, the court, upon such refusal, or when such refusal is duly brought to its attention, may summarily order his confinement at a suitable place until such time as the witness is willing to give such testimony or provide such information. No period of such confinement shall exceed the life of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the court proceeding, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term of the grand jury, including extensions,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">before which such refusal to comply with the court order occurred, but in no event shall such confinement exceed eighteen months.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> No person confined pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be admitted to bail pending the determination of an appeal taken by him from the order for his confinement if it appears that the appeal is frivolous or taken for delay. Any appeal from an order of confinement under this section shall be disposed of as soon as practicable, but not later than thirty days from the filing of such appeal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whoever escapes or attempts to escape from the custody of any facility or from any place in which or to which he is confined pursuant to this section or <ref>section 4243 of title 18</ref>, or whoever rescues or attempts to rescue or instigates, aids, or assists the escape or attempt to escape of such a person, shall be subject to imprisonment for not more than three years, or a fine of not more than $10,000, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–452, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 932</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1013</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2142</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1827.</num>
<heading> Interpreters in courts of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall establish a program to facilitate the use of certified and otherwise qualified interpreters in judicial proceedings instituted by the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Director shall prescribe, determine, and certify the qualifications of persons who may serve as certified interpreters, when the Director considers certification of interpreters to be merited, for the hearing impaired (whether or not also speech impaired) and persons who speak only or primarily a language other than the English language, in judicial proceedings instituted by the United States. The Director may certify interpreters for any language if the Director determines that there is a need for certified interpreters in that language. Upon the request of the Judicial Conference of the United States for certified interpreters in a language, the Director shall certify interpreters in that language. Upon such a request from the judicial council of a circuit and the approval of the Judicial Conference, the Director shall certify interpreters for that circuit in the language requested. The judicial council of a circuit shall identify and evaluate the needs of the districts within a circuit. The Director shall certify interpreters based on the results of criterion-referenced performance examinations. The Director shall issue regulations to carry out this paragraph within 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Judicial Improvements and Access to Justice Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Only in a case in which no certified interpreter is reasonably available as provided in subsection (d) of this section, including a case in which certification of interpreters is not provided under paragraph (1) in a particular language, may the services of otherwise qualified interpreters be used. The Director shall provide guidelines to the courts for the selection of otherwise qualified interpreters, in order to ensure that the highest standards of accuracy are maintained in all judicial proceedings subject to the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Director shall maintain a current master list of all certified interpreters and otherwise qualified interpreters and shall report periodically on the use and performance of both certified and otherwise qualified interpreters in judicial proceedings instituted by the United States and on the languages for which interpreters have been certified. The Director shall prescribe, subject to periodic review, a schedule of reasonable fees for services rendered by interpreters, certified or otherwise, used in proceedings instituted by the United States, and in doing so shall consider the prevailing rate of compensation for comparable service in other governmental entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Each United States district court shall maintain on file in the office of the clerk, and each United States attorney shall maintain on file, a list of all persons who have been certified as interpreters by the Director in accordance with subsection (b) of this section. The clerk shall make the list of certified interpreters for judicial proceeding available upon request.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The clerk of the court, or other court employee designated by the chief judge, shall be responsible for securing the services of certified interpreters and otherwise qualified interpreters required for proceedings initiated by the United States, except that the United States attorney is responsible for securing the services of such interpreters for governmental witnesses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The presiding judicial officer, with the assistance of the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, shall utilize the services of the most available certified interpreter, or when no certified interpreter is reasonably available, as determined by the presiding judicial officer, the services of an otherwise qualified interpreter, in judicial proceedings instituted by the United States, if the presiding judicial officer determines on such officer’s own motion or on the motion of a party that such party (including a defendant in a criminal case), or a witness who may present testimony in such judicial proceedings—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> speaks only or primarily a language other than the English language; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> suffers from a hearing impairment (whether or not suffering also from a speech impairment)</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">so as to inhibit such party’s comprehension of the proceedings or communication with counsel or the presiding judicial officer, or so as to inhibit such witness’ comprehension of questions and the presentation of such testimony.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon the motion of a party, the presiding judicial officer shall determine whether to require the electronic sound recording of a judicial proceeding in which an interpreter is used under this section. In making this determination, the presiding judicial officer shall consider, among other things, the qualifications of the interpreter and prior experience in interpretation of court proceedings; whether the language to be interpreted is not one of the languages for which the Director has certified interpreters, and the complexity or length of the proceeding. In a grand jury proceeding, upon the motion of the accused, the presiding judicial officer shall require the electronic sound recording of the portion of the proceeding in which an interpreter is used.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If any interpreter is unable to communicate effectively with the presiding judicial officer, the United States attorney, a party (including a defendant in a criminal case), or a witness, the presiding judicial officer shall dismiss such interpreter and obtain the services of another interpreter in accordance with this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> In any judicial proceedings instituted by the United States, if the presiding judicial officer does not appoint an interpreter under subsection (d) of this section, an individual requiring the services of an interpreter may seek assistance of the clerk of court or the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts in obtaining the assistance of a certified interpreter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any individual other than a witness who is entitled to interpretation under subsection (d) of this section may waive such interpretation in whole or in part. Such a waiver shall be effective only if approved by the presiding judicial officer and made expressly by such individual on the record after opportunity to consult with counsel and after the presiding judicial officer has explained to such individual, utilizing the services of the most available certified interpreter, or when no certified interpreter is reasonably available, as determined by the presiding judicial officer, the services of an otherwise competent interpreter, the nature and effect of the waiver.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An individual who waives under paragraph (1) of this subsection the right to an interpreter may utilize the services of a noncertified interpreter of such individual’s choice whose fees, expenses, and costs shall be paid in the manner provided for the payment of such fees, expenses, and costs of an interpreter appointed under subsection (d) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated to the Federal judiciary, and to be paid by the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, such sums as may be necessary to establish a program to facilitate the use of certified and otherwise qualified interpreters, and otherwise fulfill the provisions of this section and the Judicial Improvements and Access to Justice Act, except as provided in paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Implementation of the provisions of this section is contingent upon the availability of appropriated funds to carry out the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Such salaries, fees, expenses, and costs that are incurred with respect to Government witnesses (including for grand jury proceedings) shall, unless direction is made under paragraph (4), be paid by the Attorney General from sums appropriated to the Department of Justice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Upon the request of any person in any action for which interpreting services established pursuant to subsection (d) are not otherwise provided, the clerk of the court, or other court employee designated by the chief judge, upon the request of the presiding judicial officer, shall, where possible, make such services available to that person on a cost-reimbursable basis, but the judicial officer may also require the prepayment of the estimated expenses of providing such services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> If the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts finds it necessary to develop and administer criterion-referenced performance examinations for purposes of certification, or other examinations for the selection of otherwise qualified interpreters, the Director may prescribe for each examination a uniform fee for applicants to take such examination. In determining the rate of the fee for each examination, the Director shall consider the fees charged by other organizations for examinations that are similar in scope or nature. Notwithstanding <ref>section 3302(b) of title 31</ref>, the Director is authorized to provide in any contract or agreement for the development or administration of examinations and the collection of fees that the contractor may retain all or a portion of the fees in payment for the services. Notwithstanding paragraph (6) of this subsection, all fees collected after the effective date of this paragraph and not retained by a contractor shall be deposited in the fund established under <ref>section 1931 of this title</ref> and shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Any moneys collected under this subsection may be used to reimburse the appropriations obligated and disbursed in payment for such services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The presiding judicial officer shall approve the compensation and expenses payable to interpreters, pursuant to the schedule of fees prescribed by the Director under subsection (b)(3).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The term “presiding judicial officer” as used in this section refers to any judge of a United States district court, including a bankruptcy judge, a United States magistrate judge, and in the case of grand jury proceedings conducted under the auspices of the United States attorney, a United States attorney.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> The term “judicial proceedings instituted by the United States” as used in this section refers to all proceedings, whether criminal or civil, including pretrial and grand jury proceedings (as well as proceedings upon a petition for a writ of habeas corpus initiated in the name of the United States by a relator) conducted in, or pursuant to the lawful authority and jurisdiction of a United States district court. The term “United States district court” as used in this subsection includes any court which is created by an Act of Congress in a territory and is invested with any jurisdiction of a district court established by chapter 5 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> The interpretation provided by certified or otherwise qualified interpreters pursuant to this section shall be in the simultaneous mode for any party to a judicial proceeding instituted by the United States and in the consecutive mode for witnesses, except that the presiding judicial officer, sua sponte or on the motion of a party, may authorize a simultaneous, or consecutive interpretation when such officer determines after a hearing on the record that such interpretation will aid in the efficient administration of justice. The presiding judicial officer, on such officer’s motion or on the motion of a party, may order that special interpretation services as authorized in <ref>section 1828 of this title</ref> be provided if such officer determines that the provision of such services will aid in the efficient administration of justice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section or section 1828, the presiding judicial officer may appoint a certified or otherwise qualified sign language interpreter to provide services to a party, witness, or other participant in a judicial proceeding, whether or not the proceeding is instituted by the United States, if the presiding judicial officer determines, on such officer’s own motion or on the motion of a party or other participant in the proceeding, that such individual suffers from a hearing impairment. The presiding judicial officer shall, subject to the availability of appropriated funds, approve the compensation and expenses payable to sign language interpreters appointed under this section in accordance with the schedule of fees prescribed by the Director under subsection (b)(3) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–539, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-28">Oct. 28, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2040</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title VII</ref>, §§ 702–710, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4654–4657</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–317, title III, § 306</ref>, title IV, § 402(a), <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3852</ref>, 3854.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1828.</num>
<heading> Special interpretation services</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall establish a program for the provision of special interpretation services in criminal actions and in civil actions initiated by the United States (including petitions for writs of habeas corpus initiated in the name of the United States by relators) in a United States district court. The program shall provide a capacity for simultaneous interpretation services in multidefendant criminal actions and multidefendant civil actions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Upon the request of any person in any action for which special interpretation services established pursuant to subsection (a) are not otherwise provided, the Director, with the approval of the presiding judicial officer, may make such services available to the person requesting the services on a reimbursable basis at rates established in conformity with <ref>section 9701 of title 31</ref>, but the Director may require the prepayment of the estimated expenses of providing the services by the person requesting them.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the expenses incident to providing services under subsection (a) of this section shall be paid by the Director from sums appropriated to the Federal judiciary. A presiding judicial officer, in such officer’s discretion, may order that all or part of the expenses shall be apportioned between or among the parties or shall be taxed as costs in a civil action, and any moneys collected as a result of such order may be used to reimburse the appropriations obligated and disbursed in payment for such services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Appropriations available to the Director shall be available to provide services in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, and moneys collected by the Director under that subsection may be used to reimburse the appropriations charged for such services. A presiding judicial officer, in such officer’s discretion, may order that all or part of the expenses shall be apportioned between or among the parties or shall be taxed as costs in the action.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–539, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-28">Oct. 28, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2042</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(g)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1065</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>