<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 7—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES COURT OF FEDERAL CLAIMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 171.</num>
<heading> Appointment and number of judges; character of court; designation of chief judge</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President shall appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, sixteen judges who shall constitute a court of record known as the United States Court of Federal Claims. The court is declared to be a court established under article I of the Constitution of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The President shall designate one of the judges of the Court of Federal Claims who is less than seventy years of age to serve as chief judge. The chief judge may continue to serve as such until he reaches the age of seventy years or until another judge is designated as chief judge by the President. After the designation of another judge to serve as chief judge, the former chief judge may continue to serve as a judge of the court for the balance of the term to which appointed.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, 62 Stat 898; <ref>July 28, 1953, ch. 253, § 1</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 226</ref>; <ref>Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 39(a)</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1240</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–425, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-05-11">May 11, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 140</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 172.</num>
<heading> Tenure and salaries of judges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims shall be appointed for a term of fifteen years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each judge shall receive a salary at the rate of pay, and in the same manner, as judges of the district courts of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 898</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title X, § 1023</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4673</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 173.</num>
<heading> Times and places of holding court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The principal office of the United States Court of Federal Claims shall be in the District of Columbia, but the Court of Federal Claims may hold court at such times and in such places as it may fix by rule of court. The times and places of the sessions of the Court of Federal Claims shall be prescribed with a view to securing reasonable opportunity to citizens to appear before the Court of Federal Claims with as little inconvenience and expense to citizens as is practicable.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 898</ref>; <ref>Mar. 2, 1955, ch. 9, § 1(d)</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 10</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–426, title IV, § 403(d)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–82, title II, § 205(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 422</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 174.</num>
<heading> Assignment of judges; decisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The judicial power of the United States Court of Federal Claims with respect to any action, suit, or proceeding, except congressional reference cases, shall be exercised by a single judge, who may preside alone and hold a regular or special session of court at the same time other sessions are held by other judges.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> All decisions of the Court of Federal Claims shall be preserved and open to inspection.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 898</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 175.</num>
<heading> Official duty station; residence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The official duty station of each judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims is the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> After appointment and while in active service, each judge shall reside within fifty miles of the District of Columbia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Retired judges of the Court of Federal Claims are not subject to restrictions as to residence. The place where a retired judge maintains the actual abode in which such judge customarily lives shall be deemed to be the judge’s official duty station for the purposes of <ref>section 456 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–425, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-05-11">May 11, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 140</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–518, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2419</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 176.</num>
<heading> Removal from office</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Removal of a judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims during the term for which he is appointed shall be only for incompetency, misconduct, neglect of duty, engaging in the practice of law, or physical or mental disability. Removal shall be by the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, but removal may not occur unless a majority of all the judges of such court of appeals concur in the order of removal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Before any order of removal may be entered, a full specification of the charges shall be furnished to the judge involved, and such judge shall be accorded an opportunity to be heard on the charges.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Any cause for removal of any judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims coming to the knowledge of the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall be reported by him to the chief judge of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, and a copy of the report shall at the same time be transmitted to the judge.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 28</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 177.</num>
<heading> Disbarment of removed judges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims removed from office in accordance with <ref>section 176 of this title</ref> shall not be permitted at any time to practice before the Court of Federal Claims.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 28</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 178.</num>
<heading> Retirement of judges of the Court of Federal Claims</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims who retires from office after attaining the age and meeting the service requirements, whether continuously or otherwise, of this subsection shall, subject to subsection (f), be entitled to receive, during the remainder of the judge’s lifetime, an annuity equal to the salary payable to Court of Federal Claims judges in regular active service. The age and service requirements for retirement under this subsection are as follows:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p><b>Attained Age:</b></p></th><th><p><b>Years of Service:</b></p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>65</span></p></td><td><p>15  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>66</span></p></td><td><p>14  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>67</span></p></td><td><p>13  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>68</span></p></td><td><p>12  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>69</span></p></td><td><p>11  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>70</span></p></td><td><p>10.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A judge of the Court of Federal Claims who is not reappointed following the expiration of the term of office of such judge, and who retires upon the completion of such term shall, subject to subsection (f), be entitled to receive, during the remainder of such judge’s lifetime, an annuity equal to the salary payable to Court of Federal Claims judges in regular active service, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such judge has served at least 1 full term as judge of the Court of Federal Claims, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not earlier than 9 months before the date on which the term of office of such judge expired, and not later than 6 months before such date, such judge advised the President in writing that such judge was willing to accept reappointment as a judge of the Court of Federal Claims.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A judge of the Court of Federal Claims who has served at least 5 years, whether continuously or otherwise, as such a judge, and who retires or is removed from office upon the sole ground of mental or physical disability shall, subject to subsection (f), be entitled to receive, during the remainder of the judge’s lifetime—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an annuity equal to 50 percent of the salary payable to Court of Federal Claims judges in regular active service, if before retirement such judge served less than 10 years, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an annuity equal to the salary payable to Court of Federal Claims judges in regular active service, if before retirement such judge served at least 10 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> A judge who retires under subsection (a) or (b) may, at or after such retirement, be called upon by the chief judge of the Court of Federal Claims to perform such judicial duties with the Court of Federal Claims as may be requested of the retired judge for any period or periods specified by the chief judge, except that in the case of any such judge—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the aggregate of such periods in any one calendar year shall not (without his or her consent) exceed 90 calendar days; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> he or she shall be relieved of performing such duties during any period in which illness or disability precludes the performance of such duties.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any act, or failure to act, by an individual performing judicial duties pursuant to this subsection shall have the same force and effect as if it were the act (or failure to act) of a Court of Federal Claims judge in regular active service. Any individual performing judicial duties pursuant to this subsection shall receive the allowances for official travel and other expenses of a judge in regular active service.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any judge who retires under the provisions of subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall be designated “senior judge”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any judge who retires under this section shall not be counted as a judge of the Court of Federal Claims for purposes of the number of judgeships authorized by <ref>section 171 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> A judge shall be entitled to an annuity under this section if the judge elects an annuity under this section by notifying the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts in writing. Such an election—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may be made only while an individual is a judge of the Court of Federal Claims (except that in the case of an individual who fails to be reappointed as judge at the expiration of a term of office, such election may be made at any time before the day after the day on which his or her successor takes office); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> once made, shall, subject to subsection (k), be irrevocable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A judge who elects to receive an annuity under this section shall not be entitled to receive—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any annuity to which such judge would otherwise have been entitled under subchapter III of chapter 83, or under chapter 84 (except for subchapters III and VII), of title 5, for service performed as a judge or otherwise;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an annuity or salary in senior status or retirement under section 371 or 372 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> retired pay under section 7447 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> retired pay under <ref>section 7296 of title 38</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<content> For purposes of calculating the years of service of an individual under subsections (a) and (c), only those years of service as a judge of the Court of Federal Claims or a commissioner of the United States Court of Claims shall be credited, and that portion of the aggregate number of years of such service that is a fractional part of 1 year shall not be credited if it is less than 6 months, and shall be credited if it is 6 months or more.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> An annuity under this section shall be payable at the times and in the same manner as the salary of a Court of Federal Claims judge in regular active service. Such annuity shall begin to accrue on the day following the day on which the annuitant’s salary as a judge in regular active service ceases to accrue.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Payments under this section which would otherwise be made to a judge of the Court of Federal Claims based upon his or her service shall be paid (in whole or in part) by the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts to another person if and to the extent expressly provided for in the terms of any court decree of divorce, annulment, or legal separation, or the terms of any court order or court-approved property settlement agreement incident to any court decree of divorce, annulment, or legal separation. Any payment under this paragraph to a person bars recovery by any other person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Paragraph (1) shall apply only to payments made by the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts after the date of receipt by the Director of written notice of such decree, order, or agreement, and such additional information as the Director may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> As used in this subsection, the term “court” means any court of any State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands, and any Indian tribal court or court of Indian offense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (4), any judge of the Court of Federal Claims who retires under this section and who thereafter in the practice of law represents (or supervises or directs the representation of) a client in making any civil claim against the United States or any agency thereof shall forfeit all rights to an annuity under this section for all periods beginning on or after the first day on which he engages in any such activity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (4), if a judge of the Court of Federal Claims who retires under this section fails during any calendar year to perform judicial duties required of such judge by subsection (d), such judge shall forfeit all rights to an annuity under this section for the 1-year period which begins on the first day on which he or she so fails to perform such duties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If a judge of the Court of Federal Claims who retires under this section accepts compensation for civil office or employment under the Government of the United States (other than for the performance of judicial duties under subsection (d)), such judge shall forfeit all rights to an annuity under this section for the period for which such compensation is received.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> If a judge makes an election under this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> paragraphs (1) and (2) (and subsection (d)) shall not apply to such judge beginning on the date such election takes effect, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the annuity payable under this section to such judge, for periods beginning on or after the date such election takes effect, shall be equal to the annuity to which such judge is entitled on the day before such effective date.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> An election under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> may be made by a judge only if such judge meets the age and service requirements for retirement under subsection (a),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may be made only during the period during which such judge may make an election to receive an annuity under this section or while the judge is receiving an annuity under this section, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> shall be filed with the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such an election, once it takes effect, shall be irrevocable.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any election under this paragraph shall take effect on the first day of the first month following the month in which the election is made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding subsection (f)(1)(B), an individual who has filed an election under subsection (f) to receive an annuity may revoke such election at any time before the first day on which such annuity would (but for such revocation) begin to accrue with respect to such individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any revocation under this subsection shall be made by filing a notice thereof in writing with the Director of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">1</ref> Administrative Office of the United States Courts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of any revocation under this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for purposes of this section, the individual shall be treated as not having filed an election under subsection (f) to receive an annuity,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for purposes of <ref>section 376 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the individual shall be treated as not having filed an election under section 376(a)(1), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> section 376(g) shall not apply, and the amount credited to such individual’s account (together with interest at 3 percent per annum, compounded on December 31 of each year to the date on which the revocation is filed) shall be returned to such individual,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> no credit shall be allowed for any service as a judge of the Court of Federal Claims or as a commissioner of the United States Court of Claims unless with respect to such service either there has been deducted and withheld the amount required by chapter 83 or 84 (as the case may be) of title 5 or there has been deposited in the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund an amount equal to the amount so required, with interest,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Court of Federal Claims shall deposit in the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund an amount equal to the additional amount it would have contributed to such Fund but for the election under subsection (f), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> if subparagraph (D) is complied with, service on the Court of Federal Claims or as a commissioner of the United States Court of Claims shall be treated as service with respect to which deductions and contributions had been made during the period of service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There is established in the Treasury a fund which shall be known as the “Court of Federal Claims Judges Retirement Fund”. The Fund is appropriated for the payment of annuities and other payments under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest, in interest bearing securities of the United States, such currently available portions of the Court of Federal Claims Judges Retirement Fund as are not immediately required for payments from the Fund. The income derived from these investments constitutes a part of the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated to the Court of Federal Claims Judges Retirement Fund amounts required to reduce to zero the unfunded liability of the Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “unfunded liability” means the estimated excess, determined on an annual basis in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 9503 of title 31</ref>, of the present value of all benefits payable from the Court of Federal Claims Judges Retirement Fund, over the balance in the Fund as of the date the unfunded liability is determined. In making any determination under this subparagraph, the Comptroller General shall use the applicable information contained in the reports filed pursuant to <ref>section 9503 of title 31</ref>, with respect to the retirement annuities provided for in this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 306(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5105</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–198, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-09">Dec. 9, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1624</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 179.</num>
<heading> Personnel application and insurance programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> For purposes of construing and applying title 5, a judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims shall be deemed to be an “officer” under section 2104(a) of such title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of construing and applying chapter 89 of title 5, a judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is retired under subsection (b) of <ref>section 178 of this title</ref>, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> at the time of becoming such a retired judge—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> was enrolled in a health benefits plan under chapter 89 of title 5, but</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> did not satisfy the requirements of <ref>section 8905(b)(1) of title 5</ref> (relating to eligibility to continue enrollment as an annuitant),</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be deemed to be an annuitant meeting the requirements of <ref>section 8905(b)(1) of title 5</ref>, in accordance with the succeeding provisions of this paragraph, if the judge gives timely written notification to the chief judge of the court that the judge is willing to be called upon to perform judicial duties under <ref>section 178(d) of this title</ref> during the period of continued eligibility for enrollment, as described in subparagraph (B)(ii) or (C)(ii) (whichever applies).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (C)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in order to be eligible for continued enrollment under this paragraph, notification under subparagraph (A) shall be made before the first day of the open enrollment period preceding the calendar year referred to in clause (ii)(II); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> if such notification is timely made, the retired judge shall be eligible for continued enrollment under this paragraph for the period—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> beginning on the date on which eligibility would otherwise cease, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> ending on the last day of the calendar year next beginning after the end of the open enrollment period referred to in clause (i).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of applying this paragraph for the first time in the case of any particular judge—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> subparagraph (B)(i) shall be applied by substituting “the expiration of the term of office of the judge” for the matter following “before”; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> if the term of office of such judge expires before the first day of the open enrollment period referred to in subparagraph (B)(i), the period of continued eligibility for enrollment shall be as described in subparagraph (B)(ii); but</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent1">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> if the term of office of such judge expires on or after the first day of the open enrollment period referred to in subparagraph (B)(i), the period of continued eligibility shall not end until the last day of the calendar year next beginning after the end of the next full open enrollment period beginning after the date on which the term expires.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In the event that a retired judge remains enrolled under chapter 89 of title 5 for a period of 5 consecutive years by virtue of paragraph (1) (taking into account only periods of coverage as an active judge immediately before retirement and as a retired judge pursuant to paragraph (1)), then, effective as of the day following the last day of that 5-year period—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the provisions of chapter 89 of title 5 shall be applied as if such judge had satisfied the requirements of section 8905(b)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002010">1</ref> on the last day of such period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the provisions of paragraph (1) shall cease to apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “open enrollment period” refers to a period described in <ref>section 8905(g)(1) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> For purposes of construing and applying chapter 87 of title 5, including any adjustment of insurance rates by regulation or otherwise, a judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims in regular active service or who is retired under <ref>section 178 of this title</ref> shall be deemed to be a judge of the United States described under <ref>section 8701(a)(5) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–518, title III, § 309(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2419</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 180.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title VI, § 654(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–165]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>