<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 113—</num>
<heading>PROCESS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1691.</num>
<heading> Seal and teste of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All writs and process issuing from a court of the United States shall be under the seal of the court and signed by the clerk thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1692.</num>
<heading> Process and orders affecting property in different districts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In proceedings in a district court where a receiver is appointed for property, real, personal, or mixed, situated in different districts, process may issue and be executed in any such district as if the property lay wholly within one district, but orders affecting the property shall be entered of record in each of such districts.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1693.</num>
<heading> Place of arrest in civil action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided by Act of Congress, no person shall be arrested in one district for trial in another in any civil action in a district court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1694.</num>
<heading> Patent infringement action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In a patent infringement action commenced in a district where the defendant is not a resident but has a regular and established place of business, service of process, summons or subpoena upon such defendant may be made upon his agent or agents conducting such business.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1695.</num>
<heading> Stockholder’s derivative action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Process in a stockholder’s action in behalf of his corporation may be served upon such corporation in any district where it is organized or licensed to do business or is doing business.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1696.</num>
<heading> Service in foreign and international litigation</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The district court of the district in which a person resides or is found may order service upon him of any document issued in connection with a proceeding in a foreign or international tribunal. The order may be made pursuant to a letter rogatory issued, or request made, by a foreign or international tribunal or upon application of any interested person and shall direct the manner of service. Service pursuant to this subsection does not, of itself, require the recognition or enforcement in the United States of a judgment, decree, or order rendered by a foreign or international tribunal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> This section does not preclude service of such a document without an order of court.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 88–619, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-03">Oct. 3, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1697.</num>
<heading> Service in multiparty, multiforum actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the jurisdiction of the district court is based in whole or in part upon <ref>section 1369 of this title</ref>, process, other than subpoenas, may be served at any place within the United States, or anywhere outside the United States if otherwise permitted by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11020(b)(4)(A)(i)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1828</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>