<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 5—</num>
<heading>DISTRICT COURTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 81.</num>
<heading> Alabama</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Alabama is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Northern, Middle, and Southern Districts of Alabama.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises five divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Northwestern Division comprises the counties of Colbert, Franklin, Lauderdale, and Lawrence.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northwestern Division shall be held at Florence.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Northeastern Division comprises the counties of Cullman, Jackson, Limestone, Madison, Marshall, and Morgan.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northeastern Division shall be held at Huntsville.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Blount, Jefferson, and Shelby.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Birmingham.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Calhoun, Cherokee, Clay, Cleburne, DeKalb, Etowah, Saint Clair, and Talladega.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Anniston.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(5) The Western Division comprises the counties of Bibb, Fayette, Greene, Lamar, Marion, Pickens, Sumter, Tuscaloosa, Walker, and Winston.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Tuscaloosa.</p>
<p class="centered">Middle District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Middle District comprises three divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Autauga, Barbour, Bullock, Butler, Chilton, Coosa, Covington, Crenshaw, Elmore, Lowndes, Montgomery, and Pike.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Montgomery.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Coffee, Dale, Geneva, Henry, and Houston.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Dothan.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Chambers, Lee, Macon, Randolph, Russell, and Tallapoosa.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Opelika.</p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) The Southern District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Dallas, Hale, Marengo, Perry, and Wilcox.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Selma.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Baldwin, Choctaw, Clarke, Conecuh, Escambia, Mobile, Monroe, and Washington.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Mobile.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 873</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–36, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–179, § 1</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 81A.</num>
<heading> Alaska</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Alaska constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Anchorage, Fairbanks, Juneau, Ketchikan, and Nome.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–508, § 12(b)</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 348</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 86–70, § 23(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 82.</num>
<heading> Arizona</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Arizona constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Flagstaff, Globe, Phoenix, Prescott, Tucson, and Yuma.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–40, § 1</ref>, <date date="2019-08-09">Aug. 9, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1063</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 83.</num>
<heading> Arkansas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Arkansas is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Eastern and Western Districts of Arkansas.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises three divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Central Division comprises the counties of Cleburne, Cleveland, Conway, Dallas, Drew, Faulkner, Grant, Jefferson, Lincoln, Lonoke, Perry, Pope, Prairie, Pulaski, Saline, Stone, Van Buren, White, and Yell.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Central Division shall be held at Little Rock.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Delta Division comprises the counties of Arkansas, Chicot, Crittenden, Desha, Lee, Monroe, Phillips, and St. Francis.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Delta Division shall be held at Helena.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Clay, Craighead, Cross, Fulton, Greene, Independence, Izard, Jackson, Lawrence, Mississippi, Poinsett, Randolph, Sharp, and Woodruff.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Jonesboro.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Western District comprises six divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Texarkana Division comprises the counties of Hempstead, Howard, Lafayette, Little River, Miller, Nevada, and Sevier.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Texarkana Division shall be held at Texarkana, and may be held anywhere within the Federal courthouse in Texarkana that is located astride the State line between Texas and Arkansas.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The El Dorado Division comprises the counties of Ashley, Bradley, Calhoun, Columbia, Ouachita, and Union.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the El Dorado Division shall be held at El Dorado.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Fort Smith Division comprises the counties of Crawford, Franklin, Johnson, Logan, Polk, Scott, and Sebastian.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Fort Smith Division shall be held at Fort Smith.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Harrison Division comprises the counties of Baxter, Boone, Carroll, Marion, Newton, and Searcy.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Harrison Division shall be held at Harrison.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(5) The Fayetteville Division comprises the counties of Benton, Madison, and Washington.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Fayetteville Division shall be held at Fayetteville.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(6) The Hot Springs Division comprises the counties of Clark, Garland, Hot Springs, Montgomery, and Pike.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Hot Springs Division shall be held at Hot Springs.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–36, § 5</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 84</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–455, § 3</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–73, § 2</ref>, <date date="2019-11-26">Nov. 26, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1154</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 84.</num>
<heading> California</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">California is divided into four judicial districts to be known as the Northern, Eastern, Central, and Southern Districts of California.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises the counties of Alameda, Contra Costa, Del Norte, Humboldt, Lake, Marin, Mendocino, Monterey, Napa, San Benito, Santa Clara, Santa Cruz, San Francisco, San Mateo, and Sonoma.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern District shall be held at Eureka, Oakland, San Francisco, and San Jose.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Eastern District comprises the counties of Alpine, Amador, Butte, Calaveras, Colusa, El Dorado, Fresno, Glenn, Inyo, Kern, Kings, Lassen, Madera, Mariposa, Merced, Modoc, Mono, Nevada, Placer, Plumas, Sacramento, San Joaquin, Shasta, Sierra, Siskiyou, Solano, Stanislaus, Sutter, Tehama, Trinity, Tulare, Tuolumne, Yolo, and Yuba.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at Bakersfield, Fresno, Redding, and Sacramento.</p>
<p class="centered">Central District</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) The Central District comprises 3 divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Riverside and San Bernardino.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at a suitable site in the city of Riverside, the city of San Bernardino, or not more than 5 miles from the boundary of either such city.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Western Division comprises the counties of Los Angeles, San Luis Obispo, Santa Barbara, and Ventura.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Los Angeles.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Southern Division comprises Orange County.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Santa Ana.</p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(d) The Southern District comprises the counties of Imperial and San Diego.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern District shall be held at San Diego.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 875</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–372, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-03-18">Mar. 18, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 75</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–462, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-10-15">Oct. 15, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2053</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–357, § 2</ref>, <date date="1992-08-26">Aug. 26, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 958</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. E, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2352</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 85.</num>
<heading> Colorado</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Colorado constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Boulder, Colorado Springs, Denver, Durango, Grand Junction, Montrose, Pueblo, and Sterling.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 875</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 409</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3362</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–455, § 5</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3629</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–482, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3918</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 86.</num>
<heading> Connecticut</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Connecticut constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Bridgeport, Hartford, New Haven, New London, and Waterbury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 875</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–36, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–558</ref>, <date date="1966-09-07">Sept. 7, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 705</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 87.</num>
<heading> Delaware</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Delaware constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Wilmington.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 875</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 88.</num>
<heading> District of Columbia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The District of Columbia constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Washington.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 875</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 89.</num>
<heading> Florida</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Florida is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Northern, Middle, and Southern Districts of Florida.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises the counties of Alachua, Bay, Calhoun, Dixie, Escambia, Franklin, Gadsden, Gilchrist, Gulf, Holmes, Jackson, Jefferson, Lafayette, Leon, Levy, Liberty, Madison, Okaloosa, Santa Rosa, Taylor, Wakulla, Walton, and Washington.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern District shall be held at Gainesville, Marianna, Panama City, Pensacola, and Tallahassee.</p>
<p class="centered">Middle District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Middle District comprises the counties of Baker, Bradford, Brevard, Charlotte, Citrus, Clay, Collier, Columbia, De Soto, Duval, Flagler, Glades, Hamilton, Hardee, Hendry, Hernando, Hillsborough, Lake, Lee, Manatee, Marion, Nassau, Orange, Osceola, Pasco, Pinellas, Polk, Putnam, St. Johns, Sarasota, Seminole, Sumter, Suwannee, Union, and Volusia.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Middle District shall be held at Fernandina, Fort Myers, Jacksonville, Live Oak, Ocala, Orlando, Saint Petersburg, and Tampa.</p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) The Southern District comprises the counties of Broward, Dade, Highlands, Indian River, Martin, Monroe, Okeechobee, Palm Beach, and St. Lucie.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern District shall be held at Fort Lauderdale, Fort Pierce, Key West, Miami, and West Palm Beach.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 876</ref>; <ref>July 17, 1952, ch. 929</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 757</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–36, § 3(f)</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–562, § 1</ref>, <date date="1962-07-30">July 30, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 247</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–272, § 10</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–408, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-02">Oct. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 884</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title X, § 1021(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4672</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 90.</num>
<heading> Georgia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Georgia is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Northern, Middle, and Southern Districts of Georgia.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises four divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Gainesville Division comprises the counties of Banks, Barrow, Dawson, Fannin, Forsyth, Gilmer, Habersham, Hall, Jackson, Lumpkin, Pickens, Rabun, Stephens, Towns, Union, and White.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Gainesville Division shall be held at Gainesville.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Atlanta Division comprises the counties of Cherokee, Clayton, Cobb, De Kalb, Douglas, Fulton, Gwinnett, Henry, Newton, and Rockdale.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Atlanta Division shall be held at Atlanta.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Rome Division comprises the counties of Bartow, Catoosa, Chattooga, Dade, Floyd, Gordon, Murray, Paulding, Polk, Walker, and Whitfield.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Rome Division shall be held at Rome.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Newnan Division comprises the counties of Carroll, Coweta, Fayette, Haralson, Heard, Meriwether, Pike, Spalding, and Troup.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Newnan Division shall be held at Newnan.</p>
<p class="centered">Middle District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Middle District comprises seven divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Athens Division comprises the counties of Clarke, Elbert, Franklin, Greene, Hart, Madison, Morgan, Oconee, Oglethorpe, and Walton.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Athens Division shall be held at Athens.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Macon Division comprises the counties of Baldwin, Bibb, Bleckley, Butts, Crawford, Hancock, Houston, Jasper, Jones, Lamar, Monroe, Peach, Pulaski, Putnam, Twiggs, Upson, Washington, and Wilkinson.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Macon Division shall be held at Macon.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Columbus Division comprises the counties of Chattahoochee, Clay, Harris, Marion, Muscogee, Quitman, Randolph, Stewart, Talbot, and Taylor.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Columbus Division shall be held at Columbus.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Americus Division comprises the counties of Ben Hill, Crisp, Dooly, Lee, Macon, Schley, Sumter, Terrell, Webster, and Wilcox.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Americus Division shall be held at Americus.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(5) The Albany Division comprises the counties of Baker, Calhoun, Dougherty, Early, Miller, Mitchell, Turner, and Worth.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Albany Division shall be held at Albany.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(6) The Valdosta Division comprises the counties of Berrien, Clinch, Cook, Echols, Irwin, Lanier, Lowndes, and Tift.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Valdosta Division shall be held at Valdosta.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(7) The Thomasville Division comprises the counties of Brooks, Colquitt, Decatur, Grady, Seminole, and Thomas.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Thomasville Division shall be held at Thomasville.</p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) The Southern District comprises six divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Augusta Division comprises the Counties of Burke, Columbia, Glascock, Jefferson, Lincoln, McDuffie, Richmond, Taliaferro, Warren, and Wilkes.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Augusta Division shall be held at Augusta.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Dublin Division comprises the counties of Dodge, Johnson, Laurens, Montgomery, Telfair, Treutlen, and Wheeler.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Dublin Division shall be held at Dublin.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Savannah Division comprises the counties of Bryan, Chatham, Effingham, and Liberty.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Savannah Division shall be held at Savannah.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Waycross Division comprises the counties of Atkinson, Bacon, Brantley, Charlton, Coffee, Pierce, and Ware.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Waycross Division shall be held at Waycross.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(5) The Brunswick Division comprises the counties of Appling, Camden, Glynn, Jeff Davis, Long, McIntosh, and Wayne.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Brunswick Division shall be held at Brunswick.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(6) The Statesboro Division comprises the counties of Bulloch, Candler, Emanuel, Evans, Jenkins, Screven, Tattnall, and Toombs.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Statesboro Division shall be held at Statesboro.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 876</ref>; <ref>Aug. 16, 1949, ch. 444</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 610</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 36a</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 723</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 408(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3362</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–657, § 3</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3670</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 91.</num>
<heading> Hawaii</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Hawaii constitutes one judicial district which includes the Midway Islands, Wake Island, Johnston Island, Sand Island, Kingman Reef, Palmyra Island, Baker Island, Howland Island, Jarvis Island, Canton Island, and Enderbury Island: <i>Provided</i>, That the inclusion of Canton and Enderbury Islands in such judicial district shall in no way be construed to be prejudicial to the claims of the United Kingdom to said Islands in accordance with the agreement of <date date="1939-04-06">April 6, 1939</date>, between the Governments of the United States and of the United Kingdom to set up a regime for their use in common.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Honolulu.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 877</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 64a</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 99</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–3, § 14(i)</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–624, § 19</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 416</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 92.</num>
<heading> Idaho</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Idaho, exclusive of Yellowstone National Park, constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Boise, Coeur d’Alene, Moscow, and Pocatello.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 877</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–272, § 5</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 93.</num>
<heading> Illinois</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Illinois is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Northern, Central, and Southern Districts of Illinois.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Cook, Du Page, Grundy, Kane, Kendall, Lake, La Salle, and Will.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Chicago and Wheaton.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Western Division comprises the counties of Boone, Carroll, De Kalb, Jo Daviess, Lee, McHenry, Ogle, Stephenson, Whiteside, and Winnebago.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Freeport and Rockford.</p>
<p class="centered">Central District</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(b) The Central District comprises the counties of Adams, Brown, Bureau, Cass, Champaign, Christian, Coles, De Witt, Douglas, Edgar, Ford, Fulton, Greene, Hancock, Henderson, Henry, Iroquois, Kankakee, Knox, Livingston, Logan, McDonough, McLean, Macoupin, Macon, Marshall, Mason, Menard, Mercer, Montgomery, Morgan, Moultrie, Peoria, Piatt, Pike, Putnam, Rock Island, Sangamon, Schuyler, Scott, Shelby, Stark, Tazewell, Vermilion, Warren, and Woodford.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Central District shall be held at Champaign/Urbana, Danville, Peoria, Quincy, Rock Island, and Springfield.</p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(c) The Southern District comprises the counties of Alexander, Bond, Calhoun, Clark, Clay, Clinton, Crawford, Cumberland, Edwards, Effingham, Fayette, Franklin, Gallatin, Hamilton, Hardin, Jackson, Jasper, Jefferson, Jersey, Johnson, Lawrence, Madison, Marion, Massac, Monroe, Perry, Pope, Pulaski, Randolph, Richland, St. Clair, Saline, Union, Wabash, Washington, Wayne, White, and Williamson.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern District shall be held at Alton, Benton, Cairo, and East Saint Louis.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 878</ref>; <ref>Aug. 10, 1950, ch. 675, § 1</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–36, § 3(c)</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–272, § 8</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 297</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–408, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-02">Oct. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 884</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–573, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2458</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 406(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3361</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–130, § 2</ref>, <date date="1999-12-06">Dec. 6, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 94.</num>
<heading> Indiana</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Indiana is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Northern and Southern Districts of Indiana.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises three divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Fort Wayne Division comprises the counties of Adams, Allen, Blackford, De Kalb, Grant, Huntington, Jay, Lagrange, Noble, Steuben, Wells, and Whitley.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Fort Wayne Division shall be held at Fort Wayne.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The South Bend Division comprises the counties of Cass, Elkhart, Fulton, Kosciusko, La Porte, Marshall, Miami, Pulaski, St. Joseph, Starke, and Wabash.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the South Bend Division shall be held at South Bend.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Hammond Division comprises the counties of Benton, Carroll, Jasper, Lake, Newton, Porter, Tippecanoe, Warren, and White.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Hammond Division shall be held at Hammond and Lafayette.</p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Southern District comprises four divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Indianapolis Division comprises the counties of Bartholomew, Boone, Brown, Clinton, Decatur, Delaware, Fayette, Fountain, Franklin, Hamilton, Hancock, Hendricks, Henry, Howard, Johnson, Madison, Marion, Monroe, Montgomery, Morgan, Randolph, Rush, Shelby, Tipton, Union, and Wayne.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Indianapolis Division shall be held at Indianapolis and Richmond.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Terre Haute Division comprises the counties of Clay, Greene, Knox, Owen, Parke, Putnam, Sullivan, Vermilion, and Vigo.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Terre Haute Division shall be held at Terre Haute.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Evansville Division comprises the counties of Davies, Dubois, Gibson, Martin, Perry, Pike, Posey, Spencer, Vanderburgh, and Warrick.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Evansville Division shall be held at Evansville.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The New Albany Division comprises the counties of Clark, Crawford, Dearborn, Floyd, Harrison, Jackson, Jefferson, Jennings, Lawrence, Ohio, Orange, Ripley, Scott, Switzerland, and Washington.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the New Albany Division shall be held at New Albany.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 878</ref>; <ref>Feb. 10, 1954, ch. 6, § 2(b)(7)</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–272, § 9</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 298</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 95.</num>
<heading> Iowa</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Iowa is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Northern and Southern Districts of Iowa.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises four divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Cedar Rapids Division comprises the counties of Benton, Cedar, Grundy, Hardin, Iowa, Jones, Linn, and Tama.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Cedar Rapids Division shall be held at Cedar Rapids.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Allamakee, Black Hawk, Bremer, Buchanan, Chickasaw, Clayton, Delaware, Dubuque, Fayette, Floyd, Howard, Jackson, Mitchell, and Winneshiek.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Dubuque and Waterloo.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Western Division comprises the counties of Buena Vista, Cherokee, Clay, Crawford, Dickinson, Ida, Lyon, Monona, O’Brien, Osceola, Plymouth, Sac, Sioux, and Woodbury.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Sioux City.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Central Division comprises the counties of Butler, Calhoun, Carroll, Cerro Gordo, Emmet, Franklin, Hamilton, Hancock, Humboldt, Kossuth, Palo Alto, Pocahontas, Webster, Winnebago, Worth, and Wright.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Central Division shall be held at Fort Dodge and Mason City.</p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Southern District comprises six divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Central Division comprises the counties of Boone, Dallas, Greene, Guthrie, Jasper, Madison, Marion, Marshall, Polk, Poweshiek, Story, and Warren.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Central Division shall be held at Des Moines.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Des Moines, Henry, Lee, Louisa, and Van Buren.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Keokuk.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Western Division comprises the counties of Audubon, Cass, Fremont, Harrison, Mills, Montgomery, Page, Pottawattamie, and Shelby.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Council Bluffs.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Adair, Adams, Clarke, Decatur, Lucas, Ringgold, Taylor, Union, and Wayne.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Creston.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(5) The Davenport Division comprises the counties of Clinton, Johnson, Muscatine, Scott, and Washington.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Davenport Division shall be held at Davenport.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(6) The Ottumwa Division comprises the counties of Appanoose, Davis, Jefferson, Keokuk, Mahaska, Monroe, and Wapello.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Ottumwa Division shall be held at Ottumwa.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 879</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–462, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-15">Oct. 15, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2053</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 96.</num>
<heading> Kansas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Kansas constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Kansas City, Lawrence, Leavenworth, Salina, Topeka, Hutchinson, Wichita, Dodge City, and Fort Scott.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 880</ref>; <ref>Aug. 27, 1949, ch. 516</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 666</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–554, title I, § 141</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 97.</num>
<heading> Kentucky</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Kentucky is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Eastern and Western Districts of Kentucky.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises the counties of Anderson, Bath, Bell, Boone, Bourbon, Boyd, Boyle, Bracken, Breathitt, Campbell, Carroll, Carter, Clark, Clay, Elliott, Estill, Fayette, Fleming, Floyd, Franklin, Gallatin, Garrard, Grant, Greenup, Harlan, Harrison, Henry, Jackson, Jessamine, Johnson, Kenton, Knott, Knox, Laurel, Lawrence, Lee, Leslie, Letcher, Lewis, Lincoln, McCreary, Madison, Magoffin, Martin, Mason, Menifee, Mercer, Montgomery, Morgan, Nicholas, Owen, Owsley, Pendleton, Perry, Pike, Powell, Pulaski, Robertson, Rockcastle, Rowan, Scott, Shelby, Trimble, Wayne, Whitley, Wolfe, and Woodford.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at Ashland, Catlettsburg, Covington, Frankfort, Jackson, Lexington, London, Pikeville, and Richmond.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Western District comprises the counties of Adair, Allen, Ballard, Barren, Breckenridge, Bullitt, Butler, Caldwell, Calloway, Carlisle, Casey, Christian, Clinton, Crittenden, Cumberland, Daviess, Edmonson, Fulton, Graves, Grayson, Green, Hancock, Hardin, Hart, Henderson, Hickman, Hopkins, Jefferson, Larue, Livingston, Logan, Lyon, McCracken, McLean, Marion, Marshall, Meade, Metcalfe, Monroe, Muhlenberg, Nelson, Ohio, Oldham, Russell, Simpson, Spencer, Taylor, Todd, Trigg, Union, Warren, Washington, and Webster.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western District shall be held at Bowling Green, Louisville, Owensboro, and Paducah.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 880</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–408, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-02">Oct. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 883</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 98.</num>
<heading> Louisiana</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Louisiana is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Eastern, Middle, and Western Districts of Louisiana.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises the parishes of Assumption, Jefferson, Lafourche, Orleans, Plaquemines, Saint Bernard, Saint Charles, Saint James, Saint John the Baptist, Saint Tammany, Tangipahoa, Terrebonne, and Washington.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at New Orleans, and Houma.</p>
<p class="centered">Middle District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Middle District comprises the parishes of Ascension, East Baton Rouge, East Feliciana, Iberville, Livingston, Pointe Coupee, Saint Helena, West Baton Rouge, and West Feliciana.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Middle District shall be held at Baton Rouge.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) The Western District comprises the parishes of Acadia, Allen, Avoyelles, Beauregard, Bienville, Bossier, Caddo, Calcasieu, Caldwell, Cameron, Catahoula, Claiborne, Concordia, Jefferson Davis, De Soto, East Carroll, Evangeline, Franklin, Grant, Iberia, Jackson, Lafayette, La Salle, Lincoln, Madison, Morehouse, Natchitoches, Ouachita, Rapides, Red River, Richland, Sabine, Saint Landry, Saint Martin, Saint Mary, Tensas, Union, Vermilion, Vernon, Webster, West Carroll, and Winn.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western District shall be held at Alexandria, Lafayette, Lake Charles, Monroe, Opelousas, and Shreveport.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 881</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–36, § 4</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–208, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–408, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-02">Oct. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 883</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title II, § 203(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 350</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 99.</num>
<heading> Maine</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Maine constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Bangor and Portland.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 881</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–573, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2458</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 100.</num>
<heading> Maryland</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Maryland constitutes one judicial district comprising two divisions.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Northern Division comprises the counties of Allegany, Anne Arundel, Baltimore, Caroline, Carroll, Cecil, Dorchester, Frederick, Garrett, Harford, Howard, Kent, Queen Anne’s, Somerset, Talbot, Washington, Wicomico, and Worcester, and the City of Baltimore.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Baltimore, Cumberland, and Denton.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Southern Division comprises the counties of Calvert, Charles, Montgomery, Prince George’s, and St. Mary’s.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at a suitable site in Montgomery or Prince George’s County not more than five miles from the boundary of Montgomery and Prince George’s Counties.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 882</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–546, § 4</ref>, <date date="1970-12-14">Dec. 14, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–487, § 1</ref>, <date date="1988-10-14">Oct. 14, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 2431</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 101.</num>
<heading> Massachusetts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Massachusetts constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Boston, New Bedford, Springfield, and Worcester.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 882</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 102.</num>
<heading> Michigan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Michigan is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Eastern and Western Districts of Michigan.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Genesee, Jackson, Lapeer, Lenawee, Livingston, Macomb, Monroe, Oakland, Saint Clair, Sanilac, Shiawassee, Washtenaw, and Wayne.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Ann Arbor, Detroit, Flint, and Port Huron.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Alcona, Alpena, Arenac, Bay, Cheboygan, Clare, Crawford, Gladwin, Gratiot, Huron, Iosco, Isabella, Midland, Montmorency, Ogemaw, Oscoda, Otsego, Presque Isle, Roscommon, Saginaw, and Tuscola.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Bay City.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Western District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Allegan, Antrim, Barry, Benzie, Berrien, Branch, Calhoun, Cass, Charlevoix, Clinton, Eaton, Emmet, Grand Traverse, Hillsdale, Ingham, Ionia, Kalamazoo, Kalkaska, Kent, Lake, Leelanau, Manistee, Mason, Mecosta, Missaukee, Montcalm, Muskegon, Newaygo, Oceana, Osceola, Ottawa, Saint Joseph, Van Buren, and Wexford.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Grand Rapids, Kalamazoo, Lansing, and Traverse City.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Alger, Baraga, Chippewa, Delta, Dickinson, Gogebic, Houghton, Iron, Keweenaw, Luce, Mackinac, Marquette, Menominee, Ontonagon, and Schoolcraft.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Marquette and Sault Sainte Marie.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 882</ref>; <ref>Feb. 10, 1954, ch. 6</ref> § 2(b)(8), <ref>68 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–36, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–627</ref>, <date date="1964-10-06">Oct. 6, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1003</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–272, § 11</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 298</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 103.</num>
<heading> Minnesota</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Minnesota constitutes one judicial district comprising six divisions.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The First Division comprises the counties of Dodge, Fillmore, Houston, Mower, Olmsted, Steele, Wabasha, and Winona.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the First Division shall be held at Winona.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Second Division comprises the counties of Blue Earth, Brown, Cottonwood, Faribault, Freeborn, Jackson, Lac qui Parle, Le Sueur, Lincoln, Lyon, Martin, Murray, Nicollet, Nobles, Pipestone, Redwood, Rock, Sibley, Waseca, Watonwan, and Yellow Medicine.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Second Division shall be held at Mankato.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Third Division comprises the counties of Chisago, Dakota, Goodhue, Ramsey, Rice, Scott, and Washington.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Third Division shall be held at Saint Paul.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Fourth Division comprises the counties of Anoka, Carver, Chippewa, Hennepin, Isanti, Kandiyohi, McLeod, Meeker, Renville, Sherburne, Swift, and Wright.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Fourth Division shall be held at Minneapolis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Fifth Division comprises the counties of Aitkin, Benton, Carlton, Cass, Cook, Crow Wing, Itasca, Kanabec, Koochiching, Lake, Mille Lacs, Morrison, Pine, and Saint Louis.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Fifth Division shall be held at Duluth.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Sixth Division comprises the counties of Becker, Beltrami, Big Stone, Clay, Clearwater, Douglas, Grant, Hubbard, Kittson, Lake of the Woods, Mahnomen, Marshall, Norman, Otter Tail, Pennington, Polk, Pope, Red Lake, Roseau, Stearns, Stevens, Todd, Traverse, Wadena, and Wilkin.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Sixth Division shall be held at Fergus Falls and Bemidji.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 882</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–406, § 18</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 104.</num>
<heading> Mississippi</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Mississippi is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the northern and southern districts of Mississippi.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The northern district comprises three divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Aberdeen Division comprises the counties of Alcorn, Chickasaw, Choctaw, Clay, Itawamba, Lee, Lowndes, Monroe, Oktibbeha, Prentiss, Tishomingo, Webster, and Winston.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Aberdeen Division shall be held at Aberdeen, Ackerman, and Corinth.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Oxford Division comprises the counties of Benton, Calhoun, DeSoto, Lafayette, Marshall, Panola, Pontotoc, Quitman, Tallahatchie, Tate, Tippah, Tunica, Union, and Yalobusha.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Oxford Division shall be held at Oxford.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Greenville Division comprises the counties of Attala, Bolivar, Carroll, Coahoma, Grenada, Humphreys, Leflore, Montgomery, Sunflower, and Washington.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Greenville Division shall be held at Clarksdale, Cleveland, and Greenville.</p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The southern district comprises four divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Copiah, Hinds, Holmes, Issaquena, Kemper, Lauderdale, Leake, Madison, Neshoba, Newton, Noxubee, Rankin, Scott, Simpson, Sharkey, Smith, Warren, and Yazoo.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Jackson.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Southern Division comprises the counties of George, Greene, Hancock, Harrison, Jackson, Pearl River, and Stone.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Gulfport.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Clarke, Covington, Forrest, Jasper, Jefferson Davis, Jones, Lamar, Lawrence, Marion, Perry, Wayne, and Walthall.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Hattiesburg.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Western Division comprises the counties of Adams, Amite, Claiborne, Franklin, Jefferson, Lincoln, Pike, and Wilkinson.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Natchez.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 883</ref>; <ref>Aug. 7, 1950, ch. 601</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 415</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–92</ref>, <date date="1967-09-27">Sept. 27, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 229</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–546</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <date date="1970-12-14">Dec. 14, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–408, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-02">Oct. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 883</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–130, § 1</ref>, <date date="1999-12-06">Dec. 6, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1677</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–455, § 2</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–188, § 3</ref>, <date date="2012-10-05">Oct. 5, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–61, § 1</ref>, <date date="2013-12-20">Dec. 20, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 665</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 105.</num>
<heading> Missouri</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Missouri is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Eastern and Western Districts of Missouri.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises three divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Crawford, Dent, Franklin, Gasconade, Jefferson, Lincoln, Maries, Phelps, Saint Charles, Saint Francois, Saint Louis, Warren, and Washington, and the city of Saint Louis.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Saint Louis.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Adair, Audrain, Chariton, Clark, Knox, Lewis, Linn, Macon, Marion, Monroe, Montgomery, Pike, Ralls, Randolph, Schuyler, Scotland, and Shelby.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Hannibal.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Southeastern Division comprises the counties of Bollinger, Butler, Cape Girardeau, Carter, Dunklin, Iron, Madison, Mississippi, New Madrid, Pemiscot, Perry, Reynolds, Ripley, Saint Genevieve, Scott, Shannon, Stoddard, and Wayne.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southeastern Division shall be held at Cape Girardeau.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Western District comprises five divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Western Division comprises the counties of Bates, Carroll, Cass, Clay, Henry, Jackson, Johnson, Lafayette, Ray, Saint Clair, and Saline.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Kansas City.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Southwestern Division comprises the counties of Barton, Barry, Jasper, Lawrence, McDonald, Newton, Stone, and Vernon.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southwestern Division shall be held at Joplin.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Saint Joseph Division comprises the counties of Andrew, Atchison, Buchanan, Caldwell, Clinton, Daviess, De Kalb, Gentry, Grundy, Harrison, Holt, Livingston, Mercer, Nodaway, Platte, Putnam, Sullivan, and Worth.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Saint Joseph Division shall be held at Saint Joseph.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Central Division comprises the counties of Benton, Boone, Callaway, Camden, Cole, Cooper, Hickory, Howard, Miller, Moniteau, Morgan, Osage, and Pettis.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Central Division shall be held at Jefferson City.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(5) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Cedar, Christian, Dade, Dallas, Douglas, Greene, Howell, Laclede, Oregon, Ozark, Polk, Pulaski, Taney, Texas, Webster, and Wright.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Springfield.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 884</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–461</ref>, <date date="1962-05-31">May 31, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 85</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–462, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-15">Oct. 15, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2053</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–188, § 2</ref>, <date date="2012-10-05">Oct. 5, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 106.</num>
<heading> Montana</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Montana, exclusive of Yellowstone National Park, constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Billings, Butte, Glasgow, Great Falls, Havre, Helena, Kalispell, Lewistown, Livingston, Miles City, and Missoula.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 884</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 107.</num>
<heading> Nebraska</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nebraska constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Lincoln, North Platte, and Omaha.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 884</ref>; <ref>Aug. 9, 1955, ch. 627, § 1</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 546</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 108.</num>
<heading> Nevada</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nevada constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Carson City, Elko, Las Vegas, Reno, Ely, and Lovelock.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 885</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 324(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 109.</num>
<heading> New Hampshire</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">New Hampshire constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Concord and Littleton.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 885</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 110.</num>
<heading> New Jersey</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">New Jersey constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Camden, Newark and Trenton.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 885</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 111.</num>
<heading> New Mexico</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">New Mexico constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Albuquerque, Las Cruces, Las Vegas, Roswell, Santa Fe, and Silver City.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 885</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 112.</num>
<heading> New York</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">New York is divided into four judicial districts to be known as the Northern, Southern, Eastern, and Western Districts of New York.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises the counties of Albany, Broome, Cayuga, Chenango, Clinton, Columbia, Cortland, Delaware, Essex, Franklin, Fulton, Greene, Hamilton, Herkimer, Jefferson, Lewis, Madison, Montgomery, Oneida, Onondaga, Oswego, Otsego, Rensselaer, Saint Lawrence, Saratoga, Schenectady, Schoharie, Tioga, Tompkins, Ulster, Warren, and Washington.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern District shall be held at Albany, Auburn, Binghamton, Malone, Plattsburgh,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">1</ref> Syracuse, Utica, Watertown, and Plattsburgh.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">1</ref></p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Southern District comprises the counties of Bronx, Dutchess, New York, Orange, Putnam, Rockland, Sullivan, and Westchester and concurrently with the Eastern District, the waters within the Eastern District.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern District shall be held at New York, White Plains, and in the Middletown-Wallkill area of Orange County or such nearby location as may be deemed appropriate.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) The Eastern District comprises the counties of Kings, Nassau, Queens, Richmond, and Suffolk and concurrently with the Southern District, the waters within the counties of Bronx and New York.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at Brooklyn, Hauppauge, Hempstead (including the village of Uniondale), and Central Islip.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(d) The Western District comprises the counties of Allegany, Cattaraugus, Chautauqua, Chemung, Erie, Genesee, Livingston, Monroe, Niagara, Ontario, Orleans, Schuyler, Seneca, Steuben, Wayne, Wyoming, and Yates.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western District shall be held at Buffalo, Canandaigua, Elmira, Jamestown, and Rochester.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 885</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–217</ref>, <date date="1967-12-18">Dec. 18, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–546, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-12-14">Dec. 14, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–271, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-04-28">Apr. 28, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 221</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–408, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-02">Oct. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 885</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–573, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2458</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3361</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 324(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5120</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–317, title VI, § 609</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3860</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(1) [title III, § 306]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–37; <ref>Pub. L. 108–455, § 4</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–482, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3918</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 113.</num>
<heading> North Carolina</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">North Carolina is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Eastern, Middle, and Western Districts of North Carolina.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises the counties of Beaufort, Bertie, Bladen, Brunswick, Camden, Carteret, Chowan, Columbus, Craven, Cumberland, Currituck, Dare, Duplin, Edgecombe, Franklin, Gates, Granville, Greene, Halifax, Harnett, Hertford, Hyde, Johnston, Jones, Lenoir, Martin, Nash, New Hanover, Northampton, Onslow, Pamlico, Pasquotank, Pender, Perquimans, Pitt, Robeson, Sampson, Tyrrell, Vance, Wake, Warren, Washington, Wayne, Wilson, those portions of Hoke, Moore, Scotland, and Richmond counties encompassing the Fort Bragg Military Reservation and Camp Mackall, and that portion of Durham County encompassing the Federal Correctional Institution, Butner, North Carolina.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at Elizabeth City, Fayetteville, Greenville, New Bern, Raleigh, Wilmington, and Wilson.</p>
<p class="centered">Middle District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) <inline class="small-caps">Middle District</inline>.—The Middle District comprises the counties of Alamance, Cabarrus, Caswell, Chatham, Davidson, Davie, Durham (excluding that portion of Durham County encompassing the Federal Correctional Institution, Butner, North Carolina), Forsyth, Guilford, Hoke (excluding that portion of Hoke County encompassing the Fort Bragg Military Reservation and Camp Mackall), Lee, Montgomery, Moore (excluding that portion of Moore County encompassing the Fort Bragg Military Reservation and Camp Mackall), Orange, Person, Randolph, Richmond (excluding that portion of Richmond County encompassing the Fort Bragg Military Reservation and Camp Mackall), Rockingham, Rowan, Scotland (excluding that portion of Scotland County encompassing the Fort Bragg Military Reservation and Camp Mackall), Stanly, Stokes, Surry, and Yadkin.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Middle District shall be held at Durham, Greensboro, and Winston-Salem.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) The Western District comprises the counties of Alexander, Alleghany, Anson, Ashe, Avery, Buncombe, Burke, Caldwell, Catawba, Cherokee, Clay, Cleveland, Gaston, Graham, Haywood, Henderson, Iredell, Jackson, Lincoln, McDowell, Macon, Madison, Mecklenburg, Mitchell, Polk, Rutherford, Swain, Transylvania, Union, Watauga, Wilkes, and Yancey.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western District shall be held at Asheville, Bryson City, Charlotte, Shelby, and Statesville.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 886</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–319</ref>, <date date="1965-11-02">Nov. 2, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 1186</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–462, § 5(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1980-10-15">Oct. 15, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2053</ref>, 2054; <ref>Pub. L. 102–272</ref>, <date date="1992-04-21">Apr. 21, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 112</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–26, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-07-06">July 6, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 299</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 114.</num>
<heading> North Dakota</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">North Dakota constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent0">Court shall be held at Bismarck, Fargo, Grand Forks, and Minot.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–174, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-05-27">May 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1216</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 115.</num>
<heading> Ohio</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Ohio is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Northern and Southern Districts of Ohio.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Ashland, Ashtabula, Carroll, Columbiana, Crawford, Cuyahoga, Geauga, Holmes, Lake, Lorain, Mahoning, Medina, Portage, Richland, Stark, Summit, Trumbull, Tuscarawas, and Wayne.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Cleveland, Youngstown, and Akron.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Western Division comprises the counties of Allen, Auglaize, Defiance, Erie, Fulton, Hancock, Hardin, Henry, Huron, Lucas, Marion, Mercer, Ottawa, Paulding, Putnam, Sandusky, Seneca, Van Wert, Williams, Woods, and Wyandot.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Lima and Toledo.</p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Southern District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Western Division comprises the counties of Adams, Brown, Butler, Champaign, Clark, Clermont, Clinton, Darke, Greene, Hamilton, Highland, Lawrence, Miami, Montgomery, Preble, Scioto, Shelby, and Warren.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Cincinnati and Dayton.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Athens, Belmont, Coshocton, Delaware, Fairfield, Fayette, Franklin, Gallia, Guernsey, Harrison, Hocking, Jackson, Jefferson, Knox, Licking, Logan, Madison, Meigs, Monroe, Morgan, Morrow, Muskingum, Noble, Perry, Pickaway, Pike, Ross, Union, Vinton, and Washington.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Columbus <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref> St. Clairsville, and Steubenville.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 887</ref>; <ref>Feb. 10, 1954, ch. 6, § 2(b)(9)</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11021</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1829</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 116.</num>
<heading> Oklahoma</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Oklahoma is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Northern, Eastern, and Western Districts of Oklahoma.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises the counties of Craig, Creek, Delaware, Mayes, Nowata, Osage, Ottawa, Pawnee, Rogers, Tulsa, and Washington.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern District shall be held at Bartlesville, Miami, Pawhuska, Tulsa, and Vinita.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Eastern District comprises the counties of Adair, Atoka, Bryan, Carter, Cherokee, Choctaw, Coal, Haskell, Hughes, Johnston, Latimer, Le Flore Love, McCurtain, McIntosh, Marshall, Murray, Muskogee, Okfuskee, Okmulgee, Pittsburg, Pontotoc, Pushmataha, Seminole, Sequoyah, and Wagoner.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at Ada, Ardmore, Durant, Hugo, Muskogee, Okmulgee, Poteau, and S. McAlester.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) The Western District comprises the counties of Alfalfa, Beaver, Beckham, Blaine, Caddo, Canadian, Cimarron, Cleveland, Comanche, Cotton, Custer, Dewey, Ellis, Garfield, Garvin, Grady, Grant, Greer, Harmon, Harper, Jackson, Jefferson, Kay, Kingfisher, Kiowa, Lincoln, Logan, McClain, Major, Noble, Oklahoma, Payne, Pottawatomie, Roger Mills, Stephens, Texas, Tillman, Washita, Woods, and Woodward.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western District shall be held at Chickasha, Enid, Guthrie, Lawton, Mangum, Oklahoma City, Pauls Valley, Ponca City, Shawnee, and Woodward.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 887</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–526, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-08-04">Aug. 4, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 117.</num>
<heading> Oregon</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Oregon constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Coquille, Eugene or Springfield, Klamath Falls, Medford, Pendleton, and Portland.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 888</ref>; <ref>Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 514</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 393</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–272, § 7</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 297</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–518, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 118.</num>
<heading> Pennsylvania</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Pennsylvania is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Eastern, Middle, and Western Districts of Pennsylvania.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises the counties of Berks, Bucks, Chester, Delaware, Lancaster, Lehigh, Montgomery, Northampton, and Philadelphia.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at Allentown, Easton, Lancaster, Reading, and Philadelphia.</p>
<p class="centered">Middle District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Middle District comprises the counties of Adams, Bradford, Cameron, Carbon, Centre, Clinton, Columbia, Cumberland, Dauphin, Franklin, Fulton, Huntingdon, Juniata, Lackawanna, Lebanon, Luzerne, Lycoming, Mifflin, Monroe, Montour, Northumberland, Perry, Pike, Potter, Schuylkill, Snyder, Sullivan, Susquehanna, Tioga, Union, Wayne, Wyoming, and York.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Middle District shall be held at Harrisburg, Lewisburg, Scranton, Wilkes-Barre, and Williamsport.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) The Western District comprises the counties of Allegheny, Armstrong, Beaver, Bedford, Blair, Butler, Cambria, Clarion, Clearfield, Crawford, Elk, Erie, Fayette, Forest, Greene, Indiana, Jefferson, Lawrence, McKean, Mercer, Somerset, Venango, Warren, Washington, and Westmoreland.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western District shall be held at Erie, Johnstown, and Pittsburgh.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 888</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–272, § 6</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 297</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–573, § 4</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2458</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–396, title IX, § 9161</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1947</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(b) [title VI, § 624(a)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–50</ref>, 2681–116.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 119.</num>
<heading> Puerto Rico</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Puerto Rico constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Mayaguez, Ponce, and San Juan.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 889</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 120.</num>
<heading> Rhode Island</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Rhode Island constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Providence.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 889</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 121.</num>
<heading> South Carolina</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">South Carolina constitutes one judicial district comprising eleven divisions.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Charleston Division comprises the counties of Berkeley, Charleston, Clarendon, Colleton, Dorchester, and Georgetown.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Charleston Division shall be held at Charleston.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Columbia Division comprises the counties of Kershaw, Lee, Lexington, Richland, and Sumter.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Columbia Division shall be held at Columbia.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Florence Division comprises the counties of Chesterfield, Darlington, Dillon, Florence, Horry, Marion, Marlboro, and Williamsburg.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Florence Division shall be held at Florence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Aiken Division comprises the counties of Aiken, Allendale, and Barnwell.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Aiken Division shall be held at Aiken.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Orangeburg Division comprises the counties of Bamberg, Calhoun, and Orangeburg.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Orangeburg Division shall be held at Orangeburg.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Greenville Division comprises the counties of Greenville and Laurens.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Greenville Division shall be held at Greenville.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Rock Hill Division comprises the counties of Chester, Fairfield, Lancaster, and York.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Rock Hill Division shall be held at Rock Hill.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The Greenwood Division comprises the counties of Abbeville, Edgefield, Greenwood, McCormick, Newberry, and Saluda.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Greenwood Division shall be held at Greenwood.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The Anderson Division comprises the counties of Anderson, Oconee, and Pickens.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Anderson Division shall be held at Anderson.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The Spartanburg Division comprises the counties of Cherokee, Spartanburg, and Union.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Spartanburg Division shall be held at Spartanburg.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The Beaufort Division comprises the counties of Beaufort, Hampton, and Jasper.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Beaufort Division shall be held at Beaufort.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 889</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–242, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-10-07">Oct. 7, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 951</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–657, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3670</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–140, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 810</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 122.</num>
<heading> South Dakota</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">South Dakota constitutes one judicial district comprising four divisions.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Northern Division comprises the counties of Brown, Campbell, Clark, Codington, Corson, Day, Deuel, Edmonds, Grant, Hamlin, McPherson, Marshall, Roberts, Spink, and Walworth.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Aberdeen.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Southern Division comprises the counties of Aurora, Beadle, Bon Homme, Brookings, Brule, Charles Mix, Clay, Davison, Douglas, Hanson, Hutchinson, Kingsbury, Lake, Lincoln, McCook, Miner, Minnehaha, Moody, Sanborn, Turner, Union, and Yankton.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Sioux Falls.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The central division comprises the counties of Buffalo, Dewey, Faulk, Gregory, Haakon, Hand, Hughes, Hyde, Jerauld, Jones, Lyman, Mellette, Potter, Stanley, Sully, Todd, Tripp, and Ziebach.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Central Division shall be held at Pierre.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Western Division comprises the counties of Bennett, Butte, Custer, Fall River, Harding, Jackson, Lawrence, Meade, Pennington, Perkins, and Shannon.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Deadwood and Rapid City.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 889</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–638</ref>, <date date="1966-10-10">Oct. 10, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 883</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–376</ref>, <date date="1972-08-10">Aug. 10, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 324(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 123.</num>
<heading> Tennessee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Tennessee is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Eastern, Middle, and Western Districts of Tennessee.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises four divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Anderson, Blount, Campbell, Claiborne, Grainger, Jefferson, Knox, Loudon, Monroe, Morgan, Roane, Scott, Sevier, and Union.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Knoxville.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Northeastern Division comprises the counties of Carter, Cocke, Greene, Hamblen, Hancock, Hawkins, Johnson, Sullivan, Unicoi, and Washington.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northeastern Division shall be held at Greenville.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Bledsoe, Bradley, Hamilton, McMinn, Marion, Meigs, Polk, Rhea, and Sequatchie.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Chattanooga.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Winchester Division comprises the counties of Bedford, Coffee, Franklin, Grundy, Lincoln, Moore, Van Buren, and Warren.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Winchester Division shall be held at Winchester.</p>
<p class="centered">Middle District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Middle District comprises three divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Nashville Division comprises the counties of Cannon, Cheatham, Davidson, Dickson, Houston, Humphreys, Montgomery, Robertson, Rutherford, Stewart, Sumner, Trousdale, Williamson, and Wilson.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Nashville Division shall be held at Nashville.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Northeastern Division comprises the counties of Clay, Cumberland, De Kalb, Fentress, Jackson, Macon, Overton, Pickett, Putnam, Smith, and White.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northeastern Division shall be held at Cookeville.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Columbia Division comprises the counties of Giles, Hickman, Lawrence, Lewis, Marshall, Maury, and Wayne.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Columbia Division shall be held at Columbia.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) The Western District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Benton, Carroll, Chester, Crockett, Decatur, Dyer, Gibson, Hardeman, Hardin, Haywood, Henderson, Henry, Lake, McNairy, Madison, Obion, Perry, and Weakley.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Eastern Division also includes the waters of Tennessee River to low-water mark on the eastern shore wherever such river forms the boundary between the western and middle districts from the north line of Alabama north to the point in Henry County, Tennessee, where the south boundary of Kentucky strikes the east bank of the river.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Jackson and Dyersburg.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Western Division comprises the counties of Fayette, Lauderdale, Shelby, and Tipton.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Memphis.</p>
<p class="indent0">The district judge for the Eastern District in office on <date date="1940-11-27">November 27, 1940</date>, shall hold court in the Northern and Northeastern Divisions. The other judge of that district shall hold the terms of court in the Southern and Winchester Divisions. Each may appoint and remove all officers and employees of the court whose official headquarters are located in the divisions within which he holds court and whose appointments are vested by law in a district judge or chief judge of a district.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 890</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–36, § 3(e)</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–86</ref>, <date date="1961-07-11">July 11, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 203</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–272, § 12</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–406, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 124.</num>
<heading> Texas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Texas is divided into four judicial districts to be known as the Northern, Southern, Eastern, and Western Districts of Texas.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises seven divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Dallas Division comprises the counties of Dallas, Ellis, Hunt, Johnson, Kaufman, Navarro, and Rockwall.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Dallas Division shall be held at Dallas.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Fort Worth Division comprises the counties of Comanche, Erath, Hood, Jack, Palo Pinto, Parker, Tarrant, and Wise.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Fort Worth Division shall be held at Fort Worth.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Abilene Division comprises the counties of Callahan, Eastland, Fisher, Haskell, Howard, Jones, Mitchell, Nolan, Shackleford, Stephens, Stonewall, Taylor, and Throckmorton.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Abilene Division shall be held at Abilene.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The San Angelo Division comprises the counties of Brown, Coke, Coleman, Concho, Crockett, Glasscock, Irion, Menard, Mills, Reagan, Runnels, Schleicher, Sterling, Sutton, and Tom Green.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the San Angelo Division shall be held at San Angelo.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(5) The Amarillo Division comprises the counties of Armstrong, Brisco, Carson, Castro, Childress, Collingsworth, Dallam, Deaf Smith, Donley, Gray, Hall, Hansford, Hartley, Hemphill, Hutchinson, Lipscomb, Moore, Ochiltree, Oldham, Parmer, Potter, Randall, Roberts, Sherman, Swisher, and Wheeler.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Amarillo Division shall be held at Amarillo.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(6) The Wichita Falls Division comprises the counties of Archer, Baylor, Clay, Cottle, Foard, Hardeman, King, Knox, Montague, Wichita, Wilbarger, and Young.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Wichita Falls Division shall be held at Wichita Falls.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(7) The Lubbock Division comprises the counties of Bailey, Borden, Cochran, Crosby, Dawson, Dickens, Floyd, Gaines, Garza, Hale, Hockley, Kent, Lamb, Lubbock, Lynn, Motley, Scurry, Terry, and Yoakum.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Lubbock Division shall be held at Lubbock.</p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Southern District comprises seven divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Galveston Division comprises the counties of Brazoria, Chambers, Galveston, and Matagorda.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Galveston Division shall be held at Galveston.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Houston Division comprises the counties of Austin, Brazos, Colorado, Fayette, Fort Bend, Grimes, Harris, Madison, Montgomery, San Jacinto, Walker, Waller, and Wharton.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Houston Division shall be held at Houston.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Laredo Division comprises the counties of Jim Hogg, La Salle, McMullen, Webb, and Zapata.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Laredo Division shall be held at Laredo.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Brownsville Division comprises the counties of Cameron and Willacy.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Brownsville Division shall be held at Brownsville.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(5) The Victoria Division comprises the counties of Calhoun, DeWitt, Goliad, Jackson, Lavaca, Refugio, and Victoria.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Victoria Division shall be held at Victoria.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(6) The Corpus Christi Division comprises the counties of Aransas, Bee, Brooks, Duval, Jim Wells, Kenedy, Kleberg, Live Oak, Nueces, and San Patricio.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Corpus Christi Division shall be held at Corpus Christi.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(7) The McAllen Division comprises the counties of Hidalgo and Starr.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the McAllen Division shall be held at McAllen.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) The Eastern District comprises seven divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Tyler Division comprises the counties of Anderson, Cherokee, Gregg, Henderson, Panola, Rains, Rusk, Smith, Van Zandt, and Wood.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for Tyler Division will be held at Tyler.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Beaumont Division comprises the counties of Hardin, Jasper, Jefferson, Liberty, Newton, and Orange.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Beaumont Division is to be held at Beaumont.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Sherman Division comprises the counties of Collin, Cook, Delta, Denton, Fannin, Grayson, Hopkins, and Lamar.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Sherman Division shall be held at Sherman and Plano.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Marshall Division comprises the counties of Camp, Cass, Harrison, Marion, Morris, and Upshur.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Marshall Division shall be held at Marshall.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(5) The Texarkana Division comprises the counties of Bowie, Franklin, Red River, and Titus.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Texarkana Division shall be held at Texarkana, and may be held anywhere within the Federal courthouse in Texarkana that is located astride the State line between Texas and Arkansas.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(6) The Lufkin Division comprises the counties of Angelina, Houston, Nacogdoches, Polk, Sabine, San Augustine, Shelby, Trinity, and Tyler.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Lufkin Division shall be held at Lufkin.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(d) The Western District comprises seven divisions.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Austin Division comprises the counties of Bastrop, Blanco, Burleson, Burnet, Caldwell, Gillespie, Hays, Kimble, Lampasas, Lee, Llano, Mason, McCulloch, San Saba, Travis, Washington, and Williamson.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Austin Division shall be held at Austin.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Waco Division comprises the counties of Bell, Bosque, Coryell, Falls, Freestone, Hamilton, Hill, Leon, Limestone, McLennan, Milam, Robertson, and Somervell.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Waco Division shall be held at Waco.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The El Paso Division comprises the county of El Paso.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the El Paso Division shall be held at El Paso.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The San Antonio Division comprises the counties of Atascosa, Bandera, Bexar, Comal, Dimmit, Frio, Gonzales, Guadalupe, Karnes, Kendall, Kerr, Medina, Real, and Wilson.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the San Antonio Division shall be held at San Antonio.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(5) The Del Rio Division comprises the counties of Edwards, Kinney, Maverick, Terrell, Uvalde, Val Verde, and Zavalla.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Del Rio Division shall be held at Del Rio.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(6) The Pecos Division comprises the counties of Brewster, Culberson, Jeff Davis, Hudspeth, Loving, Pecos, Presidio, Reeves, Ward, and Winkler.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Pecos Division shall be held at Pecos and Alpine.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(7) The Midland-Odessa Division comprises the counties of Andrews, Crane, Ector, Martin, Midland, and Upton.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Midland-Odessa Division shall be held at Midland. Court may be held, in the discretion of the court, in Odessa, when courtroom facilities are made available at no expense to the Government.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 891</ref>; <ref>Feb. 10, 1954, ch. 6, § 2(b)(9)(a)</ref>, (b), <ref>68 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–298</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1957-09-04">Sept. 4, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 618</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–352</ref>, <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 772</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–282</ref>, <date date="1964-03-11">Mar. 11, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 163</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–512</ref>, <date date="1964-08-30">Aug. 30, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–216</ref>, <date date="1967-12-18">Dec. 18, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–462, § 6</ref>, <date date="1980-10-15">Oct. 15, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2054</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 407(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3362</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–157, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-03">Dec. 3, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1947</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–455, § 3</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3628</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–73, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-07-30">July 30, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1504</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 125.</num>
<heading> Utah</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Utah constitutes one judicial district comprising two divisions.</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Northern Division comprises the counties of Box Elder, Cache, Davis, Morgan, Rich, and Weber.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Salt Lake City and Ogden.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Central Division comprises the counties of Beaver, Carbon, Daggett, Duchesne, Emery, Garfield, Grand, Iron, Juab, Kane, Millard, Piute, Salt Lake, San Juan, Sanpete, Sevier, Summit, Tooele, Uintah, Utah, Wasatch, Washington, and Wayne.<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Central Division shall be held at Salt Lake City, Provo, St. George, Moab, and Monticello..<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 893</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–317, title VI, § 606</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3859</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–250, § 1</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2939</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 126.</num>
<heading> Vermont</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Vermont constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Bennington, Brattleboro, Burlington, Montpelier, Rutland, Saint Johnsbury, and Windsor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 893</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–312</ref>, <date date="1964-05-28">May 28, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 201</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 410</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3362</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 127.</num>
<heading> Virginia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Virginia is divided into two judicial districts, to be known as the Eastern and Western districts of Virginia.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises the counties of Accomac, Amelia, Arlington, Brunswick, Caroline, Charles City, Chesterfield, Dinwiddie, Elizabeth City, Essex, Fairfax, Fauquier, Gloucester, Goochland, Greensville, Hanover, Henrico, Isle of Wight, James City, King and Queen, King George, King William, Lancaster, Loudoun, Lunenburg, Mathews, Mecklenburg, Middlesex, Nansemond, New Kent, Norfolk, Northampton, Northumberland, Nottoway, Powhatan, Prince Edward, Prince George, Prince William, Princess Anne, Richmond, Southampton, Spotsylvania, Stafford, Surry, Sussex, Warwick, Westmoreland, and York.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at Alexandria, Newport News, Norfolk, and Richmond.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Western District comprises the counties of Albemarle, Alleghany, Amherst, Appomattox, Augusta, Bath, Bedford, Bland, Botetourt, Buchanan, Buckingham, Campbell, Carroll, Charlotte, Clarke, Craig, Culpeper, Cumberland, Dickenson, Floyd, Fluvanna, Franklin, Frederick, Giles, Grayson, Greene, Halifax, Henry, Highland, Lee, Louisa, Madison, Montgomery, Nelson, Orange, Page, Patrick, Pittsylvania, Pulaski, Rappahannock, Roanoke, Rockbridge, Rockingham, Russell, Scott, Shenandoah, Smyth, Tazewell, Warren, Washington, Wise, and Wythe.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western District shall be held at Abingdon, Big Stone Gap, Charlottesville, Danville, Harrisonburg, Lynchburg, and Roanoke.</p>
<p class="indent0">(c) Cities and incorporated towns are included in that district in which are included the counties within the exterior boundaries of which such cities and incorporated towns are geographically located or out of the territory of which they have been incorporated.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 893</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–383</ref>, <date date="1968-07-05">July 5, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–200, § 1</ref>, <date date="1991-12-10">Dec. 10, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1630</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 128.</num>
<heading> Washington</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Washington is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Eastern and Western Districts of Washington.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises the counties of Adams, Asotin, Benton, Chelan, Columbia, Douglas, Ferry, Franklin, Garfield, Grant, Kittitas, Klickitat, Lincoln, Okanogan, Pend Oreille, Spokane, Stevens, Walla Walla, Whitman, and Yakima.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at Spokane, Yakima, Walla Walla, and Richland.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Western District comprises the counties of Clallam, Clark, Cowlitz, Grays Harbor, Island, Jefferson, King, Kitsap, Lewis, Mason, Pacific, Pierce, San Juan, Skagit, Skamania, Snohomish, Thurston, Wahkiakum, and Whatcom.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western District shall be held at Bellingham, Seattle, Tacoma, Mount Vernon, and Vancouver.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 894</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–699</ref>, <date date="1962-09-25">Sept. 25, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–272, § 4</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 297</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. D, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 1990</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–73, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-07-30">July 30, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1504</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 129.</num>
<heading> West Virginia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">West Virginia is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Northern and Southern Districts of West Virginia.</p>
<p class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises the counties of Barbour, Berkeley, Braxton, Brooke, Calhoun, Doddridge, Gilmer, Grant, Hampshire, Hancock, Hardy, Harrison, Jefferson, Lewis, Marion, Marshall, Mineral, Monongalia, Morgan, Ohio, Pendleton, Pleasants, Pocahontas, Preston, Randolph, Ritchie, Taylor, Tucker, Tyler, Upshur, Webster, and Wetzel.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern District shall be held at Clarksburg, Elkins, Fairmont, Martinsburg, and Wheeling.</p>
<p class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Southern District comprises the counties of Boone, Cabell, Clay, Fayette, Greenbrier, Jackson, Kanawha, Lincoln, Logan, McDowell, Mason, Mercer, Mingo, Monroe, Nicholas, Putnam, Raleigh, Roane, Summers, Wayne, Wirt, Wood, and Wyoming.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern District shall be held at Beckley, Bluefield, Charleston, Huntington, Lewisburg, and Parkersburg.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 894</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–471, § 1</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2601</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 130.</num>
<heading> Wisconsin</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Wisconsin is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Eastern and Western districts of Wisconsin.</p>
<p class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises the counties of Brown, Calumet, Dodge, Door, Florence, Fond du Lac, Forest, Green Lake, Kenosha, Kewaunee, Langlade, Manitowoc, Marinette, Marquette, Menominee, Milwaukee, Oconto, Outagamie, Ozaukee, Racine, Shawano, Sheboygan, Walworth, Washington, Waukesha, Waupaca, Waushara, and Winnebago.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at Green Bay, Milwaukee, and Oshkosh.</p>
<p class="centered">Western District</p>
<p class="indent0">(b) The Western District comprises the counties of Adams, Ashland, Barron, Bayfield, Buffalo, Burnett, Chippewa, Clark, Columbia, Crawford, Dane, Douglas, Dunn, Eau Claire, Grant, Green, Iowa, Iron, Jackson, Jefferson, Juneau, La Crosse, Lafayette, Lincoln, Marathon, Monroe, Oneida, Pepin, Pierce, Polk, Portage, Price, Richland, Rock, Rusk, Saint Croix, Sauk, Sawyer, Taylor, Trempealeau, Vernon, Vilas, Washburn, and Wood.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western District shall be held at Eau Claire, La Crosse, Madison, Superior, and Wausau.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 894</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–573</ref>, <date date="1962-08-06">Aug. 6, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 307</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 131.</num>
<heading> Wyoming</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Wyoming and those portions of Yellowstone National Park situated in Montana and Idaho constitute one judicial district.</p>
<p class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Casper, Cheyenne, Evanston, Lander, Jackson, and Sheridan.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 895</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 350</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 132.</num>
<heading> Creation and composition of district courts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There shall be in each judicial district a district court which shall be a court of record known as the United States District Court for the district.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each district court shall consist of the district judge or judges for the district in regular active service. Justices or judges designated or assigned shall be competent to sit as judges of the court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided by law, or rule or order of court, the judicial power of a district court with respect to any action, suit or proceeding may be exercised by a single judge, who may preside alone and hold a regular or special session of court at the same time other sessions are held by other judges.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 895</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–176, § 2</ref>, <date date="1963-11-13">Nov. 13, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 331</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 133.</num>
<heading> Appointment and number of district judges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President shall appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, district judges for the several judicial districts, as follows:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p>Districts</p></th><th><p>Judges</p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p>Alabama:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>8  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Middle</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Alaska</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Arizona</span></p></td><td><p>13  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Arkansas:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>California:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>14  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>6  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Central</span></p></td><td><p>28  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>13  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Colorado</span></p></td><td><p>7  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Connecticut</span></p></td><td><p>8  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Delaware</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>District of Columbia</span></p></td><td><p>15  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Florida:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Middle</span></p></td><td><p>15  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>18  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Georgia:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>11  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Middle</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Hawaii</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Idaho</span></p></td><td><p>2  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Illinois:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>22  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Central</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Indiana:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Iowa:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>2  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Kansas</span></p></td><td><p>6  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Kentucky:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern and Western</span></p></td><td><p>1  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Louisiana:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>12  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Middle</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>7  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Maine</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Maryland</span></p></td><td><p>10  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Massachusetts</span></p></td><td><p>13  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Michigan:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>15  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Minnesota</span></p></td><td><p>7  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Mississippi:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>6  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Missouri:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>7  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern and Western</span></p></td><td><p>2  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Montana</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Nebraska</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Nevada</span></p></td><td><p>7  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>New Hampshire</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>New Jersey</span></p></td><td><p>17  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>New Mexico</span></p></td><td><p>7  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>New York:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>28  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>15  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>North Carolina:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Middle</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>North Dakota</span></p></td><td><p>2  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Ohio:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>11  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>8  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Oklahoma:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>1  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>6  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern, Eastern, and Western</span></p></td><td><p>1  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Oregon</span></p></td><td><p>6  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Pennsylvania:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>22  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Middle</span></p></td><td><p>6  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>10  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Puerto Rico</span></p></td><td><p>7  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Rhode Island</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>South Carolina</span></p></td><td><p>10  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>South Dakota</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Tennessee:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Middle</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Texas:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>12  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>19  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>8  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>13  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Utah</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Vermont</span></p></td><td><p>2  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Virginia:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>11  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Washington:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>4  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>7  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>West Virginia:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Northern</span></p></td><td><p>3  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Southern</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Wisconsin:</p></td><td/></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Eastern</span></p></td><td><p>5  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Western</span></p></td><td><p>2  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Wyoming</span></p></td><td><p>3.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In any case in which a judge of the United States (other than a senior judge) assumes the duties of a full-time office of Federal judicial administration, the President shall appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, an additional judge for the court on which such judge serves. If the judge who assumes the duties of such full-time office leaves that office and resumes the duties as an active judge of the court, then the President shall not appoint a judge to fill the first vacancy which occurs thereafter in that court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “office of Federal judicial administration” means a position as Director of the Federal Judicial Center, Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, or Counselor to the Chief Justice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 895</ref>; <ref>Aug. 3, 1949, ch. 387, § 2(a)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 493</ref>; <ref>Aug. 14, 1950, ch. 708</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 443</ref>; <ref>Aug. 29, 1950, ch. 819, § 1</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 562</ref>; <ref>Sept. 5, 1950, ch. 848, § 1</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 578</ref>; <ref>Feb. 10, 1954, ch. 6, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–310</ref>, <date date="1957-09-07">Sept. 7, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–508, § 12(c)</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 348</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–3, § 9(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 8</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–36, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 81</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–562, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-07-30">July 30, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–242, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1965-10-07">Oct. 7, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 951</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–372, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-03-18">Mar. 18, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 77</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–272, § 1(d)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 295</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–208, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 742</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–408, § 4(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-02">Oct. 2, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 885</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–486, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-20">Oct. 20, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1630</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–471, § 3</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2601</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–353, title II, § 202(e)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 348</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title II, § 203(d)</ref>, title III, § 303, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5101</ref>, 5105; <ref>Pub. L. 105–53, § 4</ref>, <date date="1997-10-06">Oct. 6, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1174</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(1) [title III, § 309(b)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–37; <ref>Pub. L. 106–553, § 1(a)(2) [title III, § 305(b)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2762</ref>, 2762A–85; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title III, § 312(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1786</ref>, 1787; <ref>Pub. L. 110–402, § 1(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4254</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–203, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 134.</num>
<heading> Tenure and residence of district judges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The district judges shall hold office during good behavior.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each district judge, except in the District of Columbia, the Southern District of New York, and the Eastern District of New York, shall reside in the district or one of the districts for which he is appointed. Each district judge of the Southern District of New York and the Eastern District of New York may reside within 20 miles of the district to which he or she is appointed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If the public interest and the nature of the business of a district court require that a district judge should maintain his abode at or near a particular place for holding court in the district or within a particular part of the district the judicial council of the circuit may so declare and may make an appropriate order. If the district judges of such a district are unable to agree as to which of them shall maintain his abode at or near the place or within the area specified in such an order the judicial council of the circuit may decide which of them shall do so.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 896</ref>; <ref>Aug. 3, 1949, ch. 387, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 495</ref>; <ref>Feb. 10, 1954, ch. 6, § 2(b)(13)(a)</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 12</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–3, § 9(c)</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 8</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–36, § 2(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–571, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-12">Sept. 12, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–208, § 3(e)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 742</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–317, title VI, § 607</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3860</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 135.</num>
<heading> Salaries of district judges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each judge of a district court of the United States shall receive a salary at an annual rate determined under section 225 of the Federal Salary Act of 1967 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 351–361</ref>), as adjusted by <ref>section 461 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 897</ref>; <ref>Mar. 2, 1955, ch. 9, § 1(c)</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 10</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–426, title IV, § 403(c)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–82, title II, § 205(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 136.</num>
<heading> Chief judges; precedence of district judges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In any district having more than one district judge, the chief judge of the district shall be the district judge in regular active service who is senior in commission of those judges who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are sixty-four years of age or under;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have served for one year or more as a district judge; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> have not served previously as chief judge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In any case in which no district judge meets the qualifications of paragraph (1), the youngest district judge in regular active service who is sixty-five years of age or over and who has served as district judge for one year or more shall act as the chief judge.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In any case under subparagraph (A) in which there is no district judge in regular active service who has served as a district judge for one year or more, the district judge in regular active service who is senior in commission and who has not served previously as chief judge shall act as the chief judge.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the chief judge of the district appointed under paragraph (1) shall serve for a term of seven years and shall serve after expiration of such term until another judge is eligible under paragraph (1) to serve as chief judge of the district.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (C), a district judge acting as chief judge under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (2) shall serve until a judge has been appointed who meets the qualifications under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> No district judge may serve or act as chief judge of the district after attaining the age of seventy years unless no other district judge is qualified to serve as chief judge of the district under paragraph (1) or is qualified to act as chief judge under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The chief judge shall have precedence and preside at any session which he attends.<p class="indent0">Other district judges shall have precedence and preside according to the seniority of their commissions. Judges whose commissions bear the same date shall have precedence according to seniority in age.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> A judge whose commission extends over more than one district shall be junior to all district judges except in the district in which he resided at the time he entered upon the duties of his office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If the chief judge desires to be relieved of his duties as chief judge while retaining his active status as district judge, he may so certify to the Chief Justice of the United States, and thereafter, the chief judge of the district shall be such other district judge who is qualified to serve or act as chief judge under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> If a chief judge is temporarily unable to perform his duties as such, they shall be performed by the district judge in active service, present in the district and able and qualified to act, who is next in precedence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 897</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 37</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 723</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–593, § 2</ref>, <date date="1958-08-06">Aug. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 52</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 137.</num>
<heading> Division of business among district judges</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The business of a court having more than one judge shall be divided among the judges as provided by the rules and orders of the court.<p class="indent0">The chief judge of the district court shall be responsible for the observance of such rules and orders, and shall divide the business and assign the cases so far as such rules and orders do not otherwise prescribe.</p>
<p class="indent0">If the district judges in any district are unable to agree upon the adoption of rules or orders for that purpose the judicial council of the circuit shall make the necessary orders.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Random Assignment of Rate Court Proceedings.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this paragraph, the term “performing rights society” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 101 of title 17</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination of license fee</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), in the case of any performing rights society subject to a consent decree, any application for the determination of a license fee for the public performance of music in accordance with the applicable consent decree shall be made in the district court with jurisdiction over that consent decree and randomly assigned to a judge of that district court according to the rules of that court for the division of business among district judges, provided that any such application shall not be assigned to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a judge to whom continuing jurisdiction over any performing rights society for any performing rights society consent decree is assigned or has previously been assigned; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a judge to whom another proceeding concerning an application for the determination of a reasonable license fee is assigned at the time of the filing of the application.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subparagraph (B) does not apply to an application to determine reasonable license fees made by individual proprietors under <ref>section 513 of title 17</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in paragraph (1) shall modify the rights of any party to a consent decree or to a proceeding to determine reasonable license fees, to make an application for the construction of any provision of the applicable consent decree. Such application shall be referred to the judge to whom continuing jurisdiction over the applicable consent decree is currently assigned. If any such application is made in connection with a rate proceeding, such rate proceeding shall be stayed until the final determination of the construction application. Disputes in connection with a rate proceeding about whether a licensee is similarly situated to another licensee shall not be subject to referral to the judge with continuing jurisdiction over the applicable consent decree.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 897</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–264, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3726</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 138.</num>
<heading> Terms abolished</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The district court shall not hold formal terms.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 897</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–139, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-10-16">Oct. 16, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 139.</num>
<heading> Times for holding regular sessions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The times for commencing regular sessions of the district court for transacting judicial business at the places fixed by this chapter shall be determined by the rules or orders of the court. Such rules or orders may provide that at one or more of such places the court shall be in continuous session for such purposes on all business days throughout the year. At other places a session of the court shall continue for such purposes until terminated by order of final adjournment or by commencement of the next regular session at the same place.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 897</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–139, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-10-16">Oct. 16, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 140.</num>
<heading> Adjournment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any district court may, by order made anywhere within its district, adjourn or, with the consent of the judicial council of the circuit, pretermit any regular session of court for insufficient business or other good cause.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> If the judge of a district court is unable to attend and unable to make an order of adjournment, the clerk may adjourn the court to the next regular session or to any earlier day which he may determine.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 897</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–139, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-10-16">Oct. 16, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 141.</num>
<heading> Special sessions; places; notice</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Special sessions of the district court may be held at such places in the district as the nature of the business may require, and upon such notice as the court orders.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any business may be transacted at a special session which might be transacted at a regular session.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Special sessions of the district court may be held at such places within the United States outside the district as the nature of the business may require and upon such notice as the court orders, upon a finding by either the chief judge of the district court (or, if the chief judge is unavailable, the most senior available active judge of the district court) or the judicial council of the circuit that, because of emergency conditions, no location within the district is reasonably available where such special sessions could be held.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Pursuant to this subsection, any business which may be transacted at a regular session of a district court may be transacted at a special session conducted outside the district, except that a criminal trial may not be conducted at a special session outside the State in which the crime has been committed unless the defendant consents to such a criminal trial.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in any case in which special sessions are conducted pursuant to this section, the district court may summon jurors—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in civil proceedings, from any part of the district in which the court ordinarily conducts business or the district in which it is holding a special session; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in criminal trials, from any part of the district in which the crime has been committed and, if the defendant so consents, from any district in which the court is conducting business pursuant to this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> If a district court issues an order exercising its authority under paragraph (1), the court—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> through the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> send notice of such order, including the reasons for the issuance of such order, to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 180 days after the expiration of such court order submit a brief report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives describing the impact of such order, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the reasons for the issuance of such order;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the duration of such order;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the impact of such order on litigants; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the costs to the judiciary resulting from such order; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall provide reasonable notice to the United States Marshals Service before the commencement of any special session held pursuant to such order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> If a district court issues an order exercising its authority under paragraph (1), the court shall direct the United States marshal of the district where the court is meeting to furnish transportation and subsistence to the same extent as that provided in sections 4282 and 4285 of title 18.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 897</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–139, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-10-16">Oct. 16, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–63, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-09-09">Sept. 9, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1994</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1198(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3132</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 142.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 115(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 32</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 143.</num>
<heading> Vacant judgeship as affecting proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the office of a district judge becomes vacant, all pending process, pleadings and proceedings shall, when necessary, be continued by the clerk until a judge is appointed or designated to hold such court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 898</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 144.</num>
<heading> Bias or prejudice of judge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever a party to any proceeding in a district court makes and files a timely and sufficient affidavit that the judge before whom the matter is pending has a personal bias or prejudice either against him or in favor of any adverse party, such judge shall proceed no further therein, but another judge shall be assigned to hear such proceeding.</p>
<p class="indent0">The affidavit shall state the facts and the reasons for the belief that bias or prejudice exists, and shall be filed not less than ten days before the beginning of the term at which the proceeding is to be heard, or good cause shall be shown for failure to file it within such time. A party may file only one such affidavit in any case. It shall be accompanied by a certificate of counsel of record stating that it is made in good faith.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 898</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 65</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 99</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>