<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 44—</num>
<heading>ALTERNATIVE DISPUTE RESOLUTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 651.</num>
<heading> Authorization of alternative dispute resolution</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this chapter, an alternative dispute resolution process includes any process or procedure, other than an adjudication by a presiding judge, in which a neutral third party participates to assist in the resolution of issues in controversy, through processes such as early neutral evaluation, mediation, minitrial, and arbitration as provided in sections 654 through 658.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each United States district court shall authorize, by local rule adopted under section 2071(a), the use of alternative dispute resolution processes in all civil actions, including adversary proceedings in bankruptcy, in accordance with this chapter, except that the use of arbitration may be authorized only as provided in section 654. Each United States district court shall devise and implement its own alternative dispute resolution program, by local rule adopted under section 2071(a), to encourage and promote the use of alternative dispute resolution in its district.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Existing Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In those courts where an alternative dispute resolution program is in place on the date of the enactment of the Alternative Dispute Resolution Act of 1998, the court shall examine the effectiveness of that program and adopt such improvements to the program as are consistent with the provisions and purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administration of Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each United States district court shall designate an employee, or a judicial officer, who is knowledgeable in alternative dispute resolution practices and processes to implement, administer, oversee, and evaluate the court’s alternative dispute resolution program. Such person may also be responsible for recruiting, screening, and training attorneys to serve as neutrals and arbitrators in the court’s alternative dispute resolution program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Title</inline> 9 <inline class="small-caps">Not Affected</inline>.—</heading>
<content>This chapter shall not affect title 9, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Program Support</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Federal Judicial Center and the Administrative Office of the United States Courts are authorized to assist the district courts in the establishment and improvement of alternative dispute resolution programs by identifying particular practices employed in successful programs and providing additional assistance as needed and appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4659</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–315, § 3</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 652.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consideration of Alternative Dispute Resolution in Appropriate Cases</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary and except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), each district court shall, by local rule adopted under section 2071(a), require that litigants in all civil cases consider the use of an alternative dispute resolution process at an appropriate stage in the litigation. Each district court shall provide litigants in all civil cases with at least one alternative dispute resolution process, including, but not limited to, mediation, early neutral evaluation, minitrial, and arbitration as authorized in sections 654 through 658. Any district court that elects to require the use of alternative dispute resolution in certain cases may do so only with respect to mediation, early neutral evaluation, and, if the parties consent, arbitration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Actions Exempted From Consideration of Alternative Dispute Resolution</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each district court may exempt from the requirements of this section specific cases or categories of cases in which use of alternative dispute resolution would not be appropriate. In defining these exemptions, each district court shall consult with members of the bar, including the United States Attorney for that district.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Authority of the Attorney General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall alter or conflict with the authority of the Attorney General to conduct litigation on behalf of the United States, with the authority of any Federal agency authorized to conduct litigation in the United States courts, or with any delegation of litigation authority by the Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Confidentiality Provisions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Until such time as rules are adopted under chapter 131 of this title providing for the confidentiality of alternative dispute resolution processes under this chapter, each district court shall, by local rule adopted under section 2071(a), provide for the confidentiality of the alternative dispute resolution processes and to prohibit disclosure of confidential dispute resolution communications.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4659</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–315, § 4</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2994</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 653.</num>
<heading> Neutrals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Panel of Neutrals</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each district court that authorizes the use of alternative dispute resolution processes shall adopt appropriate processes for making neutrals available for use by the parties for each category of process offered. Each district court shall promulgate its own procedures and criteria for the selection of neutrals on its panels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Qualifications and Training</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each person serving as a neutral in an alternative dispute resolution process should be qualified and trained to serve as a neutral in the appropriate alternative dispute resolution process. For this purpose, the district court may use, among others, magistrate judges who have been trained to serve as neutrals in alternative dispute resolution processes, professional neutrals from the private sector, and persons who have been trained to serve as neutrals in alternative dispute resolution processes. Until such time as rules are adopted under chapter 131 of this title relating to the disqualification of neutrals, each district court shall issue rules under section 2071(a) relating to the disqualification of neutrals (including, where appropriate, disqualification under <ref>section 455 of this title</ref>, other applicable law, and professional responsibility standards).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4660</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–315, § 5</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 654.</num>
<heading> Arbitration</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Referral of Actions to Arbitration</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary and except as provided in subsections (a), (b), and (c) of section 652 and subsection (d) of this section, a district court may allow the referral to arbitration of any civil action (including any adversary proceeding in bankruptcy) pending before it when the parties consent, except that referral to arbitration may not be made where—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the action is based on an alleged violation of a right secured by the Constitution of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> jurisdiction is based in whole or in part on <ref>section 1343 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the relief sought consists of money damages in an amount greater than $150,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Safeguards in Consent Cases</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Until such time as rules are adopted under chapter 131 of this title relating to procedures described in this subsection, the district court shall, by local rule adopted under section 2071(a), establish procedures to ensure that any civil action in which arbitration by consent is allowed under subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consent to arbitration is freely and knowingly obtained; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> no party or attorney is prejudiced for refusing to participate in arbitration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Presumptions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of subsection (a)(3), a district court may presume damages are not in excess of $150,000 unless counsel certifies that damages exceed such amount.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Existing Programs</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this chapter is deemed to affect any program in which arbitration is conducted pursuant to section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002057">1</ref> title IX of the Judicial Improvements and Access to Justice Act (<ref>Public Law 100–702</ref>), as amended by <ref>section 1 of Public Law 105–53</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4660</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–315, § 6</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 655.</num>
<heading> Arbitrators</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Powers of Arbitrators</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An arbitrator to whom an action is referred under section 654 shall have the power, within the judicial district of the district court which referred the action to arbitration—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to conduct arbitration hearings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to administer oaths and affirmations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to make awards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Standards for Certification</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each district court that authorizes arbitration shall establish standards for the certification of arbitrators and shall certify arbitrators to perform services in accordance with such standards and this chapter. The standards shall include provisions requiring that any arbitrator—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall take the oath or affirmation described in section 453; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be subject to the disqualification rules under section 455.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Immunity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>All individuals serving as arbitrators in an alternative dispute resolution program under this chapter are performing quasi-judicial functions and are entitled to the immunities and protections that the law accords to persons serving in such capacity.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4661</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–315, § 7</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 656.</num>
<heading> Subpoenas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Rule 45 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure (relating to subpoenas) applies to subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses and the production of documentary evidence at an arbitration hearing under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4662</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–315, § 8</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 657.</num>
<heading> Arbitration award and judgment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing and Effect of Arbitration Award</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An arbitration award made by an arbitrator under this chapter, along with proof of service of such award on the other party by the prevailing party or by the plaintiff, shall be filed promptly after the arbitration hearing is concluded with the clerk of the district court that referred the case to arbitration. Such award shall be entered as the judgment of the court after the time has expired for requesting a trial de novo. The judgment so entered shall be subject to the same provisions of law and shall have the same force and effect as a judgment of the court in a civil action, except that the judgment shall not be subject to review in any other court by appeal or otherwise.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sealing of Arbitration Award</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The district court shall provide, by local rule adopted under section 2071(a), that the contents of any arbitration award made under this chapter shall not be made known to any judge who might be assigned to the case until the district court has entered final judgment in the action or the action has otherwise terminated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Trial de Novo of Arbitration Awards.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time for filing demand</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Within 30 days after the filing of an arbitration award with a district court under subsection (a), any party may file a written demand for a trial de novo in the district court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Action restored to court docket</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon a demand for a trial de novo, the action shall be restored to the docket of the court and treated for all purposes as if it had not been referred to arbitration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of evidence of arbitration</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The court shall not admit at the trial de novo any evidence that there has been an arbitration proceeding, the nature or amount of any award, or any other matter concerning the conduct of the arbitration proceeding, unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the evidence would otherwise be admissible in the court under the Federal Rules of Evidence; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the parties have otherwise stipulated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4662</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–315, § 9</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2997</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 658.</num>
<heading> Compensation of arbitrators and neutrals</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The district court shall, subject to regulations approved by the Judicial Conference of the United States, establish the amount of compensation, if any, that each arbitrator or neutral shall receive for services rendered in each case under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transportation Allowances</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Under regulations prescribed by the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, a district court may reimburse arbitrators and other neutrals for actual transportation expenses necessarily incurred in the performance of duties under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4662</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–315, § 10</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2997</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>