<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 171—</num>
<heading>TORT CLAIMS PROCEDURE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2671.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in this chapter and sections 1346(b) and 2401(b) of this title, the term “Federal agency” includes the executive departments, the judicial and legislative branches, the military departments, independent establishments of the United States, and corporations primarily acting as instrumentalities or agencies of the United States, but does not include any contractor with the United States.</p>
<p class="indent0">“Employee of the government” includes (1) officers or employees of any federal agency, members of the military or naval forces of the United States, members of the National Guard while engaged in training or duty under section 115, 316, 502, 503, 504, or 505 of title 32, and persons acting on behalf of a federal agency in an official capacity, temporarily or permanently in the service of the United States, whether with or without compensation, and (2) any officer or employee of a Federal public defender organization, except when such officer or employee performs professional services in the course of providing representation under <ref>section 3006A of title 18</ref>.</p>
<p class="indent0">“Acting within the scope of his office or employment”, in the case of a member of the military or naval forces of the United States or a member of the National Guard as defined in <ref>section 101(3) of title 32</ref>, means acting in line of duty.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 982</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 124</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 106</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–506, § 8</ref>, <date date="1966-07-18">July 18, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–124, § 1</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1666</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–694, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title VI, § 665(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–169; <ref>Pub. L. 106–518, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2421</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2672.</num>
<heading> Administrative adjustment of claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of each Federal agency or his designee, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Attorney General, may consider, ascertain, adjust, determine, compromise, and settle any claim for money damages against the United States for injury or loss of property or personal injury or death caused by the negligent or wrongful act or omission of any employee of the agency while acting within the scope of his office or employment, under circumstances where the United States, if a private person, would be liable to the claimant in accordance with the law of the place where the act or omission occurred: <i>Provided</i>, That any award, compromise, or settlement in excess of $25,000 shall be effected only with the prior written approval of the Attorney General or his designee. Notwithstanding the proviso contained in the preceding sentence, any award, compromise, or settlement may be effected without the prior written approval of the Attorney General or his or her designee, to the extent that the Attorney General delegates to the head of the agency the authority to make such award, compromise, or settlement. Such delegations may not exceed the authority delegated by the Attorney General to the United States attorneys to settle claims for money damages against the United States. Each Federal agency may use arbitration, or other alternative means of dispute resolution under the provisions of subchapter IV of chapter 5 of title 5, to settle any tort claim against the United States, to the extent of the agency’s authority to award, compromise, or settle such claim without the prior written approval of the Attorney General or his or her designee.</p>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of this title relating to civil actions on tort claims against the United States, any such award, compromise, settlement, or determination shall be final and conclusive on all officers of the Government, except when procured by means of fraud.</p>
<p class="indent0">Any award, compromise, or settlement in an amount of $2,500 or less made pursuant to this section shall be paid by the head of the Federal agency concerned out of appropriations available to that agency. Payment of any award, compromise, or settlement in an amount in excess of $2,500 made pursuant to this section or made by the Attorney General in any amount pursuant to <ref>section 2677 of this title</ref> shall be paid in a manner similar to judgments and compromises in like causes and appropriations or funds available for the payment of such judgments and compromises are hereby made available for the payment of awards, compromises, or settlements under this chapter.</p>
<p class="indent0">The acceptance by the claimant of any such award, compromise, or settlement shall be final and conclusive on the claimant, and shall constitute a complete release of any claim against the United States and against the employee of the government whose act or omission gave rise to the claim, by reason of the same subject matter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 983</ref>; <ref>Apr. 25, 1949, ch. 92, § 2(b)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 62</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 125</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 106</ref>; <ref>Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1010, § 9</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 987</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–238, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-08">Sept. 8, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 471</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–506</ref>, §§ 1, 9(a), <date date="1966-07-18">July 18, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 306</ref>, 308; <ref>Pub. L. 101–552, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 2746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2673.</num>
<heading> Reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of each federal agency shall report annually to Congress all claims paid by it under <ref>section 2672 of this title</ref>, stating the name of each claimant, the amount claimed, the amount awarded, and a brief description of the claim.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 983</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2674.</num>
<heading> Liability of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States shall be liable, respecting the provisions of this title relating to tort claims, in the same manner and to the same extent as a private individual under like circumstances, but shall not be liable for interest prior to judgment or for punitive damages.</p>
<p class="indent0">If, however, in any case wherein death was caused, the law of the place where the act or omission complained of occurred provides, or has been construed to provide, for damages only punitive in nature, the United States shall be liable for actual or compensatory damages, measured by the pecuniary injuries resulting from such death to the persons respectively, for whose benefit the action was brought, in lieu thereof.</p>
<p class="indent0">With respect to any claim under this chapter, the United States shall be entitled to assert any defense based upon judicial or legislative immunity which otherwise would have been available to the employee of the United States whose act or omission gave rise to the claim, as well as any other defenses to which the United States is entitled.</p>
<p class="indent0">With respect to any claim to which this section applies, the Tennessee Valley Authority shall be entitled to assert any defense which otherwise would have been available to the employee based upon judicial or legislative immunity, which otherwise would have been available to the employee of the Tennessee Valley Authority whose act or omission gave rise to the claim as well as any other defenses to which the Tennessee Valley Authority is entitled under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 983</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–694</ref>, §§ 4, 9(c), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4564</ref>, 4567.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2675.</num>
<heading> Disposition by federal agency as prerequisite; evidence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An action shall not be instituted upon a claim against the United States for money damages for injury or loss of property or personal injury or death caused by the negligent or wrongful act or omission of any employee of the Government while acting within the scope of his office or employment, unless the claimant shall have first presented the claim to the appropriate Federal agency and his claim shall have been finally denied by the agency in writing and sent by certified or registered mail. The failure of an agency to make final disposition of a claim within six months after it is filed shall, at the option of the claimant any time thereafter, be deemed a final denial of the claim for purposes of this section. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to such claims as may be asserted under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure by third party complaint, cross-claim, or counterclaim.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Action under this section shall not be instituted for any sum in excess of the amount of the claim presented to the federal agency, except where the increased amount is based upon newly discovered evidence not reasonably discoverable at the time of presenting the claim to the federal agency, or upon allegation and proof of intervening facts, relating to the amount of the claim.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Disposition of any claim by the Attorney General or other head of a federal agency shall not be competent evidence of liability or amount of damages.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 983</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 126</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 107</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–506, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-07-18">July 18, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2676.</num>
<heading> Judgment as bar</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The judgment in an action under <ref>section 1346(b) of this title</ref> shall constitute a complete bar to any action by the claimant, by reason of the same subject matter, against the employee of the government whose act or omission gave rise to the claim.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 984</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2677.</num>
<heading> Compromise</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General or his designee may arbitrate, compromise, or settle any claim cognizable under <ref>section 1346(b) of this title</ref>, after the commencement of an action thereon.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 984</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–506, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-07-18">July 18, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 307</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2678.</num>
<heading> Attorney fees; penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No attorney shall charge, demand, receive, or collect for services rendered, fees in excess of 25 per centum of any judgment rendered pursuant to <ref>section 1346(b) of this title</ref> or any settlement made pursuant to <ref>section 2677 of this title</ref>, or in excess of 20 per centum of any award, compromise, or settlement made pursuant to <ref>section 2672 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p class="indent0">Any attorney who charges, demands, receives, or collects for services rendered in connection with such claim any amount in excess of that allowed under this section, if recovery be had, shall be fined not more than $2,000 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 984</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–506, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-07-18">July 18, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 307</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2679.</num>
<heading> Exclusiveness of remedy</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The authority of any federal agency to sue and be sued in its own name shall not be construed to authorize suits against such federal agency on claims which are cognizable under <ref>section 1346(b) of this title</ref>, and the remedies provided by this title in such cases shall be exclusive.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The remedy against the United States provided by sections 1346(b) and 2672 of this title for injury or loss of property, or personal injury or death arising or resulting from the negligent or wrongful act or omission of any employee of the Government while acting within the scope of his office or employment is exclusive of any other civil action or proceeding for money damages by reason of the same subject matter against the employee whose act or omission gave rise to the claim or against the estate of such employee. Any other civil action or proceeding for money damages arising out of or relating to the same subject matter against the employee or the employee’s estate is precluded without regard to when the act or omission occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Paragraph (1) does not extend or apply to a civil action against an employee of the Government—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which is brought for a violation of the Constitution of the United States, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which is brought for a violation of a statute of the United States under which such action against an individual is otherwise authorized.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall defend any civil action or proceeding brought in any court against any employee of the Government or his estate for any such damage or injury. The employee against whom such civil action or proceeding is brought shall deliver within such time after date of service or knowledge of service as determined by the Attorney General, all process served upon him or an attested true copy thereof to his immediate superior or to whomever was designated by the head of his department to receive such papers and such person shall promptly furnish copies of the pleadings and process therein to the United States attorney for the district embracing the place wherein the proceeding is brought, to the Attorney General, and to the head of his employing Federal agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon certification by the Attorney General that the defendant employee was acting within the scope of his office or employment at the time of the incident out of which the claim arose, any civil action or proceeding commenced upon such claim in a United States district court shall be deemed an action against the United States under the provisions of this title and all references thereto, and the United States shall be substituted as the party defendant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Upon certification by the Attorney General that the defendant employee was acting within the scope of his office or employment at the time of the incident out of which the claim arose, any civil action or proceeding commenced upon such claim in a State court shall be removed without bond at any time before trial by the Attorney General to the district court of the United States for the district and division embracing the place in which the action or proceeding is pending. Such action or proceeding shall be deemed to be an action or proceeding brought against the United States under the provisions of this title and all references thereto, and the United States shall be substituted as the party defendant. This certification of the Attorney General shall conclusively establish scope of office or employment for purposes of removal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the event that the Attorney General has refused to certify scope of office or employment under this section, the employee may at any time before trial petition the court to find and certify that the employee was acting within the scope of his office or employment. Upon such certification by the court, such action or proceeding shall be deemed to be an action or proceeding brought against the United States under the provisions of this title and all references thereto, and the United States shall be substituted as the party defendant. A copy of the petition shall be served upon the United States in accordance with the provisions of Rule 4(d)(4) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002106">1</ref> of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure. In the event the petition is filed in a civil action or proceeding pending in a State court, the action or proceeding may be removed without bond by the Attorney General to the district court of the United States for the district and division embracing the place in which it is pending. If, in considering the petition, the district court determines that the employee was not acting within the scope of his office or employment, the action or proceeding shall be remanded to the State court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Upon certification, any action or proceeding subject to paragraph (1), (2), or (3) shall proceed in the same manner as any action against the United States filed pursuant to <ref>section 1346(b) of this title</ref> and shall be subject to the limitations and exceptions applicable to those actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever an action or proceeding in which the United States is substituted as the party defendant under this subsection is dismissed for failure first to present a claim pursuant to <ref>section 2675(a) of this title</ref>, such a claim shall be deemed to be timely presented under <ref>section 2401(b) of this title</ref> if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the claim would have been timely had it been filed on the date the underlying civil action was commenced, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the claim is presented to the appropriate Federal agency within 60 days after dismissal of the civil action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may compromise or settle any claim asserted in such civil action or proceeding in the manner provided in section 2677, and with the same effect.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 984</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–258, § 1</ref>, <date date="1961-09-21">Sept. 21, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 539</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–506, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-07-18">July 18, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 307</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–694</ref>, §§ 5, 6, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4564</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2680.</num>
<heading> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The provisions of this chapter and <ref>section 1346(b) of this title</ref> shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Any claim based upon an act or omission of an employee of the Government, exercising due care, in the execution of a statute or regulation, whether or not such statute or regulation be valid, or based upon the exercise or performance or the failure to exercise or perform a discretionary function or duty on the part of a federal agency or an employee of the Government, whether or not the discretion involved be abused.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Any claim arising out of the loss, miscarriage, or negligent transmission of letters or postal matter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Any claim arising in respect of the assessment or collection of any tax or customs duty, or the detention of any goods, merchandise, or other property by any officer of customs or excise or any other law enforcement officer, except that the provisions of this chapter and <ref>section 1346(b) of this title</ref> apply to any claim based on injury or loss of goods, merchandise, or other property, while in the possession of any officer of customs or excise or any other law enforcement officer, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the property was seized for the purpose of forfeiture under any provision of Federal law providing for the forfeiture of property other than as a sentence imposed upon conviction of a criminal offense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the interest of the claimant was not forfeited;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the interest of the claimant was not remitted or mitigated (if the property was subject to forfeiture); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the claimant was not convicted of a crime for which the interest of the claimant in the property was subject to forfeiture under a Federal criminal forfeiture law..<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002107">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Any claim for which a remedy is provided by chapter 309 or 311 of title 46 relating to claims or suits in admiralty against the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Any claim arising out of an act or omission of any employee of the Government in administering the provisions of sections 1–31 of Title 50, Appendix.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002108">2</ref></content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> Any claim for damages caused by the imposition or establishment of a quarantine by the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(g)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Sept. 26, 1950, ch. 1049, § 13</ref> (5), <ref>64 Stat. 1043</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> Any claim arising out of assault, battery, false imprisonment, false arrest, malicious prosecution, abuse of process, libel, slander, misrepresentation, deceit, or interference with contract rights: <i>Provided</i>, That, with regard to acts or omissions of investigative or law enforcement officers of the United States Government, the provisions of this chapter and <ref>section 1346(b) of this title</ref> shall apply to any claim arising, on or after the date of the enactment of this proviso, out of assault, battery, false imprisonment, false arrest, abuse of process, or malicious prosecution. For the purpose of this subsection, “investigative or law enforcement officer” means any officer of the United States who is empowered by law to execute searches, to seize evidence, or to make arrests for violations of Federal law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Any claim for damages caused by the fiscal operations of the Treasury or by the regulation of the monetary system.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<content> Any claim arising out of the combatant activities of the military or naval forces, or the Coast Guard, during time of war.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(k)</num>
<content> Any claim arising in a foreign country.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(l)</num>
<content> Any claim arising from the activities of the Tennessee Valley Authority.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(m)</num>
<content> Any claim arising from the activities of the Panama Canal Company.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(n)</num>
<content> Any claim arising from the activities of a Federal land bank, a Federal intermediate credit bank, or a bank for cooperatives.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 984</ref>; <ref>July 16, 1949, ch. 340</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 444</ref>; <ref>Sept. 26, 1950, ch. 1049</ref>, §§ 2(a)(2), 13(5), <ref>64 Stat. 1038</ref>, 1043; <ref>Pub. L. 86–168, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-08-18">Aug. 18, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 389</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–253, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-03-16">Mar. 16, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 50</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–185, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-04-25">Apr. 25, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 211</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(f)(4)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>