<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 31—</num>
<heading>THE ATTORNEY GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Executive department</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of Justice is an executive department of the United States at the seat of Government.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 611</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Seal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall have a seal for the Department of Justice. The design of the seal is subject to the approval of the President.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 611</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, an Attorney General of the United States. The Attorney General is the head of the Department of Justice.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 612</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Deputy Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, a Deputy Attorney General.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 612</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–77, title VI, § 612(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-28">Nov. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 800</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4004(f)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1812</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504a.</num>
<heading> Associate Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, an Associate Attorney General.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–139, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-19">Oct. 19, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1171</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 505.</num>
<heading> Solicitor General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall appoint in the Department of Justice, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, a Solicitor General, learned in the law, to assist the Attorney General in the performance of his duties.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 612</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 506.</num>
<heading> Assistant Attorneys General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, 11 Assistant Attorneys General, who shall assist the Attorney General in the performance of his duties.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 612</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title II, § 218</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title V, § 506(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 507.</num>
<heading> Assistant Attorney General for Administration</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall appoint, with the approval of the President, an Assistant Attorney General for Administration, who shall perform such duties as the Attorney General may prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The position of Assistant Attorney General for Administration is in the competitive service.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 901 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, the Assistant Attorney General for Administration shall be the Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Justice.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 612</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(1) [title I, § 111]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–20.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 507A.</num>
<heading> Assistant Attorney General for National Security</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Of the Assistant Attorneys General appointed under section 506, one shall serve, upon the designation of the President, as the Assistant Attorney General for National Security.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The Assistant Attorney General for National Security shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve as the head of the National Security Division of the Department of Justice under <ref>section 509A of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> serve as primary liaison to the Director of National Intelligence for the Department of Justice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> perform such other duties as the Attorney General may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title V, § 506(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 508.</num>
<heading> Vacancies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In case of a vacancy in the office of Attorney General, or of his absence or disability, the Deputy Attorney General may exercise all the duties of that office, and for the purpose of <ref>section 3345 of title 5</ref> the Deputy Attorney General is the first assistant to the Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When by reason of absence, disability, or vacancy in office, neither the Attorney General nor the Deputy Attorney General is available to exercise the duties of the office of Attorney General, the Associate Attorney General shall act as Attorney General. The Attorney General may designate the Solicitor General and the Assistant Attorneys General, in further order of succession, to act as Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 612</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–139, § 2</ref>, <date date="1977-10-19">Oct. 19, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1171</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 509.</num>
<heading> Functions of the Attorney General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">All functions of other officers of the Department of Justice and all functions of agencies and employees of the Department of Justice are vested in the Attorney General except the functions—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> vested by subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 in administrative law judges employed by the Department of Justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> of the Federal Prison Industries, Inc.; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> of the Board of Directors and officers of the Federal Prison Industries, Inc.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 612</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–251, § 2(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1978-03-27">Mar. 27, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 183</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 228(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2030</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 204(d)</ref>, div. B, title IV, § 4003(b)(1), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1776</ref>, 1811.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 509A.</num>
<heading> National Security Division</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is a National Security Division of the Department of Justice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The National Security Division shall consist of the elements of the Department of Justice (other than the Federal Bureau of Investigation) engaged primarily in support of the intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, including the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Assistant Attorney General designated as the Assistant Attorney General for National Security under <ref>section 507A of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Office of Intelligence Policy and Review (or any successor organization).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The counterterrorism section (or any successor organization).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The counterespionage section (or any successor organization).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Any other element, component, or office designated by the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title V, § 506(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 509B.</num>
<heading> Section to enforce human rights laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the Human Rights Enforcement Act of 2009, the Attorney General shall establish a section within the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice with responsibility for the enforcement of laws against suspected participants in serious human rights offenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> The section established under subsection (a) is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> take appropriate legal action against individuals suspected of participating in serious human rights offenses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate any such legal action with the United States Attorney for the relevant jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall, as appropriate, consult with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In determining the appropriate legal action to take against individuals who are suspected of committing serious human rights offenses under Federal law, the section shall take into consideration the availability of criminal prosecution under the laws of the United States for such offenses or in a foreign jurisdiction that is prepared to undertake a prosecution for the conduct that forms the basis for such offenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The term “serious human rights offenses” includes violations of Federal criminal laws relating to genocide, torture, war crimes, and the use or recruitment of child soldiers under sections 1091, 2340, 2340A, 2441, and 2442 of title 18, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–122, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-22">Dec. 22, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3480</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 510.</num>
<heading> Delegation of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General may from time to time make such provisions as he considers appropriate authorizing the performance by any other officer, employee, or agency of the Department of Justice of any function of the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 612</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 511.</num>
<heading> Attorney General to advise the President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall give his advice and opinion on questions of law when required by the President.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 612</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 512.</num>
<heading> Attorney General to advise heads of executive departments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of an executive department may require the opinion of the Attorney General on questions of law arising in the administration of his department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 513.</num>
<heading> Attorney General to advise Secretaries of military departments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When a question of law arises in the administration of the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, or the Department of the Air Force, the cognizance of which is not given by statute to some other officer from whom the Secretary of the military department concerned may require advice, the Secretary of the military department shall send it to the Attorney General for disposition.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 514.</num>
<heading> Legal services on pending claims in departments and agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the head of an executive department or agency is of the opinion that the interests of the United States require the service of counsel on the examination of any witness concerning any claim, or on the legal investigation of any claim, pending in the department or agency, he shall notify the Attorney General, giving all facts necessary to enable him to furnish proper professional service in attending the examination or making the investigation, and the Attorney General shall provide for the service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 515.</num>
<heading> Authority for legal proceedings; commission, oath, and salary for special attorneys</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Attorney General or any other officer of the Department of Justice, or any attorney specially appointed by the Attorney General under law, may, when specifically directed by the Attorney General, conduct any kind of legal proceeding, civil or criminal, including grand jury proceedings and proceedings before committing magistrate judges, which United States attorneys are authorized by law to conduct, whether or not he is a resident of the district in which the proceeding is brought.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each attorney specially retained under authority of the Department of Justice shall be commissioned as special assistant to the Attorney General or special attorney, and shall take the oath required by law. Foreign counsel employed in special cases are not required to take the oath. The Attorney General shall fix the annual salary of a special assistant or special attorney.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 613</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 203(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 516.</num>
<heading> Conduct of litigation reserved to Department of Justice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise authorized by law, the conduct of litigation in which the United States, an agency, or officer thereof is a party, or is interested, and securing evidence therefor, is reserved to officers of the Department of Justice, under the direction of the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 517.</num>
<heading> Interests of United States in pending suits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Solicitor General, or any officer of the Department of Justice, may be sent by the Attorney General to any State or district in the United States to attend to the interests of the United States in a suit pending in a court of the United States, or in a court of a State, or to attend to any other interest of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 518.</num>
<heading> Conduct and argument of cases</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except when the Attorney General in a particular case directs otherwise, the Attorney General and the Solicitor General shall conduct and argue suits and appeals in the Supreme Court and suits in the United States Court of Federal Claims or in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit and in the Court of International Trade in which the United States is interested.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> When the Attorney General considers it in the interests of the United States, he may personally conduct and argue any case in a court of the United States in which the United States is interested, or he may direct the Solicitor General or any officer of the Department of Justice to do so.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 613</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–417, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1743</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 519.</num>
<heading> Supervision of litigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise authorized by law, the Attorney General shall supervise all litigation to which the United States, an agency, or officer thereof is a party, and shall direct all United States attorneys, assistant United States attorneys, and special attorneys appointed under <ref>section 543 of this title</ref> in the discharge of their respective duties.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 614</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 520.</num>
<heading> Transmission of petitions in United States Court of Federal Claims or in United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit; statement furnished by departments</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In suits against the United States in the United States Court of Federal Claims or in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit founded on a contract, agreement, or transaction with an executive department or military department, or a bureau, officer, or agent thereof, or when the matter or thing on which the claim is based has been passed on and decided by an executive department, military department, bureau, or officer authorized to adjust it, the Attorney General shall send to the department, bureau, or officer a printed copy of the petition filed by the claimant, with a request that the department, bureau, or officer furnish to the Attorney General all facts, circumstances, and evidence concerning the claim in the possession or knowledge of the department, bureau, or officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Within a reasonable time after receipt of the request from the Attorney General, the executive department, military department, bureau, or officer shall furnish the Attorney General with a written statement of all facts, information, and proofs. The statement shall contain a reference to or description of all official documents and papers, if any, as may furnish proof of facts referred to in it, or may be necessary and proper for the defense of the United States against the claim, mentioning the department, office, or place where the same is kept or may be secured. If the claim has been passed on and decided by the department, bureau, or officer, the statement shall briefly state the reasons and principles on which the decision was based. When the decision was founded on an Act of Congress it shall be cited specifically, and if any previous interpretation or construction has been given to the Act, section, or clause by the department, bureau, or officer, it shall be set forth briefly in the statement and a copy of the opinion filed, if any, attached to it. When a decision in the case has been based on a regulation of a department or when a regulation has, in the opinion of the department, bureau, or officer sending the statement, any bearing on the claim, it shall be distinctly quoted at length in the statement. When more than one case or class of cases is pending, the defense of which rests on the same facts, circumstances, and proofs, the department, bureau, or officer may certify and send one statement and it shall be held to apply to all cases as if made out, certified, and sent in each case respectively.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 614</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 118(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 521.</num>
<heading> Publication and distribution of opinions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General, from time to time—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall cause to be edited, and printed in the Government Publishing Office, such of his opinions as he considers valuable for preservation in volumes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may prescribe the manner for the distribution of the volumes.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each volume shall contain headnotes, an index, and such footnotes as the Attorney General may approve.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 614</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 522.</num>
<heading> Report of business and statistics</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General, by April 1 of each year, shall report to Congress on the business of the Department of Justice for the last preceding fiscal year, and on any other matters pertaining to the Department that he considers proper, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a statement of the several appropriations which are placed under the control of the Department and the amount appropriated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the statistics of crime under the laws of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a statement of the number of causes involving the United States, civil and criminal, pending during the preceding year in each of the several courts of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> With respect to any data, records, or other information acquired, collected, classified, preserved, or published by the Attorney General for any statistical, research, or other aggregate reporting purpose beginning not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002026">1</ref> 21st Century Department of Justice Appropriations Authorization Act and continuing thereafter, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the same criteria shall be used (and shall be required to be used, as applicable) to classify or categorize offenders and victims (in the criminal context), and to classify or categorize actors and acted upon (in the noncriminal context).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 615</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–273, § 19</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 379</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1776</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 523.</num>
<heading> Requisitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall sign all requisitions for the advance or payment of moneys appropriated for the Department of Justice, out of the Treasury, subject to the same control as is exercised on like estimates or accounts by the Government Accountability Office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 615</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 524.</num>
<heading> Availability of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Appropriations for the Department of Justice are available to the Attorney General for payment of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> notarial fees, including such additional stenographic services as are required in connection therewith in the taking of depositions, and compensation and expenses of witnesses and informants, all at the rates authorized or approved by the Attorney General or the Assistant Attorney General for Administration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> when ordered by the court, actual expenses of meals and lodging for marshals, deputy marshals, or criers when acting as bail­iffs in attendance on juries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, a claim of not more than $500 for expenses related to litigation that is beyond the control of the Department may be paid out of appropriations currently available to the Department for expenses related to litigation when the Comptroller General settles the payment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> There is established in the United States Treasury a special fund to be known as the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund (hereafter in this subsection referred to as the “Fund”) which shall be available to the Attorney General without fiscal year limitation for the following law enforcement purposes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the payment, at the discretion of the Attorney General, of any expenses necessary to seize, detain, inventory, safeguard, maintain, advertise, sell, or dispose of property under seizure, detention, or forfeited pursuant to any law enforced or administered by the Department of Justice, or of any other necessary expense incident to the seizure, detention, forfeiture, or disposal of such property including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> payments for—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> contract services;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the employment of outside contractors to operate and manage properties or provide other specialized services necessary to dispose of such properties in an effort to maximize the return from such properties; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> reimbursement of any Federal, State, or local agency for any expenditures made to perform the functions described in this clause;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> payments to reimburse any Federal agency participating in the Fund for investigative costs leading to seizures;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> payments for contracting for the services of experts and consultants needed by the Department of Justice to assist in carrying out duties related to asset seizure and forfeiture; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> payments made pursuant to guidelines promulgated by the Attorney General if such payments are necessary and directly related to seizure and forfeiture program expenses for—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the purchase or lease of automatic data processing systems (not less than a majority of which use will be related to such program);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> training;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> printing;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> the storage, protection, and destruction of controlled substances; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> contracting for services directly related to the identification of forfeitable assets, and the processing of and accounting for forfeitures;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the payment of awards for information or assistance directly relating to violations of the criminal drug laws of the United States or of chapter 77 of title 18, chapter 110 of title 18, sections 1956 and 1957 of title 18, sections 5313 and 5324 of title 31, and section 6050I of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> at the discretion of the Attorney General, the payment of awards for information or assistance leading to a civil or criminal forfeiture involving any Federal agency participating in the Fund;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the compromise and payment of valid liens and mortgages against property that has been forfeited pursuant to any law enforced or administered by the Department of Justice, subject to the discretion of the Attorney General to determine the validity of any such lien or mortgage and the amount of payment to be made, and the employment of attorneys and other personnel skilled in State real estate law as necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for disbursements authorized in connection with remission or mitigation procedures relating to property forfeited under any law enforced or administered by the Department of Justice; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> for payment for—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> costs incurred by or on behalf of the Department of Justice in connection with the removal, for purposes of Federal forfeiture and disposition, of any hazardous substance or pollutant or contaminant associated with the illegal manufacture of amphetamine or methamphetamine; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> costs incurred by or on behalf of a State or local government in connection with such removal in any case in which such State or local government has assisted in a Federal prosecution relating to amphetamine or methamphetamine, to the extent such costs exceed equitable sharing payments made to such State or local government in such case;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for equipping for law enforcement functions of any Government-owned or leased vessel, vehicle, or aircraft available for official use by any Federal agency participating in the Fund;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for equipping any vessel, vehicle, or aircraft available for official use by a State or local law enforcement agency to enable the vessel, vehicle, or aircraft to assist law enforcement functions if the vessel, vehicle, or aircraft will be used in a joint law enforcement operation with a Federal agency participating in the Fund; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> payments for other equipment directly related to seizure or forfeiture, including laboratory equipment, protective equipment, communications equipment, and the operation and maintenance costs of such equipment;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> for purchase of evidence of any violation of the Controlled Substances Act, the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act, chapter 96 of title 18, or sections 1956 and 1957 of title 18;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the payment of State and local property taxes on forfeited real property that accrued between the date of the violation giving rise to the forfeiture and the date of the forfeiture order;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> payment of overtime salaries, travel, fuel, training, equipment, and other similar costs of State or local law enforcement officers that are incurred in a joint law enforcement operation with a Federal law enforcement agency participating in the Fund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(J)</num>
<chapeau> at the discretion of the Attorney General, payments to reimburse operating expenses and program costs incurred by crime-tip organizations that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> annually waive their qualification for—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> awards for information leading to forfeiture under subparagraph (C); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> receiving payment from equitably shared forfeiture funds; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> offer rewards for information about violations of Federal criminal laws prohibiting human trafficking.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Amounts for paying the expenses authorized by subparagraphs (B), (F), and (G) shall be specified in appropriations Acts and may be used under authorities available to the organization receiving the funds. Amounts for other authorized expenditures and payments from the Fund, including equitable sharing payments, are not required to be specified in appropriations acts. The Attorney General may exempt the procurement of contract services under subparagraph (A) under the Fund from division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41, section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41, and other provisions of law as may be necessary to maintain the security and confidentiality of related criminal investigations.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any award paid from the Fund, as provided in paragraph (1)(B) or (C), shall be paid at the discretion of the Attorney General or his delegate, under existing departmental delegation policies for the payment of awards, except that the authority to pay an award of $250,000 or more shall not be delegated to any person other than the Deputy Attorney General, the Associate Attorney General, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration. Any award pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) shall not exceed $500,000. Any award pursuant to paragraph (1)(C) shall not exceed the lesser of $500,000 or one-fourth of the amount realized by the United States from the property forfeited, without both the personal approval of the Attorney General and written notice within 30 days thereof to the Chairmen and ranking minority members of the Committees on Appropriations and the Judiciary of the Senate and of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any amount under subparagraph (G) of paragraph (1) shall be paid at the discretion of the Attorney General or his delegate, except that the authority to pay $100,000 or more may be delegated only to the respective head of the agency involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> There shall be deposited in the Fund—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all amounts from the forfeiture of property under any law enforced or administered by the Department of Justice, except all proceeds of forfeitures available for use by the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to section 11(d) of the Endangered Species Act (<ref>16 U.S.C. 1540(d)</ref>) or section 6(d) of the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (<ref>16 U.S.C. 3375(d)</ref>), or the Postmaster General of the United States pursuant to <ref>39 U.S.C. 2003(b)(7)</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all amounts representing the Federal equitable share from the forfeiture of property under any Federal, State, local or foreign law, for any Federal agency participating in the Fund;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> all amounts transferred by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to <ref>section 9705(g)(4)(A) of title 31</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> all amounts collected—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> by the United States pursuant to a reimbursement order under paragraph (2) of section 413(q) of the Controlled Substances Act (<ref>21 U.S.C. 853(q)</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> pursuant to a restitution order under paragraph (1) or (3) of section 413(q) of the Controlled Substances Act for injuries to the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Amounts in the Fund, and in any holding accounts associated with the Fund, that are not currently needed for the purpose of this section shall be kept on deposit or invested in obligations of, or guaranteed by, the United States and all earnings on such investments shall be deposited in the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General shall transmit to Congress and make available to the public, not later than 4 months after the end of each fiscal year, detailed reports for the prior fiscal year as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> A report on total deposits to the Fund by State of deposit.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> A report on total expenses paid from the Fund, by category of expense and recipient agency, including equitable sharing payments.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> A report describing the number, value, and types of properties placed into official use by Federal agencies, by recipient agency.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> A report describing the number, value, and types of properties transferred to State and local law enforcement agencies, by recipient agency.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> A report, by type of disposition, describing the number, value, and types of forfeited property disposed of during the year.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> A report on the year-end inventory of property under seizure, but not yet forfeited, that reflects the type of property, its estimated value, and the estimated value of liens and mortgages outstanding on the property.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> A report listing each property in the year-end inventory, not yet forfeited, with an outstanding equity of not less than $1,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall transmit to Congress and make available to the public, not later than 2 months after final issuance, the audited financial statements for each fiscal year for the Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Reports under subparagraph (A) shall include information with respect to all forfeitures under any law enforced or administered by the Department of Justice.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> The transmittal and publication requirements in subparagraphs (A) and (B) may be satisfied by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> posting the reports on an Internet website maintained by the Department of Justice for a period of not less than 2 years; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> notifying the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate when the reports are available electronically.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The provisions of this subsection relating to deposits in the Fund shall apply to all property in the custody of the Department of Justice on or after the effective date of the Comprehensive Forfeiture Act of 1983.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(8)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as necessary for the purposes described in subparagraphs (B), (F), and (G) of paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraphs (C) and (D), at the end of each of fiscal years 1994, 1995, and 1996, the Attorney General shall transfer from the Fund not more than $100,000,000 to the Special Forfeiture Fund established by section 6073 of the Anti-Drug Abuse Act of 1988.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002027">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Transfers under subparagraph (B) may be made only from the excess unobligated balance and may not exceed one-half of the excess unobligated balance for any year. In addition, transfers under subparagraph (B) may be made only to the extent that the sum of the transfers in a fiscal year and one-half of the unobligated balance at the beginning of that fiscal year for the Special Forfeiture Fund does not exceed $100,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> For the purpose of determining amounts available for distribution at year end for any fiscal year, “excess unobligated balance” means the unobligated balance of the Fund generated by that fiscal year’s operations, less any amounts that are required to be retained in the Fund to ensure the availability of amounts in the subsequent fiscal year for purposes authorized under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Subject to the notification procedures contained in <ref>section 605 of Public Law 103–121</ref>, and after satisfying the transfer requirement in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, any excess unobligated balance remaining in the Fund on <date date="1997-09-30">September 30, 1997</date> and thereafter shall be available to the Attorney General, without fiscal year limitation, for any Federal law enforcement, litigative/prosecutive, and correctional activities, or any other authorized purpose of the Department of Justice. Any amounts provided pursuant to this subparagraph may be used under authorities available to the organization receiving the funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(9)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Following the completion of procedures for the forfeiture of property pursuant to any law enforced or administered by the Department, the Attorney General is authorized, in her discretion, to warrant clear title to any subsequent purchaser or transferee of such property.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For fiscal years 2002 and 2003, the Attorney General is authorized to transfer, under such terms and conditions as the Attorney General shall specify, real or personal property of limited or marginal value, to a State or local government agency, or its designated contractor or transferee, for use to support drug abuse treatment, drug and crime prevention and education, housing, job skills, and other community-based public health and safety programs. Each such transfer shall be subject to satisfaction by the recipient involved of any outstanding lien against the property transferred, but no such transfer shall create or confer any private right of action in any person against the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall transfer from the Fund to the Secretary of the Treasury for deposit in the Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund amounts appropriate to reflect the degree of participation of the Department of the Treasury law enforcement organizations (described in section 9705(<i>o</i>) of title 31) in the law enforcement effort resulting in the forfeiture pursuant to laws enforced or administered by the Department of Justice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subsection and notwithstanding <ref>section 9705 of title 31</ref> or any other law, property is forfeited pursuant to a law enforced or administered by the Department of Justice if it is forfeited pursuant to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a judicial forfeiture proceeding when the underlying seizure was made by an officer of a Federal law enforcement agency participating in the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund or the property was maintained by the United States Marshals Service; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a civil administrative forfeiture proceeding conducted by a Department of Justice law enforcement component or pursuant to the authority of the Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may accept, hold, administer, and use gifts, devises, and bequests of any property or services for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Department of Justice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Gifts, devises, and bequests of money, the proceeds of sale or liquidation of any other property accepted hereunder, and any income accruing from any property accepted hereunder—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be deposited in the Treasury in a separate fund and held in trust by the Secretary of the Treasury for the benefit of the Department of Justice; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are hereby appropriated, without fiscal year limitation, and shall be disbursed on order of the Attorney General.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Upon request of the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury may invest and reinvest the fund described herein in public debt securities with maturities suitable for the needs of the fund and bearing interest at rates determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States or comparable maturities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Evidences of any intangible personal property (other than money) accepted hereunder shall be deposited with the Secretary of the Treasury, who may hold or liquidate them, except that they shall be liquidated upon the request of the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For purposes of federal <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002028">2</ref> income, estate, and gift taxes, property accepted hereunder shall be considered a gift, devise, or bequest to, or for the use of, the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 615</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 2(g)(1)(B)</ref>–(D), <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1060</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II</ref>, §§ 310, 2303, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2052</ref>, 2193; <ref>Pub. L. 99–570, title I, § 1152(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3207–12</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 27</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(a) [title II, § 210(a)]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1329</ref>, 1329–18; <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6072</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4320</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–509, title III, § 1</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1403</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XVI, § 1601</ref>, title XX, §§ 2001(a), 2002, 2005, 2006, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4842</ref>, 4854, 4855; <ref>Pub. L. 102–27, title II, § 101</ref>, <date date="1991-04-10">Apr. 10, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 135</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–140, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 795</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–393, title VI, § 638(f)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1788</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–395, title I, § 114(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1845</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–550, title XV, § 1529</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4065</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–121, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1993-10-27">Oct. 27, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1164</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–317, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="1994-08-26">Aug. 26, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title IX, § 90205(b)</ref>, title XXXII, §§ 320301, 320302, 320913(a), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1994</ref>, 2114, 2128; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1091(h)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–91, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-01-06">Jan. 6, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 11</ref>, amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–99, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1996-01-26">Jan. 26, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 37</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101[(a)]</ref> [title I, § 122], <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1321</ref>, 1321–22; renumbered title I, <ref>Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1327</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(a) [title I, §§ 108, 114, 116, 117]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3009</ref>, 3009–18, 3009–22, 3009–23; <ref>Pub. L. 105–119, title I</ref>, §§ 108, 124, title II, § 211(b), <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2457</ref>, 2471, 2487; <ref>Pub. L. 105–272, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="1998-10-20">Oct. 20, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2413</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–185, § 19</ref>, <date date="2000-04-25">Apr. 25, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXVI</ref>, §§ 3613(b), 3621(a), <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1230</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3848</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, (c)(2)(A)(i), <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 237</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–392, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5251</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 525.</num>
<heading> Procurement of law books, reference books, and periodicals; sale and exchange</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the procurement of law books, reference books, and periodicals, the Attorney General may exchange or sell similar items and apply the exchange allowances or proceeds of such sales in whole or in part payment therefor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 615</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 526.</num>
<heading> Authority of Attorney General to investigate United States attorneys, marshals, trustees, clerks of court, and others</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The Attorney General may investigate the official acts, records, and accounts of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States attorneys, marshals, trustees, including trustees in cases under title 11; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at the request and on behalf of the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, the clerks of the United States courts and of the district court of the Virgin Islands, probation officers, United States magistrate judges, and court reporters;</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">for which purpose all the official papers, rec­ords, dockets, and accounts of these officers, without exception, may be examined by agents of the Attorney General at any time.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Appropriations for the examination of judicial officers are available for carrying out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 615</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–598, title II</ref>, §§ 219(a), (b), 220, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–554, title I, § 144(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3096</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. B, title IV, § 4003(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 527.</num>
<heading> Establishment of working capital fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be established a working capital fund for the Department of Justice, which shall be available, without fiscal year limitation, for expenses and equipment necessary for maintenance and operations of such administrative services as the Attorney General, with the approval of the Office of Management and Budget, determines may be performed more advantageously as central services. The capital of the fund shall consist of the amount of the fair and reasonable value of such inventories, equipment, and other assets and inventories on order pertaining to the services to be carried on by the fund as the Attorney General may transfer to the fund less related liabilities and unpaid obligations together with any appropriations made for the purpose of providing capital. The fund shall be reimbursed or credited with advance payments from applicable appropriations and funds of: (1) the Department of Justice, other Federal agencies, and other sources authorized by law for supplies, materials, and services; and (2) federally recognized tribes for supplies, materials, and services related to access to Federal law enforcement databases; at rates which will recover the expenses of operations including accrual of annual leave and depreciation of plant and equipment of the fund. The fund shall also be credited with other receipts from sale or exchange of property or in payment for loss or damage to property held by the fund. There shall be transferred into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts, as of the close of each fiscal year, any net income after making provisions for prior year losses, if any.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–613, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1975</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. B, title II, § 219</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 528.</num>
<heading> Disqualification of officers and employees of the Department of Justice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General shall promulgate rules and regulations which require the disqualification of any officer or employee of the Department of Justice, including a United States attorney or a member of such attorney’s staff, from participation in a particular investigation or prosecution if such participation may result in a personal, financial, or political conflict of interest, or the appearance thereof. Such rules and regulations may provide that a willful violation of any provision thereof shall result in removal from office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–521, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-26">Oct. 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1874</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 529.</num>
<heading> Annual report of Attorney General</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Beginning on <date date="1979-06-01">June 1, 1979</date>, and at the beginning of each regular session of Congress thereafter, the Attorney General shall report to Congress on the activities and operations of the Public Integrity Section or any other unit of the Department of Justice designated to supervise the investigation and prosecution of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any violation of Federal criminal law by any individual who holds or who at the time of such violation held a position, whether or not elective, as a Federal Government officer, employee, or special employee, if such violation relates directly or indirectly to such individual’s Federal Government position, employment, or compensation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any violation of any Federal criminal law relating to lobbying, conflict of interest, campaigns, and election to public office committed by any person, except insofar as such violation relates to a matter involving discrimination or intimidation on grounds of race, color, religion, or national origin;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any violation of Federal criminal law by any individual who holds or who at the time of such violation held a position, whether or not elective, as a State or local government officer or employee, if such violation relates directly or indirectly to such individual’s State or local government position, employment, or compensation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> such other matters as the Attorney General may deem appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such report shall include the number, type, and disposition of all investigations and prosecutions supervised by such Section or such unit, except that such report shall not disclose information which would interfere with any pending investigation or prosecution or which would improperly infringe upon the privacy rights of any individuals.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding any provision of law limiting the amount of management or administrative expenses, the Attorney General shall, not later than <date date="2003-05-02">May 2, 2003</date>, and of every year thereafter, prepare and provide to the Committees on the Judiciary and Appropriations of each House of the Congress using funds available for the underlying programs—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a report identifying and describing every grant (other than one made to a governmental entity, pursuant to a statutory formula), cooperative agreement, or programmatic services contract that was made, entered into, awarded, or, for which additional or supplemental funds were provided in the immediately preceding fiscal year, by or on behalf of the Office of Justice Programs (including any component or unit thereof, and the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services), and including, without limitation, for each such grant, cooperative agreement, or contract: the term, the dollar amount or value, a description of its specific purpose or purposes, the names of all grantees or parties, the names of each unsuccessful applicant or bidder, and a description of the specific purpose or purposes proposed in each unsuccessful application or bid, and of the reason or reasons for rejection or denial of the same; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a report identifying and reviewing every grant (other than one made to a governmental entity, pursuant to a statutory formula), cooperative agreement, or programmatic services contract made, entered into, awarded, or for which additional or supplemental funds were provided, after <date date="2002-10-01">October 1, 2002</date>, by or on behalf of the Office of Justice Programs (including any component or unit thereof, and the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services) that was programmatically and financially closed out or that otherwise ended in the immediately preceding fiscal year (or even if not yet closed out, was terminated or otherwise ended in the fiscal year that ended 2 years before the end of such immediately preceding fiscal year), and including, without limitation, for each such grant, cooperative agreement, or contract: a description of how the appropriated funds involved actually were spent, statistics relating to its performance, its specific purpose or purposes, and its effectiveness, and a written declaration by each non-Federal grantee and each non-Federal party to such agreement or to such contract, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the appropriated funds were spent for such purpose or purposes, and only such purpose or purposes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the terms of the grant, cooperative agreement, or contract were complied with; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> all documentation necessary for conducting a full and proper audit under generally accepted accounting principles, and any (additional) documentation that may have been required under the grant, cooperative agreement, or contract, have been kept in orderly fashion and will be preserved for not less than 3 years from the date of such close out, termination, or end;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that the requirement of this paragraph shall be deemed satisfied with respect to any such description, statistics, or declaration if such non-Federal grantee or such non-Federal party shall have failed to provide the same to the Attorney General, and the Attorney General notes the fact of such failure and the name of such grantee or such party in the report.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–521, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-26">Oct. 26, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1874</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, div. B, title IV, § 4003(b)(3), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1777</ref>, 1811.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 530.</num>
<heading> Payment of travel and transportation expenses of newly appointed special agents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General or the Attorney General’s designee is authorized to pay the travel expenses of newly appointed special agents and the transportation expenses of their families and household goods and personal effects from place of residence at time of selection to the first duty station, to the extent such payments are authorized by <ref>section 5723 of title 5</ref> for new appointees who may receive payments under that section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–86, § 1</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 530A.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations for travel and related expenses and for health care of personnel serving abroad</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be used from appropriations, for any fiscal year, for the Department of Justice, such sums as may be necessary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for travel and related expenses of employees of the Department of Justice serving abroad and their families, to be payable in the same manner as applicable with respect to the Foreign Service under paragraphs (2), (3), (5), (6), (8), (9), (11), and (15) of section 901 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980, and under the regulations issued by the Secretary of State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for health care for such employees and families, to be provided under section 904 of that Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6281(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4368</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–55, div. B, title II, § 218</ref>, <date date="2011-11-18">Nov. 18, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 621</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 530B.</num>
<heading> Ethical standards for attorneys for the Government</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> An attorney for the Government shall be subject to State laws and rules, and local Federal court rules, governing attorneys in each State where such attorney engages in that attorney’s duties, to the same extent and in the same manner as other attorneys in that State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall make and amend rules of the Department of Justice to assure compliance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> As used in this section, the term “attorney for the Government” includes any attorney described in section 77.2(a) of part 77 of title 28 of the Code of Federal Regulations and also includes any independent counsel, or employee of such a counsel, appointed under chapter 40.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 801(a)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–50</ref>, 2681–118.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 530C.</num>
<heading> Authority to use available funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Except to the extent provided otherwise by law, the activities of the Department of Justice (including any bureau, office, board, division, commission, subdivision, unit, or other component thereof) may, in the reasonable discretion of the Attorney General, be carried out through any means, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> through the Department’s own personnel, acting within, from, or through the Department itself;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by sending or receiving details of personnel to other branches or agencies of the Federal Government, on a reimbursable, partially-reimbursable, or nonreimbursable basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> through reimbursable agreements with other Federal agencies for work, materials, or equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> through contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements with non-Federal parties; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> as provided in subsection (b), in section 524, and in any other provision of law consistent herewith, including, without limitation, <ref>section 102(b) of Public Law 102–395</ref> (<ref>106 Stat. 1838</ref>), as incorporated by <ref>section 815(d) of Public Law 104–132</ref> (<ref>110 Stat. 1315</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Permitted Uses.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">General permitted uses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds available to the Attorney General (i.e., all funds available to carry out the activities described in subsection (a)) may be used, without limitation, for the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The purchase, lease, maintenance, and operation of passenger motor vehicles, or police-type motor vehicles for law enforcement purposes, without regard to general purchase price limitation for the then-current fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The purchase of insurance for motor vehicles, boats, and aircraft operated in official Government business in foreign countries.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Services of experts and consultants, including private counsel, as authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>, and at rates of pay for individuals not to exceed the maximum daily rate payable from time to time under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Official reception and representation expenses (i.e., official expenses of a social nature intended in whole or in predominant part to promote goodwill toward the Department or its missions, but excluding expenses of public tours of facilities of the Department of Justice), in accordance with distributions and procedures established, and rules issued, by the Attorney General, and expenses of public tours of facilities of the Department of Justice.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Unforeseen emergencies of a confidential character, to be expended under the direction of the Attorney General and accounted for solely on the certificate of the Attorney General.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Miscellaneous and emergency expenses authorized or approved by the Attorney General, the Deputy Attorney General, the Associate Attorney General, or the Assistant Attorney General for Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> In accordance with procedures established and rules issued by the Attorney General—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> attendance at meetings and seminars;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> conferences and training; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> advances of public moneys under <ref>section 3324 of title 31</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That travel advances of such moneys to law enforcement personnel engaged in undercover activity shall be considered to be public money for purposes of <ref>section 3527 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Contracting with individuals for personal services abroad, except that such individuals shall not be regarded as employees of the United States for the purpose of any law administered by the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Payment of interpreters and translators who are not citizens of the United States, in accordance with procedures established and rules issued by the Attorney General.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Expenses or allowances for uniforms as authorized by <ref>section 5901 of title 5</ref>, but without regard to the general purchase price limitation for the then-current fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<chapeau> Expenses of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> primary and secondary schooling for dependents of personnel stationed outside the United States at cost not in excess of those authorized by the Department of Defense for the same area, when it is determined by the Attorney General that schools available in the locality are unable to provide adequately for the education of such dependents; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> transportation of those dependents between their place of residence and schools serving the area which those dependents would normally attend when the Attorney General, under such regulations as he may prescribe, determines that such schools are not accessible by public means of transportation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<chapeau> payment of rewards (i.e., payments pursuant to public advertisements for assistance to the Department of Justice), in accordance with procedures and regulations established or issued by the Attorney General: <i>Provided</i>, That—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> no such reward shall exceed $3,000,000, unless—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the reward is to combat domestic terrorism or international terrorism (as defined in <ref>section 2331 of title 18</ref>); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a statute should authorize a higher amount;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> no such reward of $250,000 or more may be made or offered without the personal approval of either the Attorney General or the President;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Attorney General shall give written notice to the Chairmen and ranking minority members of the Committees on Appropriations and the Judiciary of the Senate and of the House of Representatives not later than 30 days after the approval of a reward under clause (ii);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any executive agency or military department (as defined, respectively, in sections 105 and 102 of title 5) may provide the Attorney General with funds for the payment of rewards; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> neither the failure of the Attorney General to authorize a payment nor the amount authorized shall be subject to judicial review.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> At the request of an appropriate law enforcement official of a State or political subdivision, the Attorney General may assist in the investigation of violent acts and shootings occurring in a place of public use and in the investigation of mass killings and attempted mass killings. Any assistance provided under this subparagraph shall be presumed to be within the scope of Federal office or employment.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002029">1</ref> For purposes of this subparagraph—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the term “mass killings” means 3 or more killings in a single incident; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the term “place of public use” has the meaning given that term under <ref>section 2332f(e)(6) of title 18</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Specific permitted uses.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Aircraft and boats</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds available to the Attorney General for United States Attorneys, for the Federal Bureau of Investigation, for the United States Marshals Service, for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, for the Drug Enforcement Administration, and for the Immigration and Naturalization Service may be used for the purchase, lease, maintenance, and operation of aircraft and boats, for law enforcement purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Purchase of ammunition and firearms; firearms competitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds available to the Attorney General for United States Attorneys, for the Federal Bureau of Investigation, for the United States Marshals Service, for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, for the Drug Enforcement Administration, for the Federal Prison System, for the Office of the Inspector General, and for the Immigration and Naturalization Service may be used for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the purchase of ammunition and firearms; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> participation in firearms competitions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds available to the Attorney General for construction may be used for expenses of planning, designing, acquiring, building, constructing, activating, renovating, converting, expanding, extending, remodeling, equipping, repairing, or maintaining buildings or facilities, including the expenses of acquisition of sites therefor, and all necessary expenses incident or related thereto; but the foregoing shall not be construed to mean that funds generally available for salaries and expenses are not also available for certain incidental or minor construction, activation, remodeling, maintenance, and other related construction costs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Fees and expenses of witnesses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds available to the Attorney General for fees and expenses of witnesses may be used for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> expenses, mileage, compensation, protection, and per diem in lieu of subsistence, of witnesses (including advances of public money) and as authorized by section 1821 or other law, except that no witness may be paid more than 1 attendance fee for any 1 calendar day;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> fees and expenses of neutrals in alternative dispute resolution proceedings, where the Department of Justice is a party; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> construction of protected witness safesites.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal bureau of investigation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds available to the Attorney General for the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the detection, investigation, and prosecution of crimes against the United States may be used for the conduct of all its authorized activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Immigration and naturalization service</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds available to the Attorney General for the Immigration and Naturalization Service may be used for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> acquisition of land as sites for enforcement fences, and construction incident to such fences;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> cash advances to aliens for meals and lodging en route;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> refunds of maintenance bills, immigration fines, and other items properly returnable, except deposits of aliens who become public charges and deposits to secure payment of fines and passage money; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> expenses and allowances incurred in tracking lost persons, as required by public exigencies, in aid of State or local law enforcement agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Federal prison system</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Funds available to the Attorney General for the Federal Prison System may be used for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> inmate medical services and inmate legal services, within the Federal prison system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the purchase and exchange of farm products and livestock;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the acquisition of land as provided in <ref>section 4010 of title 18</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the construction of buildings and facilities for penal and correctional institutions (including prison camps), by contract or force account, including the payment of United States prisoners for their work performed in any such construction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that no funds may be used to distribute or make available to a prisoner any commercially published information or material that is sexually explicit or features nudity.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Detention trustee</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds available to the Attorney General for the Detention Trustee may be used for all the activities of such Trustee in the exercise of all power and functions authorized by law relating to the detention of Federal prisoners in non-Federal institutions or otherwise in the custody of the United States Marshals Service and to the detention of aliens in the custody of the Immigration and Naturalization Service, including the overseeing of construction of detention facilities or for housing related to such detention, the management of funds appropriated to the Department for the exercise of detention functions, and the direction of the United States Marshals Service and Immigration Service with respect to the exercise of detention policy setting and operations for the Department of Justice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Related Provisions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitation of compensation of individuals employed as attorneys</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No funds available to the Attorney General may be used to pay compensation for services provided by an individual employed as an attorney (other than an individual employed to provide services as a foreign attorney in special cases) unless such individual is duly licensed and authorized to practice as an attorney under the law of a State, a territory of the United States, or the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reimbursements paid to governmental entities</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Funds available to the Attorney General that are paid as reimbursement to a governmental unit of the Department of Justice, to another Federal entity, or to a unit of State or local government, may be used under authorities available to the unit or entity receiving such reimbursement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Foreign Reimbursements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Whenever the Department of Justice or any component participates in a cooperative project to improve law enforcement or national security operations or services with a friendly foreign country on a cost-sharing basis, any reimbursements or contributions received from that foreign country to meet its share of the project may be credited to appropriate current appropriations accounts of the Department of Justice or any component. The amount of a reimbursement or contribution credited shall be available only for payment of the share of the project expenses allocated to the participating foreign country.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Railroad Police Training Fees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General is authorized to establish and collect a fee to defray the costs of railroad police officers participating in a Federal Bureau of Investigation law enforcement training program authorized by <ref>Public Law 106–110</ref>, and to credit such fees to the appropriation account “Federal Bureau of Investigation, Salaries and Expenses”, to be available until expended for salaries and expenses incurred in providing such services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Warranty Work</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In instances where the Attorney General determines that law enforcement-, security-, or mission-related considerations mitigate against obtaining maintenance or repair services from private sector entities for equipment under warranty, the Attorney General is authorized to seek reimbursement from such entities for warranty work performed at Department of Justice facilities, and to credit any payment made for such work to any appropriation charged therefor.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1767</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. B, title I</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 53</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–265, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2435</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 530D.</num>
<heading> Report on enforcement of laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Attorney General shall submit to the Congress a report of any instance in which the Attorney General or any officer of the Department of Justice—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> establishes or implements a formal or informal policy to refrain—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> from enforcing, applying, or administering any provision of any Federal statute, rule, regulation, program, policy, or other law whose enforcement, application, or administration is within the responsibility of the Attorney General or such officer on the grounds that such provision is unconstitutional; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> within any judicial jurisdiction of or within the United States, from adhering to, enforcing, applying, or complying with, any standing rule of decision (binding upon courts of, or inferior to those of, that jurisdiction) established by a final decision of any court of, or superior to those of, that jurisdiction, respecting the interpretation, construction, or application of the Constitution, any statute, rule, regulation, program, policy, or other law whose enforcement, application, or administration is within the responsibility of the Attorney General or such officer;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> determines—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to contest affirmatively, in any judicial, administrative, or other proceeding, the constitutionality of any provision of any Federal statute, rule, regulation, program, policy, or other law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to refrain (on the grounds that the provision is unconstitutional) from defending or asserting, in any judicial, administrative, or other proceeding, the constitutionality of any provision of any Federal statute, rule, regulation, program, policy, or other law, or not to appeal or request review of any judicial, administrative, or other determination adversely affecting the constitutionality of any such provision; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> approves (other than in circumstances in which a report is submitted to the Joint Committee on Taxation, pursuant to section 6405 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) the settlement or compromise (other than in bankruptcy) of any claim, suit, or other action—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> against the United States (including any agency or instrumentality thereof) for a sum that exceeds, or is likely to exceed, $2,000,000, excluding prejudgment interest; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> by the United States (including any agency or instrumentality thereof) pursuant to an agreement, consent decree, or order (or pursuant to any modification of an agreement, consent decree, or order) that provides injunctive or other nonmonetary relief that exceeds, or is likely to exceed, 3 years in duration: <i>Provided</i>, That for purposes of this clause, the term “injunctive or other nonmonetary relief” shall not be understood to include the following, where the same are a matter of public record—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> debarments, suspensions, or other exclusions from Government contracts or grants;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> mere reporting requirements or agreements (including sanctions for failure to report);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> requirements or agreements merely to comply with statutes or regulations;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> requirements or agreements to surrender professional licenses or to cease the practice of professions, occupations, or industries;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> any criminal sentence or any requirements or agreements to perform community service, to serve probation, or to participate in supervised release from detention, confinement, or prison; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> agreements to cooperate with the government in investigations or prosecutions (whether or not the agreement is a matter of public record).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Submission of report to the congress</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For the purposes of paragraph (1), a report shall be considered to be submitted to the Congress if the report is submitted to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the majority leader and minority leader of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Speaker, majority leader, and minority leader of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Senate Legal Counsel and the General Counsel of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A report shall be submitted—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> under subsection (a)(1)(A), not later than 30 days after the establishment or implementation of each policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> under subsection (a)(1)(B), within such time as will reasonably enable the House of Representatives and the Senate to take action, separately or jointly, to intervene in timely fashion in the proceeding, but in no event later than 30 days after the making of each determination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> under subsection (a)(1)(C), not later than 30 days after the conclusion of each fiscal-year quarter, with respect to all approvals occurring in such quarter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A report required by subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> specify the date of the establishment or implementation of the policy described in subsection (a)(1)(A), of the making of the determination described in subsection (a)(1)(B), or of each approval described in subsection (a)(1)(C);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> include a complete and detailed statement of the relevant issues and background (including a complete and detailed statement of the reasons for the policy or determination, and the identity of the officer responsible for establishing or implementing such policy, making such determination, or approving such settlement or compromise), except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such details may be omitted as may be absolutely necessary to prevent improper disclosure of national-security- or classified information, of any information subject to the deliberative-process-, executive-, attorney-work-product-, or attorney-client privileges, or of any information the disclosure of which is prohibited by section 6103 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or other law or any court order if the fact of each such omission (and the precise ground or grounds therefor) is clearly noted in the statement: <i>Provided</i>, That this subparagraph shall not be construed to deny to the Congress (including any House, Committee, or agency thereof) any such omitted details (or related information) that it lawfully may seek, subsequent to the submission of the report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the requirements of this paragraph shall be deemed satisfied—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of an approval described in subsection (a)(1)(C)(i), if an unredacted copy of the entire settlement agreement and consent decree or order (if any) is provided, along with a statement indicating the legal and factual basis or bases for the settlement or compromise (if not apparent on the face of documents provided); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of an approval described in subsection (a)(1)(C)(ii), if an unredacted copy of the entire settlement agreement and consent decree or order (if any) is provided, along with a statement indicating the injunctive or other nonmonetary relief (if not apparent on the face of documents provided); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of a determination described in subsection (a)(1)(B) or an approval described in subsection (a)(1)(C), indicate the nature, tribunal, identifying information, and status of the proceeding, suit, or action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Declaration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In the case of a determination described in subsection (a)(1)(B), the representative of the United States participating in the proceeding shall make a clear declaration in the proceeding that any position expressed as to the constitutionality of the provision involved is the position of the executive branch of the Federal Government (or, as applicable, of the President or of any executive agency or military department).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability to the President and to Executive Agencies and Military Departments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The reporting, declaration, and other provisions of this section relating to the Attorney General and other officers of the Department of Justice shall apply to the President (but only with respect to the promulgation of any unclassified Executive order or similar memorandum or order), to the head of each executive agency or military department (as defined, respectively, in sections 105 and 102 of title 5, United States Code) that establishes or implements a policy described in subsection (a)(1)(A) or is authorized to conduct litigation, and to the officers of such executive agency.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1771</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>