<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 19—</num>
<heading>DISTRIBUTION OF REPORTS AND DIGESTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 411.</num>
<heading> Supreme Court reports; printing, binding, and distribution</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The decisions of the Supreme Court of the United States shall be printed, bound, and distributed in the preliminary prints and bound volumes of the United States Reports as soon as practicable after rendition, to be charged to the proper appropriation for the judiciary. The number and distribution of the copies shall be under the control of the Joint Committee on Printing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Reports printed prior to <date date="1926-06-12">June 12, 1926</date>, shall not be furnished the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Navy, or the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The Director of the Government Publishing Office, or other printer designated by the Supreme Court of the United States, upon request, shall furnish to the Superintendent of Documents the reports required to be distributed under the provisions of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 904</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 68</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 99</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 41</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref>July 10, 1952, ch. 632, § 4</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 540</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 412.</num>
<heading> Sale of Supreme Court reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Government Publishing Office, or other printer designated by the Supreme Court of the United States shall print such additional bound volumes and preliminary prints of such reports as may be required for sale to the public. Such additional copies shall be sold by the Superintendent of Documents, as provided by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 906</ref>; <ref>July 10, 1952, ch. 632, § 5</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 541</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 413.</num>
<heading> Publications; distribution to courts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Distribution of publications to Federal courts in accordance with the provisions of this chapter shall not be made to any place where such court is held in a building not owned or controlled by the United States unless such publications are committed to the custody of an officer of the United States at such building.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General and the Director in the procurement of law books, books of reference or periodicals may exchange or sell similar items and apply the allowance or proceeds to payment in whole or in part of the cost of the items procured.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 906</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 69</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 100</ref>; <ref>July 10, 1952, ch. 632, § 6</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 541</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 414.</num>
<heading> Transmittal of books to successors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All government publications and law books furnished to justices, judges, clerks of courts, and United States attorneys of the United States and its territories and possessions, and other officers of the United States or an agency thereof shall be transmitted to their successors in office. All permanent or bound books and publications furnished under this chapter except those books furnished to the Library of Congress for international exchange shall remain the property of the United States and shall be marked plainly, “The Property of the United States”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 906</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–845, § 7</ref>, <date date="1962-10-18">Oct. 18, 1962</date>, <ref>76A Stat. 699</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 415.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 29</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>