<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 91—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES COURT OF FEDERAL CLAIMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1491.</num>
<heading> Claims against United States generally; actions involving Tennessee Valley Authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to render judgment upon any claim against the United States founded either upon the Constitution, or any Act of Congress or any regulation of an executive department, or upon any express or implied contract with the United States, or for liquidated or unliquidated damages in cases not sounding in tort. For the purpose of this paragraph, an express or implied contract with the Army and Air Force Exchange Service, Navy Exchanges, Marine Corps Exchanges, Coast Guard Exchanges, or Exchange Councils of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall be considered an express or implied contract with the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To provide an entire remedy and to complete the relief afforded by the judgment, the court may, as an incident of and collateral to any such judgment, issue orders directing restoration to office or position, placement in appropriate duty or retirement status, and correction of applicable records, and such orders may be issued to any appropriate official of the United States. In any case within its jurisdiction, the court shall have the power to remand appropriate matters to any administrative or executive body or official with such direction as it may deem proper and just. The Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to render judgment upon any claim by or against, or dispute with, a contractor arising under <ref>section 7104(b)(1) of title 41</ref>, including a dispute concerning termination of a contract, rights in tangible or intangible property, compliance with cost accounting standards, and other nonmonetary disputes on which a decision of the contracting officer has been issued under section 6 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002073">1</ref> of that Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Both the Unites <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002074">2</ref> States Court of Federal Claims and the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction to render judgment on an action by an interested party objecting to a solicitation by a Federal agency for bids or proposals for a proposed contract or to a proposed award or the award of a contract or any alleged violation of statute or regulation in connection with a procurement or a proposed procurement. Both the United States Court of Federal Claims and the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction to entertain such an action without regard to whether suit is instituted before or after the contract is awarded.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To afford relief in such an action, the courts may award any relief that the court considers proper, including declaratory and injunctive relief except that any monetary relief shall be limited to bid preparation and proposal costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In exercising jurisdiction under this subsection, the courts shall give due regard to the interests of national defense and national security and the need for expeditious resolution of the action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In any action under this subsection, the courts shall review the agency’s decision pursuant to the standards set forth in <ref>section 706 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> If an interested party who is a member of the private sector commences an action described in paragraph (1) with respect to a public-private competition conducted under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 regarding the performance of an activity or function of a Federal agency, or a decision to convert a function performed by Federal employees to private sector performance without a competition under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76, then an interested party described in <ref>section 3551(2)(B) of title 31</ref> shall be entitled to intervene in that action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Jurisdiction over any action described in paragraph (1) arising out of a maritime contract, or a solicitation for a proposed maritime contract, shall be governed by this section and shall not be subject to the jurisdiction of the district courts of the United States under the Suits in Admiralty Act (chapter 309 of title 46) or the Public Vessels Act (chapter 311 of title 46).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Nothing herein shall be construed to give the United States Court of Federal Claims jurisdiction of any civil action within the exclusive jurisdiction of the Court of International Trade, or of any action against, or founded on conduct of, the Tennessee Valley Authority, or to amend or modify the provisions of the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 with respect to actions by or against the Authority.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 940</ref>; <ref>July 28, 1953, ch. 253, § 7</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 226</ref>; <ref>Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 44(a)</ref>, (b), <ref>68 Stat. 1241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–350, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1970-07-23">July 23, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 449</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–415, § 1</ref>, <date date="1972-08-29">Aug. 29, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 652</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–563, § 14(i)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2391</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–417, title V, § 509</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 1743</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 39</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX</ref>, §§ 902(a), 907(b)(1), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>, 4519; <ref>Pub. L. 104–320, § 12(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3874</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. D, title VII, § 739(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2031</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title III, § 326(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 63</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title X, § 1061(d), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 4613</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(g)(7)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3848</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 861(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1521</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1492.</num>
<heading> Congressional reference cases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any bill, except a bill for a pension, may be referred by either House of Congress to the chief judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims for a report in conformity with <ref>section 2509 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–681, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 958</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1493.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>July 28, 1953, ch. 253, § 8</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 226</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1494.</num>
<heading> Accounts of officers, agents or contractors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to determine the amount, if any, due to or from the United States by reason of any unsettled account of any officer or agent of, or contractor with, the United States, or a guarantor, surety or personal representative of any such officer, agent or contractor, and to render judgment thereof,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002075">1</ref> where—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> claimant or the person he represents has applied to the proper department of the Government for settlement of the account;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> three years have elapsed from the date of such application without settlement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> no suit upon the same has been brought by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 941</ref>; <ref>July 28, 1953, ch. 253, § 9</ref>, <ref>67 Stat. 226</ref>; <ref>Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 44(c)</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1495.</num>
<heading> Damages for unjust conviction and imprisonment; claim against United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to render judgment upon any claim for damages by any person unjustly convicted of an offense against the United States and imprisoned.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1496.</num>
<heading> Disbursing officers’ claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to render judgment upon any claim by a disbursing officer of the United States or by his administrator or executor for relief from responsibility for loss, in line of duty, of Government funds, vouchers, records or other papers in his charge.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1497.</num>
<heading> Oyster growers’ damages from dredging operations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to render judgment upon any claim for damages to oyster growers on private or leased lands or bottoms arising from dredging operations or use of other machinery and equipment in making river and harbor improvements authorized by Act of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(c)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1498.</num>
<heading> Patent and copyright cases</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Whenever an invention described in and covered by a patent of the United States is used or manufactured by or for the United States without license of the owner thereof or lawful right to use or manufacture the same, the owner’s remedy shall be by action against the United States in the United States Court of Federal Claims for the recovery of his reasonable and entire compensation for such use and manufacture. Reasonable and entire compensation shall include the owner’s reasonable costs, including reasonable fees for expert witnesses and attorneys, in pursuing the action if the owner is an independent inventor, a nonprofit organization, or an entity that had no more than 500 employees at any time during the 5-year period preceding the use or manufacture of the patented invention by or for the United States. Nothwithstanding <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002076">1</ref> the preceding sentences, unless the action has been pending for more than 10 years from the time of filing to the time that the owner applies for such costs and fees, reasonable and entire compensation shall not include such costs and fees if the court finds that the position of the United States was substantially justified or that special circumstances make an award unjust.<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the use or manufacture of an invention described in and covered by a patent of the United States by a contractor, a subcontractor, or any person, firm, or corporation for the Government and with the authorization or consent of the Government, shall be construed as use or manufacture for the United States.</p>
<p class="indent0">The court shall not award compensation under this section if the claim is based on the use or manufacture by or for the United States of any article owned, leased, used by, or in the possession of the United States prior to <date date="1918-07-01">July 1, 1918</date>.</p>
<p class="indent0">A Government employee shall have the right to bring suit against the Government under this section except where he was in a position to order, influence, or induce use of the invention by the Government. This section shall not confer a right of action on any patentee or any assignee of such patentee with respect to any invention discovered or invented by a person while in the employment or service of the United States, where the invention was related to the official functions of the employee, in cases in which such functions included research and development, or in the making of which Government time, materials or facilities were used.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Hereafter, whenever the copyright in any work protected under the copyright laws of the United States shall be infringed by the United States, by a corporation owned or controlled by the United States, or by a contractor, subcontractor, or any person, firm, or corporation acting for the Government and with the authorization or consent of the Government, the exclusive action which may be brought for such infringement shall be an action by the copyright owner against the United States in the Court of Federal Claims for the recovery of his reasonable and entire compensation as damages for such infringement, including the minimum statutory damages as set forth in <ref>section 504(c) of title 17</ref>, United States Code: <i>Provided</i>, That a Government employee shall have a right of action against the Government under this subsection except where he was in a position to order, influence, or induce use of the copyrighted work by the Government: <i>Provided, however</i>, That this subsection shall not confer a right of action on any copyright owner or any assignee of such owner with respect to any copyrighted work prepared by a person while in the employment or service of the United States, where the copyrighted work was prepared as a part of the official functions of the employee, or in the preparation of which Government time, material, or facilities were used: <i>And provided further</i>, That before such action against the United States has been instituted the appropriate corporation owned or controlled by the United States or the head of the appropriate department or agency of the Government, as the case may be, is authorized to enter into an agreement with the copyright owner in full settlement and compromise for the damages accruing to him by reason of such infringement and to settle the claim administratively out of available appropriations.<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided by law, no recovery shall be had for any infringement of a copyright covered by this subsection committed more than three years prior to the filing of the complaint or counterclaim for infringement in the action, except that the period between the date of receipt of a written claim for compensation by the Department or agency of the Government or corporation owned or controlled by the United States, as the case may be, having authority to settle such claim and the date of mailing by the Government of a notice to the claimant that his claim has been denied shall not be counted as a part of the three years, unless suit is brought before the last-mentioned date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The provisions of this section shall not apply to any claim arising in a foreign country.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> Hereafter, whenever a plant variety protected by a certificate of plant variety protection under the laws of the United States shall be infringed by the United States, by a corporation owned or controlled by the United States, or by a contractor, subcontractor, or any person, firm, or corporation acting for the Government, and with the authorization and consent of the Government, the exclusive remedy of the owner of such certificate shall be by action against the United States in the Court of Federal Claims for the recovery of his reasonable and entire compensation as damages for such infringement: <i>Provided</i>, That a Government employee shall have a right of action against the Government under this subsection except where he was in a position to order, influence, or induce use of the protected plant variety by the Government: <i>Provided, however</i>, That this subsection shall not confer a right of action on any certificate owner or any assignee of such owner with respect to any protected plant variety made by a person while in the employment or service of the United States, where such variety was prepared as a part of the official functions of the employee, or in the preparation of which Government time, material, or facilities were used: <i>And provided further</i>, That before such action against the United States has been instituted, the appropriate corporation owned or controlled by the United States or the head of the appropriate agency of the Government, as the case may be, is authorized to enter into an agreement with the certificate owner in full settlement and compromise, for the damages accrued to him by reason of such infringement and to settle the claim administratively out of available appropriations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> Subsections (b) and (c) of this section apply to exclusive rights in mask works under chapter 9 of title 17, and to exclusive rights in designs under chapter 13 of title 17, to the same extent as such subsections apply to copyrights.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 941</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 87</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 102</ref>; <ref>Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 50(c)</ref>, <ref>65 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref>July 17, 1952, ch. 930</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 757</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–726</ref>, §§ 1, 4, <date date="1960-09-08">Sept. 8, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 855</ref>, 856; <ref>Pub. L. 91–577, title III, § 143(d)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1559</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–553, title I, § 105(c)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2599</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(d)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–702, title X, § 1020(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 4671</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–308, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–147, § 3</ref>, <date date="1997-12-16">Dec. 16, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2680</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–304, title V, § 503(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2917</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1499.</num>
<heading> Liquidated damages withheld from contractors under chapter 37 of title 40</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to render judgment upon any claim for liquidated damages withheld from a contractor or subcontractor under <ref>section 3703 of title 40</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 942</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–581, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-08-13">Aug. 13, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(e)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 40</ref>, 41; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 325(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1299</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–284, § 4(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1211</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1500.</num>
<heading> Pendency of claims in other courts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Court of Federal Claims shall not have jurisdiction of any claim for or in respect to which the plaintiff or his assignee has pending in any other court any suit or process against the United States or any person who, at the time when the cause of action alleged in such suit or process arose, was, in respect thereto, acting or professing to act, directly or indirectly under the authority of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 942</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1501.</num>
<heading> Pensions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Court of Federal Claims shall not have jurisdiction of any claim for a pension.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 942</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1502.</num>
<heading> Treaty cases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided by Act of Congress, the United States Court of Federal Claims shall not have jurisdiction of any claim against the United States growing out of or dependent upon any treaty entered into with foreign nations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 942</ref>; <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 88</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 102</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1503.</num>
<heading> Set-offs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to render judgment upon any set-off or demand by the United States against any plaintiff in such court.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref>62 Stat. 942</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1504.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(f)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 41</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1505.</num>
<heading> Indian claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction of any claim against the United States accruing after <date date="1946-08-13">August 13, 1946</date>, in favor of any tribe, band, or other identifiable group of American Indians residing within the territorial limits of the United States or Alaska whenever such claim is one arising under the Constitution, laws or treaties of the United States, or Executive orders of the President, or is one which otherwise would be cognizable in the Court of Federal Claims if the claimant were not an Indian tribe, band or group.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 89(a)</ref>, <ref>63 Stat. 102</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(g)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 41</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 1506.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(h)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 41</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1507.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction for certain declaratory judgments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to hear any suit for and issue a declaratory judgment under section 7428 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIII, § 1306(b)(9)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1720</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(i)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 41</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1508.</num>
<heading> Jurisdiction for certain partnership proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to hear and to render judgment upon any petition under section 6226 or 6228(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title IV, § 402(c)(18)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 669</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1509.</num>
<heading> No jurisdiction in cases involving refunds of tax shelter promoter and understatement penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Court of Federal Claims shall not have jurisdiction to hear any action or proceeding for any refund or credit of any penalty imposed under section 6700 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to penalty for promoting abusive tax shelters, etc.) or section 6701 of such Code (relating to penalties for aiding and abetting understatement of tax liability).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 714(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 962</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>