<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 35—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES ATTORNEYS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 541.</num>
<heading> United States attorneys</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The President shall appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, a United States attorney for each judicial district.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each United States attorney shall be appointed for a term of four years. On the expiration of his term, a United States attorney shall continue to perform the duties of his office until his successor is appointed and qualifies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Each United States attorney is subject to removal by the President.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 617</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 542.</num>
<heading> Assistant United States attorneys</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may appoint one or more assistant United States attorneys in any district when the public interest so requires.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each assistant United States attorney is subject to removal by the Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 543.</num>
<heading> Special attorneys</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may appoint attorneys to assist United States attorneys when the public interest so requires, including the appointment of qualified tribal prosecutors and other qualified attorneys to assist in prosecuting Federal offenses committed in Indian country.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Each attorney appointed under this section is subject to removal by the Attorney General.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Indian Country</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In this section, the term “Indian country” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1151 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 618</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 213(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2268</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 544.</num>
<heading> Oath of office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each United States attorney, assistant United States attorney, and attorney appointed under <ref>section 543 of this title</ref>, before taking office, shall take an oath to execute faithfully his duties.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 545.</num>
<heading> Residence</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Each United States attorney shall reside in the district for which he is appointed, except that these officers of the District of Columbia, the Southern District of New York, and the Eastern District of New York may reside within 20 miles thereof. Each assistant United States attorney shall reside in the district for which he or she is appointed or within 25 miles thereof. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to any United States attorney or assistant United States attorney appointed for the Northern Mariana Islands who at the same time is serving in the same capacity in another district. Pursuant to an order from the Attorney General or his designee, a United States attorney or an assistant United States attorney may be assigned dual or additional responsibilities that exempt such officer from the residency requirement in this subsection for a specific period as established by the order and subject to renewal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Attorney General may determine the official stations of United States attorneys and assistant United States attorneys within the districts for which they are appointed.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 618</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–530, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2028</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–91</ref>, <date date="1979-10-25">Oct. 25, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320932</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 2135</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 246</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 546.</num>
<heading> Vacancies</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subsection (b), the Attorney General may appoint a United States attorney for the district in which the office of United States attorney is vacant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Attorney General shall not appoint as United States attorney a person to whose appointment by the President to that office the Senate refused to give advice and consent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> A person appointed as United States attorney under this section may serve until the earlier of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the qualification of a United States attorney for such district appointed by the President under <ref>section 541 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the expiration of 120 days after appointment by the Attorney General under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> If an appointment expires under subsection (c)(2), the district court for such district may appoint a United States attorney to serve until the vacancy is filled. The order of appointment by the court shall be filed with the clerk of the court.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 618</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–646, § 69</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3616</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 246</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–34, § 2</ref>, <date date="2007-06-14">June 14, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 547.</num>
<heading> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided by law, each United States attorney, within his district, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> prosecute for all offenses against the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prosecute or defend, for the Government, all civil actions, suits or proceedings in which the United States is concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> appear in behalf of the defendants in all civil actions, suits or proceedings pending in his district against collectors, or other officers of the revenue or customs for any act done by them or for the recovery of any money exacted by or paid to these officers, and by them paid into the Treasury;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> institute and prosecute proceedings for the collection of fines, penalties, and forfeitures incurred for violation of any revenue law, unless satisfied on investigation that justice does not require the proceedings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> make such reports as the Attorney General may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 548.</num>
<heading> Salaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to sections 5315 through 5317 of title 5, the Attorney General shall fix the annual salaries of United States attorneys, assistant United States attorneys, and attorneys appointed under <ref>section 543 of this title</ref> at rates of compensation not in excess of the rate of basic compensation provided for Executive Level IV of the Executive Schedule set forth in <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 618</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1701(a)</ref> <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 2184</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 549.</num>
<heading> Expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Necessary office expenses of United States attorneys shall be allowed when authorized by the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 550.</num>
<heading> Clerical assistants, messengers, and private process servers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States attorneys may employ clerical assistants, messengers, and private process servers on approval of the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 619</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXVI, § 3626(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 4965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>