<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 97—</num>
<heading>JURISDICTIONAL IMMUNITIES OF FOREIGN STATES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1602.</num>
<heading> Findings and declaration of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress finds that the determination by United States courts of the claims of foreign states to immunity from the jurisdiction of such courts would serve the interests of justice and would protect the rights of both foreign states and litigants in United States courts. Under international law, states are not immune from the jurisdiction of foreign courts insofar as their commercial activities are concerned, and their commercial property may be levied upon for the satisfaction of judgments rendered against them in connection with their commercial activities. Claims of foreign states to immunity should henceforth be decided by courts of the United States and of the States in conformity with the principles set forth in this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–583, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2892</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1603.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A “foreign state”, except as used in <ref>section 1608 of this title</ref>, includes a political subdivision of a foreign state or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state as defined in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> An “agency or instrumentality of a foreign state” means any entity—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which is a separate legal person, corporate or otherwise, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> which is an organ of a foreign state or political subdivision thereof, or a majority of whose shares or other ownership interest is owned by a foreign state or political subdivision thereof, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> which is neither a citizen of a State of the United States as defined in section 1332 (c) and (e) of this title, nor created under the laws of any third country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> The “United States” includes all territory and waters, continental or insular, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A “commercial activity” means either a regular course of commercial conduct or a particular commercial transaction or act. The commercial character of an activity shall be determined by reference to the nature of the course of conduct or particular transaction or act, rather than by reference to its purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> A “commercial activity carried on in the United States by a foreign state” means commercial activity carried on by such state and having substantial contact with the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–583, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2892</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–2, § 4(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2005-02-18">Feb. 18, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 12</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1604.</num>
<heading> Immunity of a foreign state from jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to existing international agreements to which the United States is a party at the time of enactment of this Act a foreign state shall be immune from the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States and of the States except as provided in sections 1605 to 1607 of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–583, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2892</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1605.</num>
<heading> General exceptions to the jurisdictional immunity of a foreign state</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> A foreign state shall not be immune from the jurisdiction of courts of the United States or of the States in any case—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in which the foreign state has waived its immunity either explicitly or by implication, notwithstanding any withdrawal of the waiver which the foreign state may purport to effect except in accordance with the terms of the waiver;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in which the action is based upon a commercial activity carried on in the United States by the foreign state; or upon an act performed in the United States in connection with a commercial activity of the foreign state elsewhere; or upon an act outside the territory of the United States in connection with a commercial activity of the foreign state elsewhere and that act causes a direct effect in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in which rights in property taken in violation of international law are in issue and that property or any property exchanged for such property is present in the United States in connection with a commercial activity carried on in the United States by the foreign state; or that property or any property exchanged for such property is owned or operated by an agency or instrumentality of the foreign state and that agency or instrumentality is engaged in a commercial activity in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in which rights in property in the United States acquired by succession or gift or rights in immovable property situated in the United States are in issue;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> not otherwise encompassed in paragraph (2) above, in which money damages are sought against a foreign state for personal injury or death, or damage to or loss of property, occurring in the United States and caused by the tortious act or omission of that foreign state or of any official or employee of that foreign state while acting within the scope of his office or employment; except this paragraph shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any claim based upon the exercise or performance or the failure to exercise or perform a discretionary function regardless of whether the discretion be abused, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any claim arising out of malicious prosecution, abuse of process, libel, slander, misrepresentation, deceit, or interference with contract rights; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> in which the action is brought, either to enforce an agreement made by the foreign state with or for the benefit of a private party to submit to arbitration all or any differences which have arisen or which may arise between the parties with respect to a defined legal relationship, whether contractual or not, concerning a subject matter capable of settlement by arbitration under the laws of the United States, or to confirm an award made pursuant to such an agreement to arbitrate, if (A) the arbitration takes place or is intended to take place in the United States, (B) the agreement or award is or may be governed by a treaty or other international agreement in force for the United States calling for the recognition and enforcement of arbitral awards, (C) the underlying claim, save for the agreement to arbitrate, could have been brought in a United States court under this section or section 1607, or (D) paragraph (1) of this subsection is otherwise applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> A foreign state shall not be immune from the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States in any case in which a suit in admiralty is brought to enforce a maritime lien against a vessel or cargo of the foreign state, which maritime lien is based upon a commercial activity of the foreign state: <i>Provided</i>, That—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> notice of the suit is given by delivery of a copy of the summons and of the complaint to the person, or his agent, having possession of the vessel or cargo against which the maritime lien is asserted; and if the vessel or cargo is arrested pursuant to process obtained on behalf of the party bringing the suit, the service of process of arrest shall be deemed to constitute valid delivery of such notice, but the party bringing the suit shall be liable for any damages sustained by the foreign state as a result of the arrest if the party bringing the suit had actual or constructive knowledge that the vessel or cargo of a foreign state was involved; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> notice to the foreign state of the commencement of suit as provided in <ref>section 1608 of this title</ref> is initiated within ten days either of the delivery of notice as provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection or, in the case of a party who was unaware that the vessel or cargo of a foreign state was involved, of the date such party determined the existence of the foreign state’s interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Whenever notice is delivered under subsection (b)(1), the suit to enforce a maritime lien shall thereafter proceed and shall be heard and determined according to the principles of law and rules of practice of suits in rem whenever it appears that, had the vessel been privately owned and possessed, a suit in rem might have been maintained. A decree against the foreign state may include costs of the suit and, if the decree is for a money judgment, interest as ordered by the court, except that the court may not award judgment against the foreign state in an amount greater than the value of the vessel or cargo upon which the maritime lien arose. Such value shall be determined as of the time notice is served under subsection (b)(1). Decrees shall be subject to appeal and revision as provided in other cases of admiralty and maritime jurisdiction. Nothing shall preclude the plaintiff in any proper case from seeking relief in personam in the same action brought to enforce a maritime lien as provided in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> A foreign state shall not be immune from the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States in any action brought to foreclose a preferred mortgage, as defined in <ref>section 31301 of title 46</ref>. Such action shall be brought, heard, and determined in accordance with the provisions of chapter 313 of title 46 and in accordance with the principles of law and rules of practice of suits in rem, whenever it appears that had the vessel been privately owned and possessed a suit in rem might have been maintained.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>[(e)</num>
<content>, (f) Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1083(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 341</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Discovery.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), if an action is filed that would otherwise be barred by section 1604, but for section 1605A or section 1605B, the court, upon request of the Attorney General, shall stay any request, demand, or order for discovery on the United States that the Attorney General certifies would significantly interfere with a criminal investigation or prosecution, or a national security operation, related to the incident that gave rise to the cause of action, until such time as the Attorney General advises the court that such request, demand, or order will no longer so interfere.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A stay under this paragraph shall be in effect during the 12-month period beginning on the date on which the court issues the order to stay discovery. The court shall renew the order to stay discovery for additional 12-month periods upon motion by the United States if the Attorney General certifies that discovery would significantly interfere with a criminal investigation or prosecution, or a national security operation, related to the incident that gave rise to the cause of action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Subject to subparagraph (B), no stay shall be granted or continued in effect under paragraph (1) after the date that is 10 years after the date on which the incident that gave rise to the cause of action occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> After the period referred to in subparagraph (A), the court, upon request of the Attorney General, may stay any request, demand, or order for discovery on the United States that the court finds a substantial likelihood would—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> create a serious threat of death or serious bodily injury to any person;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> adversely affect the ability of the United States to work in cooperation with foreign and international law enforcement agencies in investigating violations of United States law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> obstruct the criminal case related to the incident that gave rise to the cause of action or undermine the potential for a conviction in such case.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Evaluation of evidence</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The court’s evaluation of any request for a stay under this subsection filed by the Attorney General shall be conducted ex parte and in camera.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Bar on motions to dismiss</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A stay of discovery under this subsection shall constitute a bar to the granting of a motion to dismiss under rules 12(b)(6) and 56 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall prevent the United States from seeking protective orders or asserting privileges ordinarily available to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Jurisdictional Immunity for Certain Art Exhibition Activities.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a work is imported into the United States from any foreign state pursuant to an agreement that provides for the temporary exhibition or display of such work entered into between a foreign state that is the owner or custodian of such work and the United States or one or more cultural or educational institutions within the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the President, or the President’s designee, has determined, in accordance with subsection (a) of <ref>Public Law 89–259</ref> (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2459(a)</ref>), that such work is of cultural significance and the temporary exhibition or display of such work is in the national interest; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the notice thereof has been published in accordance with subsection (a) of <ref>Public Law 89–259</ref> (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2459(a)</ref>),</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">any activity in the United States of such foreign state, or of any carrier, that is associated with the temporary exhibition or display of such work shall not be considered to be commercial activity by such foreign state for purposes of subsection (a)(3).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Nazi-era claims</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Paragraph (1) shall not apply in any case asserting jurisdiction under subsection (a)(3) in which rights in property taken in violation of international law are in issue within the meaning of that subsection and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the property at issue is the work described in paragraph (1);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the action is based upon a claim that such work was taken in connection with the acts of a covered government during the covered period;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the court determines that the activity associated with the exhibition or display is commercial activity, as that term is defined in section 1603(d); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a determination under clause (iii) is necessary for the court to exercise jurisdiction over the foreign state under subsection (a)(3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other culturally significant works</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to cases exempted under subparagraph (A), paragraph (1) shall not apply in any case asserting jurisdiction under subsection (a)(3) in which rights in property taken in violation of international law are in issue within the meaning of that subsection and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the property at issue is the work described in paragraph (1);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the action is based upon a claim that such work was taken in connection with the acts of a foreign government as part of a systematic campaign of coercive confiscation or misappropriation of works from members of a targeted and vulnerable group;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the taking occurred after 1900;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the court determines that the activity associated with the exhibition or display is commercial activity, as that term is defined in section 1603(d); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a determination under clause (iv) is necessary for the court to exercise jurisdiction over the foreign state under subsection (a)(3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “work” means a work of art or other object of cultural significance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the term “covered government” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Government of Germany during the covered period;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any government in any area in Europe that was occupied by the military forces of the Government of Germany during the covered period;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any government in Europe that was established with the assistance or cooperation of the Government of Germany during the covered period; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any government in Europe that was an ally of the Government of Germany during the covered period; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “covered period” means the period beginning on <date date="1933-01-30">January 30, 1933</date>, and ending on <date date="1945-05-08">May 8, 1945</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–583, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2892</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–640, § 1</ref>, <date date="1988-11-09">Nov. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3333</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–669, § 2</ref>, <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3969</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 325(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title II, § 221(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–11</ref>, <date date="1997-04-25">Apr. 25, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 22</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–77, title VI, § 626(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-28">Nov. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 803</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–117, div. B, § 208</ref>, <date date="2002-01-10">Jan. 10, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2299</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1083(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–222, § 3(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-09-28">Sept. 28, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 853</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–319, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1605A.</num>
<heading> Terrorism exception to the jurisdictional immunity of a foreign state</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No immunity</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A foreign state shall not be immune from the jurisdiction of courts of the United States or of the States in any case not otherwise covered by this chapter in which money damages are sought against a foreign state for personal injury or death that was caused by an act of torture, extrajudicial killing, aircraft sabotage, hostage taking, or the provision of material support or resources for such an act if such act or provision of material support or resources is engaged in by an official, employee, or agent of such foreign state while acting within the scope of his or her office, employment, or agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claim heard</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The court shall hear a claim under this section if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the foreign state was designated as a state sponsor of terrorism at the time the act described in paragraph (1) occurred, or was so designated as a result of such act, and, subject to subclause (II), either remains so designated when the claim is filed under this section or was so designated within the 6-month period before the claim is filed under this section; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in the case of an action that is refiled under this section by reason of section 1083(c)(2)(A) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 or is filed under this section by reason of section 1083(c)(3) of that Act, the foreign state was designated as a state sponsor of terrorism when the original action or the related action under section 1605(a)(7) (as in effect before the enactment of this section) or section 589 of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1997 (as contained in section 101(c) of division A of <ref>Public Law 104–208</ref>) was filed;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the claimant or the victim was, at the time the act described in paragraph (1) occurred—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a national of the United States;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a member of the armed forces; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> otherwise an employee of the Government of the United States, or of an individual performing a contract awarded by the United States Government, acting within the scope of the employee’s employment; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in a case in which the act occurred in the foreign state against which the claim has been brought, the claimant has afforded the foreign state a reasonable opportunity to arbitrate the claim in accordance with the accepted international rules of arbitration; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the act described in paragraph (1) is related to Case Number 1:00CV03110 (EGS) in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>An action may be brought or maintained under this section if the action is commenced, or a related action was commenced under section 1605(a)(7) (before the date of the enactment of this section) or section 589 of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1997 (as contained in section 101(c) of division A of <ref>Public Law 104–208</ref>) not later than the latter of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 10 years after <date date="1996-04-24">April 24, 1996</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 10 years after the date on which the cause of action arose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Private Right of Action</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A foreign state that is or was a state sponsor of terrorism as described in subsection (a)(2)(A)(i), and any official, employee, or agent of that foreign state while acting within the scope of his or her office, employment, or agency, shall be liable to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a national of the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a member of the armed forces,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an employee of the Government of the United States, or of an individual performing a contract awarded by the United States Government, acting within the scope of the employee’s employment, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the legal representative of a person described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3),</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">for personal injury or death caused by acts described in subsection (a)(1) of that foreign state, or of an official, employee, or agent of that foreign state, for which the courts of the United States may maintain jurisdiction under this section for money damages. In any such action, damages may include economic damages, solatium, pain and suffering, and punitive damages. In any such action, a foreign state shall be vicariously liable for the acts of its officials, employees, or agents.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Damages</inline>.—</heading>
<content>After an action has been brought under subsection (c), actions may also be brought for reasonably foreseeable property loss, whether insured or uninsured, third party liability, and loss claims under life and property insurance policies, by reason of the same acts on which the action under subsection (c) is based.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Special Masters.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The courts of the United States may appoint special masters to hear damage claims brought under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Transfer of funds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General shall transfer, from funds available for the program under section 1404C of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<ref>42 U.S.C. 10603c</ref>),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002080">1</ref> to the Administrator of the United States district court in which any case is pending which has been brought or maintained under this section such funds as may be required to cover the costs of special masters appointed under paragraph (1). Any amount paid in compensation to any such special master shall constitute an item of court costs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appeal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In an action brought under this section, appeals from orders not conclusively ending the litigation may only be taken pursuant to <ref>section 1292(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Property Disposition.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In every action filed in a United States district court in which jurisdiction is alleged under this section, the filing of a notice of pending action pursuant to this section, to which is attached a copy of the complaint filed in the action, shall have the effect of establishing a lien of lis pendens upon any real property or tangible personal property that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subject to attachment in aid of execution, or execution, under section 1610;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> located within that judicial district; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> titled in the name of any defendant, or titled in the name of any entity controlled by any defendant if such notice contains a statement listing such controlled entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A notice of pending action pursuant to this section shall be filed by the clerk of the district court in the same manner as any pending action and shall be indexed by listing as defendants all named defendants and all entities listed as controlled by any defendant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Enforceability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Liens established by reason of this subsection shall be enforceable as provided in chapter 111 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “aircraft sabotage” has the meaning given that term in Article 1 of the Convention for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts Against the Safety of Civil Aviation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “hostage taking” has the meaning given that term in Article 1 of the International Convention Against the Taking of Hostages;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “material support or resources” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2339A of title 18</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “armed forces” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 101 of title 10</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “national of the United States” has the meaning given that term in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “state sponsor of terrorism” means a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined, for purposes of section 6(j) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (50 U.S.C. App. 2405(j)),<sup>1</sup> section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2371</ref>), section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2780</ref>), or any other provision of law, is a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the terms “torture” and “extrajudicial killing” have the meaning given those terms in section 3 of the Torture Victim Protection Act of 1991 (<ref>28 U.S.C. 1350</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1083(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 338</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1605B.</num>
<heading> Responsibility of foreign states for international terrorism against the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section, the term “international terrorism”—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 2331 of title 18</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> does not include any act of war (as defined in that section).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibility of Foreign States</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A foreign state shall not be immune from the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States in any case in which money damages are sought against a foreign state for physical injury to person or property or death occurring in the United States and caused by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an act of international terrorism in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a tortious act or acts of the foreign state, or of any official, employee, or agent of that foreign state while acting within the scope of his or her office, employment, or agency, regardless where the tortious act or acts of the foreign state occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Claims by Nationals of the United States</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 2337(2) of title 18</ref>, a national of the United States may bring a claim against a foreign state in accordance with section 2333 of that title if the foreign state would not be immune under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A foreign state shall not be subject to the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States under subsection (b) on the basis of an omission or a tortious act or acts that constitute mere negligence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–222, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-09-28">Sept. 28, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1606.</num>
<heading> Extent of liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As to any claim for relief with respect to which a foreign state is not entitled to immunity under section 1605 or 1607 of this chapter, the foreign state shall be liable in the same manner and to the same extent as a private individual under like circumstances; but a foreign state except for an agency or instrumentality thereof shall not be liable for punitive damages; if, however, in any case wherein death was caused, the law of the place where the action or omission occurred provides, or has been construed to provide, for damages only punitive in nature, the foreign state shall be liable for actual or compensatory damages measured by the pecuniary injuries resulting from such death which were incurred by the persons for whose benefit the action was brought.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–583, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2894</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(h) [title I, § 117(b)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–480</ref>, 2681–491; <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. C, § 2002(g)(2)</ref>, formerly § 2002(f)(2), <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1543</ref>, renumbered § 2002(g)(2), <ref>Pub. L. 107–297, title II, § 201(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-26">Nov. 26, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2337</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1607.</num>
<heading> Counterclaims</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In any action brought by a foreign state, or in which a foreign state intervenes, in a court of the United States or of a State, the foreign state shall not be accorded immunity with respect to any counterclaim—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> for which a foreign state would not be entitled to immunity under section 1605 or 1605A of this chapter had such claim been brought in a separate action against the foreign state; or</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> arising out of the transaction or occurrence that is the subject matter of the claim of the foreign state; or</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> to the extent that the counterclaim does not seek relief exceeding in amount or differing in kind from that sought by the foreign state.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–583, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2894</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1083(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1608.</num>
<heading> Service; time to answer; default</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Service in the courts of the United States and of the States shall be made upon a foreign state or political subdivision of a foreign state:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by delivery of a copy of the summons and complaint in accordance with any special arrangement for service between the plaintiff and the foreign state or political subdivision; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if no special arrangement exists, by delivery of a copy of the summons and complaint in accordance with an applicable international convention on service of judicial documents; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if service cannot be made under paragraphs (1) or (2), by sending a copy of the summons and complaint and a notice of suit, together with a translation of each into the official language of the foreign state, by any form of mail requiring a signed receipt, to be addressed and dispatched by the clerk of the court to the head of the ministry of foreign affairs of the foreign state concerned, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> if service cannot be made within 30 days under paragraph (3), by sending two copies of the summons and complaint and a notice of suit, together with a translation of each into the official language of the foreign state, by any form of mail requiring a signed receipt, to be addressed and dispatched by the clerk of the court to the Secretary of State in Washington, District of Columbia, to the attention of the Director of Special Consular Services—and the Secretary shall transmit one copy of the papers through diplomatic channels to the foreign state and shall send to the clerk of the court a certified copy of the diplomatic note indicating when the papers were transmitted.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">As used in this subsection, a “notice of suit” shall mean a notice addressed to a foreign state and in a form prescribed by the Secretary of State by regulation.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Service in the courts of the United States and of the States shall be made upon an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by delivery of a copy of the summons and complaint in accordance with any special arrangement for service between the plaintiff and the agency or instrumentality; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if no special arrangement exists, by delivery of a copy of the summons and complaint either to an officer, a managing or general agent, or to any other agent authorized by appointment or by law to receive service of process in the United States; or in accordance with an applicable international convention on service of judicial documents; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> if service cannot be made under paragraphs (1) or (2), and if reasonably calculated to give actual notice, by delivery of a copy of the summons and complaint, together with a translation of each into the official language of the foreign state—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as directed by an authority of the foreign state or political subdivision in response to a letter rogatory or request or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by any form of mail requiring a signed receipt, to be addressed and dispatched by the clerk of the court to the agency or instrumentality to be served, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> as directed by order of the court consistent with the law of the place where service is to be made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> Service shall be deemed to have been made—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of service under subsection (a)(4), as of the date of transmittal indicated in the certified copy of the diplomatic note; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in any other case under this section, as of the date of receipt indicated in the certification, signed and returned postal receipt, or other proof of service applicable to the method of service employed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> In any action brought in a court of the United States or of a State, a foreign state, a political subdivision thereof, or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state shall serve an answer or other responsive pleading to the complaint within sixty days after service has been made under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> No judgment by default shall be entered by a court of the United States or of a State against a foreign state, a political subdivision thereof, or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, unless the claimant establishes his claim or right to relief by evidence satisfactory to the court. A copy of any such default judgment shall be sent to the foreign state or political subdivision in the manner prescribed for service in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–583, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1609.</num>
<heading> Immunity from attachment and execution of property of a foreign state</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to existing international agreements to which the United States is a party at the time of enactment of this Act the property in the United States of a foreign state shall be immune from attachment <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002081">1</ref> arrest <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002081">1</ref> and execution except as provided in sections 1610 and 1611 of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–583, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2895</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1610.</num>
<heading> Exceptions to the immunity from attachment or execution</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The property in the United States of a foreign state, as defined in section 1603(a) of this chapter, used for a commercial activity in the United States, shall not be immune from attachment in aid of execution, or from execution, upon a judgment entered by a court of the United States or of a State after the effective date of this Act, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the foreign state has waived its immunity from attachment in aid of execution or from execution either explicitly or by implication, notwithstanding any withdrawal of the waiver the foreign state may purport to effect except in accordance with the terms of the waiver, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the property is or was used for the commercial activity upon which the claim is based, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the execution relates to a judgment establishing rights in property which has been taken in violation of international law or which has been exchanged for property taken in violation of international law, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> the execution relates to a judgment establishing rights in property—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which is acquired by succession or gift, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which is immovable and situated in the United States: <i>Provided</i>, That such property is not used for purposes of maintaining a diplomatic or consular mission or the residence of the Chief of such mission, or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the property consists of any contractual obligation or any proceeds from such a contractual obligation to indemnify or hold harmless the foreign state or its employees under a policy of automobile or other liability or casualty insurance covering the claim which merged into the judgment, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the judgment is based on an order confirming an arbitral award rendered against the foreign state, provided that attachment in aid of execution, or execution, would not be inconsistent with any provision in the arbitral agreement, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the judgment relates to a claim for which the foreign state is not immune under section 1605A or section 1605(a)(7) (as such section was in effect on <date date="2008-01-27">January 27, 2008</date>), regardless of whether the property is or was involved with the act upon which the claim is based.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In addition to subsection (a), any property in the United States of an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state engaged in commercial activity in the United States shall not be immune from attachment in aid of execution, or from execution, upon a judgment entered by a court of the United States or of a State after the effective date of this Act, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the agency or instrumentality has waived its immunity from attachment in aid of execution or from execution either explicitly or implicitly, notwithstanding any withdrawal of the waiver the agency or instrumentality may purport to effect except in accordance with the terms of the waiver, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the judgment relates to a claim for which the agency or instrumentality is not immune by virtue of section 1605(a)(2), (3), or (5) or 1605(b) of this chapter, regardless of whether the property is or was involved in the act upon which the claim is based, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the judgment relates to a claim for which the agency or instrumentality is not immune by virtue of section 1605A of this chapter or section 1605(a)(7) of this chapter (as such section was in effect on <date date="2008-01-27">January 27, 2008</date>), regardless of whether the property is or was involved in the act upon which the claim is based.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> No attachment or execution referred to in subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall be permitted until the court has ordered such attachment and execution after having determined that a reasonable period of time has elapsed following the entry of judgment and the giving of any notice required under section 1608(e) of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<chapeau> The property of a foreign state, as defined in section 1603(a) of this chapter, used for a commercial activity in the United States, shall not be immune from attachment prior to the entry of judgment in any action brought in a court of the United States or of a State, or prior to the elapse of the period of time provided in subsection (c) of this section, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the foreign state has explicitly waived its immunity from attachment prior to judgment, notwithstanding any withdrawal of the waiver the foreign state may purport to effect except in accordance with the terms of the waiver, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the purpose of the attachment is to secure satisfaction of a judgment that has been or may ultimately be entered against the foreign state, and not to obtain jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> The vessels of a foreign state shall not be immune from arrest in rem, interlocutory sale, and execution in actions brought to foreclose a preferred mortgage as provided in section 1605(d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including but not limited to section 208(f) of the Foreign Missions Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 4308(f)</ref>), and except as provided in subparagraph (B), any property with respect to which financial transactions are prohibited or regulated pursuant to section 5(b) of the Trading with the Enemy Act (50 U.S.C. App. 5(b)),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002082">1</ref> section 620(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2370(a)</ref>), sections 202 and 203 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701–170</ref>2), or any other proclamation, order, regulation, or license issued pursuant thereto, shall be subject to execution or attachment in aid of execution of any judgment relating to a claim for which a foreign state (including any agency or instrumentality or such state) claiming such property is not immune under section 1605(a)(7) (as in effect before the enactment of section 1605A) or section 1605A.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if, at the time the property is expropriated or seized by the foreign state, the property has been held in title by a natural person or, if held in trust, has been held for the benefit of a natural person or persons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> At the request of any party in whose favor a judgment has been issued with respect to a claim for which the foreign state is not immune under section 1605(a)(7) (as in effect before the enactment of section 1605A) or section 1605A, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State should make every effort to fully, promptly, and effectively assist any judgment creditor or any court that has issued any such judgment in identifying, locating, and executing against the property of that foreign state or any agency or instrumentality of such state.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> In providing such assistance, the Secretaries—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> may provide such information to the court under seal; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> should make every effort to provide the information in a manner sufficient to allow the court to direct the United States Marshall’s office to promptly and effectively execute against that property.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The President may waive any provision of paragraph (1) in the interest of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Property in Certain Actions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to paragraph (3), the property of a foreign state against which a judgment is entered under section 1605A, and the property of an agency or instrumentality of such a state, including property that is a separate juridical entity or is an interest held directly or indirectly in a separate juridical entity, is subject to attachment in aid of execution, and execution, upon that judgment as provided in this section, regardless of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the level of economic control over the property by the government of the foreign state;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whether the profits of the property go to that government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the degree to which officials of that government manage the property or otherwise control its daily affairs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> whether that government is the sole beneficiary in interest of the property; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> whether establishing the property as a separate entity would entitle the foreign state to benefits in United States courts while avoiding its obligations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">United states sovereign immunity inapplicable</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any property of a foreign state, or agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, to which paragraph (1) applies shall not be immune from attachment in aid of execution, or execution, upon a judgment entered under section 1605A because the property is regulated by the United States Government by reason of action taken against that foreign state under the Trading With the Enemy Act or the International Emergency Economic Powers Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Third-party joint property holders</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to supersede the authority of a court to prevent appropriately the impairment of an interest held by a person who is not liable in the action giving rise to a judgment in property subject to attachment in aid of execution, or execution, upon such judgment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–583</ref>, §  4(a), <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2896</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–640, § 2</ref>, <date date="1988-11-09">Nov. 9, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3333</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–669, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3969</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 325(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–132, title II, § 221(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1242</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(h) [title I, § 117(a)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–480</ref>, 2681–491; <ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. C, § 2002(g)(1)</ref>, formerly § 2002(f)(1), <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1543</ref>, renumbered § 2002(g)(1), <ref>Pub. L. 107–297, title II, § 201(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-26">Nov. 26, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2337</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1083(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–158, title V, § 502(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1611.</num>
<heading> Certain types of property immune from execution</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of section 1610 of this chapter, the property of those organizations designated by the President as being entitled to enjoy the privileges, exemptions, and immunities provided by the International Organizations Immunities Act shall not be subject to attachment or any other judicial process impeding the disbursement of funds to, or on the order of, a foreign state as the result of an action brought in the courts of the United States or of the States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Notwithstanding the provisions of section 1610 of this chapter, the property of a foreign state shall be immune from attachment and from execution, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the property is that of a foreign central bank or monetary authority held for its own account, unless such bank or authority, or its parent foreign government, has explicitly waived its immunity from attachment in aid of execution, or from execution, notwithstanding any withdrawal of the waiver which the bank, authority or government may purport to effect except in accordance with the terms of the waiver; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the property is, or is intended to be, used in connection with a military activity and</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is of a military character, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is under the control of a military authority or defense agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding the provisions of section 1610 of this chapter, the property of a foreign state shall be immune from attachment and from execution in an action brought under section 302 of the Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1996 to the extent that the property is a facility or installation used by an accredited diplomatic mission for official purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–583, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2897</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title III, § 302(e)</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 818</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>