<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 40A—</num>
<heading>BUREAU OF ALCOHOL, TOBACCO, FIREARMS, AND EXPLOSIVES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 599A.</num>
<heading> Bureau of alcohol, tobacco, firearms, and Explosives <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002039">1</ref></heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Establishment.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There is established within the Department of Justice under the general authority of the Attorney General the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (in this section referred to as the “Bureau”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be at the head of the Bureau a Director, Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (in this subtitle <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002040">2</ref> referred to as the “Director”). The Director shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002041">3</ref> and shall perform such functions as the Attorney General shall direct. The Director shall receive compensation at the rate prescribed by law under section 5314 of title V <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002042">4</ref>, United States Code, for positions at level III of the Executive Schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General, acting through the Director and such other officials of the Department of Justice as the Attorney General may designate, shall provide for the coordination of all firearms, explosives, tobacco enforcement, and arson enforcement functions vested in the Attorney General so as to assure maximum cooperation between and among any officer, employee, or agency of the Department of Justice involved in the performance of these and related functions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Performance of transferred functions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Attorney General may make such provisions as the Attorney General determines appropriate to authorize the performance by any officer, employee, or agency of the Department of Justice of any function transferred to the Attorney General under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to the direction of the Attorney General, the Bureau shall be responsible for investigating—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> criminal and regulatory violations of the Federal firearms, explosives, arson, alcohol, and tobacco smuggling laws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the functions transferred by subsection (c) of section 1111 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as enacted on the date of the enactment of such Act); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other function related to the investigation of violent crime or domestic terrorism that is delegated to the Bureau by the Attorney General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets to the Department of Justice.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to paragraph (2),<sup>2</sup> but notwithstanding any other provision of law, there are transferred to the Department of Justice the authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms, which shall be maintained as a distinct entity within the Department of Justice, including the related functions of the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002043">5</ref> <inline class="small-caps">Building prospectus</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Prospectus PDC-98W10, giving the General Services Administration the authority for site acquisition, design, and construction of a new headquarters building for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms, is transferred, and deemed to apply, to the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives established in the Department of Justice under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1187(b)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3127</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 599B.</num>
<heading> Personnel Management demonstration <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002044">1</ref> project <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002044">1</ref></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Personnel Management Demonstration Project established under section 102 of title I of division C of the Omnibus Consolidated and Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Fiscal Year 1999 (<ref>Public Law 105–277</ref>; 122 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002045">2</ref> Stat. 2681–585) shall be transferred to the Attorney General of the United States for continued use by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, Department of Justice, and the Secretary of the Treasury for continued use by the Tax and Trade Bureau.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1187(b)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3127</ref>, 3128.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>