<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 73—</num>
<heading>INTERNATIONAL RELIGIOUS FREEDOM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6401.</num>
<heading> Findings; policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The right to freedom of religion undergirds the very origin and existence of the United States. Many of our Nation’s founders fled religious persecution abroad, cherishing in their hearts and minds the ideal of religious freedom. They established in law, as a fundamental right and as a pillar of our Nation, the right to freedom of religion. From its birth to this day, the United States has prized this legacy of religious freedom and honored this heritage by standing for religious freedom and offering refuge to those suffering religious persecution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Freedom of religious belief and practice is a universal human right and fundamental freedom articulated in numerous international instruments, including the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, the Helsinki Accords, the Declaration on the Elimination of All Forms of Intolerance and Discrimination Based on Religion or Belief, the United Nations Charter, and the European Convention for the Protection of Human Rights and Fundamental Freedoms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Article 18 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights recognizes that “Everyone has the right to freedom of thought, conscience, and religion. This right includes freedom to change his religion or belief, and freedom, either alone or in community with others and in public or private, to manifest his religion or belief in teaching, practice, worship, and observance.”. Article 18(1) of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights recognizes that “Everyone shall have the right to freedom of thought, conscience, and religion. This right shall include freedom to have or to adopt a religion or belief of his choice, and freedom, either individually or in community with others and in public or private, to manifest his religion or belief in worship, observance, practice, and teaching”. The freedom of thought, conscience, and religion is understood to protect theistic and non-theistic beliefs and the right not to profess or practice any religion. Governments have the responsibility to protect the fundamental rights of their citizens and to pursue justice for all. Religious freedom is a fundamental right of every individual, regardless of race, sex, country, creed, or nationality, and should never be arbitrarily abridged by any government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The right to freedom of religion is under renewed and, in some cases, increasing assault in many countries around the world. More than one-half of the world’s population lives under regimes that severely restrict or prohibit the freedom of their citizens to study, believe, observe, and freely practice the religious faith of their choice. Religious believers and communities suffer both government-sponsored and government-tolerated violations of their rights to religious freedom. Among the many forms of such violations are state-sponsored slander campaigns, confiscations of property, desecration of cemeteries, surveillance by security police, including by special divisions of “religious police”, severe prohibitions against construction and repair of places of worship, denial of the right to assemble and relegation of religious communities to illegal status through arbitrary registration laws, prohibitions against the pursuit of education or public office, and prohibitions against publishing, distributing, or possessing religious literature and materials. A policy or practice of routinely denying applications for visas for religious workers in a country can be indicative of a poor state of religious freedom in that country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Even more abhorrent, religious believers in many countries face such severe and violent forms of religious persecution as detention, torture, beatings, forced marriage, rape, imprisonment, enslavement, mass resettlement, and death merely for the peaceful belief in, change of or practice of their faith. In many countries, religious believers are forced to meet secretly, and religious leaders are targeted by national security forces and hostile mobs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Though not confined to a particular region or regime, religious persecution and the specific targeting of non-theists, humanists, and atheists because of their beliefs is often particularly widespread, systematic, and heinous under totalitarian governments and in countries with militant, politicized religious majorities and in regions where non-state actors exercise significant political power and territorial control.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> Congress has recognized and denounced acts of religious persecution through the adoption of the following resolutions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> House Resolution 515 of the One Hundred Fourth Congress, expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to the persecution of Christians worldwide.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Senate Concurrent Resolution 71 of the One Hundred Fourth Congress, expressing the sense of the Senate regarding persecution of Christians worldwide.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> House Concurrent Resolution 102 of the One Hundred Fourth Congress, expressing the sense of the House of Representatives concerning the emancipation of the Iranian Baha’i community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The following shall be the policy of the United States:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To condemn violations of religious freedom, and to promote, and to assist other governments in the promotion of, the fundamental right to freedom of religion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To seek to channel United States security and development assistance to governments other than those found to be engaged in gross violations of the right to freedom of religion, as set forth in the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], in the International Financial Institutions Act of 1977, and in other formulations of United States human rights policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> To be vigorous and flexible, reflecting both the unwavering commitment of the United States to religious freedom and the desire of the United States for the most effective and principled response, in light of the range of violations of religious freedom by a variety of persecuting regimes, and the status of the relations of the United States with different nations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> To work with foreign governments that affirm and protect religious freedom, in order to develop multilateral documents and initiatives to combat violations of religious freedom and promote the right to religious freedom abroad.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Standing for liberty and standing with the persecuted, to use and implement appropriate tools in the United States foreign policy apparatus, including diplomatic, political, commercial, charitable, educational, and cultural channels, to promote respect for religious freedom by all governments and peoples.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evolving policies and coordinated diplomatic responses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Because the promotion of international religious freedom protects human rights, advances democracy abroad, and advances United States interests in stability, security, and development globally, the promotion of international religious freedom requires new and evolving policies and diplomatic responses that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are drawn from the expertise of the national security agencies, the diplomatic services, and other governmental agencies and nongovernmental organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are coordinated across and carried out by the entire range of Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, § 2</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2788</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–154, § 2</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1827</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, § 2(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1426</ref>, 1427.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6402.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ambassador at Large</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Ambassador at Large” means the Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom appointed under <ref>section 6411(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Annual Report” means the Annual Report on International Religious Freedom described in <ref>section 6412(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of any determination made with respect to the taking of President <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002341">1</ref> action under paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref>, the term includes the committees described in subparagraph (A) and, where appropriate, the Committee on Banking and Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commensurate action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “commensurate action” means action taken by the President under <ref>section 6445(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commission” means the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom established in <ref>section 6431(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Country Reports on Human Rights Practices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Country Reports on Human Rights Practices” means the annual reports required to be submitted by the Department of State to Congress under sections 2151n(d) and 2304(b) of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Summary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Executive Summary” means the Executive Summary to the Annual Report, as described in <ref>section 6412(b)(1)(F) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government or foreign government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “government” or “foreign government” includes any agency or instrumentality of the government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Human Rights Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Human Rights Reports” means all reports submitted by the Department of State to Congress under sections 2151n and 2304 of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Institution of higher education</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-state actor</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “non-state actor” means a nonsovereign entity that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> exercises significant political power and territorial control;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is outside the control of a sovereign government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> often employs violence in pursuit of its objectives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Office” means the Office on International Religious Freedom established in <ref>section 6411(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Particularly severe violations of religious freedom</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “particularly severe violations of religious freedom” means systematic, ongoing, egregious violations of religious freedom, including violations such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> torture or cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prolonged detention without charges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> causing the disappearance of persons by the abduction or clandestine detention of those persons; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other flagrant denial of the right to life, liberty, or the security of persons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special Adviser</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Special Adviser” means the Special Adviser to the President on International Religious Freedom described in <ref>section 3021(i) of title 50</ref>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002342">2</ref></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special Watch List</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Special Watch List” means the Special Watch List described in <ref>section 6442(b)(1)(A)(iii) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violations of religious freedom</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “violations of religious freedom” means violations of the internationally recognized right to freedom of religion and religious belief and practice, as set forth in the international instruments referred to in <ref>section 6401(a)(2) of this title</ref> and as described in <ref>section 6401(a)(3) of this title</ref>, including violations such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> arbitrary prohibitions on, restrictions of, or punishment for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assembling for peaceful religious activities such as worship, preaching, and prayer, including arbitrary registration requirements;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> speaking freely about one’s religious beliefs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> changing one’s religious beliefs and affiliation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> not professing a particular religion, or any religion;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> possession and distribution of religious literature, including Bibles; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> raising one’s children in the religious teachings and practices of one’s choice; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any of the following acts if committed on account of an individual’s conscience, non-theistic views, or religious belief or practice: detention, interrogation, imposition of an onerous financial penalty, forced labor, forced mass resettlement, imprisonment, forced religious conversion, forcibly compelling non-believers or non-theists to recant their beliefs or to convert, beating, torture, mutilation, rape, enslavement, murder, and execution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, § 3</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2790</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, § 3</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1427</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF STATE ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6411.</num>
<heading> Office on International Religious Freedom; Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Department of State an Office on International Religious Freedom that shall be headed by the Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom appointed under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Ambassador at Large shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall report directly to the Secretary of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Ambassador at Large shall have the following responsibilities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The primary responsibilities of the Ambassador at Large shall be to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> advance the right to freedom of religion abroad, to denounce the violation of that right, and to recommend appropriate responses by the United States Government when this right is violated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> integrate United States international religious freedom policies and strategies into the foreign policy efforts of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory role</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Ambassador at Large shall be a principal adviser to the President and the principal adviser to the Secretary of State regarding matters affecting religious freedom abroad and, with advice from the Commission on International Religious Freedom, shall make recommendations regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the policies of the United States Government toward governments that violate freedom of religion or that fail to ensure the individual’s right to religious belief and practice; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> policies to advance the right to religious freedom abroad.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diplomatic representation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to the direction of the President and the Secretary of State, the Ambassador at Large is authorized to represent the United States in matters and cases relevant to religious freedom abroad in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> contacts with foreign governments, intergovernmental organizations, and specialized agencies of the United Nations, the Organization on Security and Cooperation in Europe, and other international organizations of which the United States is a member;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> multilateral conferences and meetings relevant to religious freedom abroad; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> contacts with nongovernmental organizations that have an impact on the state of religious freedom in their respective societies or regions, or internationally.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In order to promote religious freedom as an interest of United States foreign policy, the Ambassador at Large—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall coordinate international religious freedom policies across all programs, projects, and activities of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> should participate in any interagency processes on issues in which the promotion of international religious freedom policy can advance United States national security interests, including in democracy promotion, stability, security, and development globally.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting responsibilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Ambassador at Large shall have the reporting responsibilities described in <ref>section 6412 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall provide the Ambassador at Large with such funds as may be necessary for the hiring of appropriate staff for the Office, including full-time equivalent positions and other temporary staff positions needed to compile, edit, and manage the Annual Report under the direct supervision of the Ambassador at Large, and for the conduct of investigations by the Office and for necessary travel to carry out this chapter. The Secretary of State should provide the Ambassador at Large with sufficient funding to carry out the duties described in this section, including, as necessary, representation funds. On the date on which the President’s annual budget request is submitted to Congress, the Secretary shall submit an annual report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes a report on staffing levels for the International Religious Freedom Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2791</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1428</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6412.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Portions of annual Human Rights Reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Ambassador at Large shall assist the Secretary of State in preparing those portions of the Human Rights Reports that relate to freedom of religion and freedom from discrimination based on religion and those portions of other information provided Congress under sections 2151n and 2304 of this title that relate to the right to freedom of religion.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual Report on International Religious Freedom</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline for submission</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On May 1 of each year or the first day thereafter on which the appropriate House of Congress is in session, the Secretary of State, with the assistance of the Ambassador at Large, and taking into consideration the recommendations of the Commission, shall prepare and transmit to Congress an Annual Report on International Religious Freedom supplementing the most recent Human Rights Reports by providing additional detailed information with respect to matters involving international religious freedom. Each Annual Report shall contain the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Status of religious freedom</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A description of the status of religious freedom in each foreign country, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> trends toward improvement in the respect and protection of the right to religious freedom and trends toward deterioration of such right;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> violations of religious freedom engaged in or tolerated by the government of that country;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> particularly severe violations of religious freedom engaged in or tolerated by the government of that country as well as the routine denial of visa applications for religious workers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> particularly severe violations of religious freedom in that country if such country does not have a functioning government or the government of such country does not control its territory;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the identification of prisoners, to the extent possible, in that country pursuant to <ref>section 6417(d) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> any action taken by the government of that country to censor religious content, communications, or worship activities online, including descriptions of the targeted religious group, the content, communication, or activities censored, and the means used; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<chapeau> wherever applicable, an assessment and description of the nature and extent of acts of anti-Semitism and anti-Semitic incitement that occur in that country during the preceding year, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> acts of physical violence against, or harassment of, Jewish people, acts of violence against, or vandalism of, Jewish community institutions, and instances of propaganda in government and nongovernment media that incite such acts; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the actions taken by the government of that country to respond to such violence and attacks or to eliminate such propaganda or incitement, to enact and enforce laws relating to the protection of the right to religious freedom of Jewish people, and to promote anti-bias and tolerance education.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violations of religious freedom</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An assessment and description of the nature and extent of violations of religious freedom in each foreign country, including persecution of one religious group by another religious group, religious persecution by governmental and nongovernmental entities, persecution targeted at individuals or particular denominations or entire religions, persecution of lawyers, politicians, or other human rights advocates seeking to defend the rights of members of religious groups or highlight religious freedom violations, prohibitions on ritual animal slaughter or male infant circumcision, the existence of government policies violating religious freedom, including policies that discriminate against particular religious groups or members of such groups, policies that ban or restrict the public manifestation of religious belief and the peaceful involvement of religious groups or their members in the political life of each such foreign country, and the existence of government policies concerning—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> limitations or prohibitions on, or lack of availability of, openly conducted, organized religious services outside of the premises of foreign diplomatic missions or consular posts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the forced religious conversion of minor United States citizens who have been abducted or illegally removed from the United States, and the refusal to allow such citizens to be returned to the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States policies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A detailed description of United States actions, diplomatic and political coordination efforts, and other policies in support of religious freedom in each foreign country engaging in or tolerating violations of religious freedom, including a description of the measures and policies implemented during the preceding 12 months by the United States under titles I, IV, and V of this Act in opposition to violations of religious freedom and in support of international religious freedom.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International agreements in effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A description of any binding agreement with a foreign government entered into by the United States under section 6441(b) or 6442(c) of this title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training and guidelines of Government personnel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A description of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the training described in section 6472(a) and (b) of this title and section 6473(b) and (c) of this title on violations of religious freedom provided to immigration judges and consular, refugee, immigration, and asylum officers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the development and implementation of the guidelines described in sections 6472(c) and 6473(a) of this title.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Summary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An Executive Summary to the Annual Report highlighting the status of religious freedom in certain foreign countries and including the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Countries in which the United States is actively promoting religious freedom</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">An identification of foreign countries in which the United States is actively promoting religious freedom. This section of the report shall include a description of United States actions taken to promote the internationally recognized right to freedom of religion and oppose violations of such right under title IV and title V of this Act during the period covered by the Annual Report. Any country designated as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under <ref>section 6442(b)(1)(A)(ii) of this title</ref> shall be included in this section of the report. Any country in which a non-state actor designated as an entity of particular concern for religious freedom under <ref>section 6442a of this title</ref> is located shall be included in this section of the report.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Countries of significant improvement in religious freedom</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">An identification of foreign countries the governments of which have demonstrated significant improvement in the protection and promotion of the internationally recognized right to freedom of religion during the period covered by the Annual Report. This section of the report shall include a description of the nature of the improvement and an analysis of the factors contributing to such improvement, including actions taken by the United States under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Anti-Semitism in Europe</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In addition to the information required under clause (vii) of subparagraph (A), with respect to each European country in which verbal or physical threats or attacks are particularly significant against Jewish persons, places of worship, schools, cemeteries, and other religious institutions, a description of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the security challenges and needs of European Jewish communities and European law enforcement agencies in such countries to better protect such communities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, the efforts of the United States Government over the reporting period to partner with European law enforcement agencies and civil society groups regarding the sharing of information and best practices to combat anti-Semitic incidents in Europe;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> European educational programming and public awareness initiatives that aim to collaborate on educational curricula and campaigns that impart shared values of pluralism and tolerance, and showcase the positive contributions of Jews in culture, scholarship, science, and art, with special attention to those segments of the population that exhibit a high degree of anti-Semitic animus; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> efforts by European governments to adopt and apply a working definition of anti-Semitism.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Classified addendum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary of State determines that it is in the national security interests of the United States or is necessary for the safety of individuals to be identified in the Annual Report or is necessary to further the purposes of this chapter, any information required by paragraph (1), including measures or actions taken by the United States, may be summarized in the Annual Report or the Executive Summary and submitted in more detail in a classified addendum to the Annual Report or the Executive Summary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation of reports regarding violations of religious freedom</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards and investigations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall ensure that United States missions abroad maintain a consistent reporting standard and thoroughly investigate reports of violations of the internationally recognized right to freedom of religion.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contacts with nongovernmental organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In compiling data and assessing the respect of the right to religious freedom for the Human Rights Reports, the Annual Report on International Religious Freedom, and the Executive Summary, United States mission personnel shall, as appropriate, seek out and maintain contacts with religious and human rights nongovernmental organizations, with the consent of those organizations, including receiving reports and updates from such organizations and, when appropriate, investigating such reports.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title VI, § 681(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1408</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–332, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-16">Oct. 16, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1285</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–434, § 4</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5528</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6413.</num>
<heading> Establishment of religious freedom Internet site</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to facilitate access by nongovernmental organizations (NGOs) and by the public around the world to international documents on the protection of religious freedom, the Secretary of State, with the assistance of the Ambassador at Large, shall establish and maintain an Internet site containing major international documents relating to religious freedom, the Annual Report, the Executive Summary, and any other documentation or references to other sites as deemed appropriate or relevant by the Ambassador at Large.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2795</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6414.</num>
<heading> High-level contacts with nongovernmental organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">United States chiefs of mission shall seek out and contact religious nongovernmental organizations to provide high-level meetings with religious nongovernmental organizations where appropriate and beneficial. United States chiefs of mission and Foreign Service officers abroad shall seek to meet with imprisoned religious leaders where appropriate and beneficial.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2795</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6415.</num>
<heading> Programs and allocations of funds by United States missions abroad</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> United States diplomatic missions in countries the governments of which engage in or tolerate violations of the internationally recognized right to freedom of religion should develop, as part of annual program planning, a strategy to promote respect for the internationally recognized right to freedom of religion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in allocating or recommending the allocation of funds or the recommendation of candidates for programs and grants funded by the United States Government, United States diplomatic missions should give particular consideration to those programs and candidates deemed to assist in the promotion of the right to religious freedom.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2796</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6416.</num>
<heading> Equal access to United States missions abroad for conducting religious activities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to this section, the Secretary of State shall permit, on terms no less favorable than that accorded other nongovernmental activities unrelated to the conduct of the diplomatic mission, access to the premises of any United States diplomatic mission or consular post by any United States citizen seeking to conduct an activity for religious purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing and location</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall make reasonable accommodations with respect to the timing and location of such access in light of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of United States citizens requesting the access (including any particular religious concerns regarding the time of day, date, or physical setting for services);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conflicts with official activities and other nonofficial United States citizen requests;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the availability of openly conducted, organized religious services outside the premises of the mission or post;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> availability of space and resources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> necessary security precautions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretionary access for foreign nationals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State may permit access to the premises of a United States diplomatic mission or consular post to foreign nationals for the purpose of attending or participating in religious activities conducted pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2796</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6417.</num>
<heading> Prisoner lists and issue briefs on religious freedom concerns</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To encourage involvement with religious freedom concerns at every possible opportunity and by all appropriate representatives of the United States Government, it is the sense of the Congress that officials of the executive branch of Government should promote increased advocacy on such issues during meetings between foreign dignitaries and executive branch officials or Members of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prisoner lists and issue briefs on religious freedom concerns</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Ambassador at Large, the Assistant Secretary of State for Democracy, Human Rights and Labor, United States chiefs of mission abroad, regional experts, and nongovernmental human rights and religious groups, shall prepare and maintain issue briefs on religious freedom, on a country-by-country basis, consisting of lists of persons believed to be imprisoned, detained, or placed under house arrest for their religious activities, religious freedom advocacy, or efforts to protect and advance the universally recognized right to the freedom of religion, together with brief evaluations and critiques of the policies of the respective country restricting religious freedom. In considering the inclusion of names of prisoners on such lists, the Secretary of State shall exercise appropriate discretion, including concerns regarding the safety, security, and benefit to such prisoners.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall make available religious freedom issue briefs under subsection (b) to executive branch officials and Members of Congress in anticipation of bilateral contacts with foreign leaders, both in the United States and abroad.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victims list maintained by the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall make publicly available, to the extent practicable, online and in official publications, lists of persons it determines are imprisoned or detained, have disappeared, been placed under house arrest, been tortured, or subjected to forced renunciations of faith for their religious activity or religious freedom advocacy by the government of a foreign country that the Commission recommends for designation as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under <ref>section 6442(b)(1)(A)(ii) of this title</ref> or by a non-state actor that the Commission recommends for designation as an entity of particular concern for religious freedom under <ref>section 6442a of this title</ref> and include as much publicly available information as practicable on the conditions and circumstances of such persons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In compiling lists under paragraph (1), the Commission shall exercise all appropriate discretion, including consideration of the safety and security of, and benefit to, the persons who may be included on the lists and the families of such persons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2796</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>COMMISSION ON INTERNATIONAL RELIGIOUS FREEDOM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6431.</num>
<heading> Establishment and composition</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission shall be composed of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Ambassador at Large, who shall serve ex officio as a nonvoting member of the Commission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Nine <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002343">1</ref> other members, who shall be United States citizens who are not being paid as officers or employees of the United States, and who shall be appointed as follows:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Three members of the Commission shall be appointed by the President.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Three members of the Commission shall be appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate, of which two of the members shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the leader in the Senate of the political party that is not the political party of the President, and of which one of the members shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the leader in the Senate of the other political party.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Three members of the Commission shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, of which two of the members shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the leader in the House of the political party that is not the political party of the President, and of which one of the members shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the leader in the House of the other political party.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Members of the Commission shall be selected among distinguished individuals noted for their knowledge and experience in fields relevant to the issue of international religious freedom, including foreign affairs, direct experience abroad, human rights, and international law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time of appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The appointments required by paragraph (1) shall be made not later than 120 days after <date date="1998-10-27">October 27, 1998</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term of office of each member of the Commission shall be 2 years. An individual, including any member appointed to the Commission prior to <date date="2011-12-23">December 23, 2011</date>, shall not serve more than 2 terms as a member of the Commission under any circumstance. For any member serving on the Commission on such date who has completed at least 2 full terms on the Commission, such member’s term shall expire 90 days after such date. A member of the Commission may not serve after the expiration of that member’s term.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of staggered terms</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), members of the Commission appointed to serve on the Commission during the period <date date="2003-05-15">May 15, 2003</date>, through <date date="2005-05-14">May 14, 2005</date>, shall be appointed to terms in accordance with the provisions of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential appointments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the three members of the Commission appointed by the President under subsection (b)(1)(B)(i), two shall be appointed to a 1-year term and one shall be appointed to a 2-year term.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointments by the President pro tempore of the Senate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the three members of the Commission appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate under subsection (b)(1)(B)(ii), one of the appointments made upon the recommendation of the leader in the Senate of the political party that is not the political party of the President shall be appointed to a 1-year term, and the other two appointments under such clause shall be 2-year terms.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointments by the Speaker of the House of Representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the three members of the Commission appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives under subsection (b)(1)(B)(iii), one of the appointments made upon the recommendation of the leader in the House of the political party that is not the political party of the President shall be to a 1-year term, and the other two appointments under such clause shall be 2-year terms.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointments to 1-year terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term of each member of the Commission appointed to a 1-year term shall be considered to have begun on <date date="2003-05-15">May 15, 2003</date>, and shall end on <date date="2004-05-14">May 14, 2004</date>, regardless of the date of the appointment to the Commission. Each vacancy which occurs upon the expiration of the term of a member appointed to a 1-year term shall be filled by the appointment of a successor to a 2-year term.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointments to 2-year terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each appointment of a member to a two-year term shall identify the member succeeded thereby, and each such term shall end on May 14 of the year that is at least two years after the expiration of the previous term, regardless of the date of the appointment to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ineligibility for reappointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a member of the Commission attends, by being physically present or by conference call, less than 75 percent of the meetings of the Commission during one of that member’s terms on the Commission, the member shall not be eligible for reappointment to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election of Chair and Vice Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the first meeting of the Commission after May 30 of each year, a majority of the members of the Commission who are present and voting shall elect a Chair and a Vice Chair. The Vice Chair shall have been appointed by an officeholder from a different political party than the officeholder who appointed the member of the Commission who was elected Chair. The positions of Chair and Vice Chair shall be rotated annually between members who were appointed to the Commission by officeholders of different political parties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Six voting members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum for purposes of transacting business.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each year, within 15 days, or as soon as practicable, after the issuance of the International Religious Freedom Report, the Commission shall convene. The Commission shall otherwise meet at the call of the Chair or, if no Chair has been elected for that calendar year, at the call of six voting members of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any vacancy of the Commission shall not affect its powers, but shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made. A member may serve after the expiration of that member’s term until a successor has taken office. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission on a reimbursable basis (or, in the discretion of the Administrator, on a nonreimbursable basis) such administrative support services as the Commission may request to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5 while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission. Members of the Commission shall comply with the requirements set forth in chapters 300 through 304 of title 41, Code of Federal Regulations (commonly known as the “Federal Travel Regulation”) and the Department of State Standardized Regulations governing authorized travel at government expense, including regulations concerning the mode of travel, lodging and per diem expenditures, reimbursement payments, and expense reporting and documentation requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a payment is made under section 415(a) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 1415(a)</ref>) for an award or settlement in connection with a claim alleging a violation of unlawful harassment, intimidation, reprisal, or discrimination under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<ref>2 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.) that was committed personally by an individual who, at the time of committing the violation, was a Member of the Commission, the Member shall be removed from the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2797</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–55</ref>, §§ 1(a), 2(b), <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 401</ref>, 406; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title VI, § 681(b)</ref>–(d), <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1408</ref>, 1409; <ref>Pub. L. 112–75, § 2</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII</ref>, §§ 803, 806(a), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3076</ref>, 3078.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6432.</num>
<heading> Duties of Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall have as its primary responsibility—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the annual and ongoing review of the facts and circumstances of violations of religious freedom presented in the Country Reports on Human Rights Practices, the Annual Report, and the Executive Summary, as well as information from other sources as appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the making of policy recommendations to the President, the Secretary of State, and Congress with respect to matters involving international religious freedom.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy review and recommendations in response to violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission, in evaluating United States Government policies in response to violations of religious freedom, shall consider and recommend options for policies of the United States Government with respect to each foreign country the government of which has engaged in or tolerated violations of religious freedom, including particularly severe violations of religious freedom, including diplomatic inquiries, diplomatic protest, official public protest demarche of protest, condemnation within multilateral fora, delay or cancellation of cultural or scientific exchanges, delay or cancellation of working, official, or state visits, reduction of certain assistance funds, termination of certain assistance funds, imposition of targeted trade sanctions, imposition of broad trade sanctions, and withdrawal of the chief of mission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy review and recommendations in response to progress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission, in evaluating the United States Government policies with respect to countries found to be taking deliberate steps and making significant improvement in respect for the right of religious freedom, shall consider and recommend policy options, including private commendation, diplomatic commendation, official public commendation, commendation within multilateral fora, an increase in cultural or scientific exchanges, or both, termination or reduction of existing Presidential actions, an increase in certain assistance funds, and invitations for working, official, or state visits.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effects on religious communities and individuals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Together with specific policy recommendations provided under subsections (b) and (c), the Commission shall also indicate its evaluation of the potential effects of such policies, if implemented, on the religious communities and individuals whose rights are found to be violated in the country in question.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission shall, on an ongoing basis, monitor facts and circumstances of violations of religious freedom, in consultation with independent human rights groups and nongovernmental organizations, including churches and other religious communities, and make such recommendations as may be necessary to the appropriate officials and offices in the United States Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tracking; review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Commission shall regularly—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> track the implementation by the United States Government of the recommendations it makes under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> review, to the extent practicable, the effectiveness of such implemented recommendations in advancing religious freedom internationally.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2798</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII, § 804(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3077</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6432a.</num>
<heading> Powers of the Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hearings and sessions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out its duties under this subchapter, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places in the United States, take testimony and receive evidence as the Commission considers advisable to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information from Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out the provisions of this section. Upon request of the Chairperson of the Commission, the head of such department or agency shall furnish such information to the Commission, subject to applicable law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Postal services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may adopt such rules and regulations, relating to administrative procedure, as may be reasonably necessary to enable it to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Views of the Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Members of the Commission may speak in their capacity as private citizens. Statements on behalf of the Commission shall be issued in writing over the names of the Members. The Commission shall in its written statements clearly describe its statutory authority, distinguishing that authority from that of appointed or elected officials of the United States Government. Oral statements, where practicable, shall include a similar description. If a Member of the Commission is invited to speak at an event in his or her capacity as a Commissioner, the Member shall provide notice of the request to all Commissioners and the Executive Director as soon as the Commissioner becomes aware of such invitation. Speeches and responses to questions at official events shall reflect the views of the Commission. Official speeches and other prepared materials shall be made available to all Commissioners in advance of the event. If a Commissioner is speaking in his or her private capacity, he or she shall include qualifying language that the views they are representing are his or her own views and not the views of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Members of the Commission may, with the approval of the Commission, conduct such travel as is necessary to carry out the purpose of this subchapter. Each trip must be approved by a majority of the Commission. This provision shall not apply to the Ambassador-at-Large, whose travel shall not require approval by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition against payment of official travel by non-Federal sources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Members of the Commission and Commission staff may not accept payment from a non-Federal source for expenses related to official travel on behalf of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual disclosures</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than March 1 of each year, each Member of the Commission shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees (as defined in <ref>section 6433a(a) of this title</ref>) with respect to the most recently concluded 12-month period, that discloses any travel by the Member outside of the United States that was paid for or reimbursed by a person or entity other than the Member, a relative of the Member, or the Federal Government, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who paid for or reimbursed the travel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a good faith estimate of the cost of the travel, if the travel was funded by a person or entity that does not employ the Member; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> brief details of the travel and events related to such travel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 203</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 401</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII</ref>, §§ 804(b), 806(b), (c), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3077</ref>, 3078.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6432b.</num>
<heading> Commission personnel matters</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may, without regard to the civil service laws and regulations, appoint and terminate an Executive Director and such other additional personnel as may be necessary to enable the Commission to perform its duties. The decision to employ or terminate an Executive Director shall be made by an affirmative vote of at least six of the nine members of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission may provide reasonable compensation to the Executive Director without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for the Executive Director may not exceed the rate payable under level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of such title. The rate of pay for other personnel of the Commission may not exceed the rate payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of such title. All employees of the Commission shall otherwise be treated as employees whose pay is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate, including for purposes of applying the Standing Rules of the Senate. The Commission shall be treated as an employing office of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Professional staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission and the Executive Director shall hire Commission staff on the basis of professional and nonpartisan qualifications. Commissioners may not individually hire staff of the Commission. Staff shall serve the Commission as a whole and may not be assigned to the particular service of a single Commissioner or a specified group of Commissioners. This subsection does not prohibit staff personnel from assisting individual members of the Commission with particular needs related to their duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staff and services of other Federal agencies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall assist the Commission by providing on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis to the Commission such staff and administrative services as may be necessary and appropriate to perform its functions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other Federal agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the request of the Commission, the head of any Federal department or agency may detail, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that department or agency to the Commission to assist it in carrying out its functions under this subchapter. The detail of any such personnel shall be without interruption or loss of civil service or Foreign Service status or privilege.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Security clearances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Executive Director shall be required to obtain a security clearance. The Executive Director may request, on a needs-only basis and in order to perform the duties of the Commission, that other personnel of the Commission be required to obtain a security clearance. The level of clearance shall be the lowest necessary to appropriately perform the duties of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall reimburse all appropriate Government agencies for the cost of obtaining clearances for members of the Commission, for the Executive Director, and for any other personnel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 204</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 402</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–75, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII, § 805(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3077</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6433.</num>
<heading> Report of Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than May 1 of each year, the Commission shall submit a report to the President, the Secretary of State, and Congress setting forth its recommendations for United States policy options based on its evaluations under <ref>section 6432 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Classified form of report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report may be submitted in classified form, together with a public summary of recommendations, if the classification of information would further the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individual or dissenting views</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each member of the Commission may include the individual or dissenting views of the member.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 205</ref>, formerly § 203, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2799</ref>; renumbered § 205, <ref>Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 401</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6433a.</num>
<heading> Strategic plan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commission” means the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom established under <ref>section 6431 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commissioner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Commissioner” means a member of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vice Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Vice Chair” means the Vice Chair of the Commission who was appointed to such position by an elected official from the political party that is different from the political party of the elected official who appointed the Chair of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategic policy and organizational review planning process</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2015-10-16">October 16, 2015</date>, and not less frequently than biennially thereafter, the Chair and Vice Chair of the Commission, in coordination with the Commissioners, the Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom, Commission staff, and others jointly selected by the Chair and Vice Chair, shall carry out a strategic policy and organizational review planning process that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a review of the duties set forth in <ref>section 6432 of this title</ref> and the powers set forth in <ref>section 6432a of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the preparation of a written description of prioritized actions that the Commission is required to complete to fulfill the strategic plan required under subsection (d);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a review of the scope, content, and timing of the Commission’s annual report and any required changes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a review of the personnel policies set forth in <ref>section 6432b of this title</ref> and any required changes to such policies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unanimous agreement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To the greatest extent possible, the Chair, Vice Chair, and all of the Commissioners shall ensure that this section is implemented in a manner that results in unanimous agreement among the Commissioners with regard to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the strategic policy and organizational review planning process required under subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the strategic plan required under subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternative approval process</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If unanimous agreement under paragraph (1) is not possible, items for inclusion in the strategic plan may, at the joint discretion of the Chair and Vice Chair, be approved by an affirmative vote of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a majority of Commissioners appointed by an elected official from the political party of the President; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a majority of Commissioners appointed by an elected official from the political party that is not the party of the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of strategic plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Chair and Vice Chair of the Commission shall jointly submit, to the appropriate congressional committees, a written strategic plan that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of prioritized actions for the Commission for a period of time to be specified by the Commissioners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of any changes the Commission considers necessary with regard to the scope, content, and timing of the Commission’s annual report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of any changes the Commission considers necessary with regard to personnel matters; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Commission’s funding requirements for the period covered by the strategic plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pending issues</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The strategic plan required under subsection (d) may identify any issues or proposals that have not yet been resolved by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of personnel provisions and annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002344">1</ref> 6432b(a) and 6533(a) of this title, the Commission is authorized to implement provisions related to personnel and the Commission’s annual report that are included in the strategic plan submitted pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional oversight</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon request, the Commission shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> make available for inspection any information and documents requested by the appropriate congressional committees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> respond to any requests to provide testimony before the appropriate congressional committees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–71, § 4</ref>, <date date="2015-10-16">Oct. 16, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII, § 807</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6434.</num>
<heading> Applicability of other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the Commission.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 206</ref>, formerly § 204, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2799</ref>; renumbered § 206, <ref>Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 401</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(172)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4324</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6435.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission $3,500,000 for each of the fiscal years 2025 and 2026 to carry out the provisions of this chapter and <ref>section 6433a of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Amounts authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a) shall remain available until the earlier of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which they have been expended; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the date on which the Commission is terminated under <ref>section 6436 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In each fiscal year, the Commission shall only be authorized to expend amounts that have been appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) if the Commission—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> complies with the requirements set forth in <ref>section 6433a of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submits the annual financial report required under <ref>section 6435a(e) of this title</ref> to the appropriate congressional committees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 207</ref>, formerly § 205, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2800</ref>; renumbered § 207 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(2)</ref>, (4), <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 401</ref>, 403; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title VI, § 681(e)</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1409</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–75, § 4</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–271, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2951</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–71, § 5</ref>, <date date="2015-10-16">Oct. 16, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 565</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII, § 808</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3079</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–181, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-09-30">Sept. 30, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2177</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–90, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-09-30">Sept. 30, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1559</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6435a.</num>
<heading> Standards of conduct and disclosure</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with nongovernmental organizations, the Department of State, and Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall seek to effectively and freely cooperate with all entities engaged in the promotion of religious freedom abroad, governmental and nongovernmental, in the performance of the Commission’s duties under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conflict of interest and antinepotism</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Member affiliations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (3), in order to ensure the independence and integrity of the Commission, the Commission may not compensate any nongovernmental agency, project, or person related to or affiliated with any member of the Commission, whether in that member’s direct employ or not. Staff employed by the Commission may not serve in the employ of any nongovernmental agency, project, or person related to or affiliated with any member of the Commission while employed by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staff compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Staff of the Commission may not receive compensation from any other source for work performed in carrying out the duties of the Commission while employed by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), paragraph (1) shall not apply to payments made for items such as conference fees or the purchase of periodicals or other similar expenses, if such payments would not cause the aggregate value paid to any agency, project, or person for a fiscal year to exceed $250.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the Commission shall not give special preference to any agency, project, or person related to or affiliated with any member of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “affiliated” means the relationship between a member of the Commission and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an individual who holds the position of officer, trustee, partner, director, or employee of an agency, project, or person of which that member, or relative of that member of,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002345">1</ref> the Commission is an officer, trustee, partner, director, or employee; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a nongovernmental agency or project of which that member, or a relative of that member, of the Commission is an officer, trustee, partner, director, or employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Commission may contract with and compensate Government agencies or persons for the conduct of activities necessary to the discharge of its functions under this subchapter. Any such person shall be hired without interruption or loss of civil service or Foreign Service status or privilege. The Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services under the authority of <ref>section 3109(b) of title 5</ref>, except that the Commission may not expend more than $250,000 in any fiscal year to procure such services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expert study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a study requested under section 6474 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002346">2</ref> of this title, the Commission may, subject to the availability of appropriations, contract with experts and shall provide the funds for such a study. The Commission shall not be required to provide the funds for that part of the study conducted by the Comptroller General of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gifts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In order to preserve its independence, the Commission may not accept, use, or dispose of gifts or donations of services or property. An individual Commissioner or employee of the Commission may not, in his or her capacity as a Commissioner or employee, knowingly accept, use or dispose of gifts or donations of services or property, unless he or she in good faith believes such gifts or donations to have a value of less than $50 and a cumulative value during a calendar year of less than $100.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">This subsection shall not apply to the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Gifts provided on the basis of a personal friendship with a Commissioner or employee, unless the Commissioner or employee has reason to believe that the gift was provided because of the Commissioner’s position and not because of the personal friendship.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Gifts provided on the basis of a family relationship.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The acceptance of training, invitations to attend or participate in conferences or such other events as are related to the conduct of the duties of the Commission, or food or refreshment associated with such activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Items of nominal value or gifts of estimated value of $10 or less.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> De minimis gifts provided by a foreign leader or state, not exceeding a value of $260. Gifts believed by Commissioners to be in excess of $260, but which would create offense or embarrassment to the United States Government if refused, shall be accepted and turned over to the United States Government in accordance with the Foreign Gifts and Decorations Act of 1966 and the rules and regulations governing such gifts provided to Members of Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Informational materials such as documents, books, videotapes, periodicals, or other forms of communications.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Goods or services provided by any agency or component of the Government of the United States, including any commission established under the authority of such Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual financial report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to providing the reports required under <ref>section 6432 of this title</ref>, the Commission shall provide, each year no later than January 1, to the Committees on Foreign Affairs and Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and to the Committees on Foreign Relations and Appropriations of the Senate, a financial report detailing and identifying its expenditures for the preceding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall comply with all of the records management requirements set forth in chapter 31 of title 44 (commonly referred to as the “Federal Records Act of 1950”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Official email for commission business</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When conducting any Commission business on electronic accounts, Commission Members and staff shall use official Commission electronic accounts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 208</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 403</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title VI, § 681(f)</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1409</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–75, § 5</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII, § 809</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6436.</num>
<heading> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall terminate on <date date="2026-09-30">September 30, 2026</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 209</ref>, formerly § 206, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2800</ref>; renumbered § 209 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(2)</ref>, (c), <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 401</ref>, 405; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title VI, § 681(g)</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1409</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–75, § 6</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–271, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2951</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–71, § 3</ref>, <date date="2015-10-16">Oct. 16, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3076</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–181, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-09-30">Sept. 30, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2177</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–90, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-09-30">Sept. 30, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1559</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PRESIDENTIAL ACTIONS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Targeted Responses to Violations of Religious Freedom Abroad</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6441.</num>
<heading> Presidential actions in response to violations of religious freedom</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Response to violations of religious freedom</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">It shall be the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to oppose violations of religious freedom that are or have been engaged in or tolerated by the governments of foreign countries; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to promote the right to freedom of religion in those countries through the actions described in subsection (b).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of Presidential action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For each foreign country the government of which engages in or tolerates violations of religious freedom, the President shall oppose such violations and promote the right to freedom of religion in that country through the actions described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basis of actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each action taken under paragraph (1)(B) shall be based upon information regarding violations of religious freedom, as described in the latest Country Reports on Human Rights Practices, the Annual Report and Executive Summary, and on any other evidence available, and shall take into account any findings or recommendations by the Commission with respect to the foreign country.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential actions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the President, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Ambassador at Large, the Special Adviser, and the Commission, shall, as expeditiously as practicable in response to the violations described in subsection (a) by the government of a foreign country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> take one or more of the actions described in paragraphs (1) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or commensurate action in substitution thereto) with respect to such country; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> negotiate and enter into a binding agreement with the government of such country, as described in <ref>section 6445(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline for actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than September 1 of each year, the President shall take action under any of paragraphs (1) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or commensurate action in substitution thereto) with respect to each foreign country the government of which has engaged in or tolerated violations of religious freedom at any time since September 1 of the preceding year, except that in the case of action under any of paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or commensurate action in substitution thereto)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the action may only be taken after the requirements of sections 6443 and 6444 of this title have been satisfied; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the September 1 limitation shall not apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority for delay of Presidential actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may delay action under paragraph (2) described in any of paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or commensurate action in substitution thereto) if he determines and certifies to Congress that a single, additional period of time, not to exceed 90 days, is necessary pursuant to the same provisions applying to countries of particular concern for religious freedom under <ref>section 6442(c)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out subsection (b), the President shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> take the action or actions that most appropriately respond to the nature and severity of the violations of religious freedom;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> seek to the fullest extent possible to target action as narrowly as practicable with respect to the agency or instrumentality of the foreign government, or specific officials thereof, that are responsible for such violations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> when appropriate, make every reasonable effort to conclude a binding agreement concerning the cessation of such violations in countries with which the United States has diplomatic relations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines for Presidential actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to the guidelines under paragraph (1), the President, in determining whether to take a Presidential action under paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or commensurate action in substitution thereto), shall seek to minimize any adverse impact on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the population of the country whose government is targeted by the Presidential action or actions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the humanitarian activities of United States and foreign nongovernmental organizations in such country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2800</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6442.</num>
<heading> Presidential actions in response to particularly severe violations of religious freedom</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Response to particularly severe violations of religious freedom</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">It shall be the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to oppose particularly severe violations of religious freedom that are or have been engaged in or tolerated by the governments of foreign countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to promote the right to freedom of religion in those countries through the actions described in subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of Presidential action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whenever the President determines that the government of a foreign country has engaged in or tolerated particularly severe violations of religious freedom, the President shall oppose such violations and promote the right to religious freedom through one or more of the actions described in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designations of countries of particular concern for religious freedom</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual review</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 90 days after the date on which each Annual Report is submitted under <ref>section 6412(b) of this title</ref>, the President shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> review the status of religious freedom in each foreign country to determine whether the government of that country has engaged in or tolerated particularly severe violations of religious freedom in each such country during the preceding 12 months or longer;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> designate each country the government of which has engaged in or tolerated violations described in clause (i) as a country of particular concern for religious freedom; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> designate each country that engaged in or tolerated severe violations of religious freedom during the previous year, but does not meet, in the opinion of the President at the time of publication of the Annual Report, all of the criteria described in <ref>section 6402(15) of this title</ref> for designation under clause (ii) as being placed on a “Special Watch List”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basis of review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each review conducted under subparagraph (A) shall be based upon information contained in the latest Country Reports on Human Rights Practices, the Annual Report, and on any other evidence available and shall take into account any findings or recommendations by the Commission with respect to the foreign country.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any review under subparagraph (A) of a foreign country may take place singly or jointly with the review of one or more countries and may take place at any time before the date on which each Annual Report is submitted under <ref>section 6412(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determinations of responsible parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For the government of each country designated as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under paragraph (1)(A), the President shall seek to determine the agency or instrumentality thereof and the specific officials thereof that are responsible for the particularly severe violations of religious freedom engaged in or tolerated by that government in order to appropriately target Presidential actions under this section in response.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Whenever the President designates a country as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under paragraph (1)(A)(ii), the President, not later than 90 days after such designation, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the designation of the country, signed by the President;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the identification, if any, of responsible parties determined under paragraph (2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a description of the actions taken under subsection (c), the purposes of the actions taken, and the effectiveness of the actions taken.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A country that is designated as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under paragraph (1)(A)(ii) shall retain such designation until the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees that the country should no longer be so designated.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on designation as country of particular concern</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The presence or absence of a country from the Special Watch List in any given year shall not preclude the designation of such country as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under paragraph (1)(A)(ii) in any such year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential actions with respect to countries of particular concern for religious freedom</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5) with respect to each country of particular concern for religious freedom designated under subsection (b)(1)(A), the President shall, after the requirements of sections 6443 and 6444 of this title have been satisfied, but not later than 90 days (or 180 days in case of a delay under paragraph (3)) after the date of designation of the country under that subsection, carry out one or more of the following actions under subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B):</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">One or more of the Presidential actions described in paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref>, as determined by the President.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commensurate actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Commensurate action in substitution to any action described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substitution of binding agreements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In lieu of carrying out action under paragraph (1), the President may conclude a binding agreement with the respective foreign government as described in <ref>section 6445(c) of this title</ref>. The existence of a binding agreement under this paragraph with a foreign government may be considered by the President prior to making any determination or taking any action under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to authorize the entry of the United States into an agreement covering matters outside the scope of violations of religious freedom.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority for delay of Presidential actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If, on or before the date that the President is required (but for this paragraph) to take action under paragraph (1), the President determines and certifies to Congress that a single, additional period of time not to exceed 90 days is necessary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for a continuation of negotiations that have been commenced with the government of that country to bring about a cessation of the violations by the foreign country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a continuation of multilateral negotiations into which the United States has entered to bring about a cessation of the violations by the foreign country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for a review of corrective action taken by the foreign country after designation of such country as a country of particular concern; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in anticipation that corrective action will be taken by the foreign country during the 90-day period,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">then the President shall not be required to take action until the expiration of that period of time.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for ongoing Presidential action under this chapter</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President shall not be required to take action pursuant to this subsection in the case of a country of particular concern for religious freedom, if with respect to such country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the President has taken action pursuant to this chapter in a preceding year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such action is in effect at the time the country is designated as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the President reports to Congress the information described in section 6444(a)(1), (2), (3), and (4) of this title regarding the actions in effect with respect to the country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for ongoing, multiple, broad-based sanctions in response to human rights violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the time the President determines a country to be a country of particular concern, if that country is already subject to multiple, broad-based sanctions imposed in significant part in response to human rights abuses, and such sanctions are ongoing, the President may determine that one or more of these sanctions also satisfies the requirements of this subsection. In a report to Congress pursuant to section 6444(a)(1), (2), (3), and (4) of this title, and, as applicable, to <ref>section 6448 of this title</ref>, the President shall designate the specific sanction or sanctions that the President determines satisfy the requirements under this subsection and include a description of the impact of such sanction or sanctions on each country. The sanctions so designated shall remain in effect subject to <ref>section 6449 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A determination under this chapter, or any amendment made by this chapter, that a foreign country has engaged in or tolerated particularly severe violations of religious freedom shall not be construed to require the termination of assistance or other activities with respect to that country under any other provision of law, including section 2151n or 2304 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2802</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–55, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1434</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6442a.</num>
<heading> Non-state actor designations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President, concurrent with the annual foreign country review required under section 402(b)(1)(A) of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 6442(b)(1)(A)</ref>), shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review and identify any non-state actors operating in any such reviewed country or surrounding region that have engaged in particularly severe violations of religious freedom; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> designate, in a manner consistent with such Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 6401</ref> et seq.], each such non-state actor as an entity of particular concern for religious freedom.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the President designates a non-state actor under subsection (a) as an entity of particular concern for religious freedom, the President, as soon as practicable after the designation is made, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes the reasons for such designation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President should take specific actions, when practicable, to address severe violations of religious freedom of non-state actors that are designated under subsection (a)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of State annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State should include information detailing the reasons the President designated a non-state actor as an entity of particular concern for religious freedom under subsection (a) in the Annual Report required under section 102(b)(1) of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 6412(b)(1)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary of State should work with Congress and the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to create new political, financial, and diplomatic tools to address severe violations of religious freedom by non-state actors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to update the actions the President can take under section 405 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 6445</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> governments must ultimately be held accountable for the abuses that occur in their territories; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any actions the President takes after designating a non-state actor as an entity of particular concern should also involve high-level diplomacy with the government of the country in which the non-state actor is operating.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determinations of responsible parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to appropriately target Presidential actions under the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 6401</ref> et seq.), the President, with respect to each non-state actor designated as an entity of particular concern for religious freedom under subsection (a), shall seek to determine, to the extent practicable, the specific officials or members that are responsible for the particularly severe violations of religious freedom engaged in or tolerated by such non-state actor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the terms “appropriate congressional committees”, “non-state actor”, and “particularly severe violations of religious freedom” have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 6402</ref>), as amended by section 3 of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6443.</num>
<heading> Consultations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the President decides to take action under <ref>section 6441 of this title</ref> in response to violations of religious freedom and the President decides to take action under paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or commensurate action in substitution thereto) with respect to that country, or not later than 90 days after the President designates a country as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under <ref>section 6442 of this title</ref>, as the case may be, the President shall carry out the consultations required in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duty to consult with foreign governments prior to taking Presidential actions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> request consultation with the government of such country regarding the violations giving rise to designation of that country as a country of particular concern for religious freedom or to Presidential action under <ref>section 6441 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if agreed to, enter into such consultations, privately or publicly.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of multilateral fora</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the President determines it to be appropriate, such consultations may be sought and may occur in a multilateral forum, but, in any event, the President shall consult with appropriate foreign governments for the purposes of achieving a coordinated international policy on actions that may be taken with respect to a country described in subsection (a), prior to implementing any such action.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election of nondisclosure of negotiations to public</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If negotiations are undertaken or an agreement is concluded with a foreign government regarding steps to cease the pattern of violations by that government, and if public disclosure of such negotiations or agreement would jeopardize the negotiations or the implementation of such agreement, as the case may be, the President may refrain from disclosing such negotiations and such agreement to the public, except that the President shall inform the appropriate congressional committees of the nature and extent of such negotiations and any agreement reached.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duty to consult with humanitarian organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President should consult with appropriate humanitarian and religious organizations concerning the potential impact of United States policies to promote freedom of religion in countries described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duty to consult with United States interested parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall, as appropriate, consult with United States interested parties as to the potential impact of intended Presidential action or actions in countries described in subsection (a) on economic or other interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2804</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6444.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), not later than 90 days after the President decides to take action under <ref>section 6441 of this title</ref> in response to violations of religious freedom and the President decides to take action under paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or commensurate action in substitution thereto) with respect to that country, or not later than 90 days after the President designates a country as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under <ref>section 6442 of this title</ref>, as the case may be, the President shall submit a report to Congress containing the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of Presidential actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An identification of the Presidential action or actions described in paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or commensurate action in substitution thereto) to be taken with respect to the foreign country.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description of violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A description of the violations giving rise to the Presidential action or actions to be taken.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose of Presidential actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A description of the purpose of the Presidential action or actions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An evaluation, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Ambassador at Large, the Commission, the Special Adviser, the parties described in section 6443(c) and (d) of this title, and whoever else the President deems appropriate, of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the impact upon the foreign government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the impact upon the population of the country;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the impact upon the United States economy and other interested parties; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the impact on the advancement of United States interests in democracy, human rights, and security, and a description of policy tools being applied in the country, including programs that target democratic stability, economic growth, and counterterrorism.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to withhold disclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The President may withhold part or all of such evaluation from the public but shall provide the entire evaluation to Congress.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of policy options</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A statement that noneconomic policy options designed to bring about cessation of the particularly severe violations of religious freedom have reasonably been exhausted, including the consultations required in <ref>section 6443 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description of multilateral negotiations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A description of multilateral negotiations sought or carried out, if appropriate and applicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delay in transmittal of report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, on or before the date that the President is required (but for this subsection) to submit a report under subsection (a) to Congress, the President determines and certifies to Congress that a single, additional period of time not to exceed 90 days is necessary pursuant to section 6441(b)(3) or 6442(c)(3) of this title, then the President shall not be required to submit the report to Congress until the expiration of that period of time.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2805</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1435</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6445.</num>
<heading> Description of Presidential actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description of Presidential actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (d), the Presidential actions referred to in this subsection are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A private demarche.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> An official public demarche.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A public condemnation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A public condemnation within one or more multilateral fora.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The delay or cancellation of one or more scientific exchanges.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The delay or cancellation of one or more cultural exchanges.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The denial of one or more working, official, or state visits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The delay or cancellation of one or more working, official, or state visits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States development assistance in accordance with <ref>section 2151n of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Directing the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, or the Trade and Development Agency not to approve the issuance of any (or a specified number of) guarantees, insurance, extensions of credit, or participations in the extension of credit with respect to the specific government, agency, instrumentality, or official found or determined by the President to be responsible for violations under section 6441 or 6442 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States security assistance in accordance with <ref>section 2304 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Consistent with <ref>section 262d of this title</ref>, directing the United States executive directors of international financial institutions to oppose and vote against loans primarily benefiting the specific foreign government, agency, instrumentality, or official found or determined by the President to be responsible for violations under section 6441 or 6442 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<chapeau> Ordering the heads of the appropriate United States agencies not to issue any (or a specified number of) specific licenses, and not to grant any other specific authority (or a specified number of authorities), to export any goods or technology to the specific foreign government, agency, instrumentality, or official found or determined by the President to be responsible for violations under section 6441 or 6442 of this title, under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Export Administration Act of 1979;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Arms Export Control Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.]; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other statute that requires the prior review and approval of the United States Government as a condition for the export or reexport of goods or services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Prohibiting any United States financial institution from making loans or providing credits totaling more than $10,000,000 in any 12-month period to the specific foreign government, agency, instrumentality, or official found or determined by the President to be responsible for violations under section 6441 or 6442 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> Prohibiting the United States Government from procuring, or entering into any contract for the procurement of, any goods or services from the foreign government, entities, or officials found or determined by the President to be responsible for violations under section 6441 or 6442 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commensurate action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (d), the President may substitute any other action authorized by law for any action described in paragraphs (1) through (15) of subsection (a) if such action is commensurate in effect to the action substituted and if the action would further the policy of the United States set forth in <ref>section 6401(b) of this title</ref>. The President shall seek to take all appropriate and feasible actions authorized by law to obtain the cessation of the violations. If commensurate action is taken, the President shall report such action, together with an explanation for taking such action, to the appropriate congressional committees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Binding agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may negotiate and enter into a binding agreement with a foreign government that obligates such government to cease, or take substantial steps to address and phase out, the act, policy, or practice constituting the violation of religious freedom. The entry into force of a binding agreement for the cessation of the violations shall be a primary objective for the President in responding to a foreign government that has engaged in or tolerated particularly severe violations of religious freedom.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any action taken pursuant to subsection (a) or (b) may not prohibit or restrict the provision of medicine, medical equipment or supplies, food, or other humanitarian assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2806</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. F, title VI, § 1470</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3518</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6446.</num>
<heading> Effects on existing contracts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall not be required to apply or maintain any Presidential action under this part—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of procurement of defense articles or defense services—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> under existing contracts or subcontracts, including the exercise of options for production quantities, to satisfy requirements essential to the national security of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the President determines in writing and so reports to Congress that the person or other entity to which the Presidential action would otherwise be applied is a sole source supplier of the defense articles or services, that the defense articles or services are essential, and that alternative sources are not readily or reasonably available; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> if the President determines in writing and so reports to Congress that such articles or services are essential to the national security under defense coproduction agreements; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to products or services provided under contracts entered into before the date on which the President publishes his intention to take the Presidential action.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2808</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6447.</num>
<heading> Presidential waiver</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsection (c), the President may waive, for a single, 180-day period, the application of any of the actions described in paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or commensurate action in substitution thereto) with respect to a country, if the President determines and so reports to the appropriate congressional committees that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the exercise of such waiver authority would further the purposes of this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the important national interest of the United States requires the exercise of such waiver authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsection (c), the President may waive, for any additional specified period of time after the 180-day period described in subsection (a), the application of any of the actions described in paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or a commensurate substitute action) with respect to a country, if the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the respective foreign government has ceased the violations giving rise to the Presidential action; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the important national interest of the United States requires the exercise of such waiver authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than the date of the exercise of a waiver under subsection (a) or (b), the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the waiver or the intention to exercise the waiver, together with a detailed justification thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ongoing and persistent waivers of the application of any of the actions described in paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or commensurate substitute action) with respect to a country do not fulfill the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> because the promotion of religious freedom is an important interest of United States foreign policy, the President, the Secretary of State, and other executive branch officials, in consultation with Congress, should seek to find ways to address existing violations, on a case-by-case basis, through the actions described in <ref>section 6445 of this title</ref> or other commensurate substitute action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2808</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1435</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6448.</num>
<heading> Publication in Federal Register</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), the President shall cause to be published in the Federal Register the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determinations of governments, officials, and entities of particular concern</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any designation of a country of particular concern for religious freedom under <ref>section 6442(b)(1) of this title</ref>, together with, when applicable and to the extent practicable, the identities of the officials or entities determined to be responsible for the violations under <ref>section 6442(b)(2) of this title</ref>. Any designation of a non-state actor as an entity of particular concern for religious freedom under <ref>section 6442a of this title</ref> and, if applicable and to the extent practicable, the identities of individuals determined to be responsible for violations described in subsection (f) of such section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A description of any Presidential action under paragraphs (9) through (15) of <ref>section 6445(a) of this title</ref> (or commensurate action in substitution thereto) and the effective date of the Presidential action.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delays in transmittal of Presidential action reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any delay in transmittal of a Presidential action report, as described in <ref>section 6444(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waivers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any waiver under <ref>section 6447 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited disclosure of information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may limit publication of information under this section in the same manner and to the same extent as the President may limit the publication of findings and determinations described in <ref>section 2414(c) of this title</ref>, if the President determines that the publication of information under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> would be harmful to the national security of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> would not further the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2808</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1436</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6449.</num>
<heading> Termination of Presidential actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any Presidential action taken under this chapter with respect to a foreign country shall terminate on the earlier of the following dates:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Within 2 years of the effective date of the Presidential action unless expressly reauthorized by law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign government actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the determination by the President, in consultation with the Commission, and certification to Congress that the foreign government has ceased or taken substantial and verifiable steps to cease the particularly severe violations of religious freedom.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 409</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2809</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6450.</num>
<heading> Preclusion of judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No court shall have jurisdiction to review any Presidential determination or agency action under this chapter or any amendment made by this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 410</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2809</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Strengthening Existing Law</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6461.</num>
<heading> Exports of certain items used in particularly severe violations of religious freedom</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory licensing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Commerce, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall include on the list of crime control and detection instruments or equipment controlled for export and reexport under section 4605(n) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002347">1</ref> of title 50 or under any other provision of law, items being exported or reexported to countries of particular concern for religious freedom that the Secretary of Commerce, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, and in consultation with appropriate officials including the Assistant Secretary of State for Democracy, Human Rights and Labor and the Ambassador at Large, determines are being used or are intended for use directly and in significant measure to carry out particularly severe violations of religious freedom.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Licensing ban</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The prohibition on the issuance of a license for export of crime control and detection instruments or equipment under <ref>section 2304(a)(2) of this title</ref> shall apply to the export and reexport of any item included pursuant to subsection (a) on the list of crime control instruments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 423</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2810</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>REFUGEE, ASYLUM, AND CONSULAR MATTERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6471.</num>
<heading> Use of Annual Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Annual Report, together with other relevant documentation, shall serve as a resource for immigration judges and consular, refugee, and asylum officers in cases involving claims of persecution on the grounds of religion. Absence of reference by the Annual Report to conditions described by the alien shall not constitute the sole grounds for a denial of the alien’s claim.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2812</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6472.</num>
<heading> Reform of refugee policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold">, (b) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines for refugee-processing posts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines for addressing hostile biases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General and the Secretary of State shall develop and implement guidelines that address potential biases in personnel of the Immigration and Naturalization Service and of the Department of State that are hired abroad and involved with duties which could constitute an effective barrier to a refugee claim if such personnel carries a bias against the claimant on the grounds of religion, race, nationality, membership in a particular social group, or political opinion. The subject matter of this training should be culturally sensitive and tailored to provide a nonbiased, nonadversarial atmosphere for the purpose of refugee adjudications.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines for refugee-processing posts in establishing agreements with United States Government-designated refugee processing entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General and the Secretary of State shall develop and implement guidelines to ensure uniform procedures for establishing agreements with United States Government-designated refugee processing entities and personnel, and uniform procedures for such entities and personnel responsible for preparing refugee case files for use by the Immigration and Naturalization Service during refugee adjudications. These procedures should ensure, to the extent practicable, that case files prepared by such entities accurately reflect information provided by the refugee applicants and that genuine refugee applicants are not disadvantaged or denied refugee status due to faulty case file preparation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines for preventing persons with potential biases from participating in determinations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="1999-11-29">November 29, 1999</date>, the Secretary of State (after consultation with the Attorney General) shall issue guidelines to ensure that persons with potential biases against any refugee applicant, including persons employed by, or otherwise subject to influence by, governments known to be involved in persecution on account of religion, race, nationality, membership in a particular social group, or political opinion, shall not in any way be used in processing determinations of refugee status, including interpretation of conversations or examination of documents presented by such applicants.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall include in each annual report on proposed refugee admissions under <ref>section 1157(d) of title 8</ref> information about religious persecution of refugee populations eligible for consideration for admission to the United States. The Secretary of State shall include information on religious persecution of refugee populations in the formal testimony presented to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate during the consultation process under <ref>section 1157(e) of title 8</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2812</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title II, § 253]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–432.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6473.</num>
<heading> Reform of asylum policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General and the Secretary of State shall develop guidelines to ensure that persons with potential biases against individuals on the grounds of religion, race, nationality, membership in a particular social group, or political opinion, including interpreters and personnel of airlines owned by governments known to be involved in practices which would meet the definition of persecution under international refugee law, shall not in any manner be used to interpret conversations between aliens and inspection or asylum officers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training for asylum and immigration officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Ambassador at Large, and other relevant officials such as the Director of the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center, shall provide training to all officers adjudicating asylum cases, and to immigration officers performing duties under <ref>section 1225(b) of title 8</ref>, on the nature of religious persecution abroad, including country-specific conditions, instruction on the internationally recognized right to freedom of religion, instruction on methods of religious persecution practiced in foreign countries, and applicable distinctions within a country in the treatment of various religious practices and believers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training for immigration judges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Executive Office of Immigration Review of the Department of Justice shall incorporate into its initial and ongoing training of immigration judges training on the extent and nature of religious persecution internationally, including country-specific conditions, and including use of the Annual Report. Such training shall include governmental and nongovernmental methods of persecution employed, and differences in the treatment of religious groups by such persecuting entities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2813</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–132, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2412</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6473a.</num>
<heading> Designated persons list for particularly severe violations of religious freedom</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> List</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Ambassador at Large and in consultation with relevant government and nongovernment experts, shall establish and maintain a list of foreign individuals to whom a consular post has denied a visa on the grounds of particularly severe violations of religious freedom under <ref>section 1182(a)(2)(G) of title 8</ref>, or who are subject to financial sanctions or other measures for particularly severe violations of freedom religion.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The list required under paragraph (1) shall be known as the “Designated Persons List for Particularly Severe Violations of Religious Freedom”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that contains the list required under subsection (a), including, with respect to each foreign individual on the list—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of the individual and a description of the particularly severe violation of religious freedom committed by the individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the name of the country or other location in which such violation took place; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of the actions taken pursuant to this chapter or any other Act or Executive order in response to such violation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission and updates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the initial report required under paragraph (1) not later than 180 days after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> updates to the report every 180 days thereafter and as new information becomes available.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report required under paragraph (1) should be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title VI, § 605</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title V, § 501(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1437</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6474.</num>
<heading> Studies on effect of expedited removal provisions on asylum claims</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Studies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission request for participation by experts on refugee and asylum issues</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Commission so requests, the Attorney General shall invite experts designated by the Commission, who are recognized for their expertise and knowledge of refugee and asylum issues, to conduct a study, in cooperation with the Comptroller General of the United States, to determine whether immigration officers described in paragraph (2) are engaging in any of the conduct described in such paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Comptroller General</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study alone or, upon request by the Commission, in cooperation with experts designated by the Commission, to determine whether immigration officers performing duties under <ref>section 1225(b) of title 8</ref> with respect to aliens who may be eligible to be granted asylum are engaging in any of the following conduct:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Improperly encouraging such aliens to withdraw their applications for admission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Incorrectly failing to refer such aliens for an interview by an asylum officer for a determination of whether they have a credible fear of persecution (within the meaning of <ref>section 1225(b)(1)(B)(v) of title 8</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Incorrectly removing such aliens to a country where they may be persecuted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Detaining such aliens improperly or in inappropriate conditions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation by experts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a Commission request under subsection (a), the experts designated by the Commission under that subsection may submit a report to the committees described in paragraph (2). Such report may be submitted with the Comptroller General’s report under subsection (a)(2) or independently.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Comptroller General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2000-09-01">September 1, 2000</date>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report containing the results of the study conducted under subsection (a)(2). If the Commission requests designated experts to participate with the Comptroller General in the preparation and submission of the report, the Comptroller General shall grant the request.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to proceedings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), to facilitate the studies and reports, the Attorney General shall permit the Comptroller General of the United States and, in the case of a Commission request under subsection (a), the experts designated under subsection (a) to have unrestricted access to all stages of all proceedings conducted under <ref>section 1225(b) of title 8</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply in cases in which the alien objects to such access, or the Attorney General determines that the security of a particular proceeding would be threatened by such access, so long as any restrictions on the access of experts designated by the Commission under subsection (a) do not contravene international law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title VI, § 606</ref>, formerly § 605, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2814</ref>; renumbered § 606, <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title V, § 501(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1437</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6481.</num>
<heading> Business codes of conduct</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional finding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress recognizes the increasing importance of transnational corporations as global actors, and their potential for providing positive leadership in their host countries in the area of human rights.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that transnational corporations operating overseas, particularly those corporations operating in countries the governments of which have engaged in or tolerated violations of religious freedom, as identified in the Annual Report, should adopt codes of conduct—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> upholding the right to freedom of religion of their employees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensuring that a worker’s religious views and peaceful practices of belief in no way affect, or be allowed to affect, the status or terms of his or her employment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6482.</num>
<heading> Voluntary codes of conduct for United States institutions of higher education outside the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress recognizes the enduring importance of United States institutions of higher education worldwide—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for their potential for shaping positive leadership and new educational models in host countries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for their emphasis on teaching universally recognized rights of free inquiry and academic freedom.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that United States institutions of higher education operating campuses outside the United States or establishing any educational entities with foreign governments, particularly with or in countries the governments of which engage in or tolerate severe violations of religious freedom as identified in the Annual Report, should seek to adopt a voluntary code of conduct for operating in such countries that should—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> uphold the right of freedom of religion of their employees and students, including the right to manifest that religion peacefully as protected in international law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensure that the religious views and peaceful practice of religion in no way affect, or be allowed to affect, the status of a worker’s or faculty member’s employment or a student’s enrollment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make every effort in all negotiations, contracts, or memoranda of understanding engaged in or constructed with a foreign government to protect academic freedom and the rights enshrined in the United Nations Declaration of Human Rights.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title VII, § 702</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1438</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6483.</num>
<heading> Sense of Congress regarding national security strategy to promote religious freedom through United States foreign policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the annual national security strategy report of the President required under <ref>section 3043 of title 50</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> should promote international religious freedom as a foreign policy and national security priority; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> should articulate that promotion of the right to freedom of religion is a strategy that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> protects other, related human rights, and advances democracy outside the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> makes clear its importance to United States foreign policy goals of stability, security, development, and diplomacy;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> should be a guide for the strategies and activities of relevant Federal agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> should inform the Department of Defense quadrennial defense review under section 118 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002348">1</ref> of title 10 and the Department of State Quadrennial Diplomacy and Development Review.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title VII, § 703</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–281, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>