<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 104—</num>
<heading>VENEZUELA ASSISTANCE</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>SUPPORT FOR THE INTERIM PRESIDENT OF VENEZUELA AND RECOGNITION OF THE VENEZUELAN NATIONAL ASSEMBLY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9701.</num>
<heading> Findings; sense of Congress in support of the Interim President of Venezuela</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Venezuela’s electoral event on <date date="2018-05-20">May 20, 2018</date> was characterized by widespread fraud and did not comply with international standards for a free, fair, and transparent electoral process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Given the fraudulent nature of Venezuela’s <date date="2018-05-20">May 20, 2018</date> electoral event, Nicolás Maduro’s tenure as President of Venezuela ended on <date date="2019-01-10">January 10, 2019</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The National Assembly of Venezuela approved a resolution on <date date="2019-01-15">January 15, 2019</date> that terminated Nicolás Maduro’s authority as the President of Venezuela.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> On <date date="2019-01-23">January 23, 2019</date>, the President of the National Assembly of Venezuela was sworn in as the Interim President of Venezuela.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to support the decisions by the United States Government, more than 50 governments around the world, the Organization of American States, the Inter-American Development Bank, and the European Parliament to recognize National Assembly President Juan Guaidó as the Interim President of Venezuela;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to encourage the Interim President of Venezuela to advance efforts to hold democratic presidential elections in the shortest possible period; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that the Organization of American States, with support from the United States Government and partner governments, should provide diplomatic, technical, and financial support for a new presidential election in Venezuela that complies with international standards for a free, fair, and transparent electoral process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3030</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9702.</num>
<heading> Recognition of Venezuela’s democratically elected National Assembly</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Congress finds that Venezuela’s unicameral National Assembly convened on <date date="2016-01-06">January 6, 2016</date>, following democratic elections that were held on <date date="2015-12-06">December 6, 2015</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that Venezuela’s democratically elected National Assembly is the only national level democratic institution remaining in the country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States to recognize the democratically elected National Assembly of Venezuela as the only legitimate national legislative body in Venezuela.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to Venezuela’s National Assembly</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall prioritize efforts to provide technical assistance to support the democratically elected National Assembly of Venezuela in accordance with <ref>section 9731 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3031</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9703.</num>
<heading> Advancing a negotiated solution to Venezuela’s crisis</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> direct, credible negotiations led by the Interim President of Venezuela and members of Venezuela’s democratically elected National Assembly—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are supported by stakeholders in the international community that have recognized the Interim President of Venezuela;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> include the input and interests of Venezuelan civil society; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> represent the best opportunity to reach a solution to the Venezuelan crisis that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> holding a new presidential election that complies with international standards for a free, fair, and transparent electoral process;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ending Nicolás Maduro’s usurpation of presidential authorities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> restoring democracy and the rule of law;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> freeing political prisoners; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> facilitating the delivery of humanitarian aid;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> dialogue between the Maduro regime and representatives of the political opposition that commenced in October 2017, and were supported by the Governments of Mexico, of Chile, of Bolivia, and of Nicaragua, did not result in an agreement because the Maduro regime failed to credibly participate in the process; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> negotiations between the Maduro regime and representatives of the political opposition that commenced in October 2016, and were supported by the Vatican, did not result in an agreement because the Maduro regime failed to credibly participate in the process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States to support diplomatic engagement in order to advance a negotiated and peaceful solution to Venezuela’s political, economic, and humanitarian crisis that is described in subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3031</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>HUMANITARIAN RELIEF FOR VENEZUELA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9711.</num>
<heading> Humanitarian relief for the Venezuelan people</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States Government should expand efforts to peacefully address Venezuela’s humanitarian crisis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> humanitarian assistance—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> should be targeted toward those most in need and delivered through partners that uphold internationally recognized humanitarian principles; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> should not be passed through the control or distribution mechanisms of the Maduro regime.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Humanitarian relief</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> humanitarian assistance to individuals and communities in Venezuela, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> public health commodities and services, including medicines and basic medical supplies and equipment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> basic food commodities and nutritional supplements needed to address growing malnutrition and improve food security for the people of Venezuela, with a specific emphasis on the most vulnerable populations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> technical assistance to ensure that health and food commodities are appropriately selected, procured, targeted, and distributed; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Venezuelans and hosting communities, as appropriate, in neighboring countries with humanitarian aid, such as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> urgently needed health and nutritional assistance, including logistical and technical assistance to hospitals and health centers in affected communities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> food assistance for vulnerable individuals, including assistance to improve food security for affected communities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> hygiene supplies and sanitation services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aid to Venezuelans in neighboring countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The aid described in paragraph (1)(B)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> may be provided—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> directly to Venezuelans in neighboring countries, including countries of the Caribbean; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> indirectly through the communities in which the Venezuelans reside; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> should focus on the most vulnerable Venezuelans in neighboring countries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Humanitarian assistance strategy update</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall submit, to the appropriate congressional committees, an update to the Venezuela humanitarian assistance strategy described in the conference report accompanying the Consolidated Appropriations Act (<ref>Public Law 116–6</ref>), to cover a 2-year period and include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a description of the United States humanitarian assistance provided under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of United States diplomatic efforts to ensure support from international donors, including regional partners in Latin America and the Caribbean, for the provision of humanitarian assistance to the people of Venezuela;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the identification of governments that are willing to provide financial and technical assistance for the provision of such humanitarian assistance to the people of Venezuela and a description of such assistance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the identification of the financial and technical assistance to be provided by multilateral institutions, including the United Nations humanitarian agencies, the Pan American Health Organization, the Inter-American Development Bank, and the World Bank, and a description of such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diplomatic engagement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall work with relevant foreign governments and multilateral organizations to coordinate a donors summit and carry out diplomatic engagement to advance the strategy required under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated $400,000,000 for fiscal year 2020 to carry out the activities set forth in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Defined term</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3032</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9712.</num>
<heading> Support for efforts at the United Nations on the humanitarian crisis in Venezuela</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the United Nations humanitarian agencies should conduct and publish independent assessments of the humanitarian situation in Venezuela, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the extent and impact of the shortages of food, medicine, and medical supplies in Venezuela;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> basic health indicators in Venezuela, such as maternal and child mortality rates and the prevalence and treatment of communicable diseases; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the efforts needed to resolve the shortages identified in paragraph (1) and to improve the health indicators referred to in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United Nations Resident Coordinator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President should instruct the Permanent Representative to the United Nations to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States at the United Nations to support the efforts of the Resident Coordinator for Venezuela in a manner that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> contributes to Venezuela’s long-term recovery; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advances humanitarian efforts in Venezuela and for Venezuelans residing in neighboring countries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 122</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3033</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>ADDRESSING REGIME COHESION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9721.</num>
<heading> Additional restrictions on visas</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall impose the visa restrictions described in subsection (c) on any foreign person who the Secretary determines—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> is a current or former senior official of the Maduro regime, or any foreign person acting on behalf of such regime, who is knowingly responsible for, complicit in, responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, or participating in (directly or indirectly) any activity in or in relation to Venezuela, on or after <date date="2019-01-23">January 23, 2019</date>, that significantly undermines or threatens the integrity of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the democratically-elected National Assembly of Venezuela; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the President of such National Assembly, while serving as Interim President of Venezuela, or the senior government officials under the supervision of such President;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is the spouse or adult child of a foreign person described in paragraph (1); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> is the spouse or adult child of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002456">1</ref> Venezuelan person sanctioned under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> section 5(a) of the Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014 (<ref>Public Law 113–278</ref>), as amended by <ref>section 163 of this title</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002457">2</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 1903(b) of title 21</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Executive Orders 13692 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note) and 13850.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal from visa revocation list</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Pursuant to such procedures as the Secretary of State may establish to implement this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if any person described in subsection (a)(1) recognizes and pledges support for the Interim President of Venezuela or a subsequent democratically elected government of Venezuela, that person and any family members of that person who were subject to visa restrictions pursuant to subsection (a)(2) shall no longer be subject to such visa restrictions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if any person described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of subsection (a)(3) recognizes and pledges support for the Interim President of Venezuela or a subsequent democratically elected government of Venezuela, any family members of that person who were subject to visa restrictions pursuant to subsection (a)(3) shall no longer be subject to such visa restrictions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Visa restrictions described</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Visas, admission, or parole</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An alien described in subsection (a) is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> inadmissible to the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Current visas revoked</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An alien described in subsection (a) is subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immediate effect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A revocation under subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> take effect immediately; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Sanctions under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success <date date="1947-06-26">June 26, 1947</date>, and entered into force <date date="1947-11-21">November 21, 1947</date>, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to carry out or assist law enforcement activity in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rulemaking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 132</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3035</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9722.</num>
<heading> Waiver for sanctioned officials that recognize the Interim President of Venezuela</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of sanctions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a person sanctioned under any of the provisions of law described in subsection (b) recognizes and pledges supports for the Interim President of Venezuela or a subsequent democratically elected government, the person shall no longer be subject to such sanctions, pursuant to such procedures as the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury may establish to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The sanctions described in this subsection are set forth in the following provisions of law:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 5(a) of the Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014 (<ref>Public Law 113–278</ref>), as amended by <ref>section 163 of this title</ref>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002458">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Paragraph (5) <sup>1</sup> of section 5(a) of such Act, to the extent such paragraph relates to the sanctions described in paragraph (3) or (4) of such subsection.<sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Clauses (1) and (4) of section 1(a)(ii)(A) of Executive Order 13692 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subparagraph (D)(2) of section 1(a)(ii) of such Executive Order, to the extent such subparagraph relates to the provisions of law cited in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Section 1(a)(ii) of Executive Order 13850.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Paragraph (iii) of section 1(a) of such Executive Order, to the extent such paragraph relates to the provision of law cited in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rulemaking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 133</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3036</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>RESTORING DEMOCRACY AND ADDRESSING THE POLITICAL CRISIS IN VENEZUELA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9731.</num>
<heading> Support for international election observation and democratic civil society</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall work with the Organization of American States to ensure credible international observation of future elections in Venezuela that contributes to free, fair, and transparent democratic electoral processes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> shall work with nongovernmental organizations—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to strengthen democratic governance and institutions, including the democratically elected National Assembly of Venezuela;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to defend internationally recognized human rights for the people of Venezuela, including support for efforts to document crimes against humanity and violations of human rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to support the efforts of independent media outlets to broadcast, distribute, and share information beyond the limited channels made available by the Maduro regime; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to combat corruption and improve the transparency and accountability of institutions that are part of the Maduro regime.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Engagement at the Organization of American States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, acting through the United States Permanent Representative to the Organization of American States, should advocate and build diplomatic support for sending an election observation mission to Venezuela to ensure that democratic electoral processes are organized and carried out in a free, fair, and transparent manner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Briefing requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall provide a briefing on the strategy to carry out the activities described in subsection (a) to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State for fiscal year 2020, $17,500,000 to carry out the activities set forth in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) are subject to the notification requirements applicable to expenditures from the Economic Support Fund under <ref>section 2346(c) of this title</ref> and from the Development Assistance Fund under <ref>section 2413(a) of this title</ref>, to the extent that such funds are expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 143</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3038</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>SUPPORTING THE RECONSTRUCTION OF VENEZUELA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9741.</num>
<heading> Recovering assets stolen from the Venezuelan people</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovering assets</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President, acting through the Secretary of State and in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall advance a coordinated international effort—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to work with foreign governments—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to share financial investigations intelligence, as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to block the assets identified pursuant to paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to provide technical assistance to help governments establish the necessary legal framework to carry out asset forfeitures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to carry out special financial investigations to identify and track assets taken from the people and institutions of Venezuela through theft, corruption, money laundering, or other illicit means.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategy requirement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, the President, acting through the Secretary of State and in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit a strategy for carrying out the activities described in subsection (a) to Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The strategy required under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assess whether the United States or another member of the international community should establish a managed fund to hold the assets identified pursuant to subsection (a)(2) that could be returned to a future democratic government in Venezuela; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> include such recommendations as the President and the Secretary of State consider appropriate for legislative or administrative action in the United States that would be needed to establish and manage the fund described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 151</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3039</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>RESTORING THE RULE OF LAW IN VENEZUELA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9751.</num>
<heading> Developing and implementing a coordinated sanctions strategy with partners in the Western Hemisphere and the European Union</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strengthening sanctions capacity in Latin America and the Caribbean</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall offer to provide technical assistance to partner governments in Latin America and the Caribbean to assist such governments in establishing the legislative and regulatory frameworks needed to impose targeted sanctions on officials of the Maduro regime who—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> are responsible for human rights abuses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> have engaged in public corruption; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> are undermining democratic institutions and processes in Venezuela.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordinating international sanctions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall engage in diplomatic efforts with partner governments, including the Government of Canada, governments in the European Union, and governments in Latin America and the Caribbean, to impose targeted sanctions on the Maduro regime officials described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategy requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit a strategy for carrying out the activities described in subsection (a) to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State for fiscal year 2020, $3,000,000 to carry out the activities set forth in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) are subject to the notification requirements applicable to expenditures from the Economic Support Fund under <ref>section 2346(c) of this title</ref> and the International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Fund under <ref>section 2291h of this title</ref> to the extent that such funds are expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 161</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3040</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9752.</num>
<heading> Concerns over PDVSA transactions with Rosneft</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In late 2016, Venezuelan state-owned oil company Petróleos de Venezuela, S.A. (referred to in this section as “PDVSA”), through a no compete transaction, secured a loan from Russian government-controlled oil company Rosneft, using 49.9 percent of PDVSA’s American subsidiary, CITGO Petroleum Corporation, including its assets in the United States, as collateral. As a result of this transaction, 100 percent of CITGO is held as collateral by PDVSA’s creditors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> CITGO, a wholly owned subsidiary of PDVSA, is engaged in interstate commerce and owns and controls critical energy infrastructure in 19 States of the United States, including an extensive network of pipelines, 48 terminals, and 3 refineries, with a combined oil refining capacity of 749,000 barrels per day. CITGO’s refinery in Lake Charles, Louisiana, is the sixth largest refinery in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Department of the Treasury imposed sanctions on Rosneft, which is controlled by the Government of the Russian Federation, and its Executive Chairman, Igor Sechin, following Russia’s military invasion of Ukraine and its illegal annexation of Crimea in 2014.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Department of Homeland Security has designated the energy sector as critical to United States infrastructure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The growing economic crisis in Venezuela raises the probability that the Maduro regime and PDVSA will default on their international debt obligations, resulting in a scenario in which Rosneft could come into control of CITGO’s United States energy infrastructure holdings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> control of critical United States energy infrastructure by Rosneft, a Russian government-controlled entity currently under United States sanctions that is led by Igor Sechin, who is also under United States sanctions and is a close associate of Vladimir Putin, would pose a significant risk to United States national security and energy security; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a default by PDVSA on its loan from Rosneft, resulting in Rosneft coming into possession of PDVSA’s United States CITGO assets, would warrant careful consideration by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preventing Rosneft from controlling United States energy infrastructure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall take all necessary steps to prevent Rosneft from gaining control of critical United States energy infrastructure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Security risk report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, the President shall submit a report assessing the national security risks posed by potential Russian acquisition and control of CITGO’s United States energy infrastructure holdings to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 163</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3041</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9753.</num>
<heading> Countering Russian influence in Venezuela</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “Russian-Venezuelan Threat Mitigation Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Threat assessment and strategy to counter Russian influence in Venezuela</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Defined term</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Threat assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an assessment of Russian-Venezuelan security cooperation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the potential threat such cooperation poses to the United States and countries in the Western Hemisphere; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a strategy to counter threats identified in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aliens described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An alien described in this paragraph is an alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of either Secretary) knows, or has reason to believe, is acting or has acted on behalf of the Government of Russia in direct support of the security forces of the Maduro regime.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Visas, admission, or parole</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An alien described in paragraph (1) is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> inadmissible to the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Current visas revoked</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An alien described in paragraph (1) is subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immediate effect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A revocation under subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> take effect immediately; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Sanctions under paragraphs (2) and (3) shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success <date date="1947-06-26">June 26, 1947</date>, and entered into force <date date="1947-11-21">November 21, 1947</date>, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to carry out or assist law enforcement activity in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National security</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President may waive the application of this subsection with respect to an alien if the President—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determines that such a waiver is in the national interest of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submits a notice of, and justification for, such waiver to the appropriate congressional committees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sunset</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This subsection shall terminate on the date that is 1 year after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 165</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3043</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9754.</num>
<heading> Restriction on export of covered articles and services to certain security forces of Venezuela</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “Venezuela Arms Restriction Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered article or service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “covered article or service”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> for purposes of subsection (c), means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a defense article or defense service (as such terms are defined in <ref>section 2794 of this title</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any article included on the Commerce Control List set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of the Export Administration Regulations under subchapter C of chapter VII of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, and controlled for crime control purposes, if the end user is likely to use the article to violate the human rights of the citizens of Venezuela; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for purposes of subsection (d), means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any defense article or defense service of the type described in <ref>section 2794 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any article of the type included on the Commerce Control List set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of the Export Administration Regulations and controlled for crime control purposes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “foreign person” means a person that is not a United States person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “person” means an individual or entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Security forces of Venezuela</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “security forces of Venezuela” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Bolivarian National Armed Forces, including the Bolivarian National Guard;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Bolivarian National Intelligence Service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Bolivarian National Police; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Bureau for Scientific, Criminal and Forensic Investigations of the Ministry of Interior, Justice, and Peace.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “United States person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restriction on export of covered articles and services to certain security forces of Venezuela</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, covered articles or services may not be exported from the United States to any element of the security forces of the Maduro regime.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the heads of other departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determine, using such information that is available to the Secretary of State, whether any covered article or service has been transferred since July 2017 to the security forces of Venezuela without a license or other authorization as required by law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submit such determination in writing to the appropriate congressional committees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, as appropriate, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees regarding the transfer by foreign persons of covered articles or services to elements of the security forces of Venezuela that are under the authority of the Maduro regime.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters to be included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a list of all significant transfers by foreign persons of covered articles or services to such elements of the security forces of Venezuela since July 2017;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a list of all foreign persons who maintain an existing defense relationship with such elements of the security forces of Venezuela; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any known use of covered articles or services by such elements of the security forces of Venezuela or associated forces, including paramilitary groups, that have coordinated with such security forces to assault, intimidate, or murder political activists, protesters, dissidents, and other civil society leaders, including Juan Guaidó.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sunset</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section shall terminate on the earlier of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date that is 3 years after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the date on which the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the Government of Venezuela has returned to a democratic form of government with respect for the essential elements of representative democracy as set forth in Article 3 of the Inter-American Democratic Charter, adopted by the Organization of American States in Lima on <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 166</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3044</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VII—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9761.</num>
<heading> Congressional briefings</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Humanitarian assistance; sanctions coordination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 15 days after any of the congressional committees listed in paragraph (2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> of <ref>section 9711 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall provide such briefing to such committee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> of <ref>section 9751 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of State shall provide such briefing to such committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The committees listed in this paragraph are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United Nations; negotiated solution; crimes against humanity</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 15 days after any congressional committee listed in paragraph (2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation of <ref>section 9703 of this title</ref>, 9712 of this title, or 142,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002459">1</ref> the Secretary of State shall provide such briefing to such committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The congressional committees listed in this paragraph are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regime cohesion</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 15 days after a congressional committee listed in paragraph (2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation of section 131,<sup>1</sup> the Secretary of State and the Director of National Intelligence shall provide such briefing to such committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The congressional committees listed in this paragraph are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International election observation; democratic civil society</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 15 days after a congressional committee listed in subsection (a)(2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation of <ref>section 9731 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall provide such briefing to such committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Visa restrictions; sanctions waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 15 days after a congressional committee listed in subsection (b)(2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation of section 9721 or 9722 of this title, the Secretary of State shall provide such briefing to such committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery of stolen assets</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 15 days after a congressional committee listed in paragraph (2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation of <ref>section 9741 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Attorney General shall provide such briefing to such committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The congressional committees listed in this paragraph are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> PDVSA transactions with Rosneft</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 15 days after a congressional committee listed in paragraph (2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation of <ref>section 9752 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide such briefing to such committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The congressional committees listed in this paragraph are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 181</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3046</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9762.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on construction of provisions of this chapter as an authorization for the use of military force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter may be construed as an authorization for the use of military force.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 182</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3048</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9763.</num>
<heading> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The requirement to impose sanctions under this chapter shall terminate on <date date="2023-12-31">December 31, 2023</date>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title I, § 183(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3048</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>