<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>THE REPUBLIC OF THE PHILIPPINES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>LAWS AND OBLIGATIONS OF UNITED STATES</heading>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 1—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Customs Duties</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1251 to 1255.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 2—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Quotas</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1261 to 1266.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 3—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Internal Taxes</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1271 to 1274.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 4—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Immigration</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1281.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1281a.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>June 27, 1952, ch. 477</ref>, title IV, § 403(a)(35), <ref>666 Stat. 279</ref></heading>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>OBLIGATIONS OF PHILIPPINES</heading>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 1—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1291.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 2—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Customs Duties</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1301 to 1305.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 3—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Internal Taxes</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1311 to 1313.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 4—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Immigration</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1321, 1322.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num><inline class="small-caps">Part</inline> 5—</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">General Provisions</inline>
</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1331 to 1334.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>EXECUTIVE AGREEMENT BETWEEN UNITED STATES AND PHILIPPINES</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1341 to 1348.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS RELATING TO TRADE RELATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1351 to 1353.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1354.</num>
<heading> Quotas on Philippine articles</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (c) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations by International Trade Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States International Trade Commission shall at the request of the President, upon resolution of either House of Congress or concurrent resolution of both Houses of Congress, upon its own motion, or when in its judgment there is good reason therefor, upon application of any interested party, make an investigation to ascertain (1) whether imports of a Philippine article (other than an article for which a quota is established by part 2 of subchapter I) are coming, or are likely to come, into substantial competition with like articles which are the product of the United States; (2) what is the greatest amount of such article which may be entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, in the United States for consumption, without coming into substantial competition with like articles which are the product of the United States; and (3) the total amount of such article which (during the twelve months ended on the last day of the month preceding the month in which occurs the date of the beginning of the investigation) was entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, in the United States for consumption. During the course of the investigation the Commission shall hold a public hearing, of which reasonable public notice shall be given and at which parties interested shall be afforded reasonable opportunity to be present, to produce evidence, and to be heard. The Commission shall give precedence to such investigations. The Commission shall report the results of its investigations to the President, and shall send copies of such report to each House of the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 244</ref>, title V, § 504, <ref>60 Stat. 156</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–618, title I, § 171(b)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2009</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1355.</num>
<heading> Suspension of processing tax on coconut oil</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the President, after consultation with the President of the Philippines, finds that adequate supplies of neither copra nor coconut oil, the product of the Philippines, are readily available for processing in the United States, he shall so proclaim, and after the date of such proclamation the provisions of section 2470(a)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code shall be suspended until the expiration of 30 days after he proclaims that, after consultation with the President of the Philippines, he has found that such adequate supplies are so readily available.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 244</ref>, title V, § 505(b), <ref>60 Stat. 157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1356.</num>
<heading> Termination of payments into Philippine treasury</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 4 of the Act of March 8, 1902</ref> (<ref>32 Stat. 54</ref>, ch. 140), or of <ref>section 19 of the Act of March 24, 1934</ref> (<ref>48 Stat. 456</ref>, ch. 84), as added to such Act by <ref>section 6 of the Act of August 7, 1939</ref> (<ref>53 Stat. 1232</ref>, ch. 502), or of the Act of <date date="1945-11-08">November 8, 1945</date> (<ref>59 Stat. 577</ref>, ch. 454) or of any other provision of law, the proceeds of any duties or taxes, collected subsequent to <date date="1946-07-03">July 3, 1946</date>, which but for the enactment of this Act would be required to be paid into the general funds of the Treasury of the Philippines or would be held in separate or special funds and paid into the Treasury of the Philippines, shall be covered into the general fund of the Treasury of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 244</ref>, title V, § 506(a), <ref>60 Stat. 157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1357.</num>
<heading> Trade agreements with the Philippines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Until <date date="1974-07-04">July 4, 1974</date>, no trade agreement shall be made with the Philippines under <ref>section 1351 of title 19</ref>, unless, prior to such time, the President of the United States has made the proclamation provided for in <ref>section 1347 of this title</ref>, or the executive agreement provided for in subchapter III of this chapter has been terminated.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 244</ref>, title V, § 508, <ref>60 Stat. 158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1358.</num>
<heading> Rights of third countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The benefits granted by subchapters I to IV of this chapter, and by the executive agreement provided for in subchapter III, to the Philippines, Philippine articles or products, and Philippine citizens, shall not, by reason of any provision of any existing treaty or agreement with any third country, be extended to such country or its products, citizens, or subjects.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 244</ref>, title V, § 509, <ref>60 Stat. 158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1359.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1360.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of subchapters I to IV of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “person” includes partnerships, corporations, and associations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, means the States, the District of Columbia, the Territories of Alaska and Hawaii, and Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The term “ordinary customs duty” means a customs duty based on the article as such (whether or not such duty is also based in any manner on the use, value, or method of production of the article, or on the amount of like articles imported, or on any other factor); but does not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a customs duty based on an act or omission of any person with respect to the importation of the article, or of the country from which the article is exported, or from which it comes; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a countervailing duty imposed to offset a subsidy, bounty, or grant; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an anti-dumping duty imposed to offset the selling of merchandise for exportation at a price less than the prevailing price in the country of export; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any tax, fee, charge, or exaction, imposed on or in connection with importation unless the law of the country imposing it designates or imposes it as a customs duty or contains a provision to the effect that it shall be treated as a duty imposed under the customs laws; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the tax imposed by section 2491(c) of the Internal Revenue Code with respect to an article, merchandise, or combination, 10 per centum or more of the quantity by weight of which consists of, or is derived directly or indirectly from, one or more of the oils, fatty acids, or salts specified in section 2470 of the Internal Revenue Code; or the tax imposed by section 3500 of the Internal Revenue Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “Philippine article” means an article which is the product of the Philippines, unless, in the case of an article produced with the use of materials imported into the Philippines from any foreign country (except the United States) the aggregate value of such imported materials at the time of importation into the Philippines was more than twenty per centum of the value of the article imported into the United States, the value of such article to be determined in accordance with, and as of the time provided by, the customs laws of the United States in effect at the time of importation of such article. As used in this paragraph the term “value”, when used in reference to a material imported into the Philippines, includes the value of the material ascertained under the customs laws of the Philippines in effect at the time of importation into the Philippines, and, if not included in such value, the cost of bringing the material to the Philippines, but does not include the cost of landing it at the port of importation, or customs duties collected in the Philippines. For the purposes of this paragraph any imported material, used in the production of an article in the Philippines, shall be considered as having been used in the production of an article subsequently produced in the Philippines, which is the product of a chain of production in the Philippines in the course of which an article, which is the product of one stage of the chain, is used by its producer or another person, in a subsequent stage of the chain, as a material in the production of another article.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “United States article” means an article which is the product of the United States, unless, in the case of an article produced with the use of materials imported into the United States from any foreign country (except the Philippines) the aggregate value of such imported materials at the time of importation into the United States was more than twenty per centum of the value of the article imported into the Philippines, the value of such article to be determined in accordance with, and as of the time provided by, the customs laws of the Philippines in effect at the time of importation of such article. As used in this paragraph the term “value”, when used in reference to a material imported into the United States, includes the value of the material ascertained under the customs laws of the United States in effect at the time of importation into the United States, and, if not included in such value, the cost of bringing the material to the United States, but does not include the cost of landing it at the port of importation, or customs duties collected in the United States. For the purposes of this paragraph any imported material, used in the production of an article in the United States, shall be considered as having been used in the production of an article subsequently produced in the United States, which is the product of a chain of production in the United States in the course of which an article, which is the product of one stage of the chain, is used by its producer or another person, in a subsequent stage of the chain, as a material in the production of another article.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “United States duty” means the rate or rates of ordinary customs duty which (at the time and place of entry, or withdrawal from warehouse, in the United States for consumption, of the Philippine article) would be applicable to a like article if imported from that foreign country which is entitled to the lowest rate, or the lowest aggregate of rates, of ordinary customs duty with respect to such like article.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “Philippine duty” means the rate or rates of ordinary customs duty which (at the time and place of entry, or withdrawal from warehouse, in the Philippines for consumption, of the United States article) would be applicable to a like article if imported from that foreign country which is entitled to the lowest rate, or the lowest aggregate of rates, of ordinary customs duty with respect to such like article.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<chapeau> The term “internal tax” includes an internal fee, charge, or exaction, and includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the tax imposed by section 2491(c) of the Internal Revenue Code with respect to an article, merchandise, or combination, 10 per centum or more of the quantity by weight of which consists of, or is derived directly or indirectly from, one or more of the oils, fatty acids, or salts specified in section 2470 of the Internal Revenue Code; and the tax imposed by section 3500 of the Internal Revenue Code; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other tax, fee, charge, or exaction, imposed on or in connection with importation unless the law of the country imposing it designates or imposes it as a customs duty or contains a provision to the effect that it shall be treated as a duty imposed under the customs laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> For the purposes of sections 1271(b) and 1311(b) of this title, any material, used in the production of an article, shall be considered as having been used in the production of an article subsequently produced, which is the product of a chain of production in the course of which an article, which is the product of one stage of the chain, is used by its producer or another person, in a subsequent stage of the chain, as a material in the production of another article.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of paragraphs (6) and (7) of subsection (a) of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if an article is entitled to be imported from a foreign country free of ordinary customs duty, that country shall be considered as the country entitled to the lowest rate of ordinary customs duty with respect to such article; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a reduction in ordinary customs duty granted any country, by law, treaty, trade agreement, or otherwise, with respect to any article, shall be converted into the equivalent reduction in the rate of ordinary customs duty otherwise applicable to such article.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The terms “includes” and “including” when used in a definition contained in subchapters I to IV of this chapter shall not be deemed to exclude other things otherwise within the meaning of the term defined.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 244</ref>, title I, § 2, <ref>60 Stat. 141</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV–A—</num>
<heading>TRADE RELATIONS UNDER REVISED AGREEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 1371, 1372.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1373.</num>
<heading> Suspension of Philippine Trade Act of 1946</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Philippine Trade Act of 1946 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1251</ref> et seq.] (except <ref>section 506(a) of this title</ref> [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1356</ref>] relating to termination of payments into Philippine Treasury, and except amendments and repeals made by such Act) shall not apply during such time as the revised agreement is in effect.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1955, ch. 438</ref>, title III, § 302, <ref>69 Stat. 426</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 1374 to 1379.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>PROPERTY RETAINED BY THE UNITED STATES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1381.</num>
<heading> Retention by United States of title to real and personal property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall remain vested in the Government of the United States or its agencies or instrumentalities all the right, title, and interest of the said Government or its agencies or instrumentalities to all real and personal property within the Philippine Islands as may now be vested in, or later be acquired by the Government of the United States or any of its agencies or instrumentalities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1946, ch. 536, § 2</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1382.</num>
<heading> Administration of the Trading With the Enemy Act in Philippines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Trading With the Enemy Act of <date date="1917-10-06">October 6, 1917</date> (<ref>40 Stat. 411</ref>), as amended, shall continue in force in the Philippines after <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, and all powers and authority conferred upon the President of the United States or the Alien Property Custodian by the terms of the said Trading With the Enemy Act, as amended, with respect to the Philippines, shall continue thereafter to be exercised by the President of the United States, or such officer or agency as he may designate: <i>Provided</i>, That all property vested in or transferred to the President of the United States, the Alien Property Custodian, or any such officer or agency as the President of the United States may designate under the Trading With the Enemy Act, as amended, which was located in the Philippines at the time of such vesting, or the proceeds thereof, and which shall remain after the satisfaction of any claim payable under the Trading With the Enemy Act, as amended, and after the payment of such costs and expenses of administration as may by law be charged against such property or proceeds, shall be transferred by the President of the United States to the Republic of the Philippines: <i>Provided further</i>, That such property, or proceeds thereof, may be transferred by the President of the United States to the Republic of the Philippines upon indemnification acceptable to the President of the United States by the Republic of the Philippines for such claims, costs, and expenses of administration as may by law be charged against such property or proceeds thereof before final adjudication of such claims, costs, and expenses of administration: <i>Provided further</i>, That the courts of first instance of the Republic of the Philippines are given jurisdiction to make and enter all such rules as to notice or otherwise, and all such orders and decrees, and to issue such process as may be necessary and proper in the premises to enforce any orders, rules, and regulations issued by the President of the United States, the Alien Property Custodian, or such officer or agency designated by the President of the United States pursuant to the Trading With the Enemy Act, as amended, with such right of appeal therefrom as may be provided by law: <i>And provided further</i>, That any suit authorized under the Trading With the Enemy Act, as amended, with respect to property vested in or transferred to the President of the United States, the Alien Property Custodian, or any officer or agency designated by the President of the United States hereunder, which at the time of such vesting or transfer was located within the Philippines, shall after <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, be brought, in the appropriate court of first instance of the Republic of the Philippines, against the officer or agency hereunder designated by the President of the United States with such right of appeal therefrom as may be provided by law, but suits with respect to such property shall after ninety days from <date date="1950-12-21">December 21, 1950</date>, be brought only in the courts of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1946, ch. 536, § 3</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 418</ref>; <ref>Dec. 21, 1950, ch. 1144</ref>, <ref>64 Stat. 1116</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1383.</num>
<heading> Transfer of property by President of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In respect to property not transferable to the Republic of the Philippines under <ref>section 1382 of this title</ref>, the President of the United States is authorized, in his discretion and under such terms and conditions as he may deem appropriate, to transfer to the Republic of the Philippines any or all of the right, title, and interest of the Government of the United States or its agencies or instrumentalities to any or all real and personal property vested in such agencies or instrumentalities.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1946, ch. 536, § 4</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 419</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1384.</num>
<heading> Transfer of shares of corporations owning agricultural lands; consideration; indemnification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Immediately upon passage of this subchapter the Alien Property Custodian of the United States shall enter into an agreement with the President of the Philippines to transfer to the Philippine Government for a nominal cash consideration all shares now vested or hereafter vested by the Alien Property Custodian of corporations owning in fee, leasing, or otherwise operating or controlling agricultural lands in the Philippines, other agricultural lands in the Philippines, vested or hereafter vested by the Alien Property Custodian not included in the foregoing, and improved property in Manila vested or hereafter vested by the Alien Property Custodian which in his judgment is urgently needed for the operation of an administrative agency of the Philippine Government: <i>Provided</i>, That in respect to property transferred under this section to the Philippine Government, it shall be made a part of the agreement that the Philippine Government shall fully indemnify the United States for all claims payable under the Trading With the Enemy Act, as amended [<ref>50 U.S.C. 4301</ref> et seq.], and for all such costs and expenses of administration as may by law be charged against such property or proceeds thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1946, ch. 536, § 5</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 419</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1385.</num>
<heading> Ownership of naval reservations, diplomatic property, etc., unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this subchapter shall be construed as amending the provisions of the Act of <date date="1934-03-24">March 24, 1934</date> (<ref>48 Stat. 456</ref>), as amended, respecting naval reservations and fueling stations, and diplomatic or consular property, and the property of the High Commissioner to the Philippine Islands, nor as amending the provisions of <ref>section 1392 of this title</ref>, respecting bases for the mutual protection of the Philippine Islands and the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1946, ch. 536, § 6</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 419</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1386.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this subchapter the term “Philippine Government” shall mean “Government of the Commonwealth of the Philippines” until the date of independence, and thereafter it shall mean the “Government of the Republic of the Philippines”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 3, 1946, ch. 536, § 7</ref>, <ref>60 Stat. 420</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1391.</num>
<heading> Transfer of property and rights to Philippine Commonwealth</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All the property and rights which may have been acquired in the Philippine Islands by the United States under the treaties mentioned in the first section of this Act, except such land or other property as has heretofore been designated by the President of the United States for Military and other reservations of the Government of the United States, and except such land or other property or rights or interests therein as may have been sold or otherwise disposed of in accordance with law, are granted to the government of the Commonwealth of the Philippine Islands when constituted.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 24, 1934, ch. 84, § 5</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1392.</num>
<heading> Acquisition of military and naval bases by United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After negotiation with the President of the Commonwealth of the Philippines, or the President of the Filipino Republic, the President of the United States is authorized by such means as he finds appropriate to withhold or to acquire and to retain such bases, necessary appurtenances to such bases, and the rights incident thereto, in addition to any provided for by the Act of <date date="1934-03-24">March 24, 1934</date>, as he may deem necessary for the mutual protection of the Philippine Islands and of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 29, 1944, ch. 322, § 2</ref>, <ref>58 Stat. 626</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1393.</num>
<heading> Supplementary sinking fund for bond payments; purchase of bonds by United States; creation of special trust account</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> to (f). Repealed. <ref>Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 244</ref>, title V, § 511(2), <ref>60 Stat. 158</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Philippine Government shall pay to the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States, at the end of each calendar quarter, all of the moneys received during such quarter from export taxes (less refunds), imposed and collected in accordance with the provisions of this section, and said moneys shall be deposited in an account with the Treasurer of the United States and shall constitute a supplementary sinking fund for the payment of bonds of the Philippines, its Provinces, cities, and municipalities, issued prior to <date date="1934-05-01">May 1, 1934</date>, under authority of Acts of Congress: <i>Provided, however</i>, That moneys received from any export tax imposed on any article which is shipped from the Philippines to the United States prior to <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, and which is entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, shall be refunded by the independent Government of the Philippines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The said Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to accept the deposits of the proceeds of the export taxes referred to in subdivision (1) of this subsection in accordance with section 1333 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002052">1</ref> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of the Treasury of the United States, with the approval of the Philippine Government, is authorized to purchase with such supplementary sinking-fund bonds of the Philippines, its Provinces, cities, and municipalities, issued prior to <date date="1934-05-01">May 1, 1934</date>, under authority of Acts of Congress and to invest such fund in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States. Whenever the Secretary of the Treasurer <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002053">2</ref> finds that such fund is in excess of an amount adequate to meet future interest and principal payments on all such bonds, he may, with the approval of the Philippine Government, purchase with such excess any other bonds of the Philippines, its Provinces, cities, municipalities, and instrumentalities. For the purpose of this subsection obligations may be acquired on original issue at par, or by purchase of outstanding obligations at the market price. Any obligations acquired by the fund may, with the approval of the Philippine Government, be sold by the Secretary of the Treasury at the market price and the proceeds of such sale and the proceeds of the payment upon maturity or redemption of any obligations held in the supplementary sinking fund, as well as all moneys in any manner earned by such fund or on any obligations acquired by said fund, shall be paid into the said fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> During the three months preceding <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, the Philippine Government and the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States shall confer to ascertain that portion of the bonds of the Philippines, its Provinces, cities, and municipalities, issued prior to <date date="1934-05-01">May 1, 1934</date>, under authority of Acts of Congress, which will remain outstanding on <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>; and the Philippine Government shall turn over to the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States for destruction all such bonds that are then held, canceled, or uncanceled, in any of the sinking funds maintained for the payment of such bonds. After such outstanding portion of this indebtedness is thus determined, and before <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, (i) there shall be set up with the Treasurer of the United States a special trust account in the name of the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States to pay future interest and principal payments on such bonds; (ii) the Philippine Government shall pay to the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States for deposit in this special trust account all of the sinking funds maintained for the payment of such bonds; and (iii) the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States shall transfer into this special trust account all of the proceeds of the supplementary sinking fund referred to in subdivision (1) of this subsection. Any portion of such special trust account found by the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States on <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, to be in excess of an amount adequate to meet future interest and principal payments on all such outstanding bonds shall be turned over to the Treasury of the independent Government of the Philippines to be set up as an additional sinking fund to be used for the purpose of liquidating and paying all other obligations of the Philippines, its Provinces, cities, municipalities, and instrumentalities. To the extent that such special trust account is determined by the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States to be insufficient to pay interest and principal on the outstanding bonds of the Philippines, its Provinces, cities, and municipalities, issued prior to <date date="1934-05-01">May 1, 1934</date>, under authority of Acts of Congress, the Philippine Government shall, on or before <date date="1946-07-03">July 3, 1946</date>, pay to the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States for deposit in such special trust account an amount which said Secretary of the Treasury determines is required to assure payment of principal and interest on such bonds: <i>Provided, however</i>, That if the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States finds that this requirement would impose an undue hardship upon the Philippines, then the Philippine Government shall continue to provide annually the necessary funds for the payment of interest and principal on such bonds until such time as the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States determines that the amount in the special trust account is adequate to meet interest and principal payments on such bonds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> On and after <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States is authorized, with the approval of the independent Government of the Philippines, to purchase at the market price for the special trust account bonds of the Philippines, its Provinces, cities, and municipalities, issued prior to <date date="1934-05-01">May 1, 1934</date>, under authority of Acts of Congress. The Secretary of the Treasury of the United States is also authorized, with the approval of the independent Government of the Philippines, to invest all or any part of such special trust account in any interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in any obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States. Such obligations may be acquired on original issue at the issue price or by purchase of outstanding obligations at the market price, and any obligations acquired by the special trust account may, with the approval of the independent Government of the Philippines, be sold by the Secretary of the Treasury at the market price, and the proceeds of the payment upon maturity or redemption of such obligations shall be held as a part of such special trust account. Whenever the special trust account is determined by the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States to be adequate to meet interest and principal payments on all outstanding bonds of the Philippines, its Provinces, cities, and municipalities, issued prior to <date date="1934-05-01">May 1, 1934</date>, under authority of Acts of Congress, the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to pay from such trust account the principal of such outstanding bonds and to pay all interest due and owing on such bonds. All such bonds and interest coupons paid or purchased by the special trust account shall be canceled and destroyed by the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States. From time to time after <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, any moneys in such special trust account found by the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States to be in excess of an amount adequate to meet interest and principal payments on all such bonds shall be turned over to the treasurer of the independent Government of the Philippines.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 24, 1934, ch. 84, § 6</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 459</ref>; <ref>Aug. 7, 1939, ch. 502, § 1</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 1226</ref>; <ref>Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 244</ref>, title V, § 511(2), <ref>60 Stat. 158</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–346, title I, § 104(1)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-22">Sept. 22, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 622</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1394.</num>
<heading> Recognition of Philippine independence</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withdrawal of American sovereignty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the 4th day of July immediately following the expiration of a period of ten years from the date of the inauguration of the new government under the constitution provided for in this Act, the President of the United States shall by proclamation withdraw and surrender all right of possession, supervision, jurisdiction, control, or sovereignty then existing and exercised by the United States in and over the territory and people of the Philippine Islands, including all military and other reservations of the Government of the United States in the Philippines (except such naval reservations and fueling stations as are reserved under <ref>section 1391 of this title</ref>), and, on behalf of the United States, shall recognize the independence of the Philippine Islands as a separate and self-governing nation and acknowledge the authority and control over the same of the government instituted by the people thereof, under the constitution then in force.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Naval reservations and fueling stations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President of the United States is authorized and empowered to enter into negotiations with the government of the Philippine Islands, not later than two years after his proclamation recognizing the independence of the Philippine Islands, for the adjustment and settlement of all questions relating to naval reservations and fueling stations of the United States in the Philippine Islands, and pending such adjustment and settlement the matter of naval reservations and fueling stations shall remain in its present status.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property for diplomatic purposes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever the President of the United States shall find that any properties in the Philippines, owned by the Philippine Government or by private persons, would be suitable for diplomatic or consular establishments of the United States after the inauguration of the independent Government, he may, with the approval of the Philippine Government, and in exchange for the conveyance of title to the United States, transfer to the said Government or private persons any properties of the United States in the Philippines. Title to any properties so transferred to private persons, and title to any properties so acquired by the United States, shall be vested in fee simple in such persons and the United States, respectively, notwithstanding the provisions contained in subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Whenever, prior to <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, the President of the United States shall find that any properties of the United States in the Philippines would be suitable for diplomatic and consular establishments of the United States after the inauguration of the independent Government, he shall designate the same by the issuance of a proclamation or proclamations, and title to any properties so designated shall continue to be vested in fee simple in the United States notwithstanding the provisions contained in subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Title to the lands and buildings pertaining to the official residences of the United States High Commissioner to the Philippine Islands in the cities of Manila and Baguio, together with all fixtures and movable objects, shall continue to be vested in the United States after <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, notwithstanding the provisions contained in subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Administrative supervision and control over any properties acquired or designated by the President of the United States pursuant to this subsection, and over the official residences in the Philippines of the High Commissioner, shall, on and after <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, be exercised by the Secretary of State, in accordance with Acts of Congress relating to property held by the United States in foreign countries for official establishments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 24, 1934, ch. 84, § 10</ref>, <ref>48 Stat. 463</ref>; <ref>Aug. 7, 1939, ch. 502, § 3</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 1230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1395.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> As used in sections 1393 and 1394 of this title—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, but not the term “continental United States”, includes all Territories and possessions of the United States, other than the Philippines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “cordage” includes yarns, twines (including binding twine described in paragraph 1622 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002054">1</ref> of <ref>section 1201 of title 19</ref>), cords, cordage, rope and cable, tarred or untarred, wholly or in chief value of manila (abaca) or other hard fiber.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Philippine Government” means the Government of the Commonwealth of the Philippines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “United States duty”, when used in connection with the computation of export taxes, means the lowest rate of ordinary customs duty in effect at the time of the shipment of the article concerned from the Philippines and applicable to like articles imported into the continental United States from any foreign country, except Cuba, or when more than one rate of ordinary customs duty is applicable to such like articles, the aggregate of such rates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “refined sugars” possesses the same meaning as the term “direct-consumption sugar” as defined in section 1101 <sup>1</sup> of title 7.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “Philippine article” means an article the growth, produce, or manufacture of the Philippines, in the production of which no materials of other than Philippine or United States origin valued in excess of 20 per centum of the total value of such article was used and which is brought into the United States from the Philippines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “American article” means an article the growth, produce, or manufacture of the United States, in the production of which no materials of other than Philippine or United States origin valued in excess of 20 per centum of the total value of such article was used and which is brought into the Philippines from the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “Philippine import duty” means the lowest rate of ordinary customs duty applicable at the port of arrival, at the time of entry, or withdrawal from warehouse, for consumption of the article concerned, to like articles imported into the Philippines from any other foreign country, or when more than one rate of ordinary customs duty is applicable to such like articles, the aggregate of such rates.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> As used in subsection (a) of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The terms “includes” and “including” shall not be deemed to exclude other things otherwise within the meaning of the term defined.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “ordinary customs duty” shall not include any import duty or charge which is imposed to compensate for an internal tax imposed in respect of a like domestic product or in respect of a commodity from which the imported product has been manufactured or produced in whole or in part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Mar. 24, 1934, ch. 84, § 18</ref>, as added <ref>Aug. 7, 1939, ch. 502, § 5</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 1231</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>