<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 80—</num>
<heading>DIPLOMATIC TELECOMMUNICATIONS SERVICE PROGRAM OFFICE (DTS-PO)</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7301.</num>
<heading> Reorganization; duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reorganization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Diplomatic Telecommunications Service Program Office established pursuant to title V of <ref>Public Law 102–140</ref> shall be reorganized in accordance with this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The duties of the DTS–PO include implementing a program for the establishment and maintenance of a DTS Network capable of providing multiple levels of service to meet the wide-ranging needs of all United States Government departments and agencies operating from diplomatic and consular facilities outside of the United States, including national security needs for secure, reliable, and robust communications capabilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–567, title III, § 321</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–259, title V, § 501(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7302.</num>
<heading> Establishment of the Diplomatic Telecommunications Service Governance Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Governance Board</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established the Diplomatic Telecommunications Service Governance Board to direct and oversee the activities and performance of the DTS–PO.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Agent.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall designate, from among the departments and agencies of the United States Government that use the DTS Network, a department or agency as the DTS–PO Executive Agent.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Executive Agent designated under subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> nominate a Director of the DTS–PO for approval by the Governance Board in accordance with subsection (e); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> perform such other duties as established by the Governance Board in the determination of written implementing arrangements and other relevant and appropriate governance processes and procedures under paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for implementing arrangements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the requirements of this chapter, the Governance Board shall determine the written implementing arrangements and other relevant and appropriate governance processes and procedures to manage, oversee, resource, or otherwise administer the DTS–PO.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall designate from among the departments and agencies that use the DTS Network—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> four departments and agencies to each appoint one voting member of the Governance Board from the personnel of such departments and agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other departments and agencies that the Director considers appropriate to each appoint one nonvoting member of the Governance Board from the personnel of such departments and agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting and nonvoting members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Governance Board shall consist of voting members and nonvoting members as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voting members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The voting members shall consist of a Chair, who shall be designated by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the four members appointed by departments and agencies designated under paragraph (1)(A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonvoting members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The nonvoting members shall consist of the members appointed by departments and agencies designated under paragraph (1)(B) and shall act in an advisory capacity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair duties and authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Chair of the Governance Board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> preside over all meetings and deliberations of the Governance Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide the Secretariat functions of the Governance Board; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> propose bylaws governing the operation of the Governance Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum, decisions, meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A quorum of the Governance Board shall consist of the presence of the Chair and four voting members. The decisions of the Governance Board shall require a majority of the voting membership. The Chair shall convene a meeting of the Governance Board not less than four times each year to carry out the functions of the Governance Board. The Chair or any voting member may convene a meeting of the Governance Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Governance Board duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Governance Board shall have the following duties with respect to the DTS–PO:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To approve and monitor the plans, services, priorities, policies, and pricing methodology of the DTS–PO for bandwidth costs and projects carried out at the request of a department or agency that uses the DTS Network.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To provide to the DTS–PO Executive Agent the recommendation of the Governance Board with respect to the approval, disapproval, or modification of each annual budget request for the DTS–PO, prior to the submission of any such request by the Executive Agent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To review the performance of the DTS–PO against plans approved under paragraph (1) and the management activities and internal controls of the DTS–PO.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To require from the DTS–PO any plans, reports, documents, and records the Governance Board considers necessary to perform its oversight responsibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To conduct and evaluate independent audits of the DTS–PO.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> To approve or disapprove the nomination of the Director of the DTS–PO by the Executive Agent with a majority vote of the Governance Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> To recommend to the Executive Agent the replacement of the Director of the DTS–PO with a majority vote of the Governance Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National security interests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Governance Board shall ensure that those enhancements of, and the provision of service for, telecommunication capabilities that involve the national security interests of the United States receive the highest prioritization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–567, title III, § 322</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–259, title V, § 501(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7303.</num>
<heading> Funding of the Diplomatic Telecommunications Service</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for the operations, maintenance, development, enhancement, modernization, and investment costs of the DTS Network and the DTS–PO. Funds appropriated for allocation to the DTS–PO shall remain available to the DTS–PO for a period of two fiscal years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The DTS–PO shall charge a department or agency that uses the DTS Network for only those bandwidth costs attributable to such department or agency and for specific projects carried out at the request of such department or agency, pursuant to the pricing methodology for such bandwidth costs and such projects approved under <ref>section 7302(e)(1) of this title</ref>, for which amounts have not been appropriated for allocation to the DTS–PO. The DTS–PO is authorized to directly receive payments from departments or agencies that use the DTS Network and to invoice such departments or agencies for the fees under this section either in advance of, or upon or after, providing the bandwidth or performing such projects. Such funds received from such departments or agencies shall remain available to the DTS–PO for a period of two fiscal years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–567, title III, § 323</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–259, title V, § 501(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7304.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> DTS Network</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “DTS Network” means the worldwide telecommunications network supporting all United States Government agencies and departments operating from diplomatic and consular facilities outside of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> DTS–PO</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “DTS–PO” means the Diplomatic Telecommunications Service Program Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Governance Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Governance Board” means the Diplomatic Telecommunications Service Governance Board established under <ref>section 7302(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–567, title III, § 324</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 111–259, title V, § 501(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2738</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>