<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 83—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES LEADERSHIP AGAINST HIV/AIDS, TUBERCULOSIS, AND MALARIA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7601.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> During the last 20 years, HIV/AIDS has assumed pandemic proportions, spreading from the most severely affected regions, sub-Saharan Africa and the Caribbean, to all corners of the world, and leaving an unprecedented path of death and devastation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> According to the Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS), more than 65,000,000 individuals worldwide have been infected with HIV since the epidemic began, more than 25,000,000 of these individuals have lost their lives to the disease, and more than 14,000,000 children have been orphaned by the disease. HIV/AIDS is the fourth-highest cause of death in the world.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> At the end of 2002, an estimated 42,000,000 individuals were infected with HIV or living with AIDS, of which more than 75 percent live in Africa or the Caribbean. Of these individuals, more than 3,200,000 were children under the age of 15 and more than 19,200,000 were women.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Women are four times more vulnerable to infection than are men and are becoming infected at increasingly high rates, in part because many societies do not provide poor women and young girls with the social, legal, and cultural protections against high risk activities that expose them to HIV/AIDS.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Women and children who are refugees or are internally displaced persons are especially vulnerable to sexual exploitation and violence, thereby increasing the possibility of HIV infection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> As the leading cause of death in sub-Saharan Africa, AIDS has killed more than 19,400,000 individuals (more than 3 times the number of AIDS deaths in the rest of the world) and will claim the lives of one-quarter of the population, mostly adults, in the next decade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An estimated 2,000,000 individuals in Latin America and the Caribbean and another 7,100,000 individuals in Asia and the Pacific region are infected with HIV or living with AIDS. Infection rates are rising alarmingly in Eastern Europe (especially in the Russian Federation), Central Asia, and China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> HIV/AIDS threatens personal security by affecting the health, lifespan, and productive capacity of the individual and the social cohesion and economic well-being of the family.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> HIV/AIDS undermines the economic security of a country and individual businesses in that country by weakening the productivity and longevity of the labor force across a broad array of economic sectors and by reducing the potential for economic growth over the long term.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> HIV/AIDS destabilizes communities by striking at the most mobile and educated members of society, many of whom are responsible for security at the local level and governance at the national and subnational levels as well as many teachers, health care personnel, and other community workers vital to community development and the effort to combat HIV/AIDS. In some countries the overwhelming challenges of the HIV/AIDS epidemic are accelerating the outward migration of critically important health care professionals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> HIV/AIDS weakens the defenses of countries severely affected by the HIV/AIDS crisis through high infection rates among members of their military forces and voluntary peacekeeping personnel. According to UNAIDS, in sub-Saharan Africa, many military forces have infection rates as much as five times that of the civilian population.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> HIV/AIDS poses a serious security issue for the international community by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> increasing the potential for political instability and economic devastation, particularly in those countries and regions most severely affected by the disease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> decreasing the capacity to resolve conflicts through the introduction of peacekeeping forces because the environments into which these forces are introduced pose a high risk for the spread of HIV/AIDS; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> increasing the vulnerability of local populations to HIV/AIDS in conflict zones from peacekeeping troops with HIV infection rates significantly higher than civilian populations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The devastation wrought by the HIV/AIDS pandemic is compounded by the prevalence of tuberculosis and malaria, particularly in developing countries where the poorest and most vulnerable members of society, including women, children, and those individuals living with HIV/AIDS, become infected. According to the World Health Organization (WHO), HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria accounted for more than 5,700,000 deaths in 2001 and caused debilitating illnesses in millions more.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Together, HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and related diseases are undermining agricultural production throughout Africa. According to the United Nations Food and Agricultural Organization, 7,000,000 agricultural workers throughout 25 African countries have died from AIDS since 1985. Countries with poorly developed agricultural systems, which already face chronic food shortages, are the hardest hit, particularly in sub-Saharan Africa, where high HIV prevalence rates are compounding the risk of starvation for an estimated 14,400,000 people.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Tuberculosis is the cause of death for one out of every three people with AIDS worldwide and is a highly communicable disease. HIV infection is the leading threat to tuberculosis control. Because HIV infection so severely weakens the immune system, individuals with HIV and latent tuberculosis infection have a 100 times greater risk of developing active tuberculosis diseases thereby increasing the risk of spreading tuberculosis to others. Tuberculosis, in turn, accelerates the onset of AIDS in individuals infected with HIV.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Malaria, the most deadly of all tropical parasitic diseases, has been undergoing a dramatic resurgence in recent years due to increasing resistance of the malaria parasite to inexpensive and effective drugs. At the same time, increasing resistance of mosquitoes to standard insecticides makes control of transmission difficult to achieve. The World Health Organization estimates that between 300,000,000 and 500,000,000 new cases of malaria occur each year, and annual deaths from the disease number between 2,000,000 and 3,000,000. Persons infected with HIV are particularly vulnerable to the malaria parasite. The spread of HIV infection contributes to the difficulties of controlling resurgence of the drug resistant malaria parasite.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> HIV/AIDS is first and foremost a health problem. Successful strategies to stem the spread of the HIV/AIDS pandemic will require clinical medical interventions, the strengthening of health care delivery systems and infrastructure, and determined national leadership and increased budgetary allocations for the health sector in countries affected by the epidemic as well as measures to address the social and behavioral causes of the problem and its impact on families, communities, and societal sectors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> Basic interventions to prevent new HIV infections and to bring care and treatment to people living with AIDS, such as voluntary counseling and testing and mother-to-child transmission programs, are achieving meaningful results and are cost-effective. The challenge is to expand these interventions from a pilot program basis to a national basis in a coherent and sustainable manner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> Appropriate treatment of individuals with HIV/AIDS can prolong the lives of such individuals, preserve their families, prevent children from becoming orphans, and increase productivity of such individuals by allowing them to lead active lives and reduce the need for costly hospitalization for treatment of opportunistic infections caused by HIV.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> Nongovernmental organizations, including faith-based organizations, with experience in health care and HIV/AIDS counseling, have proven effective in combating the HIV/AIDS pandemic and can be a resource in assisting indigenous organizations in severely affected countries in their efforts to provide treatment and care for individuals infected with HIV/AIDS.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> Faith-based organizations are making an important contribution to HIV prevention and AIDS treatment programs around the world. Successful HIV prevention programs in Uganda, Jamaica, and elsewhere have included local churches and faith-based groups in efforts to promote behavior changes to prevent HIV, to reduce stigma associated with HIV infection, to treat those afflicted with the disease, and to care for orphans. The Catholic Church alone currently cares for one in four people being treated for AIDS worldwide. Faith-based organizations possess infrastructure, experience, and knowledge that will be needed to carry out these programs in the future and should be an integral part of United States efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Uganda has experienced the most significant decline in HIV rates of any country in Africa, including a decrease among pregnant women from 20.6 percent in 1991 to 7.9 percent in 2000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Uganda made this remarkable turnaround because President Yoweri Museveni spoke out early, breaking long-standing cultural taboos, and changed widespread perceptions about the disease. His leadership stands as a model for ways political leaders in Africa and other developing countries can mobilize their nations, including civic organizations, professional associations, religious institutions, business and labor to combat HIV/AIDS.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Uganda’s successful AIDS treatment and prevention program is referred to as the ABC model: “Abstain, Be faithful, use Condoms”, in order of priority. Jamaica, Zambia, Ethiopia and Senegal have also successfully used the ABC model. Beginning in 1986, Uganda brought about a fundamental change in sexual behavior by developing a low-cost program with the message: “Stop having multiple partners. Be faithful. Teenagers, wait until you are married before you begin sex.”.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> By 1995, 95 percent of Ugandans were reporting either one or zero sexual partners in the past year, and the proportion of sexually active youth declined significantly from the late 1980s to the mid-1990s. The greatest percentage decline in HIV infections and the greatest degree of behavioral change occurred in those 15 to 19 years old. Uganda’s success shows that behavior change, through the use of the ABC model, is a very successful way to prevent the spread of HIV.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<chapeau> The magnitude and scope of the HIV/AIDS crisis demands a comprehensive, long-term, international response focused upon addressing the causes, reducing the spread, and ameliorating the consequences of the HIV/AIDS pandemic, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prevention and education, care and treatment, basic and applied research, and training of health care workers, particularly at the community and provincial levels, and other community workers and leaders needed to cope with the range of consequences of the HIV/AIDS crisis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> development of health care infrastructure and delivery systems through cooperative and coordinated public efforts and public and private partnerships;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> development and implementation of national and community-based multisector strategies that address the impact of HIV/AIDS on the individual, family, community, and nation and increase the participation of at-risk populations in programs designed to encourage behavioral and social change and reduce the stigma associated with HIV/AIDS; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> coordination of efforts between international organizations such as the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria, the Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS), the World Health Organization (WHO), national governments, and private sector organizations, including faith-based organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<chapeau> The United States has the capacity to lead and enhance the effectiveness of the international community’s response by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing substantial financial resources, technical expertise, and training, particularly of health care personnel and community workers and leaders;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promoting vaccine and microbicide research and the development of new treatment protocols in the public and commercial pharmaceutical research sectors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> making available pharmaceuticals and diagnostics for HIV/AIDS therapy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> encouraging governments and faith-based and community-based organizations to adopt policies that treat HIV/AIDS as a multisectoral public health problem affecting not only health but other areas such as agriculture, education, the economy, the family and society, and assisting them to develop and implement programs corresponding to these needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> promoting healthy lifestyles, including abstinence, delaying sexual debut, monogamy, marriage, faithfulness, use of condoms, and avoiding substance abuse; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> encouraging active involvement of the private sector, including businesses, pharmaceutical and biotechnology companies, the medical and scientific communities, charitable foundations, private and voluntary organizations and nongovernmental organizations, faith-based organizations, community-based organizations, and other nonprofit entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> Prostitution and other sexual victimization are degrading to women and children and it should be the policy of the United States to eradicate such practices. The sex industry, the trafficking of individuals into such industry, and sexual violence are additional causes of and factors in the spread of the HIV/AIDS epidemic. One in nine South Africans is living with AIDS, and sexual assault is rampant, at a victimization rate of one in three women. Meanwhile in Cambodia, as many as 40 percent of prostitutes are infected with HIV and the country has the highest rate of increase of HIV infection in all of Southeast Asia. Victims of coercive sexual encounters do not get to make choices about their sexual activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<content> Strong coordination must exist among the various agencies of the United States to ensure effective and efficient use of financial and technical resources within the United States Government with respect to the provision of international HIV/AIDS assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<content> In his address to Congress on <date date="2003-01-28">January 28, 2003</date>, the President announced the Administration’s intention to embark on a five-year emergency plan for AIDS relief, to confront HIV/AIDS with the goals of preventing 7,000,000 new HIV/AIDS infections, treating at least 2,000,000 people with life-extending drugs, and providing humane care for millions of people suffering from HIV/AIDS, and for children orphaned by HIV/AIDS.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<content> In this address to Congress, the President stated the following: “Today, on the continent of Africa, nearly 30,000,000 people have the AIDS virus—including 3,000,000 children under the age of 15. There are whole countries in Africa where more than one-third of the adult population carries the infection. More than 4,000,000 require immediate drug treatment. Yet across that continent, only 50,000 AIDS victims—only 50,000—are receiving the medicine they need.”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(27)</num>
<content> Furthermore, the President focused on care and treatment of HIV/AIDS in his address to Congress, stating the following: “Because the AIDS diagnosis is considered a death sentence, many do not seek treatment. Almost all who do are turned away. A doctor in rural South Africa describes his frustration. He says, ‘We have no medicines. Many hospitals tell people, you’ve got AIDS, we can’t help you. Go home and die.’ In an age of miraculous medicines, no person should have to hear those words. AIDS can be prevented. Anti-retroviral drugs can extend life for many years * * * Ladies and gentlemen, seldom has history offered a greater opportunity to do so much for so many.”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(28)</num>
<content> Finally, the President stated that “[w]e have confronted, and will continue to confront, HIV/AIDS in our own country”, proposing now that the United States should lead the world in sparing innocent people from a plague of nature, and asking Congress “to commit $15,000,000,000 over the next five years, including nearly $10,000,000,000 in new money, to turn the tide against AIDS in the most afflicted nations of Africa and the Caribbean”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(29)</num>
<content> On <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, the President signed this chapter into law, launching the largest international public health program of its kind ever created.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(30)</num>
<chapeau> Between 2003 and 2008, the United States, through the President’s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) and in conjunction with other bilateral programs and the multilateral Global Fund has helped to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide antiretroviral therapy for over 1,900,000 people;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that over 150,000 infants, most of whom would have likely been infected with HIV during pregnancy or childbirth, were not infected; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide palliative care and HIV prevention assistance to millions of other people.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(31)</num>
<content> While United States leadership in the battles against HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria has had an enormous impact, these diseases continue to take a terrible toll on the human race.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(32)</num>
<chapeau> According to the 2007 AIDS Epidemic Update of the Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an estimated 2,100,000 people died of AIDS-related causes in 2007; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an estimated 2,500,000 people were newly infected with HIV during that year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(33)</num>
<content> According to the World Health Organization, malaria kills more than 1,000,000 people per year, 70 percent of whom are children under 5 years of age.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(34)</num>
<content> According to the World Health Organization, ⅓ of the world’s population is infected with the tuberculosis bacterium, and tuberculosis is 1 of the greatest infectious causes of death of adults worldwide, killing 1,600,000 people per year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(35)</num>
<content> Efforts to promote abstinence, fidelity, the correct and consistent use of condoms, the delay of sexual debut, and the reduction of concurrent sexual partners represent important elements of strategies to prevent the transmission of HIV/AIDS.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(36)</num>
<chapeau> According to UNAIDS—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> women and girls make up nearly 60 percent of persons in sub-Saharan Africa who are HIV positive;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> women and girls are more biologically, economically, and socially vulnerable to HIV infection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> gender issues are critical components in the effort to prevent HIV/AIDS and to care for those affected by the disease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(37)</num>
<content> Children who have lost a parent to HIV/AIDS, who are otherwise directly affected by the disease, or who live in areas of high HIV prevalence may be vulnerable to the disease or its socioeconomic effects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(38)</num>
<content> Lack of health capacity, including insufficient personnel and inadequate infrastructure, in sub-Saharan Africa and other regions of the world is a critical barrier that limits the effectiveness of efforts to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria, and to achieve other global health goals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(39)</num>
<chapeau> On <date date="2007-03-30">March 30, 2007</date>, the Institute of Medicine of the National Academies released a report entitled “PEPFAR Implementation: Progress and Promise”, which found that budget allocations setting percentage levels for spending on prevention, care, and treatment and for certain subsets of activities within the prevention category—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have “adversely affected implementation of the U.S. Global AIDS Initiative”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have inhibited comprehensive, integrated, evidence based approaches;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> “have been counterproductive”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> “may have been helpful initially in ensuring a balance of attention to activities within the 4 categories of prevention, treatment, care, and orphans and vulnerable children”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> “have also limited PEPFAR’s ability to tailor its activities in each country to the local epidemic and to coordinate with the level of activities in the countries’ national plans”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> should be removed by Congress and replaced with more appropriate mechanisms that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> “ensure accountability for results from Country Teams to the U.S. Global AIDS Coordinator and to Congress”; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> “ensure that spending is directly linked to and commensurate with necessary efforts to achieve both country and overall performance targets for prevention, treatment, care, and orphans and vulnerable children”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(40)</num>
<chapeau> The United States Government has endorsed the principles of harmonization in coordinating efforts to combat HIV/AIDS commonly referred to as the “Three Ones”, which includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 1 agreed HIV/AIDS action framework that provides the basis for coordination of the work of all partners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 1 national HIV/AIDS coordinating authority, with a broadbased multisectoral mandate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 1 agreed HIV/AIDS country-level monitoring and evaluating system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(41)</num>
<chapeau> In the Abuja Declaration on HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis and Other Related Infectious Diseases, of April 26–27, 2001 (referred to in this chapter as the “Abuja Declaration”), the Heads of State and Government of the Organization of African Unity (OAU)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> declared that they would “place the fight against HIV/AIDS at the forefront and as the highest priority issue in our respective national development plans”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> committed “TO TAKE PERSONAL RESPONSIBILITY AND PROVIDE LEADERSHIP for the activities of the National AIDS Commissions/Councils”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> resolved “to lead from the front the battle against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis and Other Related Infectious Diseases by personally ensuring that such bodies were properly convened in mobilizing our societies as a whole and providing focus for unified national policymaking and programme implementation, ensuring coordination of all sectors at all levels with a gender perspective and respect for human rights, particularly to ensure equal rights for people living with HIV/AIDS”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> pledged “to set a target of allocating at least 15% of our annual budget to the improvement of the health sector”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, § 2</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 712</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2919</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7602.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> AIDS</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “AIDS” means the acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Global AIDS Coordinator</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Global AIDS Coordinator” means the Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Global Fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Global Fund” means the public-private partnership known as the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria established pursuant to Article 80 of the Swiss Civil Code.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> HIV</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “HIV” means the human immunodeficiency virus, the pathogen that causes AIDS.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> HIV/AIDS</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “HIV/AIDS” means, with respect to an individual, an individual who is infected with HIV or living with AIDS.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Impact evaluation research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “impact evaluation research” means the application of research methods and statistical analysis to measure the extent to which change in a population-based outcome can be attributed to program intervention instead of other environmental factors.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operations research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “operations research” means the application of social science research methods, statistical analysis, and other appropriate scientific methods to judge, compare, and improve policies and program outcomes, from the earliest stages of defining and designing programs through their development and implementation, with the objective of the rapid dissemination of conclusions and concrete impact on programming.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Paraprofessional</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “paraprofessional” means an individual who is trained and employed as a health agent for the provision of basic assistance in the identification, prevention, or treatment of illness or disability.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partner government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “partner government” means a government with which the United States is working to provide assistance to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, or malaria on behalf of people living within the jurisdiction of such government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program monitoring</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “program monitoring” means the collection, analysis, and use of routine program data to determine—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> how well a program is carried out; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> how much the program costs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relevant executive branch agencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “relevant executive branch agencies” means the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, and any other department or agency of the United States that participates in international HIV/AIDS activities pursuant to the authorities of such department or agency or the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, § 3</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 717</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, § 3</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2921</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7603.</num>
<heading> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of this chapter is to strengthen and enhance United States leadership and the effectiveness of the United States response to the HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria pandemics and other related and preventable infectious diseases as part of the overall United States health and development agenda by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> establishing comprehensive, coordinated, and integrated 5-year, global strategies to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> building on progress and successes to date;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improving harmonization of United States efforts with national strategies of partner governments and other public and private entities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> emphasizing capacity building initiatives in order to promote a transition toward greater sustainability through the support of country-driven efforts;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> providing increased resources for bilateral and multilateral efforts to fight HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria as integrated components of United States development assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> intensifying efforts to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prevent HIV infection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure the continued support for, and expanded access to, treatment and care programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> enhance the effectiveness of prevention, treatment, and care programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> address the particular vulnerabilities of girls and women;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> encouraging the expansion of private sector efforts and expanding public-private sector partnerships to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> reinforcing efforts to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> develop safe and effective vaccines, microbicides, and other prevention and treatment technologies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improve diagnostics capabilities for HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> helping partner countries to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> strengthen health systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> expand health workforce; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> address infrastructural weaknesses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, § 4</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 717</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, § 4</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2922</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7604.</num>
<heading> Authority to consolidate and combine reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">With respect to the reports required by this chapter to be submitted by the President, to ensure an efficient use of resources, the President may, in his discretion and notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, consolidate or combine any of these reports, except for the report required by <ref>section 7611 of this title</ref>, so long as the required elements of each report are addressed and reported within a 90-day period from the original deadline date for submission of the report specified in this chapter. The President may also enter into contracts with organizations with relevant expertise to develop, originate, or contribute to any of the reports required by this chapter to be submitted by the President, with the exception of the 5-year strategy.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, § 5</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 718</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, § 5</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2922</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>POLICY PLANNING AND COORDINATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7611.</num>
<heading> Development of a comprehensive, five-year, global strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall establish a comprehensive, integrated, 5-year strategy to expand and improve efforts to combat global HIV/AIDS. This strategy shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> further strengthen the capability of the United States to be an effective leader of the international campaign against this disease and strengthen the capacities of nations experiencing HIV/AIDS epidemics to combat this disease;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> maintain sufficient flexibility and remain responsive to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> changes in the epidemic;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> challenges facing partner countries in developing and implementing an effective national response; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> evidence-based improvements and innovations in the prevention, care, and treatment of HIV/AIDS;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> situate United States efforts to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria within the broader United States global health and development agenda, establishing a roadmap to link investments in specific disease programs to the broader goals of strengthening health systems and infrastructure and to integrate and coordinate HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, or malaria programs with other health or development programs, as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> provide a plan to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prevent 12,000,000 new HIV infections worldwide;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> support—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the increase in the number of individuals with HIV/AIDS receiving antiretroviral treatment above the goal established under <ref>section 7672(a)(3) of this title</ref> and increased pursuant to paragraphs (1) through (3) of <ref>section 7673(d) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> additional treatment through coordinated multilateral efforts;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> support care for 12,000,000 individuals infected with or affected by HIV/AIDS, including 5,000,000 orphans and vulnerable children affected by HIV/AIDS, with an emphasis on promoting a comprehensive, coordinated system of services to be integrated throughout the continuum of care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> help partner countries in the effort to achieve goals of 80 percent access to counseling, testing, and treatment to prevent the transmission of HIV from mother to child, emphasizing a continuum of care model;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> help partner countries to provide care and treatment services to children with HIV in proportion to their percentage within the HIV-infected population in each country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> promote preservice training for health professionals designed to strengthen the capacity of institutions to develop and implement policies for training health workers to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> equip teachers with skills needed for HIV/AIDS prevention and support for persons with, or affected by, HIV/AIDS;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> provide and share best practices for combating HIV/AIDS with health professionals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> promote pediatric HIV/AIDS training for physicians, nurses, and other health care workers, through public-private partnerships if possible, including through the designation, if appropriate, of centers of excellence for training in pediatric HIV/AIDS prevention, care, and treatment in partner countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> help partner countries to train and support retention of health care professionals and paraprofessionals, with the target of training and retaining at least 140,000 new health care professionals and paraprofessionals with an emphasis on training and in country deployment of critically needed doctors and nurses and to strengthen capacities in developing countries, especially in sub-Saharan Africa, to deliver primary health care with the objective of helping countries achieve staffing levels of at least 2.3 doctors, nurses, and midwives per 1,000 population, as called for by the World Health Organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> include multisectoral approaches and specific strategies to treat individuals infected with HIV/AIDS and to prevent the further transmission of HIV infections, with a particular focus on the needs of families with children (including the prevention of mother-to-child transmission), women, young people, orphans, and vulnerable children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> establish a timetable with annual global treatment targets with country-level benchmarks for antiretroviral treatment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> expand the integration of timely and relevant research within the prevention, care, and treatment of HIV/AIDS;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> include a plan for program monitoring, operations research, and impact evaluation and for the dissemination of a best practices report to highlight findings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> support the in-country or intra-regional training, preferably through public-private partnerships, of scientific investigators, managers, and other staff who are capable of promoting the systematic uptake of clinical research findings and other evidence-based interventions into routine practice, with the goal of improving the quality, effectiveness, and local leadership of HIV/AIDS health care;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> expand and accelerate research on and development of HIV/AIDS prevention methods for women, including enhancing inter-agency collaboration, staffing, and organizational infrastructure dedicated to microbicide research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> provide for consultation with local leaders and officials to develop prevention strategies and programs that are tailored to the unique needs of each country and community and targeted particularly toward those most at risk of acquiring HIV infection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<chapeau> make the reduction of HIV/AIDS behavioral risks a priority of all prevention efforts by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> promoting abstinence from sexual activity and encouraging monogamy and faithfulness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> encouraging the correct and consistent use of male and female condoms and increasing the availability of, and access to, these commodities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> promoting the delay of sexual debut and the reduction of multiple concurrent sexual partners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> promoting education for discordant couples (where an individual is infected with HIV and the other individual is uninfected or whose status is unknown) about safer sex practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> promoting voluntary counseling and testing, addiction therapy, and other prevention and treatment tools for illicit injection drug users and other substance abusers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> educating men and boys about the risks of procuring sex commercially and about the need to end violent behavior toward women and girls;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> supporting partner country and community efforts to identify and address social, economic, or cultural factors, such as migration, urbanization, conflict, gender-based violence, lack of empowerment for women, and transportation patterns, which directly contribute to the transmission of HIV;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> supporting comprehensive programs to promote alternative livelihoods, safety, and social reintegration strategies for commercial sex workers and their families;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> promoting cooperation with law enforcement to prosecute offenders of trafficking, rape, and sexual assault crimes with the goal of eliminating such crimes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> working to eliminate rape, gender-based violence, sexual assault, and the sexual exploitation of women and children;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> include programs to reduce the transmission of HIV, particularly addressing the heightened vulnerabilities of women and girls to HIV in many countries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<chapeau> support other important means of preventing or reducing the transmission of HIV, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> medical male circumcision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the maintenance of a safe blood supply;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> promoting universal precautions in formal and informal health care settings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> educating the public to recognize and to avoid risks to contract HIV through blood exposures during formal and informal health care and cosmetic services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> investigating suspected nosocomial infections to identify and stop further nosocomial transmission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> other mechanisms to reduce the transmission of HIV;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> increase support for prevention of mother-to-child transmission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> build capacity within the public health sector of developing countries by improving health systems and public health infrastructure and developing indicators to measure changes in broader public health sector capabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> increase the coordination of HIV/AIDS programs with development programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<chapeau> provide a framework for expanding or developing existing or new country or regional programs, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> drafting compacts or other agreements, as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> establishing criteria and objectives for such compacts and agreements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> promoting sustainability;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> provide a plan for national and regional priorities for resource distribution and a global investment plan by region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<chapeau> provide a plan to address the immediate and ongoing needs of women and girls, which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> addresses the vulnerabilities that contribute to their elevated risk of infection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes specific goals and targets to address these factors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provides clear guidance to field missions to integrate gender across prevention, care, and treatment programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> sets forth gender-specific indicators to monitor progress on outcomes and impacts of gender programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> supports efforts in countries in which women or orphans lack inheritance rights and other fundamental protections to promote the passage, implementation, and enforcement of such laws;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> supports life skills training, especially among women and girls, with the goal of reducing vulnerabilities to HIV/AIDS;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> addresses and prevents gender-based violence; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> addresses the posttraumatic and psychosocial consequences and provides postexposure prophylaxis protecting against HIV infection to victims of gender-based violence and rape;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<chapeau> provide a plan to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> determine the local factors that may put men and boys at elevated risk of contracting or transmitting HIV;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> address male norms and behaviors to reduce these risks, including by reducing alcohol abuse;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> promote responsible male behavior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> promote male participation and leadership at the community level in efforts to promote HIV prevention, reduce stigma, promote participation in voluntary counseling and testing, and provide care, treatment, and support for persons with HIV/AIDS;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> provide a plan to address the vulnerabilities and needs of orphans and children who are vulnerable to, or affected by, HIV/AIDS;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> encourage partner countries to develop health care curricula and promote access to training tailored to individuals receiving services through, or exiting from, existing programs geared to orphans and vulnerable children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<content> provide a framework to work with international actors and partner countries toward universal access to HIV/AIDS prevention, treatment, and care programs, recognizing that prevention is of particular importance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<content> enhance the coordination of United States bilateral efforts to combat global HIV/AIDS with other major public and private entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<chapeau> enhance the attention given to the national strategic HIV/AIDS plans of countries receiving United States assistance by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reviewing the planning and programmatic decisions associated with that assistance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> helping to strengthen such national strategies, if necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(27)</num>
<chapeau> support activities described in the Global Plan to Stop TB, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> expanding and enhancing the coverage of the Directly Observed Treatment Short-course (DOTS) in order to treat individuals infected with tuberculosis and HIV, including multi-drug resistant or extensively drug resistant tuberculosis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> improving coordination and integration of HIV/AIDS and tuberculosis programming;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(28)</num>
<content> ensure coordination between the Global AIDS Coordinator and the Malaria Coordinator and address issues of comorbidity between HIV/AIDS and malaria; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(29)</num>
<content> include a longer term estimate of the projected resource needs, progress toward greater sustainability and country ownership of HIV/AIDS programs, and the anticipated role of the United States in the global effort to combat HIV/AIDS during the 10-year period beginning on <date date="2013-10-01">October 1, 2013</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2009-10-01">October 1, 2009</date>, the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that sets forth the strategy described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include a discussion of the following elements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The purpose, scope, methodology, and general and specific objectives of the strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The problems, risks, and threats to the successful pursuit of the strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The desired goals, objectives, activities, and outcome-related performance measures of the strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> A description of future costs and resources needed to carry out the strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> A delineation of United States Government roles, responsibility, and coordination mechanisms of the strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> A description of the strategy—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to promote harmonization of United States assistance with that of other international, national, and private actors as elucidated in the “Three Ones”; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to address existing challenges in harmonization and alignment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> A description of the manner in which the strategy will—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> further the development and implementation of the national multisectoral strategic HIV/AIDS frameworks of partner governments; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> enhance the centrality, effectiveness, and sustainability of those national plans.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> A description of how the strategy will seek to achieve the specific targets described in subsection (a) and other targets, as appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> A description of, and rationale for, the timetable for annual global treatment targets with country-level estimates of numbers of persons in need of antiretroviral treatment, country-level benchmarks for United States support for assistance for antiretroviral treatment, and numbers of persons enrolled in antiretroviral treatment programs receiving United States support. If global benchmarks are not achieved within the reporting period, the report shall include a description of steps being taken to ensure that global benchmarks will be achieved and a detailed breakdown and justification of spending priorities in countries in which benchmarks are not being met, including a description of other donor or national support for antiretroviral treatment in the country, if appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<chapeau> A description of how operations research is addressed in the strategy and how such research can most effectively be integrated into care, treatment, and prevention activities in order to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> improve program quality and efficiency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ascertain cost effectiveness;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> ensure transparency and accountability;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> assess population-based impact;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> disseminate findings and best practices; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> optimize delivery of services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> An analysis of United States-assisted strategies to prevent the transmission of HIV/AIDS, including methodologies to promote abstinence, monogamy, faithfulness, the correct and consistent use of male and female condoms, reductions in concurrent sexual partners, and delay of sexual debut, and of intended monitoring and evaluation approaches to measure the effectiveness of prevention programs and ensure that they are targeted to appropriate audiences.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> Within the analysis required under subparagraph (K), an examination of additional planned means of preventing the transmission of HIV including medical male circumcision, maintenance of a safe blood supply, public education about risks to acquire HIV infection from blood exposures, promotion of universal precautions, investigation of suspected nosocomial infections and other tools.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> A description of efforts to assist partner country and community to identify and address social, economic, or cultural factors, such as migration, urbanization, conflict, gender-based violence, lack of empowerment for women, and transportation patterns, which directly contribute to the transmission of HIV.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<chapeau> A description of the specific targets, goals, and strategies developed to address the needs and vulnerabilities of women and girls to HIV/AIDS, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> activities directed toward men and boys;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> activities to enhance educational, microfinance, and livelihood opportunities for women and girls;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> activities to promote and protect the legal empowerment of women, girls, and orphans and vulnerable children;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> programs targeted toward gender-based violence and sexual coercion;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> strategies to meet the particular needs of adolescents;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> assistance for victims of rape, sexual abuse, assault, exploitation, and trafficking; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> programs to prevent alcohol abuse.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> A description of strategies to address male norms and behaviors that contribute to the transmission of HIV, to promote responsible male behavior, and to promote male participation and leadership in HIV/AIDS prevention, care, treatment, and voluntary counseling and testing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(P)</num>
<chapeau> A description of strategies—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> to address the needs of orphans and vulnerable children, including an analysis of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> factors contributing to children’s vulnerability to HIV/AIDS; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> vulnerabilities caused by the impact of HIV/AIDS on children and their families; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in areas of higher HIV/AIDS prevalence, to promote a community-based approach to vulnerability, maximizing community input into determining which children participate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> A description of capacity-building efforts undertaken by countries themselves, including adherents of the Abuja Declaration and an assessment of the impact of International Monetary Fund macroeconomic and fiscal policies on national and donor investments in health.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(R)</num>
<chapeau> A description of the strategy to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> strengthen capacity building within the public health sector;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> improve health care in those countries;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> help countries to develop and implement national health workforce strategies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> strive to achieve goals in training, retaining, and effectively deploying health staff;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> promote the use of codes of conduct for ethical recruiting practices for health care workers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> increase the sustainability of health programs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(S)</num>
<chapeau> A description of the criteria for selection, objectives, methodology, and structure of compacts or other framework agreements with countries or regional organizations, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the role of civil society;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the degree of transparency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> benchmarks for success of such compacts or agreements; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the relationship between such compacts or agreements and the national HIV/AIDS and public health strategies and commitments of partner countries.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(T)</num>
<content> A strategy to better coordinate HIV/AIDS assistance with nutrition and food assistance programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(U)</num>
<content> A description of transnational or regional initiatives to combat regionalized epidemics in highly affected areas such as the Caribbean.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> A description of planned resource distribution and global investment by region.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(W)</num>
<content> A description of coordination efforts in order to better implement the Stop TB Strategy and to address the problem of coinfection of HIV/AIDS and tuberculosis and of projected challenges or barriers to successful implementation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(X)</num>
<content> A description of coordination efforts to address malaria and comorbidity with malaria and HIV/AIDS.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study of progress toward achievement of policy objectives</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Design and budget plan for data evaluation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Global AIDS Coordinator shall enter into a contract with the Institute of Medicine of the National Academies that provides that not later than 18 months after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, the Institute, in consultation with the Global AIDS Coordinator and other relevant parties representing the public and private sector, shall provide the Global AIDS Coordinator with a design plan and budget for the evaluation and collection of baseline and subsequent data to address the elements set forth in paragraph (2)(B). The Global AIDS Coordinator shall submit the budget and design plan to the appropriate congressional committees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 4 years after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, the Institute of Medicine of the National Academies shall publish a study that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an assessment of the performance of United States-assisted global HIV/AIDS programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the impact on health of prevention, treatment, and care efforts that are supported by United States funding, including multilateral and bilateral programs involving joint operations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The study conducted under this paragraph shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an assessment of progress toward prevention, treatment, and care targets;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an assessment of the effects on health systems, including on the financing and management of health systems and the quality of service delivery and staffing;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an assessment of efforts to address gender-specific aspects of HIV/AIDS, including gender related constraints to accessing services and addressing underlying social and economic vulnerabilities of women and men;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the impact of treatment and care programs on 5-year survival rates, drug adherence, and the emergence of drug resistance;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the impact of prevention programs on HIV incidence in relevant population groups;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the impact on child health and welfare of interventions authorized under this chapter on behalf of orphans and vulnerable children;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the impact of programs and activities authorized in this chapter on child mortality; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> recommendations for improving the programs referred to in subparagraph (A)(i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methodologies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Assessments and impact evaluations conducted under the study shall utilize sound statistical methods and techniques for the behavioral sciences, including random assignment methodologies as feasible. Qualitative data on process variables should be used for assessments and impact evaluations, wherever possible.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Institute of Medicine may enter into contracts or cooperative agreements or award grants to conduct the study under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the study under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comptroller General report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 3 years after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report on the global HIV/AIDS programs of the United States to the appropriate congressional committees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description and assessment of the monitoring and evaluation practices and policies in place for these programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment of coordination within Federal agencies involved in these programs, examining both internal coordination within these programs and integration with the larger global health and development agenda of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an assessment of procurement policies and practices within these programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an assessment of harmonization with national government HIV/AIDS and public health strategies as well as other international efforts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> an assessment of the impact of global HIV/AIDS funding and programs on other United States global health programming; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> recommendations for improving the global HIV/AIDS programs of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Best practices report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, and annually thereafter, the Global AIDS Coordinator shall publish a best practices report that highlights the programs receiving financial assistance from the United States that have the potential for replication or adaption, particularly at a low cost, across global AIDS programs, including those that focus on both generalized and localized epidemics.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dissemination of findings</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication on Internet website</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Global AIDS Coordinator shall disseminate the full findings of the annual best practices report on the Internet website of the Office of the Global AIDS Coordinator.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dissemination guidance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Global AIDS Coordinator shall develop guidance to ensure timely submission and dissemination of significant information regarding best practices with respect to global AIDS programs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inspectors General</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oversight plan</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Inspectors General of the Department of State and Broadcasting Board of Governors, the Department of Health and Human Services, and the United States Agency for International Development shall jointly develop coordinated annual plans for oversight activity in each of the fiscal years 2009 through March 25 of fiscal year 2025, with regard to the programs authorized under this chapter and sections 2151b–2, 2151b–3, and 2151b–4 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The plans developed under subparagraph (A) shall include a schedule for financial audits, inspections, and performance reviews, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The first plan developed under subparagraph (A) shall be completed not later than the later of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content><date date="2008-09-01">September 1, 2008</date>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 60 days after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 2010 through 2013 plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each of the plans for fiscal years 2010 through 2013 developed under subparagraph (A) shall be completed not later than 30 days before each of the fiscal years 2010 through 2013, respectively.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 2014 plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The plan developed under subparagraph (A) for fiscal year 2014 shall be completed not later than 60 days after <date date="2013-12-02">December 2, 2013</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each of the last eleven plans developed under subparagraph (A) shall be completed not later than 30 days before each of the fiscal years 2015 through 2025, respectively.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In order to avoid duplication and maximize efficiency, the Inspectors General described in paragraph (1) shall coordinate their activities with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Government Accountability Office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Inspectors General of the Department of Commerce, the Department of Defense, the Department of Labor, and the Peace Corps, as appropriate, pursuant to the 2004 Memorandum of Agreement Coordinating Audit Coverage of Programs and Activities Implementing the President’s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief, or any successor agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Global AIDS Coordinator and the Coordinator of the United States Government Activities to Combat Malaria Globally shall make available necessary funds not exceeding $15,000,000 during the 5-year period beginning on <date date="2008-10-01">October 1, 2008</date> to the Inspectors General described in paragraph (1) for the audits, inspections, and reviews described in that paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual study</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2009-09-30">September 30, 2009</date>, and annually thereafter through <date date="2025-03-25">March 25, 2025</date>, the Global AIDS Coordinator shall complete a study of treatment providers that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> represents a range of countries and service environments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> estimates the per-patient cost of antiretroviral HIV/AIDS treatment and the care of people with HIV/AIDS not receiving antiretroviral treatment, including a comparison of the costs for equivalent services provided by programs not receiving assistance under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> estimates per-patient costs across the program and in specific categories of service providers, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> urban and rural providers;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> country-specific providers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> other subcategories, as appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 2013 through 2025 studies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The studies required to be submitted by <date date="2014-09-30">September 30, 2014</date>, and annually thereafter through <date date="2025-03-25">March 25, 2025</date>, shall include, in addition to the elements set forth under paragraph (1), the following elements:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A plan for conducting cost studies of United States assistance under <ref>section 2151b–2 of this title</ref> in partner countries, taking into account the goal for more systematic collection of data, as well as the demands of such analysis on available human and fiscal resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> A comprehensive and harmonized expenditure analysis by partner country, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an analysis of Global Fund and national partner spending and comparable data across United States, Global Fund, and national partner spending; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> where providing such comparable data is not currently practicable, an explanation of why it is not currently practicable, and when it will be practicable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the completion of each study under paragraph (1), the Global AIDS Coordinator shall make the results of such study available on a publicly accessible Web site.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partner country defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “partner country” means a country with a minimum United States Government investment of HIV/AIDS assistance of at least $5,000,000 in the prior fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Message</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Global AIDS Coordinator shall develop a message, to be prominently displayed by each program receiving funds under this chapter, that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> demonstrates that the program is a commitment by citizens of the United States to the global fight against HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> enhances awareness by program recipients that the program is an effort on behalf of the citizens of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 718</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–56</ref>, §§ 2, 3(a), <date date="2013-12-02">Dec. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 648</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–305, § 2</ref>, <date date="2018-12-11">Dec. 11, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–47, div. F, title VII, § 7072(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-03-23">Mar. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 852</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7612.</num>
<heading> HIV/AIDS response Coordinator</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, the President shall specify the necessary financial and personnel resources, from funds appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref> for HIV/AIDS assistance, that shall be assigned to and under the direct control of the Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally to establish and maintain the duties and supporting activities assigned to the Coordinator by this chapter and the amendments made by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of separate account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the general fund of the Treasury a separate account which shall be known as the “Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally Fund” and which shall be administered by the Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally. There shall be deposited into the Fund all amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref> for HIV/AIDS assistance, except for amounts appropriated for United States contributions to the Global Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> full-time country level coordinators, preferably with management experience, should head each HIV/AIDS country team for United States missions overseeing significant HIV/AIDS programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> foreign service nationals provide critically important services in the design and implementation of United States country-level HIV/AIDS programs and their skills and experience as public health professionals should be recognized within hiring and compensation practices; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> staffing levels for United States country-level HIV/AIDS teams should be adequately maintained to fulfill oversight and other obligations of the positions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 721</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2935</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7612a.</num>
<heading> HIV/AIDS Working Capital Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In furtherance of the purposes of <ref>section 2151b–2 of this title</ref>, and to assist in providing a safe, secure, reliable, and sustainable supply chain of pharmaceuticals and other products needed to provide care and treatment of persons with HIV/AIDS and related infections, the Coordinator of the United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally (the “Coordinator”) is authorized to establish an HIV/AIDS Working Capital Fund (in this section referred to as the “HIV/AIDS Fund”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Funds deposited during any fiscal year in the HIV/AIDS Fund shall be available without fiscal year limitation and used for pharmaceuticals and other products needed to provide care and treatment of persons with HIV/AIDS and related infections, including, but not limited to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> anti-retroviral drugs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> other pharmaceuticals and medical items needed to provide care and treatment to persons with HIV/AIDS and related infections;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> laboratory and other supplies for performing tests related to the provision of care and treatment to persons with HIV/AIDS and related infections;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other medical supplies needed for the operation of HIV/AIDS treatment and care centers, including products needed in programs for the prevention of mother-to-child transmission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> pharmaceuticals and health commodities needed for the provision of palliative care; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> laboratory and clinical equipment, as well as equipment needed for the transportation and care of HIV/AIDS supplies, and other equipment needed to provide prevention, care and treatment of HIV/AIDS described above.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> There may be deposited during any fiscal year in the HIV/AIDS Fund payments for HIV/AIDS pharmaceuticals and products provided from the HIV/AIDS Fund received from applicable appropriations and funds of the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Defense, or other Federal agencies and other sources at actual cost of the HIV/AIDS pharmaceuticals and other products, actual cost plus the additional costs of providing such HIV/AIDS pharmaceuticals and other products, or at any other price agreed to by the Coordinator or his designee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> There may be deposited in the HIV/AIDS Fund payments for the loss of, or damage to, HIV/AIDS pharmaceuticals and products held in the HIV/AIDS Fund, rebates, reimbursements, refunds and other credits applicable to the operation of the HIV/AIDS Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> At the close of each fiscal year the Coordinator may transfer out of the HIV/AIDS Fund to other HIV/AIDS programmatic areas such amounts as the Coordinator determines to be in excess of the needs of the HIV/AIDS Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> At the close of each fiscal year the Coordinator shall submit a report to the Committees on Appropriations detailing the financial activities of the HIV/AIDS Fund, including sources of income and information regarding disbursements.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. D, title V, § 525(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>SUPPORT FOR MULTILATERAL FUNDS, PROGRAMS, AND PUBLIC-PRIVATE PARTNERSHIPS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7621.</num>
<heading> Sense of Congress on public-private partnerships</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Innovative partnerships between governments and organizations in the private sector (including foundations, universities, corporations, faith-based and community-based organizations, and other nongovernmental organizations) have proliferated in recent years, particularly in the area of health.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Public-private sector partnerships multiply local and international capacities to strengthen the delivery of health services in developing countries and to accelerate research for vaccines and other pharmaceutical products that are essential to combat infectious diseases decimating the populations of these countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> These partnerships maximize the unique capabilities of each sector while combining financial and other resources, scientific knowledge, and expertise toward common goals which neither the public nor the private sector can achieve alone.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Sustaining existing public-private partnerships and building new ones are critical to the success of the international community’s efforts to combat HIV/AIDS and other infectious diseases around the globe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the sustainment and promotion of public-private partnerships should be a priority element of the strategy pursued by the United States to combat the HIV/AIDS pandemic and other global health crises; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States should systematically track the evolution of these partnerships and work with others in the public and private sector to profile and build upon those models that are most effective.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 723</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7622.</num>
<heading> Participation in the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings; sense of Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The establishment of the Global Fund in January 2002 is consistent with the general principles for an international AIDS trust fund first outlined by Congress in the Global AIDS and Tuberculosis Relief Act of 2000 (<ref>Public Law 106–264</ref>) [<ref>22 U.S.C. 6801</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The Global Fund is an innovative financing mechanism which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has made progress in many areas in combating HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> represents the multilateral component of this chapter, extending United States efforts to more than 130 countries around the world.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The Global Fund and United States bilateral assistance programs—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are demonstrating increasingly effective coordination, with each possessing certain comparative advantages in the fight against HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> often work most effectively in concert with each other.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> The United States Government—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is the largest supporter of the Global Fund in terms of resources and technical support;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> made the founding contribution to the Global Fund; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is fully committed to the success of the Global Fund as a multilateral public-private partnership.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> transparency and accountability are crucial to the long-term success and viability of the Global Fund;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the Global Fund has made significant progress toward addressing concerns raised by the Government Accountability Office by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> improving risk assessment and risk management capabilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> providing clearer guidance for and oversight of Local Fund Agents; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> strengthening the Office of the Inspector General for the Global Fund;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the provision of sufficient resources and authority to the Office of the Inspector General for the Global Fund to ensure that office has the staff and independence necessary to carry out its mandate will be a measure of the commitment of the Global Fund to transparency and accountability;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> regular, publicly published financial, programmatic, and reporting audits of the Fund, its grantees, and Local Fund Agents are also important benchmarks of transparency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> the Global Fund should establish and maintain a system to track—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of funds disbursed to each subrecipient on the grant’s fiscal cycle; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the distribution of resources, by grant and principal recipient, for prevention, care, treatment, drug and commodity purchases, and other purposes;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> relevant national authorities in recipient countries should exempt from duties and taxes all products financed by Global Fund grants and procured by any principal recipient or subrecipient for the purpose of carrying out such grants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Global Fund, UNAIDS, and the Global AIDS Coordinator should work together to standardize program indicators wherever possible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> for purposes of evaluating total amounts of funds contributed to the Global Fund under subsection (d)(4)(A)(i), the timetable for evaluations of contributions from sources other than the United States should take into account the fiscal calendars of other major contributors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Global Fund should not support activities involving the “Affordable Medicines Facility-Malaria” or similar entities pending compelling evidence of success from pilot programs as evaluated by the Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat Malaria Globally.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority for United States participation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States participation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The United States is hereby authorized to participate in the Global Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Privileges and immunities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Global Fund shall be considered a public international organization for purposes of <ref>section 288 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The United States Government regards the imposition by recipient countries of taxes or tariffs on goods or services provided by the Global Fund, which are supported through public and private donations, including the substantial contribution of the American people, as inappropriate and inconsistent with standards of good governance. The Global AIDS Coordinator or other representatives of the United States Government shall work with the Global Fund to dissuade governments from imposing such duties, tariffs, or taxes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, and annually thereafter for the duration of the Global Fund, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the Global Fund, including contributions pledged to, contributions (including donations from the private sector) received by, and projects funded by the Global Fund, and the mechanisms established for transparency and accountability in the grant-making process.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States financial participation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to any other funds authorized to be appropriated for bilateral or multilateral HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, or malaria programs, of the amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President up to $2,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2009,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002385">1</ref> and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2010 through 2013, for contributions to the Global Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reprogramming of fiscal year 2001 funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Funds made available for fiscal year 2001 under section 141 of the Global AIDS and Tuberculosis Relief Act of 2000 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 6841</ref>]—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are authorized to remain available until expended; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be transferred to, merged with, and made available for the same purposes as, funds made available for fiscal years 2004 through 2008 under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> At any time during fiscal years 2004 through March 25 of fiscal year 2025, no United States contribution to the Global Fund may cause the total amount of United States Government contributions to the Global Fund to exceed 33 percent of the total amount of funds contributed to the Global Fund from all sources. Contributions to the Global Fund from the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development and the International Monetary Fund shall not be considered in determining compliance with this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If, at any time during any of the fiscal years 2009 through March 25 of fiscal year 2025, the President determines that the Global Fund has provided assistance to a country, the government of which the Secretary of State has determined, for purposes of section 4605(j)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002386">2</ref> of title 50, has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism, then the United States shall withhold from its contribution for the next fiscal year an amount equal to the amount expended by the Fund to the government of each such country.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> If at any time the President determines that the expenses of the Governing, Administrative, and Advisory Bodies (including the Partnership Forum, the Foundation Board, the Secretariat, and the Technical Review Board) of the Global Fund exceed 10 percent of the total expenditures of the Fund for any 2-year period, the United States shall withhold from its contribution for the next fiscal year an amount equal the to the average annual amount expended by the Fund for such 2-year period for the expenses of the Governing, Administrative, and Advisory Bodies in excess of 10 percent of the total expenditures of the Fund.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The President may waive the application of clause (iii) if the President determines that extraordinary circumstances warrant such a waiver. No waiver under this clause may be for any period that exceeds 1 year.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> If, at any time during any of the fiscal years 2004 through 2008, the President determines that the salary of any individual employed by the Global Fund exceeds the salary of the Vice President of the United States (as determined under <ref>section 104 of title 3</ref>) for that fiscal year, then the United States shall withhold from its contribution for the next fiscal year an amount equal to the aggregate amount by which the salary of each such individual exceeds the salary of the Vice President of the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Any amount made available that is withheld by reason of subparagraph (A)(i) shall be contributed to the Global Fund as soon as practicable, subject to subparagraph (A)(i), after additional contributions to the Global Fund are made from other sources.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Any amount made available that is withheld by reason of clause (ii) or (iii) of subparagraph (A) is authorized to be made available to carry out <ref>section 2151b–2 of this title</ref> or section 2151b–3 or 2151b–4 of this title. Amounts made available under the preceding sentence are in addition to amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding clause (i), after July 31 of each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2024 and March 25 of fiscal year 2025, any amount made available that is withheld by reason of subparagraph (A)(i) is authorized to be made available to carry out sections 2151b–2, 2151b–3, and 2151b–4 of this title.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The President may suspend the application of subparagraph (A) with respect to a fiscal year if the President determines that an international health emergency threatens the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> The President shall notify the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate not less than 5 days before making a determination under clause (i) with respect to the application of subparagraph (A)(i) and shall include in the notification—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a justification as to why increased United States Government contributions to the Global Fund is preferable to increased United States assistance to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria on a bilateral basis; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> an explanation as to why other government donors to the Global Fund are unable to provide adequate contributions to the Fund.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, 20 percent of the amounts appropriated pursuant to this chapter for a contribution to support the Global Fund for each of the fiscal years 2010 through 2024 and for fiscal year 2025 through March 25 of such fiscal year shall be withheld from obligation to the Global Fund until the Secretary of State certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the Global Fund—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has established an evaluation framework for the performance of Local Fund Agents (referred to in this paragraph as “LFAs”);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is undertaking a systematic assessment of the performance of LFAs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> has adopted, and is implementing, a policy to publish on a publicly available Web site in an open, machine readable format—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> grant performance reviews;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all reports of the Inspector General of the Global Fund, in a manner that is consistent with the Policy for Disclosure of Reports of the Inspector General, approved at the 16th Meeting of the Board of the Global Fund;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> decision points of the Board of the Global Fund;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> reports from Board committees to the Board; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a regular collection, analysis, and reporting of performance data and funding of grants of the Global Fund, which covers all principal recipients and all subrecipients on the fiscal cycle of each grant, and includes the distribution of resources, by grant and principal recipient and subrecipient, for prevention, care, treatment, drugs, and commodities purchase, and other purposes as practicable;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> is maintaining an independent, well-staffed Office of the Inspector General that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> reports directly to the Board of the Global Fund; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> compiles regular, publicly published audits, in an open, machine readable format, of financial, programmatic, and reporting aspects of the Global Fund, its grantees, and LFAs;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> has established, and is reporting publicly, in an open, machine readable format, on, standard indicators for all program areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> has established a methodology to track and is publicly reporting on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all subrecipients and the amount of funds disbursed to each subrecipient on the grant’s fiscal cycle;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all principal recipients and subrecipients and the amount of funds disbursed to each principal recipient and subrecipient on the fiscal cycle of the grant;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> expenditure data—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> tracked by principal recipients and subrecipients by program area, where practicable, prevention, care, and treatment and reported in a format that allows comparison with other funding streams in each country; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> if such expenditure data is not available, outlay or disbursement data, and an explanation of progress made toward providing such expenditure data; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> high-quality grant performance evaluations measuring inputs, outputs, and outcomes, as appropriate, with the goal of achieving outcome reporting;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> has published an annual report on a publicly available Web site in an open, machine readable format, that includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a list of all countries imposing import duties and internal taxes on any goods or services financed by the Global Fund;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a description of the types of goods or services on which the import duties and internal taxes are levied;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the total cost of the import duties and internal taxes;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> recovered import duties or internal taxes; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the status of country status-agreements;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> through its Secretariat, has taken meaningful steps to prevent national authorities in recipient countries from imposing taxes or tariffs on goods or services provided by the Fund;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is maintaining its status as a financing institution focused on programs directly related to HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<chapeau> is maintaining and making progress on—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> sustaining its multisectoral approach, through country coordinating mechanisms; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the implementation of grants, as reflected in the proportion of resources allocated to different sectors, including governments, civil society, and faith- and community-based organizations; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> has established procedures providing access by the Office of Inspector General of the Department of State and Broadcasting Board of Governors, as cognizant Inspector General, and the Inspector General of the Health and Human Services and the Inspector General of the United States Agency for International Development, to Global Fund financial data, and other information relevant to United States contributions (as determined by the Inspector General in consultation with the Global AIDS Coordinator).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Summaries of Board decisions and United States positions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Following each meeting of the Board of the Global Fund, the Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally shall report on the public website of the Coordinator a summary of Board decisions and how the United States Government voted and its positions on such decisions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency technical review panel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally, established in <ref>section 2651a(f)(1) of this title</ref>, shall establish in the executive branch an interagency technical review panel.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The interagency technical review panel shall serve as a “shadow” panel to the Global Fund by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> periodically reviewing all proposals received by the Global Fund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing guidance to the United States persons who are representatives on the panels, committees, and boards of the Global Fund, on the technical efficacy, suitability, and appropriateness of the proposals, and ensuring that such persons are fully informed of technical inadequacies or other aspects of the proposals that are inconsistent with the purposes of this chapter or any other Act relating to the provision of foreign assistance in the area of AIDS.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The interagency technical review panel shall consist of qualified medical and development experts who are officers or employees of the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of State, and the United States Agency for International Development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Coordinator referred to in paragraph (1) shall chair the interagency technical review panel.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring by Comptroller General</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Comptroller General shall monitor and evaluate projects funded by the Global Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Comptroller General shall on a biennial basis shall prepare and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the results of the monitoring and evaluation described in paragraph (1) for the preceding 2-year period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of information to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally shall make available to the Congress the following documents within 30 days of a request by the Congress for such documents:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> All financial and accounting statements for the Global Fund and the Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally Fund, including administrative and grantee statements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Reports provided to the Global Fund and the Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally Fund by organizations contracted to audit recipients of funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Project proposals submitted by applicants for funding from the Global Fund and the Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally Fund, but which were not funded.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Progress reports submitted to the Global Fund and the Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally Fund by grantees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of the Congress regarding encouragement of private contributions to the Global Fund</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the President should—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> conduct an outreach campaign that is designed to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> inform the public of the existence of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Global Fund; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any entity that will accept private contributions intended for use by the Global Fund; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> encourage private contributions to the Global Fund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> encourage private contributions intended for use by the Global Fund by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establishing and operating an Internet website, and publishing information about the website; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> making public service announcements on radio and television.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 724</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title V, § 595(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2936</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–56, § 4</ref>, <date date="2013-12-02">Dec. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 649</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–305, § 3</ref>, <date date="2018-12-11">Dec. 11, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–47, div. F, title VII, § 7072(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-03-23">Mar. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7623.</num>
<heading> Combating HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria by strengthening health policies and health systems of partner countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be the policy of the United States Government—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to invest appropriate resources authorized under this chapter—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to carry out activities to strengthen HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria health policies and health systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide workforce training and capacity-building consistent with the goals and objectives of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to support the development of a sound policy environment in partner countries to increase the ability of such countries—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to maximize utilization of health care resources from donor countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to increase national investments in health and education and maximize the effectiveness of such investments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to improve national HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria strategies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to deliver evidence-based services in an effective and efficient manner; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to reduce barriers that prevent recipients of services from achieving maximum benefit from such services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to improve public finance management systems</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Consistent with the authority under <ref>section 2151aa of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the Treasury, acting through the head of the Office of Technical Assistance, is authorized to provide assistance for advisors and partner country finance, health, and other relevant ministries to improve the effectiveness of public finance management systems in partner countries to enable such countries to receive funding to carry out programs to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria and to manage such programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref> for HIV/AIDS assistance, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Treasury such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2013 to carry out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Global AIDS Coordinator, in collaboration with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), shall develop and implement a plan to combat HIV/AIDS by strengthening health policies and health systems of partner countries as part of USAID’s “Health Systems 2020” project. Recognizing that human and institutional capacity form the core of any health care system that can sustain the fight against HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria, the plan shall include a strategy to encourage postsecondary educational institutions in partner countries, particularly in Africa, in collaboration with United States postsecondary educational institutions, including historically black colleges and universities, to develop such human and institutional capacity and in the process further build their capacity to sustain the fight against these diseases.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title II, § 204</ref> as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2942</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7624.</num>
<heading> Facilitating vaccine development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical assistance for developing countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, utilizing public-private partners, as appropriate, and working in coordination with other international development agencies, is authorized to strengthen the capacity of developing countries’ governmental institutions to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> collect evidence for informed decision-making and introduction of new vaccines, including potential HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria vaccines, if such vaccines are determined to be safe and effective;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> review protocols for clinical trials and impact studies and improve the implementation of clinical trials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensure adequate supply chain and delivery systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advanced market commitments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The purpose of this subsection is to improve global health by requiring the United States to participate in negotiations for advance market commitments for the development of future vaccines, including potential vaccines for HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Negotiation requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of the Treasury shall enter into negotiations with the appropriate officials of the International Bank of Reconstruction and Development (World Bank) and the GAVI Alliance, the member nations of such entities, and other interested parties to establish advanced market commitments to purchase vaccines to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria, and other related infectious diseases.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In negotiating the United States participation in programs for advanced market commitments, the Secretary of the Treasury shall take into account whether programs for advance market commitments include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> legally binding contracts for product purchase that include a fair market price for up to a maximum number of treatments, creating a strong market incentive;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> clearly defined and transparent rules of program participation for qualified developers and suppliers of the product;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> clearly defined requirements for eligible vaccines to ensure that they are safe and effective and can be delivered in developing country contexts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> dispute settlement mechanisms; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> sufficient flexibility to enable the contracts to be adjusted in accord with new information related to projected market size and other factors while still maintaining the purchase commitment at a fair price.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the United States negotiations to participate in programs for the advanced market commitments under this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the President shall produce a comprehensive report, written by a study group of qualified professionals from relevant Federal agencies and initiatives, nongovernmental organizations, and industry representatives, that sets forth a coordinated strategy to accelerate development of vaccines for infectious diseases, such as HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis, which includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> initiatives to create economic incentives for the research, development, and manufacturing of vaccines for HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria, and other infectious diseases;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an expansion of public-private partnerships and the leveraging of resources from other countries and the private sector; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> efforts to maximize United States capabilities to support clinical trials of vaccines in developing countries and to address the challenges of delivering vaccines in developing countries to minimize delays in access once vaccines are available.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>BILATERAL EFFORTS</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">General Assistance and Programs</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7631.</num>
<heading> Assistance to combat HIV/AIDS</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to funds available under section 104(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151b(c)</ref>) for such purpose or under any other provision of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], there are authorized to be appropriated to the President, from amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref>, such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2013 to carry out section 104A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as added by subsection (a) [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151b–2</ref>].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amount authorized to be appropriated by paragraph (1) for the fiscal years 2009 through 2013, such sums as may be necessary are authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 104A(d)(4) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (as added by subsection (a)) [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151b–2(d)(4)</ref>], relating to the procurement and distribution of HIV/AIDS pharmaceuticals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Food and nutritional support</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">As indicated in the report produced by the Institute of Medicine, entitled “PEPFAR Implementation: Progress and Promise”, inadequate caloric intake has been clearly identified as a principal reason for failure of clinical response to antiretroviral therapy. In recognition of the impact of malnutrition as a clinical health issue for many persons living with HIV/AIDS that is often associated with health and economic impacts on these individuals and their families, the Global AIDS Coordinator and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> follow World Health Organization guidelines for HIV/AIDS food and nutrition services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> integrate nutrition programs with HIV/AIDS activities through effective linkages among the health, agricultural, and livelihood sectors and establish additional services in circumstances in which referrals are inadequate or impossible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> provide, as a component of care and treatment programs for persons with HIV/AIDS, food and nutritional support to individuals infected with, and affected by, HIV/AIDS who meet established criteria for nutritional support (including clinically malnourished children and adults, and pregnant and lactating women in programs in need of supplemental support), including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> anthropometric and dietary assessment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> counseling; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> therapeutic and supplementary feeding;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide food and nutritional support for children affected by HIV/AIDS and to communities and households caring for children affected by HIV/AIDS; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> in communities where HIV/AIDS and food insecurity are highly prevalent, support programs to address these often intersecting health problems through community-based assistance programs, with an emphasis on sustainable approaches.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2013 to carry out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An organization, including a faith-based organization, that is otherwise eligible to receive assistance under section 104A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151b–2</ref>], under this chapter, or under any amendment made by this chapter or by the Tom Lantos and Henry J. Hyde United States Global Leadership Against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria Reauthorization Act of 2008, for HIV/AIDS prevention, treatment, or care—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> shall not be required, as a condition of receiving such assistance—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to endorse or utilize a multisectoral or comprehensive approach to combating HIV/AIDS; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to endorse, utilize, make a referral to, become integrated with, or otherwise participate in any program or activity to which the organization has a religious or moral objection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall not be discriminated against in the solicitation or issuance of grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under such provisions of law for refusing to meet any requirement described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No funds made available to carry out this chapter, or any amendment made by this chapter, may be used to promote or advocate the legalization or practice of prostitution or sex trafficking. Nothing in the preceding sentence shall be construed to preclude the provision to individuals of palliative care, treatment, or post-exposure pharmaceutical prophylaxis, and necessary pharmaceuticals and commodities, including test kits, condoms, and, when proven effective, microbicides.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No funds made available to carry out this chapter, or any amendment made by this chapter, may be used to provide assistance to any group or organization that does not have a policy explicitly opposing prostitution and sex trafficking, except that this subsection shall not apply to the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria, the World Health Organization, the International AIDS Vaccine Initiative or to any United Nations agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress relating to food assistance for individuals living with HIV/AIDS</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The United States provides more than 60 percent of all food assistance worldwide.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> According to the United Nations World Food Program and other United Nations agencies, food insecurity of individuals infected or living with HIV/AIDS is a major problem in countries with large populations of such individuals, particularly in African countries.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Although the United States is willing to provide food assistance to these countries in need, a few of the countries object to part or all of the assistance because of fears of benign genetic modifications to the foods.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Healthy and nutritious foods for individuals infected or living with HIV/AIDS are an important complement to HIV/AIDS medicines for such individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Individuals infected with HIV have higher nutritional requirements than individuals who are not infected with HIV, particularly with respect to the need for protein. Also, there is evidence to suggest that the full benefit of therapy to treat HIV/AIDS may not be achieved in individuals who are malnourished, particularly in pregnant and lactating women.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It is therefore the sense of Congress that United States food assistance should be accepted by countries with large populations of individuals infected or living with HIV/AIDS, particularly African countries, in order to help feed such individuals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title V, § 595(3)</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title III, § 301(f)</ref>–(h), <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2956</ref>, 2957.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7631a.</num>
<heading> United States Agency for International Development</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in coordination with the Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally, may facilitate availability and accessibility of microbicides, provided that such pharmaceuticals are approved, tentatively approved, or otherwise authorized for use by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Food and Drug Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a stringent regulatory agency acceptable to the Secretary of Health and Human Services; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a quality assurance mechanism acceptable to the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref> for HIV/AIDS assistance, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2013 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title II, § 203(e)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7632.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations to combat tuberculosis</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to funds available under section 104(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151b(c)</ref>) for such purpose or under any other provision of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], there are authorized to be appropriated to the President, from amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref>, a total of $4,000,000,000 for the 5-year period beginning on <date date="2008-10-01">October 1, 2008</date>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002387">1</ref> to carry out section 104B of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as added by subsection (a) [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151b–3</ref>].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of prior year funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unobligated balances of funds made available for fiscal year 2001, 2002, or 2003 under section 104(c)(7) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151b(c)(7)</ref> (as in effect immediately before <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>) shall be transferred to, merged with, and made available for the same purposes as funds made available for fiscal years 2009 through 2013.<sup>1</sup> under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 736</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title III, § 302(f)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2959</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7633.</num>
<heading> Assistance to combat malaria</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to funds available under section 104(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151b(c)</ref>) for such purpose or under any other provision of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], there are authorized to be appropriated to the President, from amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref>, $5,000,000,000 during the 5-year period beginning on <date date="2008-10-01">October 1, 2008</date> to carry out section 104C of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as added by subsection (a) [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151b–4</ref>], including for the development of anti-malarial pharmaceuticals by the Medicines for Malaria Venture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of prior year funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unobligated balances of funds made available for fiscal year 2001, 2002, or 2003 under section 104(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151b(c)</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002388">1</ref> (as in effect immediately before <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>) and made available for the control of malaria shall be transferred to, merged with, and made available for the same purposes as funds made available for fiscal years 2009 through 2013 under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Providing assistance for the prevention, control, treatment, and the ultimate eradication of malaria is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a major objective of the foreign assistance program of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> 1 component of a comprehensive United States global health strategy to reduce disease burdens and strengthen communities around the world.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of a comprehensive 5-Year strategy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall establish a comprehensive, 5-year strategy to combat global malaria that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> strengthens the capacity of the United States to be an effective leader of international efforts to reduce <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002389">2</ref> malaria burden;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> maintains sufficient flexibility and remains responsive to the ever-changing nature of the global malaria challenge;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> includes specific objectives and multisectoral approaches and strategies to reduce the prevalence, mortality, incidence, and spread of malaria;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> describes how this strategy would contribute to the United States’ overall global health and development goals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> clearly explains how outlined activities will interact with other United States Government global health activities, including the 5-year global AIDS strategy required under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> expands public-private partnerships and leverage of resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> coordinates among relevant Federal agencies to maximize human and financial resources and to reduce duplication among these agencies, foreign governments, and international organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> coordinates with other international entities, including the Global Fund;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> maximizes United States capabilities in the areas of technical assistance and training and research, including vaccine research; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> establishes priorities and selection criteria for the distribution of resources based on factors such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the size and demographics of the population with malaria;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the needs of that population;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the country’s existing infrastructure; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the ability to closely coordinate United States Government efforts with national malaria control plans of partner countries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 736</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title III, § 303(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2960</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7634.</num>
<heading> Malaria response Coordinator</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the United States Agency for International Development a Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat Malaria Globally (referred to in this section as the “Malaria Coordinator”), who shall be appointed by the President.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Malaria Coordinator, acting through nongovernmental organizations (including faith-based and community-based organizations), partner country finance, health, and other relevant ministries, and relevant executive branch agencies as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out this section, is authorized to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> operate internationally to carry out prevention, care, treatment, support, capacity development, and other activities to reduce the prevalence, mortality, and incidence of malaria;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide grants to, and enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, nongovernmental organizations (including faith-based organizations) to carry out this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> transfer and allocate executive branch agency funds that have been appropriated for the purposes described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Malaria Coordinator has primary responsibility for the oversight and coordination of all resources and international activities of the United States Government relating to efforts to combat malaria.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Malaria Coordinator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> facilitate program and policy coordination of antimalarial efforts among relevant executive branch agencies and nongovernmental organizations by auditing, monitoring, and evaluating such programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that each relevant executive branch agency undertakes antimalarial programs primarily in those areas in which the agency has the greatest expertise, technical capability, and potential for success;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> coordinate relevant executive branch agency activities in the field of malaria prevention and treatment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> coordinate planning, implementation, and evaluation with the Global AIDS Coordinator in countries in which both programs have a significant presence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> coordinate with national governments, international agencies, civil society, and the private sector; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> establish due diligence criteria for all recipients of funds appropriated by the Federal Government for malaria assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance for the World Health Organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the President may provide financial assistance to the Roll Back Malaria Partnership of the World Health Organization to improve the capacity of countries with high rates of malaria and other affected countries to implement comprehensive malaria control programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of assistance efforts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out this section and in accordance with <ref>section 2151b–4 of this title</ref>, the Malaria Coordinator shall coordinate the provision of assistance by working with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> relevant executive branch agencies, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Department of State (including the Office of the Global AIDS Coordinator);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Department of Health and Human Services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Office of the United States Trade Representative;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> relevant multilateral institutions, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the World Health Organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the United Nations Children’s Fund;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the United Nations Development Programme;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Global Fund;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the World Bank; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Roll Back Malaria Partnership;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> program delivery and efforts to lift barriers that would impede effective and comprehensive malaria control programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> partner or recipient country governments and national entities including universities and civil society organizations (including faith- and community-based organizations).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out this section, the Malaria Coordinator, in accordance with <ref>section 2151b–4 of this title</ref>, shall ensure that operations and implementation research conducted under this chapter will closely complement the clinical and program research being undertaken by the National Institutes of Health. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention should advise the Malaria Coordinator on priorities for operations and implementation research and should be a key implementer of this research.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To ensure that adequate malaria controls are established and implemented, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention should advise the Malaria Coordinator on monitoring, surveillance, and evaluation activities and be a key implementer of such activities under this chapter. Such activities shall complement, rather than duplicate, the work of the World Health Organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes United States assistance for the prevention, treatment, control, and elimination of malaria.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report required under paragraph (1) shall describe—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the countries and activities to which malaria resources have been allocated;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of people reached through malaria assistance programs, including data on children and pregnant women;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> research efforts to develop new tools to combat malaria, including drugs and vaccines;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the collaboration and coordination of United States antimalarial efforts with the World Health Organization, the Global Fund, the World Bank, other donor governments, major private efforts, and relevant executive agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the coordination of United States antimalarial efforts with the national malarial strategies of other donor or partner governments and major private initiatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the estimated impact of United States assistance on childhood mortality and morbidity from malaria;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the coordination of antimalarial efforts with broader health and development programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the constraints on implementation of programs posed by health workforce shortages or capacities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the number of personnel trained as health workers and the training levels achieved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 737</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2961</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7635.</num>
<heading> Report on treatment activities by relevant executive branch agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 15 months after <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, the President shall submit to appropriate congressional committees a report on the programs and activities of the relevant executive branch agencies that are directed to the treatment of individuals in foreign countries infected with HIV or living with AIDS.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a description of the activities of relevant executive branch agencies with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the treatment of opportunistic infections;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the use of antiretrovirals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the status of research into successful treatment protocols for individuals in the developing world;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> technical assistance and training of local health care workers (in countries affected by the pandemic) to administer antiretrovirals, manage side effects, and monitor patients’ viral loads and immune status;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the status of strategies to promote sustainability of HIV/AIDS pharmaceuticals (including antiretrovirals) and the effects of drug resistance on HIV/AIDS patients; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the status of appropriate law enforcement officials working to ensure that HIV/AIDS pharmaceutical treatment is not diminished through illegal counterfeiting and black market sales of such pharmaceuticals;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> information on existing pilot projects, including a discussion of why a given population was selected, the number of people treated, the cost of treatment, the mechanisms established to ensure that treatment is being administered effectively and safely, and plans for scaling up pilot projects (including projected timelines and required resources); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an explanation of how those activities relate to efforts to prevent the transmission of the HIV infection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 739</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7636.</num>
<heading> Study on illegal diversions of prescription drugs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with other agencies, shall submit a report to the Congress that includes the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A thorough accounting of evidence indicating illegal diversion into the United States of prescription drugs donated or sold for humanitarian efforts, and an estimate of the extent of such diversion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Recommendations to increase the administrative and enforcement powers of the United States to identify, monitor, and prevent the illegal diversion into the United States of prescription drugs donated or sold for humanitarian efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Recommendations and guidelines to advise and provide technical assistance to developing countries on how to implement a program that minimizes diversion into the United States of prescription drugs donated or sold for humanitarian efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 740</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Assistance for Women, Children, and Families</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7651.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Approximately 2,000 children around the world are infected each day with HIV through mother-to-child transmission. Transmission can occur during pregnancy, labor, and delivery or through breast feeding. Over 90 percent of these cases are in developing nations with little or no access to public health facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Mother-to-child transmission is largely preventable with the proper application of pharmaceuticals, therapies, and other public health interventions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Certain antiretroviral drugs reduce mother-to-child transmission by nearly 50 percent. Universal availability of this drug could prevent up to 400,000 infections per year and dramatically reduce the number of AIDS-related deaths.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> At the United Nations Special Session on HIV/AIDS in June 2001, the United States committed to the specific goals with respect to the prevention of mother-to-child transmission, including the goals of reducing the proportion of infants infected with HIV by 20 percent by the year 2005 and by 50 percent by the year 2010, as specified in the Declaration of Commitment on HIV/AIDS adopted by the United Nations General Assembly at the Special Session.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Several United States Government agencies including the United States Agency for International Development and the Centers for Disease Control are already supporting programs to prevent mother-to-child transmission in resource-poor nations and have the capacity to expand these programs rapidly by working closely with foreign governments and nongovernmental organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Efforts to prevent mother-to-child transmission can provide the basis for a broader response that includes care and treatment of mothers, fathers, and other family members who are infected with HIV or living with AIDS.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> HIV/AIDS has devastated the lives of countless children and families across the globe. Since the epidemic began, an estimated 13,200,000 children under the age of 15 have been orphaned by AIDS, that is they have lost their mother or both parents to the disease. The Joint United Nations Program on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS) estimates that this number will double by the year 2010.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> HIV/AIDS also targets young people between the ages of 15 to 24, particularly young women, many of whom carry the burden of caring for family members living with HIV/AIDS. An estimated 10,300,000 young people are now living with HIV/AIDS. One-half of all new infections are occurring among this age group.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 740</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7652.</num>
<heading> Policy and requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Government’s response to the global HIV/AIDS pandemic should place high priority on the prevention of mother-to-child transmission, the care and treatment of family members and caregivers, and the care of children orphaned by AIDS. To the maximum extent possible, the United States Government should seek to leverage its funds by seeking matching contributions from the private sector, other national governments, and international organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The 5-year United States Government strategy required by <ref>section 7611 of this title</ref> shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish a target for the prevention and treatment of mother-to-child transmission of HIV that, by 2013, will reach at least 80 percent of pregnant women in those countries most affected by HIV/AIDS in which the United States has HIV/AIDS programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish a target that, by 2013, the proportion of children receiving care and treatment under this chapter is proportionate to their numbers within the population of HIV infected individuals in each country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> integrate care and treatment with prevention of mother-to-child transmission of HIV programs to improve outcomes for HIV-affected women and families as soon as is feasible and support strategies that promote successful follow-up and continuity of care of mother and child;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> expand programs designed to care for children orphaned by, affected by, or vulnerable to HIV/AIDS;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> ensure that women in prevention of mother-to-child transmission of HIV programs are provided with, or referred to, appropriate maternal and child services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> develop a timeline for expanding access to more effective regimes to prevent mother-to-child transmission of HIV, consistent with the national policies of countries in which programs are administered under this chapter and the goal of achieving universal use of such regimes as soon as possible.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prevention of Mother-to-Child Transmission Expert Panel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Global AIDS Coordinator shall establish a panel of experts to be known as the Prevention of Mother-to-Child Transmission Panel (referred to in this subsection as the “Panel”) to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide an objective review of activities to prevent mother-to-child transmission of HIV; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide recommendations to the Global AIDS Coordinator and to the appropriate congressional committees for scale-up of mother-to-child transmission prevention services under this chapter in order to achieve the target established in subsection (b)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Panel shall be convened and chaired by the Global AIDS Coordinator, who shall serve as a nonvoting member. The Panel shall consist of not more than 15 members (excluding the Global AIDS Coordinator), to be appointed by the Global AIDS Coordinator not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 2 members from the Department of Health and Human Services with expertise relating to the prevention of mother-to-child transmission activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 2 members from the United States Agency for International Development with expertise relating to the prevention of mother-to-child transmission activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 2 representatives from among health ministers of national governments of foreign countries in which programs under this chapter are administered;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> 3 members representing organizations implementing prevention of mother-to-child transmission activities under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> 2 health care researchers with expertise relating to global HIV/AIDS activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> representatives from among patient advocate groups, health care professionals, persons living with HIV/AIDS, and non-governmental organizations with expertise relating to the prevention of mother-to-child transmission activities, giving priority to individuals in foreign countries in which programs under this chapter are administered.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of Panel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Panel shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assess the effectiveness of current activities in reaching the target described in subsection (b)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> review scientific evidence related to the provision of mother-to-child transmission prevention services, including programmatic data and data from clinical trials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> review and assess ways in which the Office of the United States Global AIDS Coordinator collaborates with international and multilateral entities on efforts to prevent mother-to-child transmission of HIV in affected countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> identify barriers and challenges to increasing access to mother-to-child transmission prevention services and evaluate potential mechanisms to alleviate those barriers and challenges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> identify the extent to which stigma has hindered pregnant women from obtaining HIV counseling and testing or returning for results, and provide recommendations to address such stigma and its effects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> identify opportunities to improve linkages between mother-to-child transmission prevention services and care and treatment programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> recommend specific activities to facilitate reaching the target described in subsection (b)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Panel is first convened, the Panel shall submit a report containing a detailed statement of the recommendations, findings, and conclusions of the Panel to the appropriate congressional committees.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall be made available to the public.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration by Coordinator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Coordinator shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> consider any recommendations contained in the report submitted under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> include in the annual report required under <ref>section 2151b–2(f) of this title</ref> a description of the activities conducted in response to the recommendations made by the Panel and an explanation of any recommendations not implemented at the time of the report.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Panel such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2011 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Panel shall terminate on the date that is 60 days after the date on which the Panel submits the report to the appropriate congressional committees under paragraph (4).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title III</ref>, §§ 307, 309, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2963</ref>, 2964.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7653.</num>
<heading> Annual reports on prevention of mother-to-child transmission of the HIV infection</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, and annually thereafter for a period of 10 years, the President shall submit to appropriate congressional committees a report on the activities of relevant executive branch agencies during the reporting period to assist in the prevention of mother-to-child transmission of the HIV infection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a statement of whether or not all relevant executive branch agencies have met the goal described in <ref>section 7652(b)(1) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a description of efforts made by the relevant executive branch agencies to expand those activities, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information on the number of sites supported for the prevention of mother-to-child transmission of the HIV infection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the specific activities supported;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number of women tested and counseled; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the number of women receiving preventative drug therapies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting period defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “reporting period” means, in the case of the initial report, the period since <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, and, in the case of any subsequent report, the period since the date of submission of the most recent report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7654.</num>
<heading> Pilot program of assistance for children and families affected by HIV/AIDS</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, acting through the United States Agency for International Development, should establish a program of assistance that would demonstrate the feasibility of the provision of care and treatment to orphans and other children and young people affected by HIV/AIDS in foreign countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The program should—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> build upon and be integrated into programs administered as of <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, by the relevant executive branch agencies for children affected by HIV/AIDS;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> work in conjunction with indigenous community-based programs and activities, particularly those that offer proven services for children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> reduce the stigma of HIV/AIDS to encourage vulnerable children infected with HIV or living with AIDS and their family members and caregivers to avail themselves of voluntary counseling and testing, and related programs, including treatments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ensure the importance of inheritance rights of women, particularly women in African countries, due to the exponential growth in the number of young widows, orphaned girls, and grandmothers becoming heads of households as a result of the HIV/AIDS pandemic;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide, in conjunction with other relevant executive branch agencies, the range of services for the care and treatment, including the provision of antiretrovirals and other necessary pharmaceuticals, of children, parents, and caregivers infected with HIV or living with AIDS;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> provide nutritional support and food security, and the improvement of overall family health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> work with parents, caregivers, and community-based organizations to provide children with educational opportunities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> provide appropriate counseling and legal assistance for the appointment of guardians and the handling of other issues relating to the protection of children.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 18 months after <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, the President should submit a report on the implementation of this section to the appropriate congressional committees. Such report should include a description of activities undertaken to carry out subsection (b)(4).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to amounts otherwise available for such purpose, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President, from amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref>, such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2004 through 2008 to carry out the program. A significant percentage of the amount appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under the preceding sentence for a fiscal year should be made available to carry out subsection (b)(4).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 742</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7655.</num>
<heading> Pilot program on family survival partnerships</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to authorize the President to establish a program, through a public-private partnership, for the provision of medical care and support services to HIV positive parents and their children identified through existing programs to prevent mother-to-child transmission of HIV in countries with or at risk for severe HIV epidemic with particular attention to resource constrained countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President is authorized to establish a program for the award of grants to eligible administrative organizations to enable such organizations to award subgrants to eligible entities to expand activities to prevent the mother-to-child transmission of HIV by providing medical care and support services to HIV infected parents and their children.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Amounts provided under a grant awarded under paragraph (1) shall be used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to award subgrants to eligible entities to enable such entities to carry out activities described in subsection (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for administrative support and subgrant management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for administrative data collection and reporting concerning grant activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for the monitoring and evaluation of grant activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> for training and technical assistance for subgrantees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> to promote sustainability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subgrants</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An organization awarded a grant under subsection (b) shall use amounts received under the grant to award subgrants to eligible entities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a subgrant under paragraph (1), an entity shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be a local health organization, an international organization, or a partnership of such organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> demonstrate to the awarding organization that such entity—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is currently administering a proven intervention to prevent mother-to-child transmission of HIV in countries with or at risk for severe HIV epidemic with particular attention to resource constrained countries, as determined by the President;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has demonstrated support for the proposed program from relevant government entities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is able to provide HIV care, including antiretroviral treatment when medically indicated, to HIV positive women, men, and children with the support of the project funding.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local health and international organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (2)(A)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “local health organization” means a public sector health system, nongovernmental organization, institution of higher education, community-based organization, or nonprofit health system that provides directly, or has a clear link with a provider for the indirect provision of, primary health care services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the term “international organization” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a nonprofit international entity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an international charitable institution;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a private voluntary international entity; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a multilateral institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In awarding subgrants under this subsection, the organization shall give priority to eligible applicants that are currently administering a program of proven intervention to HIV positive individuals to prevent mother-to-child transmission in countries with or at risk for severe HIV epidemic with particular attention to resource constrained countries, and who are currently administering a program to HIV positive women, men, and children to provide life-long care in family-centered care programs using non-Federal funds.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of subgrant recipients</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In awarding subgrants under this subsection, the organization should—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> consider applicants from a range of health care settings, program approaches, and geographic locations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if appropriate, award not less than 1 grant to an applicant to fund a national system of health care delivery to HIV positive families.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of subgrant funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An eligible entity awarded a subgrant under this subsection shall use subgrant funds to expand activities to prevent mother-to-child transmission of HIV by providing medical treatment and care and support services to parents and their children, which may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing treatment and therapy, when medically indicated, to HIV-infected women, their children, and families;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the hiring and training of local personnel, including physicians, nurses, other health care providers, counselors, social workers, outreach personnel, laboratory technicians, data managers, and administrative support personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> paying laboratory costs, including costs related to necessary equipment and diagnostic testing and monitoring (including rapid testing), complete blood counts, standard chemistries, and liver function testing for infants, children, and parents, and costs related to the purchase of necessary laboratory equipment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> purchasing pharmaceuticals for HIV-related conditions, including antiretroviral therapies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> funding support services, including adherence and psychosocial support services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> operational support activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> conducting community outreach and capacity building activities, including activities to raise the awareness of individuals of the program carried out by the subgrantee, other communications activities in support of the program, local advisory board functions, and transportation necessary to ensure program participation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall require that each organization awarded a grant under subsection (b)(1) to submit an annual report that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the progress of programs funded under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the benchmarks of success of programs funded under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> recommendations of how best to proceed with the programs funded under this section upon the expiration of funding under subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the President, from amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref>, such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2004 through 2008 to carry out the program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on administrative expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An organization shall ensure that not more than 7 percent of the amount of a grant received under this section by the organization is used for administrative expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title III, § 315</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 743</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7671.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the President to carry out this chapter and the amendments made by this chapter $48,000,000,000 for the 5-year period beginning on <date date="2008-10-01">October 1, 2008</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in subsection (a) are authorized to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of authorizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Authorizations of appropriations under subsection (a) shall remain available until the appropriations are made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7672.</num>
<heading> Sense of Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Increase in HIV/AIDS antiretroviral treatment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is a sense of the Congress that an urgent priority of United States assistance programs to fight HIV/AIDS should be the rapid increase in distribution of antiretroviral treatment so that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by the end of fiscal year 2004, at least 500,000 individuals with HIV/AIDS are receiving antiretroviral treatment through United States assistance programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by the end of fiscal year 2005, at least 1,000,000 such individuals are receiving such treatment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by the end of fiscal year 2006, at least 2,000,000 such individuals are receiving such treatment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective distribution of HIV/AIDS funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that, of the amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under <ref>section 7671 of this title</ref> for HIV/AIDS assistance, 10 percent should be used for orphans and vulnerable children.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7673.</num>
<heading> Allocation of funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Balanced funding requirement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Global AIDS Coordinator shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> provide balanced funding for prevention activities for sexual transmission of HIV/AIDS; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that activities promoting abstinence, delay of sexual debut, monogamy, fidelity, and partner reduction are implemented and funded in a meaningful and equitable way in the strategy for each host country based on objective epidemiological evidence as to the source of infections and in consultation with the government of each host county <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002390">1</ref> involved in HIV/AIDS prevention activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prevention strategy</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Global AIDS Coordinator shall establish an HIV sexual transmission prevention strategy governing the expenditure of funds authorized under this chapter to prevent the sexual transmission of HIV in any host country with a generalized epidemic.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In each host country described in subparagraph (A), if the strategy established under subparagraph (A) provides less than 50 percent of the funds described in subparagraph (A) for activities promoting abstinence, delay of sexual debut, monogamy, fidelity, and partner reduction, the Global AIDS Coordinator shall, not later than 30 days after the issuance of this strategy, report to the appropriate congressional committees on the justification for this decision.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Programs and activities that implement or purchase new prevention technologies or modalities, such as medical male circumcision, public education about risks to acquire HIV infection from blood exposures, promoting universal precautions, investigating suspected nosocomial infections, pre-exposure pharmaceutical prophylaxis to prevent transmission of HIV, or microbicides and programs and activities that provide counseling and testing for HIV or prevent mother-to-child prevention of HIV, shall not be included in determining compliance with paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, and annually thereafter as part of the annual report required under <ref>section 2151b–2(e) of this title</ref>, the President shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> submit a report on the implementation of paragraph (2) for the most recently concluded fiscal year to the appropriate congressional committees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> make the report described in subparagraph (A) available to the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Orphans and vulnerable children</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For fiscal years 2009 through 2024 and fiscal year 2025 through March 25 of such fiscal year, not less than 10 percent of the amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out the provisions of <ref>section 2151b–2 of this title</ref> for HIV/AIDS assistance for each such fiscal year shall be expended for assistance for orphans and other children affected by, or vulnerable to, HIV/AIDS, of which such amount at least 50 percent shall be provided through non-profit, nongovernmental organizations, including faith-based organizations, that implement programs on the community level.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding allocation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2024 and for fiscal year 2025 through March 25 of such fiscal year, more than half of the amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out the provisions of <ref>section 2151b–2 of this title</ref> shall be expended for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> antiretroviral treatment for HIV/AIDS;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> clinical monitoring of HIV-seropositive people not in need of antiretroviral treatment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> care for associated opportunistic infections;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> nutrition and food support for people living with HIV/AIDS; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> other essential HIV/AIDS-related medical care for people living with HIV/AIDS.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment, prevention, and care goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2013—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the treatment goal under <ref>section 7672(a)(3) of this title</ref> shall be increased above 2,000,000 by at least the percentage increase in the amount appropriated for bilateral global HIV/AIDS assistance for such fiscal year compared with fiscal year 2008;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any increase in the treatment goal under <ref>section 7672(a)(3) of this title</ref> above the percentage increase in the amount appropriated for bilateral global HIV/AIDS assistance for such fiscal year compared with fiscal year 2008 shall be based on long-term requirements, epidemiological evidence, the share of treatment needs being met by partner governments and other sources of treatment funding, and other appropriate factors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the treatment goal under <ref>section 7672(a)(3) of this title</ref> shall be increased above the number calculated under paragraph (1) by the same percentage that the average United States Government cost per patient of providing treatment in countries receiving bilateral HIV/AIDS assistance has decreased compared with fiscal year 2008; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the prevention and care goals established in clauses (i) and (iv) of <ref>section 2151b–2(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref> shall be increased consistent with epidemiological evidence and available resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 746</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–293, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2966</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–56, § 6</ref>, <date date="2013-12-02">Dec. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 654</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–305, § 4</ref>, <date date="2018-12-11">Dec. 11, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 4403</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–47, div. F, title VII, § 7072(c)</ref>, <date date="2024-03-23">Mar. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7674.</num>
<heading> Assistance from the United States private sector to prevent and reduce HIV/AIDS in sub-Saharan Africa</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that United States businesses should be encouraged to provide assistance to sub-Saharan African countries to prevent and reduce the incidence of HIV/AIDS in sub-Saharan Africa. In providing such assistance, United States businesses should be encouraged to consider the establishment of an HIV/AIDS Response Fund in order to provide for coordination among such businesses in the collection and distribution of the assistance to sub-Saharan African countries.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 746</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>INTERNATIONAL FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7681.</num>
<heading> Report on expansion of debt relief to non-HIPC countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to Congress a report on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the options and costs associated with the expansion of debt relief provided by the Enhanced HIPC Initiative to include poor countries that were not eligible for inclusion in the Enhanced HIPC Initiative;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> options for burden-sharing among donor countries and multilateral institutions of costs associated with the expansion of debt relief; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> options, in addition to debt relief, to ensure debt sustainability in poor countries, particularly in cases when the poor country has suffered an external economic shock or a natural disaster.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific options to be considered</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Among the options for the expansion of debt relief provided by the Enhanced HIPC Initiative, consideration should be given to making eligible for that relief poor countries for which outstanding public and publicly guaranteed debt requires annual payments in excess of 10 percent or, in the case of a country suffering a public health crisis (as defined in <ref>section 262p–8(e) of this title</ref>), not more than 5 percent, of the amount of the annual current revenues received by the country from internal resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enhanced HIPC Initiative defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “Enhanced HIPC Initiative” means the multilateral debt initiative for heavily indebted poor countries presented in the Report of G–7 Finance Ministers on the Cologne Debt Initiative to the Cologne Economic Summit, Cologne, June 18–20, 1999.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 749</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7682.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the President such sums as may be necessary for the fiscal year 2004 and each fiscal year thereafter to carry out <ref>section 262p–8 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) are authorized to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–25, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 749</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>