<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 47—</num>
<heading>NUCLEAR NON-PROLIFERATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3201.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares that the proliferation of nuclear explosive devices or of the direct capability to manufacture or otherwise acquire such devices poses a grave threat to the security interests of the United States and to continued international progress toward world peace and development. Recent events emphasize the urgency of this threat and the imperative need to increase the effectiveness of international safeguards and controls on peaceful nuclear activities to prevent proliferation. Accordingly, it is the policy of the United States to—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> actively pursue through international initiatives mechanisms for fuel supply assurances and the establishment of more effective international controls over the transfer and use of nuclear materials and equipment and nuclear technology for peaceful purposes in order to prevent proliferation, including the establishment of common international sanctions;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> take such actions as are required to confirm the reliability of the United States in meeting its commitments to supply nuclear reactors and fuel to nations which adhere to effective non-proliferation policies by establishing procedures to facilitate the timely processing of requests for subsequent arrangements and export licenses;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> strongly encourage nations which have not ratified the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons to do so at the earliest possible date; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> cooperate with foreign nations in identifying and adapting suitable technologies for energy production and, in particular, to identify alternative options to nuclear power in aiding such nations to meet their energy needs, consistent with the economic and material resources of those nations and environmental protection.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3202.</num>
<heading> Congressional statement of purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter to promote the policies set forth above by—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> establishing a more effective framework for international cooperation to meet the energy needs of all nations and to ensure that the worldwide development of peaceful nuclear activities and the export by any nation of nuclear materials and equipment and nuclear technology intended for use in peaceful nuclear activities do not contribute to proliferation;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> authorizing the United States to take such actions as are required to ensure that it will act reliably in meeting its commitment to supply nuclear reactors and fuel to nations which adhere to effective non-proliferation policies;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> providing incentives to the other nations of the world to join in such international cooperative efforts and to ratify the Treaty; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> ensuring effective controls by the United States over its exports of nuclear materials and equipment and of nuclear technology.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3203.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “Commission” means the Nuclear Regulatory Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “IAEA” means International Atomic Energy Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> “nuclear materials and equipment” means source material, special nuclear material, production facilities, utilization facilities, and components, items or substances determined to have significance for nuclear explosive purposes pursuant to subsection 109b <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002244">1</ref> of the 1954 Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2139(b)</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “physical security measures” means measures to reasonably ensure that source or special nuclear material will only be used for authorized purposes and to prevent theft and sabotage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “sensitive nuclear technology” means any information (including information incorporated in a production or utilization facility or important component part thereof) which is not available to the public and which is important to the design, construction, fabrication, operation or maintenance of a uranium enrichment or nuclear fuel reprocessing facility or a facility for the production of heavy water, but shall not include Restricted Data controlled pursuant to chapter 12 of the 1954 Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2161</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “1954 Act” means the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended [<ref>42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “the Treaty” means the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> All other terms used in this chapter not defined in this section shall have the meanings ascribed to them by the 1954 Act, the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 [<ref>42 U.S.C. 5801</ref> et seq.], and the Treaty.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, § 4</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1225(e)(1), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES INITIATIVES TO PROVIDE ADEQUATE NUCLEAR FUEL SUPPLY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3221.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States, as a matter of national policy, shall take such actions and institute such measures as may be necessary and feasible to assure other nations and groups of nations that may seek to utilize the benefits of atomic energy for peaceful purposes that it will provide a reliable supply of nuclear fuel to those nations and groups of nations which adhere to policies designed to prevent proliferation. Such nuclear fuel shall be provided under agreements entered into pursuant to <ref>section 2201 of title 42</ref> or as otherwise authorized by law. The United States shall ensure that it will have available the capacity on a long-term basis to enter into new fuel supply commitments consistent with its non-proliferation policies and domestic energy needs. The Commission shall, on a timely basis, authorize the export of nuclear materials and equipment when all the applicable statutory requirements are met.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 121</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3222.</num>
<heading> Uranium enrichment capacity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy is directed to initiate construction planning and design, construction, and operation activities for expansion of uranium enrichment capacity, as elsewhere provided by law. Further the Secretary as well as the Nuclear Regulatory Commission and the Secretary of State are directed to establish and implement procedures which will ensure to the maximum extent feasible, consistent with this chapter, orderly processing of subsequent arrangements and export licenses with minimum time delay.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1225(e)(2), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3223.</num>
<heading> International undertakings</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of international approaches for meeting future worldwide nuclear fuel needs; international nuclear fuel authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Consistent with <ref>section 3224 of this title</ref>, the President shall institute prompt discussions with other nations and groups of nations, including both supplier and recipient nations, to develop international approaches for meeting future worldwide nuclear fuel needs. In particular, the President is authorized and urged to seek to negotiate as soon as practicable with nations possessing nuclear fuel production facilities or source material, and such other nations and groups of nations, such as the IAEA, as may be deemed appropriate, with a view toward the timely establishment of binding international undertakings providing for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the establishment of an international nuclear fuel authority (INFA) with responsibility for providing agreed upon fuel services and allocating agreed upon quantities of fuel resources to ensure fuel supply on reasonable terms in accordance with agreements between INFA and supplier and recipient nations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a set of conditions consistent with subsection (d) under which international fuel assurances under INFA auspices will be provided to recipient nations, including conditions which will ensure that the transferred materials will not be used for nuclear explosive devices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> devising, consistent with the policy goals set forth in <ref>section 2153b of title 42</ref>, feasible and environmentally sound approaches for the siting, development, and management under effective international auspices and inspection of facilities for the provision of nuclear fuel services, including the storage of special nuclear material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the establishment of repositories for the storage of spent nuclear reactor fuel under effective international auspices and inspection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the establishment of arrangements under which nations placing spent fuel in such repositories would receive appropriate compensation for the energy content of such spent fuel if recovery of such energy content is deemed necessary or desirable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> sanctions for violation of the provisions of or for abrogation of such binding international undertakings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold">, (c) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adherence of nations to policies designed to prevent proliferation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The fuel assurances contemplated by this section shall be for the benefit of nations that adhere to policies designed to prevent proliferation. In negotiating the binding international undertakings called for in this section, the President shall, in particular, seek to ensure that the benefits of such undertakings are available to non-nuclear-weapon states only if such states accept IAEA safeguards on all their peaceful nuclear activities, do not manufacture or otherwise acquire any nuclear explosive device, do not establish any new enrichment or reprocessing facilities under their de facto or de jure control, and place any such existing facilities under effective international auspices and inspection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on progress of negotiations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report required by <ref>section 3281 of this title</ref> shall include information on the progress made in any negotiations pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional approval of non-treaty international undertakings; submission of proposals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President may not enter into any binding international undertaking negotiated pursuant to subsection (a) which is not a treaty until such time as such proposed undertaking has been submitted to the Congress and has been approved by concurrent resolution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The proposals prepared pursuant to subsection (b) shall be submitted to the Congress as part of an annual authorization Act for the Department of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 122</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3224.</num>
<heading> Reevaluation of nuclear fuel cycle</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall take immediate initiatives to invite all nuclear supplier and recipient nations to reevaluate all aspects of the nuclear fuel cycle, with emphasis on alternatives to an economy based on the separation of pure plutonium or the presence of high enriched uranium, methods to deal with spent fuel storage, and methods to improve the safeguards for existing nuclear technology. The President shall, in the first report required by <ref>section 3281 of this title</ref>, detail the progress of such international reevaluation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 123</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3224a.</num>
<heading> Studies and agreements by Secretary of Energy on multinational or international basis concerning spent fuel storage facilities and transportation systems; congressional consent; authorization of appropriations; limitations on use of funds; exceptions; special nuclear material for India</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Department of Energy is hereby authorized to undertake studies, in cooperation with other nations, on a multinational or international basis designed to determine the general feasibility of expanding capacity of existing spent fuel storage facilities; to enter into agreements, subject to the consent of the Congress (by joint or concurrent resolution or legislation hereafter enacted), with other nations or groups of nations, for providing appropriate support to increase international or multinational spent fuel storage capacity; to conduct studies on the feasibility of establishing regional storage sites; and to conduct studies on international transportation and storage systems. For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this section, there is included in subsection 101(20) of this Act authorization of appropriations in the amount of $20,000,000: <i>Provided</i>, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, that none of the funds made available to the Secretary of Energy under any other authorization or appropriation Act shall be used, directly or indirectly, for the repurchase, transportation or storage of any foreign spent nuclear fuel (including any nuclear fuel irradiated in any nuclear power reactor located outside of the United States and operated by any foreign legal entity, government or nongovernment, regardless of the legal ownership or control of the fuel or the reactor, and regardless of the origin or licensing of the fuel or the reactor, but not including fuel irradiated in a research reactor, and not including fuel irradiated in a power reactor if the President determines that (1) use of funds for repurchase, transportation or storage of such fuel is required by an emergency situation, (2) it is in the interest of the common defense and security of the United States to take such action, and (3) he notifies the Congress of the determination and action, with a detailed explanation and justification thereof, as soon as possible) unless the President formally notifies, with the report information specified herein, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives of such use of funds thirty calendar days, during such time as either House of Congress is in session, before the commitment, expenditure, or obligation of such funds: <i>And provided further</i>, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, that none of the funds appropriated pursuant to this Act or any other funds made available to the Secretary of Energy under any other authorization or appropriation Act shall be used, directly or indirectly, for the repurchase, transportation, or storage of any such foreign spent nuclear fuel for storage or other disposition, interim or permanent, in the United States, unless the use of the funds for that specific purpose has been (1) previously and expressly authorized by Congress in legislation hereafter enacted, (2) previously and expressly authorized by a concurrent resolution, or (3) the President submits a plan for such use, with the report information specified herein, thirty days during which the Congress is in continuous session, as defined in the Impoundment Control Act of 1974 [<ref>2 U.S.C. 681</ref> et seq.], prior to such use and neither House of Congress approves a resolution of disapproval of the plan prior to the expiration of the aforementioned thirty-day period. If such a resolution of disapproval has been introduced, but has not been reported by the Committee on or before the twentieth day after transmission of the Presidential message, a privileged motion shall be in order in the respective body to discharge the Committee from further consideration of the resolution and to provide for its immediate consideration, using the procedures specified for consideration of an impoundment resolution in section 1017 of the Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<ref>31 U.S.C. 1407</ref>) [<ref>2 U.S.C. 688</ref>]. Any report or plan proposed under this proviso shall include information and any supporting documentation thereof relating to policy objectives, technical description and discussion, geographic information, cost data, justification and projections, legal and regulatory considerations, environmental impact information and any related bilateral or international agreements, arrangements or understandings: <i>And provided further</i>, That nothing contained in this section shall be construed in any executive branch action, administrative proceeding, regulatory proceeding, or legal proceeding as being intended to delay, modify, or reverse the Memorandum and Order of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission of <date date="1977-06-28">June 28, 1977</date>, for the issuance of License No. XSNM–845 to the agent-applicant for the Government of India and the subsequent export thereby licensed of the special nuclear material to be used as fuel for the Tarapur Atomic Power Station or any other order of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to issue a license for the export of special nuclear material and subsequent exports thereby licensed, or any consideration by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission of a license application for the export of special nuclear material.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–238, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1978-02-25">Feb. 25, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 55</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 9(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4588</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES INITIATIVES TO STRENGTHEN THE INTERNATIONAL SAFEGUARDS SYSTEM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3241.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The United States is committed to continued strong support for the principles of the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, to a strengthened and more effective International Atomic Energy Agency and to a comprehensive safeguards system administered by the Agency to deter proliferation. Accordingly, the United States shall seek to act with other nations to—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> continue to strengthen the safeguards program of the IAEA and, in order to implement this section, contribute funds, technical resources, and other support to assist the IAEA in effectively implementing safeguards;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> ensure that the IAEA has the resources to carry out the provisions of Article XII of the Statute of the IAEA;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> improve the IAEA safeguards system (including accountability) to ensure—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the timely detection of a possible diversion of source or special nuclear materials which could be used for nuclear explosive devices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the timely dissemination of information regarding such diversion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the timely implementation of internationally agreed procedures in the event of such diversion;</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> ensure that the IAEA receives on a timely basis the data needed for it to administer an effective and comprehensive international safeguards program and that the IAEA provides timely notice to the world community of any evidence of a violation of any safeguards agreement to which it is a party; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> encourage the IAEA, to the maximum degree consistent with the Statute, to provide nations which supply nuclear materials and equipment with the data needed to assure such nations of adherence to bilateral commitments applicable to such supply.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3242.</num>
<heading> Training program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of Energy, in consultation with the Commission, shall establish and operate a safeguards and physical security training program to be made available to persons from nations and groups of nations which have developed or acquired, or may be expected to develop or acquire, nuclear materials and equipment for use for peaceful purposes. Any such program shall include training in the most advanced safeguards and physical security techniques and technology, consistent with the national security interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3243.</num>
<heading> Negotiations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The United States shall seek to negotiate with other nations and groups of nations to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> adopt general principles and procedures, including common international sanctions, to be followed in the event that a nation violates any material obligation with respect to the peaceful use of nuclear materials and equipment or nuclear technology, or in the event that any nation violates the principles of the Treaty, including the detonation by a non-­nuclear-weapon state of a nuclear explosive device; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish international procedures to be followed in the event of diversion, theft, or sabotage of nuclear materials or sabotage of nuclear facilities, and for recovering nuclear materials that have been lost or stolen, or obtained or used by a nation or by any person or group in contravention of the principles of the Treaty.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3244.</num>
<heading> Actions to combat international nuclear terrorism</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions to be taken by President</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress hereby directs the President—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to seek universal adherence to the Convention on the Physical Protection of Nuclear Material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conduct a review, enlisting the participation of all relevant departments and agencies of the Government, to determine whether the recommendations on Physical Protection of Nuclear Material published by the International Atomic Energy Agency are adequate to deter theft, sabotage, and the use of nuclear facilities and materials in acts of international terrorism, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transmit the results of this review to the Director-General of the International Atomic Energy Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to take, in concert with United States allies and other countries, such steps as may be necessary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to keep to a minimum the amount of weapons-grade nuclear material in international transit, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to ensure that when any such material is transported internationally, it is under the most effective means for adequately protecting it from acts or attempted acts of sabotage or theft by terrorist groups or nations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> to seek agreement in the United Nations Security Council to establish—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an effective regime of international sanctions against any nation or subnational group which conducts or sponsors acts of international nuclear terrorism, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> measures for coordinating responses to all acts of international nuclear terrorism, including measures for the recovery of stolen nuclear material and the clean-up of nuclear releases.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall report to the Congress annually, in the reports required by <ref>section 3281 of this title</ref>, on the progress made during the preceding year in achieving the objectives described in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 99–399, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 874</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES ASSISTANCE TO DEVELOPING COUNTRIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3261.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of policy; Presidential report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States shall endeavor to cooperate with other nations, international institutions, and private organizations in establishing programs to assist in the development of non-nuclear energy resources, to cooperate with both developing and industrialized nations in protecting the international environment from contamination arising from both nuclear and non-nuclear energy activities, and shall seek to cooperate with and aid developing countries in meeting their energy needs through the development of such resources and the application of non-nuclear technologies consistent with the economic factors, the material resources of those countries, and environmental protection. The United States shall additionally seek to encourage other industrialized nations and groups of nations to make commitments for similar cooperation and aid to developing countries. The President shall report annually to Congress on the level of other nations’ and groups of nations’ commitments under such program and the relation of any such commitments to United States efforts under this title. In cooperating with and providing such assistance to developing countries, the United States shall give priority to parties to the Treaty.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 148</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3262.</num>
<heading> Programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Energy development programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The United States shall initiate a program, consistent with the aims of <ref>section 3261 of this title</ref>, to cooperate with developing countries for the purpose of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> meeting the energy needs required for the development of such countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reducing the dependence of such countries on petroleum fuels, with emphasis given to utilizing solar and other renewable energy resources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> expanding the energy alternatives available to such countries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Energy assessments and cooperative projects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Such program shall include cooperation in evaluating the energy alternatives of developing countries, facilitating international trade in energy commodities, developing energy resources, and applying suitable energy technologies. The program shall include both general and country-specific energy assessments and cooperative projects in resource exploration and production, training, research and development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exchange of scientists, technicians, and energy experts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As an integral part of such program, the Department of Energy, under the general policy guidance of the Department of State and in cooperation with the Agency for International Development and other Federal agencies as appropriate, shall initiate, as soon as practicable, a program for the exchange of United States scientists, technicians, and energy experts with those of developing countries to implement the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated such sums as are contained in annual authorization Acts for the Department of Energy, including such sums which have been authorized for such purposes under previous legislation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with related United States activities abroad</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under the direction of the President, the Secretary of State shall ensure the coordination of the activities authorized by this subchapter with other related activities of the United States conducted abroad, including the programs authorized by sections 2151a(c), 2151d(a)(2),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002245">1</ref> and 2151q <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002245">1</ref> of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 149</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>EXECUTIVE REPORTING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3281.</num>
<heading> Annual Presidential report to Congress on governmental efforts to prevent proliferation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of Government activities; description of progress; assessment of impact of prog­ress; determinations regarding non-nuclear-weapon states; counterproductiveness of policies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall review all activities of Government departments and agencies relating to preventing proliferation and shall make a report to Congress in January of 1979 and annually in January of each year thereafter on the Government’s efforts to prevent proliferation. This report shall include but not be limited to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a description of the progress made toward—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> negotiating the initiatives contemplated in sections 3223 and 3224 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> negotiating the international arrangements or other mutual undertakings contemplated in <ref>section 2153b of title 42</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> encouraging non-nuclear-weapon states that are not party to the Treaty to adhere to the Treaty or, pending such adherence, to enter into comparable agreements with respect to safeguards and to foreswear the development of any nuclear explosive devices, and discouraging nuclear exports to non-nuclear-weapon states which have not taken such steps;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> strengthening the safeguards of the IAEA as contemplated in <ref>section 3241 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> renegotiating agreements for cooperation as contemplated in <ref>section 2153c(a) of title 42</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assessment of the impact of the progress described in paragraph (1) on the non-proliferation policy of the United States; an explanation of the precise reasons why progress has not been made on any particular point and recommendations with respect to appropriate measures to encourage progress; and a statement of what legislative modifications, if any, are necessary in his judgment to achieve the non-proliferation policy of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> a determination as to which non-nuclear-weapon states with which the United States has an agreement for cooperation in effect or under negotiation, if any, have—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> detonated a nuclear device; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> refused to accept the safeguards of the IAEA on all of their peaceful nuclear activities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> refused to give specific assurances that they will not manufacture or otherwise acquire any nuclear explosive device; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> engaged in activities involving source or special nuclear material and having direct significance for the manufacture or acquisition of nuclear explosive devices;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an assessment of whether any of the policies set forth in this chapter have, on balance, been counterproductive from the standpoint of preventing proliferation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a description of the progress made toward establishing procedures to facilitate the timely processing of requests for subsequent arrangements and export licenses in order to enhance the reliability of the United States in meeting its commitments to supply nuclear reactors and fuel to nations which adhere to effective non-proliferation policies; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002246">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> a description of the implementation of nuclear and nuclear-related dual-use export controls in the preceding calendar year, including a summary by type of commodity and destination of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> all transactions for which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an export license was issued for any good controlled under <ref>section 2139a(c) of title 42</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an export license was issued under <ref>section 2139(b) of title 42</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> approvals were issued under the Export Administration Act of 1979, or <ref>section 2139(b)(3) of title 42</ref>, for the retransfer of any item, technical data, component, or substance; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> authorizations were made as required by <ref>section 2077(b)(2) of title 42</ref> to engage, directly or indirectly, in the production of special nuclear material;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> each instance in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a sanction has been imposed under <ref>section 6301(a) of this title</ref> or <ref>section 6303 of this title</ref> or <ref>section 2799aa–1(b)(1) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> sales or leases have been denied under <ref>section 2753(f) of this title</ref> or transactions prohibited by reason of acts relating to proliferation of nuclear explosive devices as described in <ref>section 2780(d) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a sanction has not been imposed by reason of <ref>section 6301(c)(2) of this title</ref> or the imposition of a sanction has been delayed under <ref>section 2799aa–1(b)(4) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<chapeau> a waiver of a sanction has been made under—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content><ref>section 6301(f) of this title</ref> or <ref>section 6303 of this title</ref>,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content><ref>section 2375(d) of this title</ref>, or paragraph (5) or (6)(B) of <ref>section 2799aa–1(b) of this title</ref>,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content><ref>section 2780(g) of this title</ref> with respect to the last sentence of <ref>section 2780(d) of this title</ref>, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content><ref>section 2364 of this title</ref> with respect to <ref>section 2375 of this title</ref> or <ref>section 2753(f) of this title</ref>, the last sentence of <ref>section 2780(d) of this title</ref>, or 2799aa–1(b)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002247">2</ref> of this title; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the progress of those independent states of the former Soviet Union that are non-nuclear-weapon states and of the Baltic states towards achieving the objective of applying full scope safeguards to all their peaceful nuclear activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Portions of the information required by paragraph (6) may be submitted in classified form, as necessary. Any such information that may not be published or disclosed under section 12(c)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002248">3</ref> of the Export Administration Act of 1979 shall be submitted as confidential.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Analysis of civil agreements for cooperation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the first report required by this section, the President shall analyze each civil agreement for cooperation negotiated pursuant to <ref>section 2153 of title 42</ref>, and shall discuss the scope and adequacy of the requirements and obligations relating to safeguards and other controls therein.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 150</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 811</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 507</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3282.</num>
<heading> Reports by departments and agencies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports by Nuclear Regulatory Commission and Department of Energy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The annual reports to the Congress by the Commission and the Department of Energy which are otherwise required by law shall also include views and recommendations regarding the policies and actions of the United States to prevent proliferation which are the statutory responsibility of those agencies. The Department’s report shall include a detailed analysis of the proliferation implications of advanced enrichment and reprocessing techniques, advanced reactors, and alternative nuclear fuel cycles. This part of the report shall include a comprehensive version which includes any relevant classified information and a summary unclassified version.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional reporting requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reporting requirements of this subchapter are in addition to and not in lieu of any other reporting requirements under applicable law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Committees on Foreign Relations and Governmental Affairs of Senate and Committee on International Relations of House of Representatives to be kept informed</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Department of State, the Department of Defense, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Energy, the Commission, and, with regard to subparagraph (B), the Director of Central Intelligence, shall keep the Committees on Foreign Relations and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives fully and currently informed with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> their activities to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter and to otherwise prevent proliferation, including the proliferation of nuclear, chemical, or biological weapons, or their means of delivery; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the current activities of foreign nations which are of significance from the proliferation standpoint.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For the purposes of this subsection with respect to paragraph (1)(B), the phrase “fully and currently informed” means the transmittal of credible information not later than 60 days after becoming aware of the activity concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Classified portions of reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any classified portions of the reports required by this chapter shall be submitted to the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and the House Foreign Affairs Committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access by Secretary of Defense to information regarding nuclear proliferation matters; applicability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Defense shall have access, on a timely basis, to all information regarding nuclear proliferation matters which the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Energy has or is entitled to have. Such access shall include access to all communications, materials, documents, and records relating to nuclear proliferation matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> This subsection does not apply to any intradepartmental document of the Department of State or the Department of Energy, or any portion of such document, that is solely concerned with internal, confidential advice on policy concerning the conduct of interagency deliberations on nuclear proliferation matters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 95–242, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 151</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIII, § 1370</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4004</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–437, § 9(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4588</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1225(e)(6), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7)</ref>, [div. B, title XI, § 1131], <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–492.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>