<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 23—</num>
<heading>PROTECTION OF CITIZENS ABROAD</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1731.</num>
<heading> Protection to naturalized citizens abroad</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All naturalized citizens of the United States while in foreign countries are entitled to and shall receive from this Government the same protection of persons and property which is accorded to native-born citizens.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2000.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1732.</num>
<heading> Release of citizens imprisoned by foreign governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever it is made known to the President that any citizen of the United States has been unjustly deprived of his liberty by or under the authority of any foreign government, it shall be the duty of the President forthwith to demand of that government the reasons of such imprisonment; and if it appears to be wrongful and in violation of the rights of American citizenship, the President shall forthwith demand the release of such citizen, and if the release so demanded is unreasonably delayed or refused, the President shall use such means, not amounting to acts of war and not otherwise prohibited by law, as he may think necessary and proper to obtain or effectuate the release; and all the facts and proceedings relative thereto shall as soon as practicable be communicated by the President to Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(R.S. § 2001; <ref>Pub. L. 101–222, § 9</ref>, <date date="1989-12-12">Dec. 12, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1733.</num>
<heading> Interagency Hostage Recovery Coordinator</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency Hostage Recovery Coordinator</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2015-11-25">November 25, 2015</date>, the President shall designate an existing Federal official to coordinate efforts to secure the release of United States persons who are hostages held abroad. For purposes of carrying out the duties described in paragraph (2), such official shall have the title of “Interagency Hostage Recovery Coordinator”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Coordinator shall have the following duties:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Coordinate activities of the Federal Government relating to each hostage situation described in paragraph (1) to ensure efforts to secure the release of hostages are properly resourced and correct lines of authority are established and maintained.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Chair a fusion cell consisting of appropriate personnel of the Federal Government with purview over each hostage situation described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Ensure sufficient representation of each Federal agency and department at each fusion cell established under subparagraph (B) and issue procedures for adjudication and appeal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Develop processes and procedures to keep family members of hostages described in paragraph (1) informed of the status of such hostages, inform such family members of updates that do not compromise the national security of the United States, and coordinate with the Federal Government’s family engagement coordinator or other designated senior representative.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quarterly report and briefing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On a quarterly basis, the Coordinator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes a summary of each hostage situation described in subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each report under this <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002075">1</ref> subparagraph (A) may be submitted in classified or unclassified form.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Briefing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">On a quarterly basis, the Coordinator shall provide to the Senators representing the State, and the Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner of the House of Representatives representing the district, where a hostage described in subsection (a)(1) resides a briefing with respect to the status of such hostage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1092</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>HOSTAGE RECOVERY AND HOSTAGE-TAKING ACCOUNTABILITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1741.</num>
<heading> Assistance for United States nationals unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall review, as expeditiously as possible, the cases of United States nationals detained abroad to determine if there is credible information that they are being detained unlawfully or wrongfully, based on criteria which may include whether—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> United States officials receive or possess credible information indicating innocence of the detained individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the individual is being detained solely or substantially because he or she is a United States national;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the individual is being detained solely or substantially to influence United States Government policy or to secure economic or political concessions from the United States Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the detention appears to be because the individual sought to obtain, exercise, defend, or promote freedom of the press, freedom of religion, or the right to peacefully assemble;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the individual is being detained in violation of the laws of the detaining country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> independent nongovernmental organizations or journalists have raised legitimate questions about the innocence of the detained individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the United States mission in the country where the individual is being detained has received credible reports that the detention is a pretext for an illegitimate purpose;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the individual is detained in a country where the Department of State has determined in its annual human rights reports that the judicial system is not independent or impartial, is susceptible to corruption, or is incapable of rendering just verdicts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> the individual is being detained in inhumane conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> due process of law has been sufficiently impaired so as to render the detention arbitrary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> United States diplomatic engagement is likely necessary to secure the release of the detained individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referrals to Special Envoy; notification to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Upon a determination by the Secretary of State, based on the totality of the circumstances, that there is credible information that the detention of a United States national abroad is unlawful or wrongful, and regardless of whether the detention is by a foreign government or a nongovernmental actor, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> expeditiously transfer responsibility for such case from the Bureau of Consular Affairs of the Department of State to the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not later than 14 days after such determination, notify the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives of such determination and provide such committees with a summary of the facts that led to such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The notification described in paragraph (1)(B) may be classified, if necessary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an annual report with respect to United States nationals for whom the Secretary determines there is credible information of unlawful or wrongful detention abroad.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The report required under this paragraph shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if necessary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include current estimates of the number of individuals so detained, as well as relevant information about particular cases, such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of the individual, unless the provision of such information is inconsistent with <ref>section 552a of title 5</ref> (commonly known as the “Privacy Act of 1974”);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> basic facts about the case;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a summary of the information that such individual may be detained unlawfully or wrongfully;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a description of specific efforts, legal and diplomatic, taken on behalf of the individual since the last reporting period, including a description of accomplishments and setbacks; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a description of intended next steps.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resources for United States nationals unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resource guidance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, and after consulting with relevant organizations that advocate on behalf of United States nationals detained abroad and the Family Engagement Coordinator established pursuant to <ref>section 1741b(c)(2) of this title</ref>, the Secretary of State shall provide resource guidance in writing for government officials and families of unjustly or wrongfully detained individuals.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The resource guidance required under subparagraph (A) should include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> information to help families understand United States policy concerning the release of United States nationals unlawfully or wrongfully held abroad;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> contact information for officials in the Department of State or other government agencies suited to answer family questions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> relevant information about options available to help families obtain the release of unjustly or wrongfully detained individuals, such as guidance on how families may engage with United States diplomatic and consular channels to ensure prompt and regular access for the detained individual to legal counsel, family members, humane treatment, and other services;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> guidance on submitting public or private letters from members of Congress or other individuals who may be influential in securing the release of an individual; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> appropriate points of contacts, such as legal resources and counseling services, who have a record of assisting victims’ families.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel assistance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Family advocacy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For the purpose of facilitating meetings between the United States Government and the family members of United States nationals unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad, the Secretary shall provide financial assistance to cover the costs of travel to and from Washington, D.C., including travel by air, train, bus, or other transit as appropriate, to any individual who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> is—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a family member of a United States national unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad as determined by the Secretary under subsection (a); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<chapeau> an appropriate individual who—</chapeau>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> is approved by the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs; and</content>
</item>
<item class="indent5">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> does not represent in any legal capacity a United States national unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad or the family of such United States national;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has a permanent address that is more than 50 miles from Washington, D.C.; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> requests such assistance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel and lodging</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For each such United States national unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad, the financial assistance described in subparagraph (A) shall be provided for not more than 2 trips per fiscal year, unless the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs determines that a third trip is warranted.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Any trip described in clause (i) shall—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> consist of not more than 2 family members or other individuals approved in accordance with subparagraph (A)(i)(II), unless the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs determines that circumstances warrant an additional family member or other individual approved in accordance with subparagraph (A)(i)(II) and approves assistance to such third family member or other individual; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> not exceed more than 2 nights lodging, unless the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs determines that circumstances warrant an additional night, which shall not exceed the applicable government rate.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return travel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If other United States Government assistance is unavailable, the Secretary may provide to a United States national unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad as determined by the Secretary under subsection (a), United States assistance, as necessary, for return travel to the United States upon release of such United States national.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall seek to make available physical health services, mental health services, and other support as appropriate, including providing information on available legal or financial resources, to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any United States national unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any family member of such United States national.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For any support described in subparagraph (A) for an individual described in clause (i) or (ii) of such subparagraph that commences following the return of a United States national who was unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad, such support shall be made available for up to 5 years from the date on which any individual identified in subparagraph (A) chooses to avail themselves of the support described in that subparagraph, unless the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs determines that circumstances warrant extending such support.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The time limitation under clause (i) does not apply to any support provided during the pendency of the detention of a United States national unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall notify the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than 14 days after such time that total expenditures to carry out paragraphs (2) and (3) in any fiscal year surpass $250,000 for any fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds authorized to be appropriated for the Department of State, which may include funds made available for unforeseen emergencies arising in the diplomatic and consular service, may be used to provide the support authorized by this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Foreign Relations and Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs and Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a detailed description of expenditures made pursuant to paragraphs (2) and (3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a detailed description of types of support provided pursuant to paragraph (3), provided that such description does not identify any individuals receiving any physical or mental health support, in order to protect their privacy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number and location of visits outside of Washington, D.C., during the prior fiscal year made by the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs to family members of each United States national unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sunset</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The authority and requirements under paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5) shall terminate on <date date="2027-12-31">December 31, 2027</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Family member defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “family member” means a spouse, father, mother, child, brother, sister, grandparent, grandchild, aunt, uncle, nephew, niece, cousin, father-in-law, mother-in-law, son-in-law, daughter-in-law, brother-in-law, sister-in-law, stepfather, stepmother, stepson, stepdaughter, stepbrother, stepsister, half brother, or half sister.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timeline for unlawful or wrongful detention determinations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credible information determinations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not less frequently than every 180 days, the Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Consular Affairs and the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs shall review the cases where there is potential credible information that any United States national is being detained wrongfully and which has been identified through official government channels to both bureaus.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report of findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after each review under subparagraph (A), the Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs and the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs shall jointly submit to Congress a classified report identifying the United States nationals identified as a result of the review in subparagraph (A) detained overseas who have not, as of the date of the report, been determined by the Secretary to be unlawfully or wrongfully detained.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification to family members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a United States national detained overseas identified in the report under subparagraph (B), the Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs shall notify a family member (as that term is defined in subsection (d)(8)) or the legal representative of the United States national not later than 30 days after the transmittal of the report required by subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Status determinations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B) and to the extent practicable, not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary of State receives an assessment from the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs or the head of any other relevant bureau of the Department of State that credible information exists that a United States national is being detained unlawfully or wrongfully, the Secretary shall determine whether the United States national is in fact being unlawfully or wrongfully detained.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The Secretary may waive the requirement under subparagraph (A) to make an unlawful or wrongful detention determination if the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> determines that making such a determination may jeopardize the safety or interests of the United States national being detained abroad or the national security interests of the United States; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> submits to Congress a classified report describing the reasons for the waiver.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A waiver under clause (i) shall expire on the date that is 180 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the report on the waiver to Congress pursuant to clause (i)(II).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Renewal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary may renew a waiver granted pursuant to clause (i) in the manner provided under such clause.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Declarations of invalidity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the release of a United States national determined to be unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad and the return of that national, the President shall issue to that national a letter, to be known as a “declaration of invalidity”, that officially declares the detention abroad of the national as invalid for the purpose of completing any documentation that warrants a background investigation or review of prior offenses, such as a conviction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3091</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCI, § 9102</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3858</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. F, title LXIV, § 6409</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 1003</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXVII</ref>, §§ 7701, 7707, 7708, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2553</ref>, 2556, 2557.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1741a.</num>
<heading> Special Envoy for Hostage Affairs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be a Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall report to the Secretary of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rank</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Special Envoy shall have the rank and status of ambassador.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> lead diplomatic engagement on United States hostage policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate all diplomatic engagements and strategy in support of hostage recovery efforts, in coordination with the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell and consistent with policy guidance communicated through the Hostage Response Group;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in coordination with the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell as appropriate, coordinate diplomatic engagements regarding cases in which a foreign government has detained a United States national and the United States Government regards such detention as unlawful or wrongful;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> provide senior representation from the Special Envoy’s office to the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell established under <ref>section 1741b of this title</ref> and the Hostage Response Group established under <ref>section 1741c of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> ensure that families of United States nationals unlawfully or wrongly detained abroad receive updated information about developments in cases and government policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Family Engagement Coordinator</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There shall be, in the Office of the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, a Family Engagement Coordinator, who shall ensure—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> for a United States national unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any interaction by executive branch officials with any family member of such United States national occurs in a coordinated fashion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such family member receives consistent and accurate information from the United States Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> appropriate coordination with the Family Engagement Coordinator described in <ref>section 1741b(c)(2) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for a United States national held hostage abroad, that any engagement with a family member is coordinated with, consistent with, and not duplicative of the efforts of the Family Engagement Coordinator described in <ref>section 1741b(c)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3093</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCI, § 9103</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3858</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1741b.</num>
<heading> Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall establish an interagency Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Participation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall direct the heads of each of the following executive departments, agencies, and offices to make available personnel to participate in the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Department of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Department of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Department of Justice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Other agencies as the President, from time to time, may designate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a Director, who shall be a full-time senior officer or employee of the United States Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a Family Engagement Coordinator who shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> work to ensure that all interactions by executive branch officials with a hostage’s family occur in a coordinated fashion and that the family receives consistent and accurate information from the United States Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if directed, perform the same function as set out in subparagraph (A) with regard to the family of a United States national who is unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> other officers and employees as deemed appropriate by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate efforts by participating agencies to ensure that all relevant information, expertise, and resources are brought to bear to secure the safe recovery of United States nationals held hostage abroad;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if directed, coordinate the United States Government’s response to other hostage-takings occurring abroad in which the United States has a national interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if directed, coordinate or assist the United States Government’s response to help secure the release of United States nationals unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> pursuant to policy guidance coordinated through the National Security Council—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identify and recommend hostage recovery options and strategies to the President through the National Security Council or the Deputies Committee of the National Security Council;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coordinate efforts by participating agencies to ensure that information regarding hostage events, including potential recovery options and engagements with families and external actors (including foreign governments), is appropriately shared within the United States Government to facilitate a coordinated response to a hostage-taking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assess and track all hostage-takings of United States nationals abroad and provide regular reports to the President and Congress on the status of such cases and any measures being taken toward the hostages’ safe recovery;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide a forum for intelligence sharing and, with the support of the Director of National Intelligence, coordinate the declassification of relevant information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> coordinate efforts by participating agencies to provide appropriate support and assistance to hostages and their families in a coordinated and consistent manner and to provide families with timely information regarding significant events in their cases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> make recommendations to agencies in order to reduce the likelihood of United States nationals’ being taken hostage abroad and enhance United States Government preparation to maximize the probability of a favorable outcome following a hostage-taking; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> coordinate with agencies regarding congressional, media, and other public inquiries pertaining to hostage events.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell shall be located within the Federal Bureau of Investigation for administrative purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3094</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1741c.</num>
<heading> Hostage Response Group</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall establish a Hostage Response Group, chaired by a designated member of the National Security Council or the Deputies Committee of the National Security Council, to be convened on a regular basis, to further the safe recovery of United States nationals held hostage abroad or unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad, and to be tasked with coordinating the United States Government response to other hostage-takings occurring abroad in which the United States has a national interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The regular members of the Hostage Response Group shall include the Director of the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell, the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell’s Family Engagement Coordinator, the Special Envoy appointed pursuant to <ref>section 1741a of this title</ref>, and representatives from the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Defense, the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, the Central Intelligence Agency, and other agencies as the President, from time to time, may designate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Hostage Recovery Group shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify and recommend hostage recovery options and strategies to the President through the National Security Council;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> coordinate the development and implementation of United States hostage recovery policies, strategies, and procedures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> receive regular updates from the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell and the Special Envoy for Hostage Affairs on the status of United States nationals being held hostage or unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad and measures being taken to effect safe recoveries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> coordinate the provision of policy guidance to the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell, including reviewing recovery options proposed by the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell and working to resolve disputes within the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> as appropriate, direct the use of resources at the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell to coordinate or assist in the safe recovery of United States nationals unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> as appropriate, direct the use of resources at the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell to coordinate the United States Government response to other hostage-takings occurring abroad in which the United States has a national interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Hostage Response Group shall meet regularly.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Hostage Response Group shall regularly provide recommendations on hostage recovery options and strategies to the National Security Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1741c–1.</num>
<heading> Report on strategies for reducing likelihood of United States nationals being unlawfully or wrongfully detained or taken hostage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, in coordination with the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell, the Hostage Response Group, and relevant agencies, as appropriate, shall submit to the President and Congress a classified report that identifies and recommends options and strategies to reduce the likelihood of United States nationals being unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad or taken hostage.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title III, § 305A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXVII, § 7702</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2553</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1741c–2.</num>
<heading> Coordination with transportation authorities and industry on Department of State travel advisories</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with the Department of Homeland Security</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and representatives of any other Federal agency determined necessary, and in consultation with the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs and the Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs, develop messaging and informational guidance to be delivered at all United States international airports and on relevant United States Government websites warning United States nationals of the risks of wrongful or unlawful detention or hostage-taking in covered countries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Messaging and guidance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The messaging and guidance described under paragraph (1) may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> posters, brochures, and other informational materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> web banners or other warnings to be displayed on relevant United States Government websites and webpages;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> verbal warnings at United States international airports to United States nationals whose destinations, to the extent they are discernable, are covered countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other methods deemed appropriate by the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and representatives of any other Federal agency determined necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of State coordination with United States airlines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and representatives of any other Federal agency determined necessary, and in consultation with the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs and Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Consular Affairs, work with United States airlines to provide warnings about the risk of wrongful or unlawful detention and hostage-taking to United States nationals booking travel through their airlines to a covered country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than one year after <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, the Secretary of State shall, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and representatives of any other Federal agency determined necessary, submit to Congress a report detailing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the additional steps taken to warn United States nationals of the risks of wrongful or unlawful detention and hostage-taking abroad, including those described in this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> efforts to improve the visibility and expand the reach of Department of State travel advisories concerning the risks to United States nationals of wrongful or unlawful detention and hostage-taking abroad; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> additional recommendations on steps the United States Government might take to improve the awareness of United States nationals of the risk of wrongful or unlawful detention and hostage-taking abroad.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered country defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “covered country” means a country for which a Department of State travel advisory contains either the “K—Kidnapping or Hostage Taking” or “D—Wrongful Detention” Risk Indicators.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title III, § 305B</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXVII, § 7705</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1741d.</num>
<heading> Authorization of imposition of sanctions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person the President determines, based on credible evidence—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is responsible for or is complicit in, or responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, the hostage-taking of a United States national abroad or the unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national abroad; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> knowingly provides financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services in support of, an activity described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Visas, admission, or parole</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An alien described in subsection (a) may be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> inadmissible to the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Current visas revoked</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">An alien described in subsection (a) may be subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immediate effect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">A revocation under clause (i) may—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> take effect immediately; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Blocking of property</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The President may exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.), to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of a foreign person described in subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inapplicability of national emergency requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref>) shall not apply for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for intelligence activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception to comply with international obligations and for law enforcement activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Sanctions under subsection (b)(1) shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success <date date="1947-06-26">June 26, 1947</date>, and entered into force <date date="1947-11-21">November 21, 1947</date>, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to carry out or assist law enforcement activity in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of subsection (b)(2) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out that subsection shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1705</ref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may terminate the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a person if the President determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information exists that the person did not engage in the activity for which sanctions were imposed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the person has been prosecuted appropriately for the activity for which sanctions were imposed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the person has credibly demonstrated a significant change in behavior, has paid an appropriate consequence for the activity for which sanctions were imposed, and has credibly committed to not engage in an activity described in subsection (a) in the future; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the termination of the sanctions is in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the President terminates sanctions pursuant to subsection (d),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002076">1</ref> the President shall report to the appropriate congressional committees a written justification for such termination within 15 days.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of regulatory authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1702</ref> and 1704) to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception relating to importation of goods</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions authorized under this subchapter shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Good defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this paragraph, the term “good” means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “foreign person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any citizen or national of a foreign country (including any such individual who is also a citizen or national of the United States); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any entity not organized solely under the laws of the United States or existing solely in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “United States person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an individual who is a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any person in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1741e.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the United States Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States national</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “United States national” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a United States national as defined in section 1101(a)(22) or <ref>section 1408 of title 8</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a lawful permanent resident alien with significant ties to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3098</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1741f.</num>
<heading> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter may be construed to authorize a private right of action.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3099</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>