<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 90—</num>
<heading>VOLUNTEERS FOR PROSPERITY PROGRAM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8301.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Americans engaged in international volunteer service, and the organizations deploying them—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> play critical roles in responding to the needs of people living throughout the developing world; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> advance the international public diplomacy of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Volunteers for Prosperity Program has successfully promoted international volunteer service by skilled American professionals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In its first 4 years, the VfP Program helped to mobilize 74,000 skilled Americans, including doctors, nurses, engineers, businesspeople, and teachers, through a network of 250 nonprofit organizations and companies in the United States, to carry out development and humanitarian efforts for those affected by great global challenges in health, the environment, poverty, illiteracy, financial literacy, disaster relief, and other challenges.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> The VfP Program has undertaken activities, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> direct outreach to leading nonprofit organizations and companies in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promotion of the work of skilled Americans and nonprofit organizations and companies in the United States as it relates to international volunteer service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> public recognition of skilled American volunteers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> support for organizations that utilize skilled Americans as volunteers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> participation in the development of special initiatives to further opportunities for skilled Americans; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> leadership of an innovative public-private partnership to provide eligible skilled <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002401">1</ref> with financial assistance for volunteer assignments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–13, title V, § 5101</ref>, <date date="2009-04-21">Apr. 21, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1597</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8302.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> VfP Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “VfP Office” means the Office of Volunteers for Prosperity of the United States Agency for International Development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> VfP Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “VfP Program” means the Volunteers for Prosperity Program established through Executive Order 13317.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> VfPServe</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “VfPServe” means a program established by the VfP Office, in cooperation with the USA Freedom Corps, to provide eligible skilled professionals with fixed amount stipends to offset the travel and living costs of volunteering abroad.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–13, title V, § 5102</ref>, <date date="2009-04-21">Apr. 21, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8303.</num>
<heading> Office of Volunteers for Prosperity</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The VfP Office shall pursue the objectives of the VfP Program described in subsection (b) by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> implementing the VfPServe Program to provide eligible skilled professionals with matching grants to offset the travel and living expenses of volunteering abroad with nonprofit organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> otherwise promoting short- and long-term international volunteer service by skilled American professionals, including connecting such professionals with nonprofit organizations, to achieve such objectives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> helping nonprofit organizations in the United States recruit and effectively manage additional skilled American professionals for volunteer assignments throughout the developing world;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> providing recognition for skilled American volunteers and the organizations deploying them;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> helping nonprofit organizations and corporations in the United States to identify resources and opportunities in international volunteer service utilizing skilled Americans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> encouraging the establishment of international volunteer programs for employees of United States corporations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> encouraging international voluntary service by highly skilled Americans to promote health and prosperity throughout the world.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> VfP Program objectives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The objectives of the VfP Program should include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> eliminating extreme poverty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reducing world hunger and malnutrition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> increasing access to safe potable water;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> enacting universal education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> reducing child mortality and childhood diseases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> combating the spread of preventable diseases, including HIV, malaria, and tuberculosis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> providing educational and work skill support for girls and empowering women to achieve independence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> creating sustainable business and entrepreneurial opportunities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> increasing access to information technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Volunteers for Prosperity Service Incentive Program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The VfP Office may provide matching grants to offset the travel and living costs of volunteering abroad to any eligible organization that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has members who possess skills relevant to addressing any objective described in subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> provides a dollar-for-dollar match for such grant—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> through the organization with which the individual is serving; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by raising private funds.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nondiscrimination requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The VfP Office may not provide a stipend to an individual under paragraph (1) unless the nonprofit organization to which the individual is assigned has certified to the VfP Office that it does not discriminate with respect to any project or activity receiving Federal financial assistance, including a stipend under this chapter, because of race, religion, color, national origin, sex, political affiliation, or beliefs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with ineligible service categories</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Service carried out by a volunteer receiving funds under this section may not provide a direct benefit to any—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> business organized for profit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> labor union;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> partisan political organization; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> religious or faith-based organization for the purpose of proselytization, worship or any other explicitly religious activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall make available the amounts appropriated pursuant to <ref>section 8304 of this title</ref> to the VfP Office to pursue the objectives described in subsection (b) by carrying out the functions described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts made available under paragraph (1) may be used by the VfP Office to provide personnel and other resources to develop, manage, and expand the VfP Program, under the supervision of the United States Agency for International Development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The VfP Office shall coordinate its efforts with other public and private efforts that aim to send skilled professionals to serve in developing nations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The VfP Office shall submit an annual report to Congress on the activities of the VfP Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–13, title V, § 5103</ref>, <date date="2009-04-21">Apr. 21, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8304.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this chapter $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2010, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2011 through 2014.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not more than 10 percent of the amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) may be expended for the administrative costs of the United States Agency for International Development to manage the VfP Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–13, title V, § 5104</ref>, <date date="2009-04-21">Apr. 21, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1600</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>