<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 107—</num>
<heading>SUDAN DEMOCRATIC TRANSITION, ACCOUNTABILITY, AND FISCAL TRANSPARENCY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10001.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, in this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International financial institutions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “international financial institutions” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the International Monetary Fund;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the International Development Association;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the International Finance Corporation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Inter-American Development Bank;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Asian Development Bank;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Inter-American Investment Corporation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the African Development Bank;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the Multilateral Investment Guaranty Agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> any multilateral financial institution, established after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, that could provide financial assistance to the Government of Sudan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sovereignty Council</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Sovereignty Council” means the governing body of Sudan during the transitional period that consists of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 5 civilians selected by the Forces of Freedom and Change;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 5 members selected by the Transitional Military Council; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> 1 member selected by agreement between the Forces of Freedom and Change and the Transitional Military Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sudanese security and intelligence services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Sudanese security and intelligence services” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Sudan Armed Forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Rapid Support Forces,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002461">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Sudan’s Popular Defense Forces and other paramilitary units;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Sudan’s police forces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the General Intelligence Service, previously known as the National Intelligence and Security Services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> related entities, such as Sudan’s Military Industry Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transitional period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “transitional period” means the 39-month period beginning on <date date="2019-08-17">August 17, 2019</date> (the date of the signing of Sudan’s constitutional charter), during which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the members of the Sovereignty Council described in paragraph (3)(B) select a chair of the Council for the first 21 months of the period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the members of the Sovereignty Council described in paragraph (3)(A) select a chair of the Council for the remaining 18 months of the period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1262</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3967</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10002.</num>
<heading> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to support a civilian-led political transition in Sudan that results in a democratic government, which is accountable to its people, respects and promotes human rights, is at peace internally and with its neighbors, and can be a partner for regional stability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to support the implementation of Sudan’s constitutional charter for the transitional period; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to pursue a strategy of calibrated engagement with Sudan that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> facilitating an environment for free, fair, and credible democratic elections and a pluralistic and representative political system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> supporting reforms that improve transparency and accountability, remove restrictions on civil and political liberties, and strengthen the protection of human rights, including religious freedom;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> strengthening civilian institutions, judicial independence, and the rule of law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> empowering civil society and independent media;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> promoting national reconciliation and enabling a just, comprehensive, and sustainable peace;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> promoting the role of women in government, the economy, and society, in recognition of the seminal role that women played in the social movement that ousted former president Omar al-Bashir;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> promoting accountability for genocide, war crimes, crimes against humanity, and sexual and gender-based violence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> encouraging the development of civilian oversight over and professionalization of the Sudanese security and intelligence services and strengthening accountability for human rights violations and abuses, corruption, or other abuses of power;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> promoting economic reform, private sector engagement, and inclusive economic development while combating corruption and illicit economic activity, including that which involves the Sudanese security and intelligence services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> securing unfettered humanitarian access across all regions of Sudan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> supporting improved development outcomes, domestic resource mobilization, and catalyzing market-based solutions to improve access to health, education, water and sanitation, and livelihoods; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> promoting responsible international and regional engagement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1263</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3968</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10003.</num>
<heading> Support for democratic governance, rule of law, human rights, and fundamental freedoms</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the political transition in Sudan, following several months of popular protests against the regime of Omar al-Bashir, represents an opportunity for the United States to support democracy, good governance, rule of law, human rights, and fundamental freedoms in Sudan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 7101</ref> et seq.] and the Child Soldiers Prevention Act of 2008), the President is authorized to provide assistance under part I and chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq. and 2346 et seq.)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide for democracy and governance programs that strengthen and build the capacity of representative civilian government institutions, political parties, and civil society in Sudan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to support the organization of free, fair, and credible elections in Sudan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to provide technical support for legal and policy reforms that improve transparency and accountability and protect human rights, including religious freedom, and civil liberties in Sudan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> to support human rights and fundamental freedoms in Sudan, including the freedoms of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> religion or belief;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> expression, including for members of the press;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assembly; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> association;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to support measures to improve and increase women’s participation in the political, economic, and social sectors of Sudan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to support other related democracy, good governance, rule of law, and fundamental freedom programs and activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated to carry out part I and chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq. and 2346 et seq.) for fiscal years 2021 and 2022, $20,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated for each such fiscal year to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1264</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3969</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10004.</num>
<heading> Support for development programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 7101</ref> et seq.] and the Child Soldiers Prevention Act of 2008), the President is authorized to provide assistance under part I and chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq. and 2346 et seq.) and under the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.) for programs in Sudan—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to increase agricultural and livestock productivity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote economic growth, increase private sector productivity and advance market-based solutions to address development challenges;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to support women’s economic empowerment and economic opportunities for youth and previously marginalized populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to improve equal access to quality basic education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to support the capacity of universities to equip students to participate in a pluralistic and global society through virtual exchange and other programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to improve access to water, sanitation, and hygiene projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> to build the capacity of national and subnational government officials to support the transparent management of public resources, promote good governance through combating corruption and improving accountability, increase economic productivity, and increase domestic resource mobilization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> to support other related economic assistance programs and activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated to carry out part I and chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq. and 2346 et seq.) for fiscal years 2021 and 2022, $80,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated for each such fiscal year to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1265</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10005.</num>
<heading> Support for conflict mitigation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 7101</ref> et seq.] and the Child Soldiers Prevention Act of 2008), the President is authorized to provide assistance under part I and chapters 4, 5, and 6 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq., 2346 et seq., and 2348 et seq.)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to support long-term peace and stability in Sudan by promoting national reconciliation and enabling a just, comprehensive, and sustainable peace, especially in regions that have been underdeveloped or affected by war, such as the states of Darfur, South Kordofan, Blue Nile, Red Sea, and Kassala;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to support civil society and other organizations working to address conflict prevention, mitigation, and resolution mechanisms and people-to-people reconciliation in Sudan, especially those addressing issues of marginalization and vulnerable groups, equal protection under the law, natural resource management, compensation and restoration of property, voluntary return, and sustainable solutions for displaced persons and refugees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to strengthen civilian oversight of the Sudanese security and intelligence services and ensure that such services are not contributing to the perpetuation of conflict in Sudan and to the limitation of the civil liberties of all people in Sudan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to assist in the human rights vetting and professional training of security force personnel due to be employed or deployed by the Sudanese security and intelligence services in regions that have been underdeveloped or affected by war, such as the states of Darfur, South Kordofan, Blue Nile, Red Sea, and Kassala, including members of any security forces being established pursuant to a peace agreement relating to such regions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> to support provisions of the Comprehensive Peace Agreement of 2005 and Abyei protocol, as appropriate, unless otherwise superseded by a new agreement signed in good faith—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> between stakeholders in this region and the Governments of Sudan and South Sudan to hold a free, fair, and credible referendum on the status of Abyei; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> between stakeholders in this region and the Government of Sudan to support popular consultations on the status of the states of South Kordofan and Blue Nile; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to support other related conflict mitigation programs and activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated to carry out part I and chapters 4 and 6 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq., 2346 et seq., and 2348 et seq.) for fiscal years 2021 and 2022, $20,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated for each such fiscal year to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1266</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10006.</num>
<heading> Support for accountability for war crimes, crimes against humanity, and genocide in Sudan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State should conduct robust diplomatic engagement to promote accountability and provide technical support to ensure that credible, transparent, and independent investigations of gross violations of human rights perpetrated by the Government of Sudan under former President Omar al-Bashir and the Transitional Military Council since <date date="1989-06-30">June 30, 1989</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 7101</ref> et seq.] and the Child Soldiers Prevention Act of 2008), the President is authorized to provide assistance under part I and chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq. and 2346 et seq.)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to build the capacity of civilian investigators within and outside of Sudan on how to document, investigate, develop findings of, identify, and locate those responsible for war crimes, crimes against humanity, or genocide in Sudan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to collect, document, and protect evidence of war crimes, crimes against humanity, and genocide in Sudan and preserve the chain of custody for such evidence, including by providing support for Sudanese, foreign, and international nongovernmental organizations, and other entities engaged in such investigative activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to build Sudan’s judicial capacity to support prosecutions in domestic courts and support investigations by hybrid or international courts as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to protect witnesses who participate in court proceedings or other transitional justice mechanisms; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to support other related conflict mitigation programs and activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated to carry out part I and chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq. and 2346 et seq.) for fiscal years 2021 and 2022, $10,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated for each such fiscal year to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1267</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3971</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10007.</num>
<heading> Suspension of assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to suspend the provision of assistance authorized under section 10003, 10004, 10005, or 10006 of this title to the Government of Sudan if the President determines that conditions in Sudan or the composition of the Government of Sudan changes such that it is no longer in the United States national interest to continue to provide such assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 30 days after making a determination under subsection (a), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that describes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the political and security conditions in Sudan that led to such determination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any planned diplomatic engagement to restart the provision of such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1268</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10008.</num>
<heading> Multilateral assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of the Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Sudan’s economic challenges are a legacy of decades of kleptocracy, economic mismanagement, and war;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Sudan’s economic recovery will depend on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> combating corruption and illicit economic activity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ending internal conflicts in the states of Darfur, South Kordofan, and Blue Nile; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> promoting inclusive economic growth and development; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the COVID–19 outbreak constitutes a grave danger to Sudan’s economic stability, public health, and food security and jeopardizes the transition to a civilian-led government that promotes the democratic aspirations of the Sudanese people.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responding to the COVID–19 outbreak</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During the transitional period, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Treasury may instruct the United States Executive Director at each international financial institution to use the voice and vote of the United States to support loans or other utilization of the funds of the respective institution for Sudan for the purpose of addressing basic human needs, responding to the COVID–19 outbreak and its impact on the country’s economic stability, or promoting democracy, governance, or public financial management in Sudan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Debt relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the removal of Sudan from the State Sponsors of Terrorism List, and once the Sovereignty Council is chaired by a civilian leader, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State should engage with international financial institutions and other bilateral official creditors to advance agreement through the Heavily Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) Initiative to restructure, reschedule, or cancel the sovereign debt of Sudan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 3 months after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, and not less frequently than once every 6 months thereafter during the transitional period, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall report to the appropriate congressional committees regarding the extent to which the transitional government of Sudan has taken demonstrable steps to strengthen governance and improve fiscal transparency, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establishing civilian control over the finances and assets of the Sudanese security and intelligence services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> developing a transparent budget that accounts for all expenditures related to the security and intelligence services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identifying the shareholdings in all public and private companies not exclusively dedicated to the national defense held or managed by the security and intelligence services, and publicly disclosing, evaluating, and transferring all such shareholdings to the Ministry of Finance of the Government of Sudan or to any specialized entity of the Government of Sudan established under law for this purpose, which is ultimately accountable to a civilian authority;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> ceasing the involvement of the security and intelligence services officials, and their immediate family members, in the illicit trade in mineral resources, including petroleum and gold;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> implementing a publicly transparent methodology for the Government of Sudan to recover, evaluate, hold, manage, or divest any state assets and the profits derived from the assets that may have been transferred to the National Congress Party, an affiliate of the National Congress Party, or an official of the National Congress Party in the individual capacity of such an official;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> identifying and monitoring the nature and purpose of offshore financial resources controlled by the security and intelligence services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> strengthening banking regulation and supervision and addressing anti-money laundering and counter-terrorism financing deficiencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref>section 10001 of this title</ref>, in this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1269</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10009.</num>
<heading> Coordinated support to recover assets stolen from the Sudanese people</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Attorney General, shall seek to advance the efforts of the Government of Sudan to recover assets stolen from the Sudanese people, including with regard to international efforts—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to identify and track assets taken from the people and institutions of Sudan through theft, corruption, money laundering, or other illicit means; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to assets identified pursuant to paragraph (1), to work with foreign governments and international organizations—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to share financial investigations intelligence, as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to oversee and manage the assets identified pursuant to paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to advance civil forfeiture litigation, as appropriate, including providing technical assistance to help governments establish the necessary legal framework to carry out asset forfeitures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> to work with the Government of Sudan to ensure that a credible mechanism is established to ensure that any recovered assets are managed in a transparent and accountable fashion and ultimately used for the benefit of the Sudanese people, provided that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> returned assets are not used for partisan political purposes; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> there are robust financial management and oversight measures to safeguard repatriated assets.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1270</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10010.</num>
<heading> Limitation on assistance to the Sudanese security and intelligence services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may not provide assistance (other than assistance authorized under <ref>section 10005 of this title</ref>) to the Sudanese security and intelligence services until the President submits to Congress a certification that the Government of Sudan has met the conditions described in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception; waiver</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State may, as appropriate and notwithstanding any other provision of law, provide assistance for the purpose of professionalizing the Sudanese security and intelligence services, through institutions such as the Africa Center for Strategic Studies and the United States Institute of Peace.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President may waive the limitation on the provision of assistance under subsection (a) if, not later than 30 days before the assistance is to be provided, the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a list of the activities and participants to which such waiver would apply;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a justification that the waiver is in the national security interest of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a certification that the participants have met the requirements of either <ref>section 2378d of this title</ref> for programs funded through Department of State appropriations or <ref>section 362 of title 10</ref> for programs funded through Department of Defense appropriations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The conditions described in this subsection are that the Sudanese security and intelligence services—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have demonstrated progress in undertaking security sector reform, including reforms that professionalize such security and intelligence services, improve transparency, and reforms to the laws governing the Sudanese security forces, such as of the National Security Act, 2010 and the Armed Forces Act, 2007;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> support efforts to respect human rights, including religious freedom, and hold accountable any members of such security and intelligence services responsible for human rights violations and abuses, including by taking demonstrable steps to cooperate with local or international mechanisms of accountability, to ensure that those responsible for war crimes, crimes against humanity, and genocide committed in Sudan are brought to justice;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> are under civilian oversight, subject to the rule of law, and are not undertaking actions to undermine a civilian-led transitional government or an elected civilian government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> have refrained from targeted attacks against religious or ethnic minority groups, have negotiated in good faith during the peace process and constructively participated in the implementation of any resulting peace agreements, and do not impede inclusive political participation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> allow unfettered humanitarian access by United Nations organizations and specialized agencies and domestic and international humanitarian organizations to civilian populations in conflict-affected areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> cooperate with the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees and organizations affiliated with the United Nations to allow for the protection of displaced persons and the safe, voluntary, sustainable, and dignified return of refugees and internally displaced persons; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> take constructive steps to investigate all reports of unlawful recruitment of children by Sudanese security forces and prosecute those found to be responsible.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The certification described in subsection (a) containing the conditions described in paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sunset</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section shall terminate on the date that is the earlier of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date that is 2 years after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the date on which the President determines that a successful rotation of military to civilian leadership in the Sovereignty Council has occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1270A</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10011.</num>
<heading> Reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on accountability for human rights abuses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, and annually thereafter for 2 years, the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> summarizes reports of gross violations of human rights, including sexual and gender-based violence, committed against civilians in Sudan, including members of the Sudanese security and intelligence services or any associated militias, between December 2018 and the date of the submission of the report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provides an update on any potential transitional justice mechanisms in Sudan to investigate, charge, and prosecute alleged perpetrators of gross violations of human rights in Sudan since <date date="1989-06-30">June 30, 1989</date>, including with respect to the <date date="2019-06-03">June 3, 2019</date> massacre in Khartoum;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> provides an analysis of whether the gross violations of human rights summarized pursuant to paragraph (1) amount to war crimes, crimes against humanity, or genocide; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> identifies specific cases since the beginning of the transitional period in which members of the Sudanese security and intelligence services have been charged and prosecuted for actions that constitute gross violations of human rights perpetrated since <date date="1989-06-30">June 30, 1989</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on certain activities and finances of senior officials of the government of Sudan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, and 1 year thereafter, the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> describes the actions and involvement of any previous or current senior officials of the Government of Sudan since the establishment of the transitional government in August 2019 in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> directing, carrying out, or overseeing gross violations of human rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> directing, carrying out, or overseeing the unlawful use or recruitment of children by armed groups or armed forces in the context of conflicts in Sudan, Libya, Yemen, or other countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> directing, carrying out, or colluding in significant acts of corruption;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> directing, carrying out, or overseeing any efforts to circumvent the establishment of civilian control over the finances and assets of the Sudanese security and intelligence services; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> facilitating, supporting, or financing terrorist activity in Sudan or other countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> identifies Sudanese and foreign financial institutions, including offshore financial institutions, in which senior officials of the Government of Sudan whose actions are described in paragraph (1) hold significant assets, and provides an estimate of the value of such assets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identifies any information United States Government agencies have obtained since August 2019 regarding persons, foreign governments, and Sudanese or foreign financial institutions that knowingly facilitate, finance, or otherwise benefit from corruption or illicit economic activity in Sudan, including the export of mineral resources, and, in particular, if that trade is violating any United States restrictions that remain in place by legislation or Executive order;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> identifies any information United States Government agencies have obtained since August 2019 regarding senior officials of the Government of Sudan who are personally involved in the illicit trade in mineral resources, including petroleum and gold; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> identifies any information United States Government agencies have obtained since August 2019 regarding individuals or foreign governments that have provided funds to individual members of the Sovereignty Council or the Cabinet outside of the Central Bank of Sudan or the Ministry of Finance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on sanctions pursuant to Executive Order No. 13400</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that identifies the senior Sudanese government officials that President determines meet the criteria to be sanctionable pursuant to Executive Order No. 13400 (71 Fed. Reg. 25483; relating to blocking property of persons in connection with the conflict in Sudan’s Darfur region).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reports required under subsections (b) and (c) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1270B</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3975</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10012.</num>
<heading> United States strategy for support to a civilian-led government in Sudan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit a strategy to the appropriate congressional committees that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a clear articulation of specific United States goals and objectives with respect to a successful completion of the transitional period and a plan to achieve such goals and objectives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of assistance and diplomatic engagement to support a civilian-led government in Sudan for the remainder of the transitional period, including any possible support for the organization of free, fair, and credible elections;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> an assessment of the legal and policy reforms that have been and need to be taken by the government in Sudan during the transitional period in order to promote—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> human rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> freedom of religion, speech, press, assembly, and association; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> accountability for human rights abuses, including for sexual and gender-based violence perpetrated by members of the Sudanese security and intelligence services;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a description of efforts to address the legal and policy reforms mentioned in paragraph (3);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a description of humanitarian and development assistance to Sudan and a plan for coordinating such assistance with international donors, regional partners, and local partners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a description of monitoring and evaluation plans for all forms of assistance to be provided under the strategy in accordance with the monitoring and evaluation requirements of <ref>section 2394c of this title</ref>, including a detailed description of all associated goals and benchmarks for measuring impact; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> an assessment of security sector reforms undertaken by the Government of Sudan, including efforts to demobilize or integrate militias and to foster civilian control of the armed services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a detailed description of the efforts taken to implement this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> recommendations for legislative or administrative measures to facilitate the implementation of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1270C</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 3977</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>