<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 78—</num>
<heading>TRAFFICKING VICTIMS PROTECTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7101.</num>
<heading> Purposes and findings</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are to combat trafficking in persons, a contemporary manifestation of slavery whose victims are predominantly women and children, to ensure just and effective punishment of traffickers, and to protect their victims.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> As the 21st century begins, the degrading institution of slavery continues throughout the world. Trafficking in persons is a modern form of slavery, and it is the largest manifestation of slavery today. At least 700,000 persons annually, primarily women and children, are trafficked within or across international borders. Approximately 50,000 women and children are trafficked into the United States each year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Many of these persons are trafficked into the international sex trade, often by force, fraud, or coercion. The sex industry has rapidly expanded over the past several decades. It involves sexual exploitation of persons, predominantly women and girls, involving activities related to prostitution, pornography, sex tourism, and other commercial sexual services. The low status of women in many parts of the world has contributed to a burgeoning of the trafficking industry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Trafficking in persons is not limited to the sex industry. This growing transnational crime also includes forced labor and involves significant violations of labor, public health, and human rights standards worldwide.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Traffickers primarily target women and girls, who are disproportionately affected by poverty, the lack of access to education, chronic unemployment, discrimination, and the lack of economic opportunities in countries of origin. Traffickers lure women and girls into their networks through false promises of decent working conditions at relatively good pay as nannies, maids, dancers, factory workers, restaurant workers, sales clerks, or models. Traffickers also buy children from poor families and sell them into prostitution or into various types of forced or bonded labor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Traffickers often transport victims from their home communities to unfamiliar destinations, including foreign countries away from family and friends, religious institutions, and other sources of protection and support, leaving the victims defenseless and vulnerable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Victims are often forced through physical violence to engage in sex acts or perform slavery-like labor. Such force includes rape and other forms of sexual abuse, torture, starvation, imprisonment, threats, psychological abuse, and coercion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Traffickers often make representations to their victims that physical harm may occur to them or others should the victim escape or attempt to escape. Such representations can have the same coercive effects on victims as direct threats to inflict such harm.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Trafficking in persons is increasingly perpetrated by organized, sophisticated criminal enterprises. Such trafficking is the fastest growing source of profits for organized criminal enterprises worldwide. Profits from the trafficking industry contribute to the expansion of organized crime in the United States and worldwide. Trafficking in persons is often aided by official corruption in countries of origin, transit, and destination, thereby threatening the rule of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Trafficking includes all the elements of the crime of forcible rape when it involves the involuntary participation of another person in sex acts by means of fraud, force, or coercion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Trafficking also involves violations of other laws, including labor and immigration codes and laws against kidnapping, slavery, false imprisonment, assault, battery, pandering, fraud, and extortion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Trafficking exposes victims to serious health risks. Women and children trafficked in the sex industry are exposed to deadly diseases, including HIV and AIDS. Trafficking victims are sometimes worked or physically brutalized to death.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Trafficking in persons substantially affects interstate and foreign commerce. Trafficking for such purposes as involuntary servitude, peonage, and other forms of forced labor has an impact on the nationwide employment network and labor market. Within the context of slavery, servitude, and labor or services which are obtained or maintained through coercive conduct that amounts to a condition of servitude, victims are subjected to a range of violations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Involuntary servitude statutes are intended to reach cases in which persons are held in a condition of servitude through nonviolent coercion. In United States v. Kozminski, 487 U.S. 931 (1988), the Supreme Court found that <ref>section 1584 of title 18</ref>, should be narrowly interpreted, absent a definition of involuntary servitude by Congress. As a result, that section was interpreted to criminalize only servitude that is brought about through use or threatened use of physical or legal coercion, and to exclude other conduct that can have the same purpose and effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Existing legislation and law enforcement in the United States and other countries are inadequate to deter trafficking and bring traffickers to justice, failing to reflect the gravity of the offenses involved. No comprehensive law exists in the United States that penalizes the range of offenses involved in the trafficking scheme. Instead, even the most brutal instances of trafficking in the sex industry are often punished under laws that also apply to lesser offenses, so that traffickers typically escape deserved punishment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> In the United States, the seriousness of this crime and its components is not reflected in current sentencing guidelines, resulting in weak penalties for convicted traffickers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> In some countries, enforcement against traffickers is also hindered by official indifference, by corruption, and sometimes even by official participation in trafficking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> Existing laws often fail to protect victims of trafficking, and because victims are often illegal immigrants in the destination country, they are repeatedly punished more harshly than the traffickers themselves.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> Additionally, adequate services and facilities do not exist to meet victims’ needs regarding health care, housing, education, and legal assistance, which safely reintegrate trafficking victims into their home countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> Victims of severe forms of trafficking should not be inappropriately incarcerated, fined, or otherwise penalized solely for unlawful acts committed as a direct result of being trafficked, such as using false documents, entering the country without documentation, or working without documentation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> Because victims of trafficking are frequently unfamiliar with the laws, cultures, and languages of the countries into which they have been trafficked, because they are often subjected to coercion and intimidation including physical detention and debt bondage, and because they often fear retribution and forcible removal to countries in which they will face retribution or other hardship, these victims often find it difficult or impossible to report the crimes committed against them or to assist in the investigation and prosecution of such crimes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> Trafficking of persons is an evil requiring concerted and vigorous action by countries of origin, transit or destination, and by international organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> One of the founding documents of the United States, the Declaration of Independence, recognizes the inherent dignity and worth of all people. It states that all men are created equal and that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights. The right to be free from slavery and involuntary servitude is among those unalienable rights. Acknowledging this fact, the United States outlawed slavery and involuntary servitude in 1865, recognizing them as evil institutions that must be abolished. Current practices of sexual slavery and trafficking of women and children are similarly abhorrent to the principles upon which the United States was founded.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> The United States and the international community agree that trafficking in persons involves grave violations of human rights and is a matter of pressing international concern. The international community has repeatedly condemned slavery and involuntary servitude, violence against women, and other elements of trafficking, through declarations, treaties, and United Nations resolutions and reports, including the Universal Declaration of Human Rights; the 1956 Supplementary Convention on the Abolition of Slavery, the Slave Trade, and Institutions and Practices Similar to Slavery; the 1948 American Declaration on the Rights and Duties of Man; the 1957 Abolition of Forced Labor Convention; the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights; the Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment; United Nations General Assembly Resolutions 50/167, 51/66, and 52/98; the Final Report of the World Congress against Sexual Exploitation of Children (Stockholm, 1996); the Fourth World Conference on Women (Beijing, 1995); and the 1991 Moscow Document of the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<content> Trafficking in persons is a transnational crime with national implications. To deter international trafficking and bring its perpetrators to justice, nations including the United States must recognize that trafficking is a serious offense. This is done by prescribing appropriate punishment, giving priority to the prosecution of trafficking offenses, and protecting rather than punishing the victims of such offenses. The United States must work bilaterally and multilaterally to abolish the trafficking industry by taking steps to promote cooperation among countries linked together by international trafficking routes. The United States must also urge the international community to take strong action in multilateral fora to engage recalcitrant countries in serious and sustained efforts to eliminate trafficking and protect trafficking victims.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 102</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7102.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abuse or threatened abuse of law or legal process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “abuse or threatened abuse of the legal process” means the use or threatened use of a law or legal process, whether administrative, civil, or criminal, in any manner or for any purpose for which the law was not designed, in order to exert pressure on another person to cause that person to take some action or refrain from taking some action.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coercion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “coercion” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> threats of serious harm to or physical restraint against any person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any scheme, plan, or pattern intended to cause a person to believe that failure to perform an act would result in serious harm to or physical restraint against any person; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the abuse or threatened abuse of the legal process.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial sex act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “commercial sex act” means any sex act on account of which anything of value is given to or received by any person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concrete actions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “concrete actions” means actions that demonstrate increased efforts by the government of a country to meet the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking, including any of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Enforcement actions taken.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Investigations actively underway.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Prosecutions conducted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Convictions attained.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Training provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Programs and partnerships actively underway.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Efforts to prevent severe forms of trafficking, including programs to reduce the vulnerability of particularly vulnerable populations, involving survivors of trafficking in community engagement and policy making, engagement with foreign migrants, ending recruitment fees, and other such measures.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Victim services offered, including immigration services and restitution.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The amount of money the government has committed to the actions described in subparagraphs (A) through (H).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credible information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “credible information” includes all of the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Reports by the Department of State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Reports of other Federal agencies, including the Department of Labor’s List of Goods Produced by Child Labor or Forced Labor and List of Products Produced by Forced Labor or Indentured Child Labor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Documentation provided by a foreign country, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> copies of relevant laws, regulations, and policies adopted or modified; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an official record of enforcement actions taken, judicial proceedings, training conducted, consultations conducted, programs and partnerships launched, and services provided.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Materials developed by civil society organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Information from survivors of human trafficking, vulnerable persons, and whistleblowers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> All relevant media and academic reports that, in light of reason and common sense, are worthy of belief.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Information developed by multilateral institutions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> An assessment of the impact of the actions described in subparagraphs (A) through (I) of paragraph (5) on the prevalence of human trafficking in the country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Debt bondage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “debt bondage” means the status or condition of a debtor arising from a pledge by the debtor of his or her personal services or of those of a person under his or her control as a security for debt, if the value of those services as reasonably assessed is not applied toward the liquidation of the debt or the length and nature of those services are not respectively limited and defined.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Involuntary servitude</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “involuntary servitude” includes a condition of servitude induced by means of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any scheme, plan, or pattern intended to cause a person to believe that, if the person did not enter into or continue in such condition, that person or another person would suffer serious harm or physical restraint; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the abuse or threatened abuse of the legal process.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking” means the standards set forth in <ref>section 7106 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> any assistance under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], other than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assistance under chapter 4 of part II of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> et seq.] in support of programs of nongovernmental organizations that is made available for any program, project, or activity eligible for assistance under chapter 1 of part I of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.];</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assistance under chapter 8 of part I of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2291</ref> et seq.];</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any other narcotics-related assistance under part I of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.] or under chapter 4 or 5 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002360">1</ref> part II of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> et seq., 2347 et seq.], but any such assistance provided under this clause shall be subject to the prior notification procedures applicable to reprogrammings pursuant to section 634A of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2394–1</ref>];</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> disaster relief assistance, including any assistance under chapter 9 of part I of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2292</ref> et seq.];</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> antiterrorism assistance under chapter 8 of part II of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2349aa</ref> et seq.];</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> assistance for refugees;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> humanitarian and other development assistance in support of programs of nongovernmental organizations under chapters 1 and 10 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002361">2</ref> of that Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> any support under subchapter II of chapter 103 of this title relating to the United States International Development Finance Corporation;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> other programs involving trade-related or humanitarian assistance; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> sales, or financing on any terms, under the Arms Export Control Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.], other than sales or financing provided for narcotics-related purposes following notification in accordance with the prior notification procedures applicable to reprogrammings pursuant to section 634A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2394–1</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Severe forms of trafficking in persons</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “severe forms of trafficking in persons” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sex trafficking in which a commercial sex act is induced by force, fraud, or coercion, or in which the person induced to perform such act has not attained 18 years of age; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the recruitment, harboring, transportation, provision, or obtaining of a person for labor or services, through the use of force, fraud, or coercion for the purpose of subjection to involuntary servitude, peonage, debt bondage, or slavery.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sex trafficking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “sex trafficking” means the recruitment, harboring, transportation, provision, obtaining, patronizing, or soliciting of a person for the purpose of a commercial sex act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and territories and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Task Force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Task Force” means the Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking established under <ref>section 7103 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States” means the fifty States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victim of a severe form of trafficking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “victim of a severe form of trafficking” means a person subject to an act or practice described in paragraph (9) <sup>2</sup>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victim of trafficking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “victim of trafficking” means a person subjected to an act or practice described in paragraph (9) or (10) <sup>2</sup>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(18)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grounds related to human trafficking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “grounds related to human trafficking” means grounds related to the criteria for inadmissibility to the United States described in subsection (a)(2)(H) of <ref>section 1182 of title 8</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 103</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1469</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–193, § 8(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2887</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title III, § 304(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5087</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII, § 1212(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 143</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 239</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. F, title VI, § 1470(p)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3518</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–427, § 2</ref>, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299R(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4028</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7103.</num>
<heading> Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall establish an Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall appoint the members of the Task Force, which shall include the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, the United States Trade Representative, and such other officials as may be designated by the President.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Task Force shall be chaired by the Secretary of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities of the Task Force</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Task Force shall carry out the following activities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Coordinate the implementation of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Measure and evaluate progress of the United States and other countries in the areas of trafficking prevention, protection, and assistance to victims of trafficking, and prosecution and enforcement against traffickers, including the role of public corruption in facilitating trafficking. The Task Force shall have primary responsibility for assisting the Secretary of State in the preparation of the reports described in <ref>section 7107 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Expand interagency procedures to collect and organize data, including significant research and resource information on domestic and international trafficking and providing an annual report on the case referrals received from the national human trafficking hotline by Federal departments and agencies. Any data collection procedures and reporting requirements established under this subsection shall respect the confidentiality of victims of trafficking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Engage in efforts to facilitate cooperation among countries of origin, transit, and destination. Such efforts shall aim to strengthen local and regional capacities to prevent trafficking, prosecute traffickers and assist trafficking victims, and shall include initiatives to enhance cooperative efforts between destination countries and countries of origin and assist in the appropriate reintegration of stateless victims of trafficking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Examine the role of the international “sex tourism” industry in the trafficking of persons and in the sexual exploitation of women and children around the world.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Engage in consultation and advocacy with governmental and nongovernmental organizations, among other entities, to advance the purposes of this chapter, and make reasonable efforts to distribute information to enable all relevant Federal Government agencies to publicize the National Human Trafficking Resource Center Hotline on their websites, in all headquarters offices, and in all field offices throughout the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than <date date="2004-05-01">May 1, 2004</date>, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on Foreign Affairs <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002362">1</ref> the Committee on Financial Services,, <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002363">2</ref> and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, a report on Federal agencies that are implementing any provision of this chapter, or any amendment made by this chapter, which shall include, at a minimum, information on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of persons who received benefits or other services under subsections (b) and (f) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002364">3</ref> of <ref>section 7105 of this title</ref> in connection with programs or activities funded or administered by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Labor, the Attorney General, the Board of Directors of the Legal Services Corporation, and other appropriate Federal agencies during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of persons who have been granted continued presence in the United States under <ref>section 7105(c)(3) of this title</ref> during the preceding fiscal year and the mean and median time taken to adjudicate applications submitted under such section, including the time from the receipt of an application by law enforcement to the issuance of continued presence, and a description of any efforts being taken to reduce the adjudication and processing time while ensuring the safe and competent processing of the applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number of persons who have applied for, been granted, or been denied a visa or otherwise provided status under subparagraph (T)(i) or (U)(i) of <ref>section 1101(a)(15) of title 8</ref> during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the number of persons who have applied for, been granted, or been denied a visa or status under clause (ii) of <ref>section 1101(a)(15)(T) of title 8</ref> during the preceding fiscal year, broken down by the number of such persons described in subclauses (I), (II), and (III) of such clause (ii);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the amount of Federal funds expended in direct benefits paid to individuals described in subparagraph (D) in conjunction with T visa status;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the number of persons who have applied for, been granted, or been denied a visa or status under <ref>section 1101(a)(15)(U)(i) of title 8</ref> during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the mean and median time in which it takes to adjudicate applications submitted under the provisions of law set forth in subparagraph (C), including the time between the receipt of an application and the issuance of a visa and work authorization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> any efforts being taken to reduce the adjudication and processing time, while ensuring the safe and competent processing of the applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the number of persons who have been charged or convicted under one or more of sections 1581, 1583, 1584, 1589, 1590, 1591, 1592, or 1594 of title 18 during the preceding fiscal year and the sentences imposed against each such person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the amount, recipient, and purpose of each grant issued by any Federal agency to carry out the purposes of sections 7104 and 7105 of this title, or <ref>section 2152d of this title</ref>, during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> the nature of training conducted pursuant to <ref>section 7105(c)(4) of this title</ref> during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> the amount, recipient, and purpose of each grant under sections 20702 and 20705 of title 34; <sup>3</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<chapeau> activities by the Department of Defense to combat trafficking in persons, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> educational efforts for, and disciplinary actions taken against, members of the United States Armed Forces;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the development of materials used to train the armed forces of foreign countries;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> all known trafficking in persons cases reported to the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> efforts to ensure that United States Government contractors and their employees or United States Government subcontractors and their employees do not engage in trafficking in persons; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> all trafficking in persons activities of contractors reported to the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<chapeau> activities or actions by Federal departments and agencies to enforce—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content><ref>section 7104(g) of this title</ref> and any similar law, regulation, or policy relating to United States Government contractors and their employees or United States Government subcontractors and their employees that engage in severe forms of trafficking in persons, the procurement of commercial sex acts, or the use of forced labor, including debt bondage;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content><ref>section 1307 of title 19</ref> (relating to prohibition on importation of convict-made goods), including any determinations by the Secretary of Homeland Security to waive the restrictions of such section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> prohibitions on the procurement by the United States Government of items or services produced by slave labor, consistent with Executive Order 13107 (<date date="1998-12-10">December 10, 1998</date>);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> the activities undertaken by the Senior Policy Operating Group to carry out its responsibilities under subsection (g); and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002365">4</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> the activities undertaken by Federal agencies to train appropriate State, tribal, and local government and law enforcement officials to identify victims of severe forms of trafficking, including both sex and labor trafficking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(Q)</num>
<chapeau> the activities undertaken by Federal agencies in cooperation with State, tribal, and local law enforcement officials to identify, investigate, and prosecute offenses under sections 1581, 1583, 1584, 1589, 1590, 1591, 1592, 1594, 2251, 2251A, 2421, 2422, and 2423 of title 18, or equivalent State offenses, including, in each fiscal year—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number, age, gender, country of origin, and citizenship status of victims identified for each offense;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of individuals charged, and the number of individuals convicted, under each offense;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the number of individuals referred for prosecution for State offenses, including offenses relating to the purchasing of commercial sex acts;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the number of victims granted continued presence in the United States under <ref>section 7105(c)(3) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the number of victims granted a visa or otherwise provided status under subparagraph (T)(i) or (U)(i) of <ref>section 1101(a)(15) of title 8</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the number of individuals required by a court order to pay restitution in connection with a violation of each offense under title 18, the amount of restitution required to be paid under each such order, and the amount of restitution actually paid pursuant to each such order;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> the age, gender, race, country of origin, country of citizenship, and description of the role in the offense of individuals convicted under each offense; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> the number of convictions obtained under chapter 77 of title 18, aggregated separately by the form of offense committed with respect to the victim, including recruiting, enticing, harboring, transporting, providing, obtaining, advertising, maintaining, patronizing, or soliciting a human trafficking victim;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(R)</num>
<content> the activities undertaken by the Department of Justice and the Department of Health and Human Services to meet the specific needs of minor victims of domestic trafficking, including actions taken pursuant to subsection (f) and section 20702(a) <sup>3</sup> of title 34, and the steps taken to increase cooperation among Federal agencies to ensure the effective and efficient use of programs for which the victims are eligible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(S)</num>
<content> tactics and strategies employed by human trafficking task forces sponsored by the Department of Justice to reduce demand for trafficking victims;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(T)</num>
<content> the efforts of the United States to eliminate money laundering related to human trafficking and the number of investigations, arrests, indictments, and convictions in money laundering cases with a nexus to human trafficking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(U)</num>
<content> with respect to applications described in subparagraph (B), (C), (D), or (F), when available, if the application was denied, the reason for the denial and the length of time it took for the denial to be issued; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(V)</num>
<chapeau> disaggregated data regarding—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of victims trafficked by third parties and by family members;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> victims trafficked by victim age; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> victims trafficked by the type of trafficking.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office To Monitor and Combat Trafficking</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall establish within the Department of State an Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking, which shall provide assistance to the Task Force. Any such Office shall be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, with the rank of Ambassador-at-Large. The Director shall have the primary responsibility for assisting the Secretary of State in carrying out the purposes of this chapter and may have additional responsibilities as determined by the Secretary. The Director shall consult with nongovernmental organizations and multilateral organizations, and with trafficking victims or other affected persons. The Director shall have the authority to take evidence in public hearings or by other means. The agencies represented on the Task Force are authorized to provide staff to the Office on a nonreimbursable basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Director shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all policy, funding, and programming decisions regarding funds made available for trafficking in persons programs that are centrally controlled by the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> coordinating any trafficking in persons programs of the Department of State or the United States Agency for International Development that are not centrally controlled by the Director.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional strategies for combating trafficking in persons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each regional bureau in the Department of State shall contribute to the realization of the anti-trafficking goals and objectives of the Secretary of State. Each year, in cooperation with the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons, each regional bureau shall submit a list of anti-trafficking goals and objectives to the Secretary of State for each country in the geographic area of responsibilities of the regional bureau. Host governments shall be informed of the goals and objectives for their particular country and, to the extent possible, host government officials should be consulted regarding the goals and objectives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Senior Policy Operating Group</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There shall be established within the executive branch a Senior Policy Operating Group.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership; related matters</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Operating Group shall consist of the senior officials designated as representatives of the appointed members of the Task Force (pursuant to Executive Order No. 13257 of <date date="2002-02-13">February 13, 2002</date>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Operating Group shall be chaired by the Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking of the Department of State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Operating Group shall meet on a regular basis at the call of the Chairperson.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Operating Group shall coordinate activities of Federal departments and agencies regarding policies (including grants and grant policies) involving the international trafficking in persons and the implementation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each Federal department or agency represented on the Operating Group shall fully share all information with such Group regarding the department or agency’s plans, before and after final agency decisions are made, on all matters relating to grants, grant policies, and other significant actions regarding the international trafficking in persons and the implementation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2003-12-19">December 19, 2003</date>, the President shall promulgate regulations to implement this section, including regulations to carry out paragraph (4).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 105</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1473</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), (c)(1), <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2880</ref>, 2881; <ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, title II, § 205, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3564</ref>, 3571; <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title I</ref>, §§ 101, 102, title II, § 231, title III, § 304(a), <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5045</ref>, 5072, 5087; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVII, § 1707</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2098</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII</ref>, §§ 1201, 1203(a), 1231, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 136</ref>, 138, 144; <ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 259</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–392</ref>, §§ 16, 18(a), <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5257</ref>, 5258; <ref>Pub. L. 115–425, title I, § 121(a)</ref>, title II, § 201, <date date="2019-01-08">Jan. 8, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5478</ref>, 5482; <ref>Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(85)</ref>, div. C, title XXXV, § 3562, div. F, title LXXI, § 7154(b), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1553</ref>, 2009, 2260; <ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7103a.</num>
<heading> Creating, building, and strengthening partnerships against significant trafficking in persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Declaration of purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to promote collaboration and cooperation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> between the United States Government and governments listed on the annual Trafficking in Persons Report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> between foreign governments and civil society actors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> between the United States Government and private sector entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnerships</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Director of the office established pursuant to <ref>section 7103(e)(1) of this title</ref>, in coordination and cooperation with other officials at the Department of State, officials at the Department of Labor, and other relevant officials of the United States Government, shall promote, build, and sustain partnerships between the United States Government and private entities, including foundations, universities, corporations, community-based organizations, and other nongovernmental organizations, to ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> United States citizens do not use any item, product, or material produced or extracted with the use and labor from victims of severe forms of trafficking; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such entities do not contribute to trafficking in persons involving sexual exploitation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program to address emergency situations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, acting through the Director established pursuant to <ref>section 7103(e)(1) of this title</ref>, is authorized to establish a fund to assist foreign governments in meeting unexpected, urgent needs in prevention of trafficking in persons, protection of victims, and prosecution of trafficking offenders.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Child protection compacts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Secretary of Labor, and the heads of other relevant agencies, is authorized to provide assistance under this section for each country that enters into a child protection compact with the United States to support policies and programs that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prevent and respond to violence, exploitation, and abuse against children; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> measurably reduce the trafficking of minors by building sustainable and effective systems of justice, prevention, and protection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A child protection compact under this subsection shall establish a multi-year plan for achieving shared objectives in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter. The compact should take into account, if applicable, the national child protection strategies and national action plans for human trafficking of a country, and shall describe—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the specific objectives the foreign government and the United States Government expect to achieve during the term of the compact;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the responsibilities of the foreign government and the United States Government in the achievement of such objectives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the particular programs or initiatives to be undertaken in the achievement of such objectives and the amount of funding to be allocated to each program or initiative by both countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> regular outcome indicators to monitor and measure progress toward achieving such objectives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a multi-year financial plan, including the estimated amount of contributions by the United States Government and the foreign government, and proposed mechanisms to implement the plan and provide oversight;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> how a country strategy will be developed to sustain progress made toward achieving such objectives after expiration of the compact; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> how child protection data will be collected, tracked, and managed to provide strengthened case management and policy planning.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Assistance under this subsection may be provided in the form of grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts to or with national governments, regional or local governmental units, or non-governmental organizations or private entities with expertise in the protection of victims of severe forms of trafficking in persons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the agencies set forth in paragraph (1) and relevant officers of the Department of Justice, shall select countries with which to enter into child protection compacts. The selection of countries under this paragraph shall be based on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the selection criteria set forth in paragraph (5); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> objective, documented, and quantifiable indicators, to the maximum extent possible.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A country shall be selected under paragraph (4) on the basis of criteria developed by the Secretary of State in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the Secretary of Labor. Such criteria shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a documented high prevalence of trafficking in persons within the country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> demonstrated political motivation and sustained commitment by the government of such country to undertake meaningful measures to address severe forms of trafficking in persons, including prevention, protection of victims, and the enactment and enforcement of anti-trafficking laws against perpetrators.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension and termination of assistance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary may suspend or terminate assistance provided under this subsection in whole or in part for a country or entity if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the country or entity is engaged in activities that are contrary to the national security interests of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the country or entity has engaged in a pattern of actions inconsistent with the criteria used to determine the eligibility of the country or entity, as the case may be; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the country or entity has failed to adhere to its responsibilities under the Compact.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reinstatement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may reinstate assistance for a country or entity suspended or terminated under this paragraph only if the Secretary determines that the country or entity has demonstrated a commitment to correcting each condition for which assistance was suspended or terminated under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 105A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII, § 1202</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 136</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7103b.</num>
<heading> Survivors of Human Trafficking Empowerment Act</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “Survivors of Human Trafficking Empowerment Act”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the United States Advisory Council on Human Trafficking (referred to in this section as the “Council”), which shall provide advice and recommendations to the Senior Policy Operating Group established under <ref>section 7103(g) of this title</ref> (referred to in this section as the “Group”) and the President’s Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking established under section 7103(a) of such title (referred to in this section as the “Task Force”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Council shall be composed of not less than 8 and not more than 14 individuals who are survivors of human trafficking.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representation of survivors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To the extent practicable, members of the Council shall be survivors of trafficking, who shall accurately reflect the diverse backgrounds of survivors of trafficking, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> survivors of sex trafficking and survivors of labor trafficking; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> survivors who are United States citizens and survivors who are aliens lawfully present in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, the President shall appoint the members of the Council.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term; reappointment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each member of the Council shall serve for a term of 2 years and may be reappointed by the President to serve 1 additional 2-year term.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Council shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be a nongovernmental advisory body to the Group;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> meet, at its own discretion or at the request of the Group, not less frequently than annually to review Federal Government policy and programs intended to combat human trafficking, including programs relating to the provision of services for victims and serve as a point of contact for Federal agencies reaching out to human trafficking survivors for input on programming and policies relating to human trafficking in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> formulate assessments and recommendations to ensure that policy and programming efforts of the Federal Government conform, to the extent practicable, to the best practices in the field of human trafficking prevention; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> meet with the Group not less frequently than annually, and not later than 45 days before a meeting with the Task Force, to formally present the findings and recommendations of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, and each year thereafter until the date described in subsection (h),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002366">1</ref> the Council shall submit a report that contains the findings derived from the reviews conducted pursuant to subsection (d)(2) to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the chair of the Task Force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the members of the Group;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committees on Foreign Affairs, Homeland Security, Appropriations, and the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Committees on Foreign Relations, Appropriations, Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Judiciary of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employee status</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Members of the Council—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall not be considered employees of the Federal Government for any purpose;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with the applicable provisions under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may each receive compensation for each day such member is engaged in the actual performance of the duties of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplicability of FACA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Council shall not be subject to the requirements under the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).<sup>1</sup></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 243</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–425, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="2019-01-08">Jan. 8, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5477</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299R(c)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4027</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–348, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7104.</num>
<heading> Prevention of trafficking</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic alternatives to prevent and deter trafficking</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall establish and carry out international initiatives to enhance economic opportunity for potential victims of trafficking as a method to deter trafficking. Such initiatives may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> microcredit lending programs, training in business development, skills training, and job counseling;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> programs to promote women’s participation in economic decisionmaking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> programs to keep children, especially girls, in elementary and secondary schools, and to educate persons who have been victims of trafficking;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> development of educational curricula regarding the dangers of trafficking; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> grants to nongovernmental organizations to accelerate and advance the political, economic, social, and educational roles and capacities of women in their countries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public awareness and information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President, acting through the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of State, shall establish and carry out programs to increase public awareness, particularly among potential victims of trafficking, of the dangers of trafficking and the protections that are available for victims of trafficking.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants to assist in the recognition of trafficking</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In this paragraph:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> ESEA terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The terms “elementary school”, “local educational agency”, “other staff”, and “secondary school” have the meanings given the terms in <ref>section 7801 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> High-intensity child sex trafficking area</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “high-intensity child sex trafficking area” means a metropolitan area designated by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation as having a high rate of children involved in sex trafficking.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Labor trafficking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “labor trafficking” means conduct described in section 7102(9)(B) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002367">1</ref> of this title.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> School staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “school staff” means teachers, nurses, school leaders and administrators, and other staff at elementary schools and secondary schools.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sex trafficking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “sex trafficking” means the conduct described in section 7102(9)(A) <sup>1</sup> of this title.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Education and the Secretary of Labor, may award grants to local educational agencies, in partnership with a nonprofit, nongovernmental agency, to establish, expand, and support programs—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to educate school staff to recognize and respond to signs of labor trafficking and sex trafficking; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to provide age-appropriate information to students on how to avoid becoming victims of labor trafficking and sex trafficking.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Amounts awarded under this paragraph shall be used for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> education regarding—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> avoiding becoming victims of labor trafficking and sex trafficking;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> indicators that an individual is a victim or potential victim of labor trafficking or sex trafficking;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> options and procedures for referring such an individual, as appropriate, to information on such trafficking and services available for victims of such trafficking;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> reporting requirements and procedures in accordance with applicable Federal and State law; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> how to carry out activities authorized under subparagraph (A)(ii); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a plan, developed and implemented in consultation with local law enforcement agencies, to ensure the safety of school staff and students reporting such trafficking.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In awarding grants under this paragraph, the Secretary shall give priority to local educational agencies serving a high-intensity child sex trafficking area.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Border interdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall establish and carry out programs of border interdiction outside the United States. Such programs shall include providing grants to foreign nongovernmental organizations that provide for transit shelters operating at key border crossings and that help train survivors of trafficking in persons to educate and train border guards and officials, and other local law enforcement officials, to identify traffickers and victims of severe forms of trafficking, and the appropriate manner in which to treat such victims. Such programs shall also include, to the extent appropriate, monitoring by such survivors of trafficking in persons of the implementation of border interdiction programs, including helping in the identification of such victims to stop the cross-border transit of victims. The President shall ensure that any program established under this subsection provides the opportunity for any trafficking victim who is freed to return to his or her previous residence if the victim so chooses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International media</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall establish and carry out programs that support the production of television and radio programs, including documentaries, to inform vulnerable populations overseas of the dangers of trafficking, and to increase awareness of the public in countries of destination regarding the slave-like practices and other human rights abuses involved in trafficking, including fostering linkages between individuals working in the media in different countries to determine the best methods for informing such populations through such media.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Combating international sex tourism</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development and dissemination of materials</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President, pursuant to such regulations as may be prescribed, shall ensure that materials are developed and disseminated to alert travelers that sex tourism (as described in subsections (b) through (f) of <ref>section 2423 of title 18</ref>) is illegal, will be prosecuted, and presents dangers to those involved. Such materials shall be disseminated to individuals traveling to foreign destinations where the President determines that sex tourism is significant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring of compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall monitor compliance with the requirements of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Feasibility report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2003-12-19">December 19, 2003</date>, the President shall transmit to the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the Senate a report that describes the feasibility of such United States Government materials being disseminated through public-private partnerships to individuals traveling to foreign destinations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall consult with appropriate nongovernmental organizations with respect to the establishment and conduct of initiatives and programs described in subsections (a) through (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of certain grants, contracts and cooperative agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall ensure that any grant, contract, or cooperative agreement provided or entered into by a Federal department or agency under which funds are to be provided to a private entity, in whole or in part, shall include a condition that authorizes the department or agency to terminate the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, or take any of the other remedial actions authorized under <ref>section 7104b(c) of this title</ref>, without penalty, if the grantee or any subgrantee, or the contractor or any subcontractor, engages in, or uses labor recruiters, brokers, or other agents who engage in—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> severe forms of trafficking in persons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the procurement of a commercial sex act during the period of time that the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement is in effect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the use of forced labor in the performance of the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> acts that directly support or advance trafficking in persons, including the following acts:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Destroying, concealing, removing, confiscating, or otherwise denying an employee access to that employee’s identity or immigration documents.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Failing to provide return transportation or pay for return transportation costs to an employee from a country outside the United States to the country from which the employee was recruited upon the end of employment if requested by the employee, unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> exempted from the requirement to provide or pay for such return transportation by the Federal department or agency providing or entering into the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the employee is a victim of human trafficking seeking victim services or legal redress in the country of employment or a witness in a human trafficking enforcement action.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Soliciting a person for the purpose of employment, or offering employment, by means of materially false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises regarding that employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Charging recruited employees placement or recruitment fees.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Providing or arranging housing that fails to meet the host country housing and safety standards.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prevention of trafficking in conjunction with post-conflict and humanitarian emergency assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Agency for International Development, the Department of State, and the Department of Defense shall incorporate anti-trafficking and protection measures for vulnerable populations, particularly women and children, into their post-conflict and humanitarian emergency assistance and program activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional measures to prevent and deter trafficking</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall establish and carry out programs to prevent and deter trafficking in persons, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> technical assistance and other support to improve the capacity of foreign governments to investigate, identify, and carry out inspections of private entities, including labor recruitment centers, at which trafficking victims may be exploited, particularly exploitation involving forced and child labor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> technical assistance and other support for foreign governments and nongovernmental organizations to provide immigrant populations with information, in the native languages of the major immigrant groups of such populations, regarding the rights of such populations in the foreign country and local in-country nongovernmental organization-operated hotlines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> technical assistance to provide legal frameworks and other programs to foreign governments and nongovernmental organizations to ensure that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> foreign migrant workers are provided the same protection as nationals of the foreign country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> labor recruitment firms are regulated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> workers providing domestic services in households are provided protection under labor rights laws; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> assistance to foreign governments to register vulnerable populations as citizens or nationals of the country to reduce the ability of traffickers to exploit such populations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prevention of child trafficking through child marriage</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall establish and implement a multi-year, multi-sectoral strategy—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to prevent child marriage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote the empowerment of girls at risk of child marriage in developing countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that should address the unique needs, vulnerabilities, and potential of girls younger than 18 years of age in developing countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> that targets areas in developing countries with high prevalence of child marriage; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> that includes diplomatic and programmatic initiatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency action to prevent funding of human trafficking</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">At the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Labor, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall each submit a report to the Administrator of General Services that includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the name and contact information of the individual within the agency’s Office of Legal Counsel or Office of Acquisition Policy who is responsible for overseeing the implementation of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> subsection (g);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> title XVII of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 7104a</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any regulation in the Federal Acquisition Regulation (48 C.F.R. 1 et seq.) that is related to any subject matter referred to in clause (i) or (ii);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> agency action to ensure that contractors are educated on the applicable laws and regulations listed in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> agency action to ensure that the acquisition workforce and agency officials understand implementation of the laws and regulations listed in subparagraph (A), including best practices for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> ensuring compliance with such laws and regulations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assessing the serious, repeated, willful, or pervasive nature of any violation of such laws or regulations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> evaluating steps contractors have taken to correct any such violation;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of contracts containing language referring to the laws and regulations listed in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of contracts that did not contain any language referring to such laws and regulations;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of allegations of severe forms of trafficking in persons received; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the source type of the allegation (such as contractor, subcontractor, employee of contractor or subcontractor, or an individual outside of the contract);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of such allegations investigated by the agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a summary of any findings from such investigations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any improvements recommended by the agency to prevent such conduct from recurring;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of such allegations referred to the Attorney General for prosecution under <ref>section 3271 of title 18</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the outcomes of such referrals;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> any remedial action taken as a result of such investigation, including whether—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a contractor or subcontractor (at any tier) was debarred or suspended due to a violation of a law or regulation relating to severe forms of trafficking in persons; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a contract was terminated pursuant to subsection (g) as a result of such violation;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any other assistance offered to agency contractors to ensure compliance with a law or regulation relating to severe forms of trafficking in persons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> any interagency meetings or data sharing regarding suspended or disbarred contractors or subcontractors (at any tier) for severe forms of trafficking in persons; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> any contract with a contractor or subcontractor (at any tier) located outside the United States and the country location, where safe to reveal location, for each such contractor or subcontractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information regarding human trafficking-related visa denials</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall ensure that the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons and the Bureau of Diplomatic Security of the Department of State receive timely and regular information regarding United States visa denials based, in whole or in part, on grounds related to human trafficking.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decisions regarding allocation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall ensure that decisions regarding the allocation of resources of the Department of State related to combating human trafficking and to law enforcement presence at United States diplomatic and consular posts appropriately take into account—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the information described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the information included in the most recent report submitted in accordance with <ref>section 7107(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 106</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–193, § 3</ref>, <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2875</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, title II, § 201(b), <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3560</ref>, 3569; <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5046</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVII, § 1702</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2093</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII, § 1207(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 141</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–425, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a), 112, <date date="2019-01-08">Jan. 8, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5473</ref>, 5476; <ref>Pub. L. 115–427, § 4</ref>, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299R(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4027</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7104a.</num>
<heading> Compliance plan and certification requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of an executive agency may not provide or enter into a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement if the estimated value of the services required to be performed under the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement outside the United States exceeds $500,000, unless a duly designated representative of the recipient of such grant, contract, or cooperative agreement certifies to the contracting or grant officer prior to receiving an award and on an annual basis thereafter, after having conducted due diligence, that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the recipient has implemented a plan to prevent the activities described in <ref>section 7104(g) of this title</ref>, as amended by section 1702, and is in compliance with that plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the recipient has implemented procedures to prevent any activities described in such <ref>section 7104(g) of this title</ref> and to monitor, detect, and terminate any subcontractor, subgrantee, or employee of the recipient engaging in any activities described in such section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to the best of the representative’s knowledge, neither the recipient, nor any subcontractor or subgrantee of the recipient or any agent of the recipient or of such a subcontractor or subgrantee, is engaged in any of the activities described in such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any plan or procedures implemented pursuant to subsection (a) shall be appropriate to the size and complexity of the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement and to the nature and scope of its activities, including the number of non-United States citizens expected to be employed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The recipient shall provide a copy of the plan to the contracting or grant officer upon request, and as appropriate, shall post the useful and relevant contents of the plan or related materials on its website and at the workplace.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Administrator for the United States Agency for International Development, and the heads of such other executive agencies as the President deems appropriate, shall establish minimum requirements for contractor plans and procedures to be implemented pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVII, § 1703</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2094</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7104b.</num>
<heading> Monitoring and investigation of trafficking in persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referral and investigation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referral</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the contracting or grant officer of an executive agency for a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement receives credible information that a recipient of the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement; any subgrantee or subcontractor of the recipient; or any agent of the recipient or of such a subgrantee or subcontractor, has engaged in an activity described in <ref>section 7104(g) of this title</ref>, as amended by section 1702, including a report from a contracting officer representative, an auditor, an alleged victim or victim’s representative, or any other credible source, the contracting or grant officer shall promptly refer the matter to the agency’s Office of Inspector General for investigation. The contracting officer may also direct the contractor to take specific steps to abate an alleged violation or enforce the requirements of a compliance plan implemented pursuant to <ref>section 7104a of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An Inspector General who receives a referral under paragraph (1) or otherwise receives credible information that a recipient of the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement; any subgrantee or subcontractor of the recipient; or any agent of the recipient or of such a subgrantee or subcontractor, has engaged in an activity described in <ref>section 7104(g) of this title</ref>, as amended by section 1702, shall promptly review the referral or information and determine whether to initiate an investigation of the matter. In the event that an Inspector General does not initiate an investigation, the Inspector General shall document the rationale for the decision not to investigate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal investigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the matter is referred to the Department of Justice for criminal prosecution, the Inspector General may suspend any investigation under this subsection pending the outcome of the criminal prosecution. The Inspector General shall notify the head of the executive agency that awarded the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement of an indictment, information, or criminal complaint against the recipient of a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement; any subgrantee or subcontractor of the recipient; or any agent of the recipient or of a subgrantee or subcontractor. If the criminal investigation results in a decision not to prosecute, the Inspector General shall promptly determine whether to resume any investigation that was suspended pursuant to this paragraph. In the event that an Inspector General does not resume an investigation, the Inspector General shall document the rationale for the decision.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon completion of an investigation under subsection (a), the Inspector General shall submit a report on the investigation to the head of the executive agency that awarded the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement. The report shall include the Inspector General’s conclusions regarding whether or not any allegations that the recipient of a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement; any subcontractor or subgrantee of the recipient; or any agent of the recipient or of such a subcontractor or subgrantee, engaged in any of the activities described in <ref>section 7104(g) of this title</ref>, as amended by section 1702, are substantiated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedial actions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Upon receipt of an Inspector General’s report substantiating an allegation that the recipient of a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement; any subgrantee or subcontractor of the recipient; or any agent of the recipient or of a subgrantee or subcontractor, engaged in any of the activities described in <ref>section 7104(g) of this title</ref>, as amended by section 1702, or notification of an indictment, information, or criminal complaint for an offense under subsection (a)(3), the head of agency shall refer the matter to the agency suspension and debarment official and consider taking one or more of the following remedial actions:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Requiring the recipient to remove an employee from the performance of work under the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Requiring the recipient to terminate a subcontract or subgrant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Suspending payments under the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement until such time as the recipient of the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement has taken appropriate remedial action.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Withholding award fees, consistent with the award fee plan, for the performance period in which the agency determined the contractor or subcontractor engaged in any of the activities described in such <ref>section 7104(g) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Declining to exercise available options under the contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Terminating the contract for default or cause, in accordance with the termination clause for the contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings clause</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as limiting the scope of applicable remedies available to the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mitigating factor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Where applicable, the head of an executive agency may consider whether the contractor or grantee had a plan in place under <ref>section 7104a of this title</ref>, and was in compliance with that plan at the time of the violation, as a mitigating factor in determining which remedies, if any, should apply.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aggravating factor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Where applicable, the head of an executive agency may consider the failure of a contractor or grantee to abate an alleged violation or enforce the requirements of a compliance plan when directed by a contracting officer pursuant to subsection (a)(1) as an aggravating factor in determining which remedies, if any, should apply.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of report conclusions in FAPIIS</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The head of an executive agency shall ensure that any substantiated allegation in the report under subsection (b) is included in the Federal Awardee Performance and Integrity Information System (FAPIIS) and that the contractor has an opportunity to respond to any such report in accordance with applicable statutes and regulations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVII, § 1704</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2094</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–211, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-10-17">Oct. 17, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7104c.</num>
<heading> Notification to Inspectors General and cooperation with government</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of an executive agency making or awarding a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement shall require that the recipient of the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> immediately inform the Inspector General of the executive agency of any information it receives from any source that alleges credible information that the recipient; any subcontractor or subgrantee of the recipient; or any agent of the recipient or of such a subcontractor or subgrantee, has engaged in conduct described in <ref>section 7104(g) of this title</ref>, as amended by section 1702 of this Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> fully cooperate with any Federal agencies responsible for audits, investigations, or corrective actions relating to trafficking in persons.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVII, § 1705</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2097</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7104d.</num>
<heading> Rules of construction; effective date</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Excluding section 1706, nothing in this title shall be construed to supersede, enlarge, or diminish the common law or statutory liabilities of any grantee, subgrantee, contractor, subcontractor, or other party covered by section 106(g) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 7104(g)</ref>), as amended by section 1702.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Department of Justice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this title shall be construed as diminishing or otherwise modifying the authority of the Attorney General to investigate activities covered by this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation and effective dates</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracting requirements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Not later than 270 days after <date date="2013-01-02">January 2, 2013</date>, the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall be amended to carry out the requirements of sections 1702, 1703, and 1704(c), and the second sentence of section 1704(a)(1), of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The requirements of sections 1702, 1703, and 1704(c), and the second sentence of section 1704(a)(1), of this title, shall apply to grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements entered into on or after the date that is 270 days after <date date="2013-01-02">January 2, 2013</date>, and to task and delivery orders awarded on or after such date pursuant to contracts entered before, on, or after such date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigative and procedural requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Federal agencies shall implement the requirements of sections 1704, 1705, and 1707 (other than subsection (c) of section 1704) not later than 90 days after <date date="2013-01-02">January 2, 2013</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal law changes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amendments made by section 1706 shall take effect upon the date of enactment and shall apply to conduct taking place on or after such date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVII, § 1708</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2098</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7104e.</num>
<heading> Preventing future trafficking in the United States through receipt of complaints abroad</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall ensure that each diplomatic or consular post or other mission designates an employee to be responsible for receiving information from—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any person who was a victim of a severe form of trafficking in persons (as such term is defined in section 7102(14) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002368">1</ref> of this title) while present in the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any person who has information regarding a victim described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any information received pursuant to subsection (a) shall be transmitted to the Department of Justice, the Department of Labor, the Department of Homeland Security, and to any other relevant Federal agency for appropriate response. The Attorney General, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the head of any other such relevant Federal agency shall establish a process to address any actions to be taken in response to such information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance from foreign governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The employee designated for receiving information pursuant to subsection (a) should coordinate with foreign governments or civil society organizations in the countries of origin of victims of severe forms of trafficking in persons, with the permission of and without compromising the safety of such victims, to ensure that such victims receive any additional support available.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–425, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2019-01-08">Jan. 8, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5474</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7105.</num>
<heading> Protection and assistance for victims of trafficking</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance for victims in other countries</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in consultation with appropriate nongovernmental organizations, shall establish and carry out programs and initiatives in foreign countries to assist in the safe integration, reintegration, or resettlement, as appropriate, of victims of trafficking. Such programs and initiatives shall be designed to meet the appropriate assistance needs of such persons and their children, as identified by the Task Force, and shall be carried out in a manner which takes into account the cross-border, regional, and transnational aspects of trafficking in persons. In addition, such programs and initiatives shall, to the maximum extent practicable, include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Support for local in-country nongovernmental organization-operated hotlines, culturally and linguistically appropriate protective shelters, and regional and international nongovernmental organization networks and databases on trafficking, including support to assist nongovernmental organizations in establishing service centers and systems that are mobile and extend beyond large cities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Support for nongovernmental organizations and advocates to provide legal, social, and other services and assistance to trafficked individuals, particularly those individuals in detention, and by facilitating contact between relevant foreign government agencies and such nongovernmental organizations to facilitate cooperation between the foreign governments and such organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Education and training for trafficked women and girls.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The safe integration or reintegration of trafficked individuals into an appropriate community or family, with full respect for the wishes, dignity, and safety of the trafficked individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Support for developing or increasing programs to assist families of victims in locating, repatriating, and treating their trafficked family members, in assisting the voluntary repatriation of these family members or their integration or resettlement into appropriate communities, and in providing them with treatment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> In cooperation and coordination with relevant organizations, such as the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, the International Organization for Migration, and private nongovernmental organizations that contract with, or receive grants from, the United States Government to assist refugees and internally displaced persons, support for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> increased protections for refugees and internally displaced persons, including outreach and education efforts to prevent such refugees and internally displaced persons from being exploited by traffickers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> performance of best interest determinations for unaccompanied and separated children who come to the attention of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, its partner organizations, or any organization that contracts with the Department of State in order to identify child trafficking victims and to assist their safe integration, reintegration, and resettlement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In establishing and conducting programs and initiatives described in paragraph (1), the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall take all appropriate steps to enhance cooperative efforts among foreign countries, including countries of origin of victims of trafficking, to assist in the integration, reintegration, or resettlement, as appropriate, of victims of trafficking, including stateless victims. In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary and the Administrator shall take all appropriate steps to ensure that cooperative efforts among foreign countries are undertaken on a regional basis and shall brief Congress annually on such efforts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victims in the United States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for benefits and services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding title IV of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 [<ref>8 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.], an alien who is a victim of a severe form of trafficking in persons, or an alien classified as a nonimmigrant under <ref>section 1101(a)(15)(T)(ii) of title 8</ref>, shall be eligible for benefits and services under any Federal or State program or activity funded or administered by any official or agency described in subparagraph (B) to the same extent as an alien who is admitted to the United States as a refugee under <ref>section 1157 of title 8</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to expand benefits and services</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Subject to subparagraph (C) and, in the case of nonentitlement programs, to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Labor, the Board of Directors of the Legal Services Corporation, and the heads of other Federal agencies shall expand benefits and services to victims of severe forms of trafficking in persons in the United States, and aliens classified as a nonimmigrant under <ref>section 1101(a)(15)(T)(ii) of title 8</ref>, without regard to the immigration status of such victims. In the case of nonentitlement programs funded by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, such benefits and services may include services to assist potential victims of trafficking in achieving certification and to assist minor dependent children of victims of severe forms of trafficking in persons or potential victims of trafficking.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National human trafficking hotline</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Beginning in fiscal year 2017, and in each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall make grants for a national communication system to assist victims of severe forms of trafficking in persons in communicating with service providers. The Secretary shall give priority to grant applicants that have experience in providing telephone services to victims of severe forms of trafficking in persons. The contact information of the national human trafficking hotline (including options to reach out to the hotline such as through phone, text, or TTY) shall be posted as follows:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> In a visible place in all Federal buildings.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall seek to coordinate with the owners and operators of aircraft, airports, over-the road buses, bus stations, passenger trains, and passenger railroad stations to place the contact information of the national human trafficking hotline in the restrooms of each such aircraft, airport, over the-road bus, bus station, passenger train, and passenger railroad station operating within the United States.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and in coordination with the heads of such other Federal agencies as may be appropriate, shall place the contact information of the national human trafficking hotline at each port of entry.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of victim of a severe form of trafficking in persons</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For the purposes of this paragraph, the term “victim of a severe form of trafficking in persons” means only a person—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> who has been subjected to an act or practice described in <ref>section 7102(8) of this title</ref> as in effect on <date date="2000-10-28">October 28, 2000</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> who has not attained 18 years of age; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> who is the subject of a certification under subparagraph (E).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2880</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Subject to clause (ii), the certification referred to in subparagraph (C) is a certification by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, after consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, that the person referred to in subparagraph (C)(ii)(II)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is willing to assist in every reasonable way in the investigation and prosecution of severe forms of trafficking in persons or is unable to cooperate with such a request due to physical or psychological trauma; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(aa)</num>
<content> has made a bona fide application for a visa under <ref>section 1101(a)(15)(T) of title 8</ref>, as added by subsection (e), that has not been denied; or</content>
</item>
<item class="indent4">
<num>(bb)</num>
<content> is a person whose continued presence in the United States the Secretary of Homeland Security is ensuring in order to effectuate prosecution of traffickers in persons.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of effectiveness</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A certification referred to in subparagraph (C), with respect to a person described in clause (i)(II)(bb), shall be effective only for so long as the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that the continued presence of such person is necessary to effectuate prosecution of traffickers in persons.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation and prosecution defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">For the purpose of a certification under this subparagraph, the term “investigation and prosecution” includes—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> identification of a person or persons who have committed severe forms of trafficking in persons;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> location and apprehension of such persons;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> testimony at proceedings against such persons; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> responding to and cooperating with requests for evidence and information.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to investigations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In making the certification described in this subparagraph with respect to the assistance to investigation or prosecution described in clause (i)(I), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall consider statements from State and local law enforcement officials that the person referred to in subparagraph (C)(ii)(II) has been willing to assist in every reasonable way with respect to the investigation and prosecution of State and local crimes such as kidnapping, rape, slavery, or other forced labor offenses, where severe forms of trafficking appear to have been involved.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No requirement of official certification for United States citizens and lawful permanent residents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Nothing in this section may be construed to require United States citizens or lawful permanent residents who are victims of severe forms of trafficking to obtain an official certification from the Secretary of Health and Human Services in order to access any of the specialized services described in this subsection or any other Federal benefits and protections to which they are otherwise entitled.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(G)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for interim assistance of children</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Upon receiving credible information that a child described in subparagraph (C)(ii)(I) who is seeking assistance under this paragraph may have been subjected to a severe form of trafficking in persons, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall promptly determine if the child is eligible for interim assistance under this paragraph. The Secretary shall have exclusive authority to make interim eligibility determinations under this clause. A determination of interim eligibility under this clause shall not affect the independent determination whether a child is a victim of a severe form of trafficking.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall notify the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security not later than 24 hours after all interim eligibility determinations have been made under clause (i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Assistance under this paragraph may be provided to individuals determined to be eligible under clause (i) for a period of up to 90 days and may be extended for an additional 30 days.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Long-term assistance for children</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Before the expiration of the period for interim assistance under clause (iii), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall determine if the child referred to in clause (i) is eligible for assistance under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">In making a determination under subclause (I), the Secretary shall consult with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and nongovernmental organizations with expertise on victims of severe form <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002369">1</ref> of trafficking.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(III)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Letter of eligibility</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">If the Secretary, after receiving information the Secretary believes, taken as a whole, indicates that the child is eligible for assistance under this paragraph, the Secretary shall issue a letter of eligibility. The Secretary may not require that the child cooperate with law enforcement as a condition for receiving such letter of eligibility.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(H)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of children for interim assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 24 hours after a Federal, State, or local official discovers that a person who is under 18 years of age may be a victim of a severe form of trafficking in persons, the official shall notify the Secretary of Health and Human Services to facilitate the provision of interim assistance under subparagraph (G).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Attorney General may make grants to States, Indian tribes, units of local government, and nonprofit, nongovernmental victims’ service organizations to develop, expand, or strengthen victim service programs for victims of human trafficking, including programs that provide trauma-informed care or housing options to such victims who are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> between 12 and 24 years of age; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> homeless, in foster care, or involved in the criminal justice system;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> transitioning out of the foster care system; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> women or girls in underserved populations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of grant funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Of amounts made available for grants under this paragraph, there shall be set aside—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> three percent for research, evaluation, and statistics;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 5 percent for training and technical assistance, including increasing capacity and expertise on security for and protection of service providers from intimidation or retaliation for their activities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> one percent for management and administration.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Federal share of a grant made under this paragraph may not exceed 75 percent of the total project cost. In general, this project match requirement may be satisfied by contributions or expenditures committed to improve victim support services that promote victim recovery and reintegration into society, provided that these contributions and expenditures are consistent with applicable grant requirements and approved project scope.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In selecting recipients of grants under this paragraph that are only available for law enforcement operations or task forces, the Attorney General may give priority to any applicant that files an attestation with the Attorney General stating that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the grant funds awarded under this paragraph—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> will be used to assist in the prevention of severe forms of trafficking in persons;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> will be used to strengthen efforts to investigate and prosecute those who knowingly benefit financially from participation in a venture that has engaged in any act of human trafficking;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> will be used to take affirmative measures to avoid arresting, charging, or prosecuting victims of human trafficking for any offense that is the direct result of their victimization; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> will not be used to require a victim of human trafficking to collaborate with law enforcement officers as a condition of access to any shelter or restorative services; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the applicant will provide dedicated resources for anti-human trafficking law enforcement officers for a period that is longer than the duration of the grant received under this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trafficking victim regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2000-10-28">October 28, 2000</date>, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State shall promulgate regulations for law enforcement personnel, immigration officials, and Department of State officials to implement the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protections while in custody</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Victims of severe forms of trafficking, while in the custody of the Federal Government and to the extent practicable, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not be detained in facilities inappropriate to their status as crime victims;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> receive necessary medical care and other assistance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> be provided protection if a victim’s safety is at risk or if there is danger of additional harm by recapture of the victim by a trafficker, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> taking measures to protect trafficked persons and their family members from intimidation and threats of reprisals and reprisals from traffickers and their associates; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ensuring that the names and identifying information of trafficked persons and their family members are not disclosed to the public.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Victims of severe forms of trafficking shall have access to information about their rights and translation services. To the extent practicable, victims of severe forms of trafficking shall have access to information about federally funded or administered anti-trafficking programs that provide services to victims of severe forms of trafficking.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to permit continued presence in the United States</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trafficking victims</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If a Federal law enforcement official files an application stating that an alien is a victim of a severe form of trafficking and may be a potential witness to such trafficking, the Secretary of Homeland Security may permit the alien to remain in the United States to facilitate the investigation and prosecution of those responsible for such crime.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Safety</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">While investigating and prosecuting suspected traffickers, Federal law enforcement officials described in clause (i) shall endeavor to make reasonable efforts to protect the safety of trafficking victims, including taking measures to protect trafficked persons and their family members from intimidation, threats of reprisals, and reprisals from traffickers and their associates.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuation of presence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary shall permit an alien described in clause (i) who has filed a civil action under <ref>section 1595 of title 18</ref> to remain in the United States until such action is concluded. If the Secretary, in consultation with the Attorney General, determines that the alien has failed to exercise due diligence in pursuing such action, the Secretary may revoke the order permitting the alien to remain in the United States.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iv)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Notwithstanding clause (iii), an alien described in such clause may be deported before the conclusion of the administrative and legal proceedings related to a complaint described in such clause if such alien is inadmissible under paragraph (2)(A)(i)(II), (2)(B), (2)(C), (2)(E), (2)(H), (2)(I), (3)(A)(i), (3)(A)(iii), (3)(B), or (3)(C) of <ref>section 1182(a) of title 8</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parole for relatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Law enforcement officials may submit written requests to the Secretary of Homeland Security, in accordance with <ref>section 1229b(b)(6) of title 8</ref>, to permit the parole into the United States of certain relatives of an alien described in subparagraph (A)(i).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and local law enforcement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> develop materials to assist State and local law enforcement officials in working with Federal law enforcement to obtain continued presence for victims of a severe form of trafficking in cases investigated or prosecuted at the State or local level; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> distribute the materials developed under clause (i) to State and local law enforcement officials.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training of Government personnel</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Appropriate personnel of the Department of State, including members of the Service (as such term is defined in <ref>section 3903 of this title</ref>), the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Labor, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and the Department of Justice shall be trained in identifying victims of severe forms of trafficking and providing for the protection of such victims, including juvenile victims. The Attorney General and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall provide training to State and local officials to improve the identification and protection of such victims in order to fulfill the purposes described in section 20708 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002370">2</ref> of title 34.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training components</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Training under this paragraph shall include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a distance learning course on trafficking-in-persons issues and the Department of State’s obligations under this Act, which shall be designed for embassy reporting officers, regional bureaus’ trafficking-in-persons coordinators, and their superiors;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> specific trafficking-in-persons briefings for all ambassadors and deputy chiefs of mission before such individuals depart for their posts;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> at least annual reminders to all personnel referred to in clauses (i) and (ii), including appropriate personnel from other Federal departments and agencies, at each diplomatic or consular post of the Department of State located outside the United States of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> key problems, threats, methods, and warning signs of trafficking in persons specific to the country or jurisdiction in which each such post is located; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> appropriate procedures to report information that any such personnel may acquire about possible cases of trafficking in persons; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a discussion clarifying that an individual who knowingly solicits or patronizes a commercial sex act from a person who was a minor (consistent with <ref>section 1591(c) of title 18</ref>) or was subject to force, fraud, or coercion is guilty of an offense under chapter 77 of title 18 and is a party to a human trafficking offense.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in subsection (c) shall be construed as creating any private cause of action against the United States or its officers or employees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection from removal for certain crime victims</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold">–(4) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section, or in the amendments made by this section, shall be construed as prohibiting the Secretary of Homeland Security from instituting removal proceedings under <ref>section 1229a of title 8</ref> against an alien admitted as a nonimmigrant under <ref>section 1101(a)(15)(T)(i) of title 8</ref>, as added by subsection (e), for conduct committed after the alien’s admission into the United States, or for conduct or a condition that was not disclosed to the Secretary of Homeland Security prior to the alien’s admission as a nonimmigrant under such <ref>section 1101(a)(15)(T)(i) of title 8</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002371">3</ref> Assistance for United States citizens and lawful permanent residents</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall establish a program to assist United States citizens and aliens lawfully admitted for permanent residence (as defined in <ref>section 1101(a)(20) of title 8</ref>) who are victims of severe forms of trafficking. In determining the assistance that would be most beneficial for such victims, the Secretary and the Attorney General shall consult with nongovernmental organizations that provide services to victims of severe forms of trafficking in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of existing programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to specialized services required for victims described in paragraph (1), the program established pursuant to paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> facilitate communication and coordination between the providers of assistance to such victims;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide a means to identify such providers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide a means to make referrals to programs for which such victims are already eligible, including programs administered by the Department of Justice and the Department of Health and Human Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Attorney General may award grants to States, Indian tribes, units of local government, and nonprofit, nongovernmental victim service organizations to develop, expand, and strengthen victim service programs authorized under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum Federal share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Federal share of a grant awarded under this paragraph may not exceed 75 percent of the total costs of the projects described in the application submitted by the grantee.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <sup>3</sup> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On or before October 31 of each year, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees setting forth, with respect to the preceding fiscal year, the number, if any, of otherwise eligible applicants who did not receive visas under <ref>section 1101(a)(15)(T) of title 8</ref>, as added by subsection (e), or who were unable to adjust their status under section 1255(<i>l</i>) of title 8, solely on account of the unavailability of visas due to a limitation imposed by section 1184(<i>o</i>)(2) or 1255(<i>l</i>)(4)(A) of title 8.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 107</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title VI, § 682(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1409</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–193</ref>, §§ 4(a)(1)–(3), 6(a)(2), 8(b)(2), <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2877</ref>, 2880, 2887; <ref>Pub. L. 109–162, title VIII, § 804</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3055</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3560</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title II, § 213(c)</ref>, formerly <ref>Pub. L. 115–393, title V, § 501(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5276</ref>, renumbered <ref>§ 213(c) of Pub. L. 109–164</ref> by <ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title I, § 106(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6205</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title I, § 104</ref>, title II, §§ 205(a)(1), 212, 213(a)(1), (3), <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5046</ref>, 5060, 5063, 5064, 5066; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII</ref>, §§ 1203(b), 1234, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 139</ref>, 146; <ref>Pub. L. 114–22, title I, § 102</ref>, title II, §§ 224, 231, title VI, § 603, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 230</ref>, 250, 259; <ref>Pub. L. 114–271, § 1(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2016-12-14">Dec. 14, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–392, § 18(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5258</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–393, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5272</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–425, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2019-01-08">Jan. 8, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–301, § 2</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–42, div. C, title V, § 545</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 178</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7105a.</num>
<heading> Increasing effectiveness of anti-trafficking programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Awarding of grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In administering funds made available to carry out this Act within and outside the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> solicitations of grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts for such programs shall be made publicly available;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts shall be subject to full and open competition, in accordance with applicable laws; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the internal department or agency review process for such grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts shall not be subject to ad hoc or intermittent review or influence by individuals or organizations outside the United States Government except as provided under paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An applicant desiring a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this Act shall certify that, to the extent practicable, persons or entities providing legal services, social services, health services, or other assistance have completed, or will complete, training in connection with trafficking in persons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If appropriate, applicants should indicate collaboration with nongovernmental organizations, including organizations with expertise in trafficking in persons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evaluation of anti-trafficking programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall establish a system to evaluate the effectiveness and efficiency of the assistance provided under anti-trafficking programs established under this Act on a program-by-program basis in order to maximize the long-term sustainable development impact of such assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (1), the President shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establish performance goals for the assistance described in paragraph (1), expressed in an objective and quantifiable form, to the extent practicable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensure that performance indicators are used for programs authorized under this Act to measure and assess the achievement of the performance goals described in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide a basis for recommendations for adjustments to the assistance described in paragraph (1) to enhance the impact of such assistance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> ensure that evaluations are conducted by subject matter experts in and outside the United States Government, to the extent practicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Targeted use of anti-trafficking programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In providing assistance under this chapter, the President should take into account the priorities and country assessments contained in the most recent report submitted by the Secretary of State to Congress pursuant to <ref>section 7107(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency with other programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall ensure that the design, monitoring, and evaluation of United States assistance programs for emergency relief, development, and poverty alleviation under part I and chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq. and 2346 et seq.) and other similar United States assistance programs are consistent with United States policies and other United States programs relating to combating trafficking in persons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For each of the fiscal years 2008 through 2011, not more than 5 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this chapter may be used to carry out this section, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> evaluations of promising anti-trafficking programs and projects funded by the disbursing agency pursuant to this Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> evaluations of emerging problems or global trends.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 107A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5047</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7105b.</num>
<heading> Improving domestic victim screening procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Victim screening tools</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2018-10-01">October 1, 2018</date>, the Attorney General shall compile and disseminate, to all grantees who are awarded grants to provide victims’ services under subsection (b) or (f) of <ref>section 7105 of this title</ref>, information about reliable and effective tools for the identification of victims of human trafficking.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of screening procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning not later than <date date="2018-10-01">October 1, 2018</date>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall identify recommended practices for the screening of human trafficking victims and shall encourage the use of such practices by grantees receiving a grant to provide victim services to youth under subsection (b) or (f) of <ref>section 7105 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 107B</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–393, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5273</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7106.</num>
<heading> Minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking applicable to the government of a country of origin, transit, or destination for victims of severe forms of trafficking are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The government of the country should prohibit severe forms of trafficking in persons and punish acts of such trafficking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For the knowing commission of any act of sex trafficking involving force, fraud, coercion, or in which the victim of sex trafficking is a child incapable of giving meaningful consent, or of trafficking which includes rape or kidnapping or which causes a death, the government of the country should prescribe punishment commensurate with that for grave crimes, such as forcible sexual assault.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the knowing commission of any act of a severe form of trafficking in persons, the government of the country should prescribe punishment that is sufficiently stringent to deter and that adequately reflects the heinous nature of the offense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The government of the country should make serious and sustained efforts to eliminate severe forms of trafficking in persons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In determinations under subsection (a)(4), the following factors should be considered as indicia of serious and sustained efforts to eliminate severe forms of trafficking in persons:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whether the government of the country vigorously investigates and prosecutes acts of severe forms of trafficking in persons, and convicts and sentences persons responsible for such acts, that take place wholly or partly within the territory of the country, including, as appropriate, requiring incarceration of individuals convicted of such acts. For purposes of the preceding sentence, suspended or significantly-reduced sentences for convictions of principal actors in cases of severe forms of trafficking in persons shall be considered, on a case-by-case basis, whether to be considered an indicator of serious and sustained efforts to eliminate severe forms of trafficking in persons. After reasonable requests from the Department of State for data regarding investigations, prosecutions, convictions, and sentences, a government which does not provide such data, consistent with a demonstrably increasing capacity of such government to obtain such data, shall be presumed not to have vigorously investigated, prosecuted, convicted or sentenced such acts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Whether the government of the country protects victims of severe forms of trafficking in persons and encourages their assistance in the investigation and prosecution of such trafficking, including provisions for legal alternatives to their removal to countries in which they would face retribution or hardship, and ensures that victims are not inappropriately incarcerated, fined, or otherwise penalized solely for unlawful acts as a direct result of being trafficked, including by providing training to law enforcement and immigration officials regarding the identification and treatment of trafficking victims using approaches that focus on the needs of the victims.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Whether the government of the country has adopted measures to prevent severe forms of trafficking in persons, such as measures to inform and educate the public, including potential victims, about the causes and consequences of severe forms of trafficking in persons, measures to establish the identity of local populations, including birth registration, citizenship, and nationality, measures to ensure that its nationals who are deployed abroad as part of a diplomatic, peacekeeping, or other similar mission do not engage in or facilitate severe forms of trafficking in persons or exploit victims of such trafficking, a transparent system for remediating or punishing such public officials as a deterrent, measures to prevent the use of forced labor or child labor in violation of international standards, effective bilateral, multilateral, or regional information sharing and cooperation arrangements with other countries, and effective policies or laws regulating foreign labor recruiters and holding them civilly and criminally liable for fraudulent recruiting.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Whether the government of the country cooperates with other governments in the investigation and prosecution of severe forms of trafficking in persons and has entered into bilateral, multilateral, or regional law enforcement cooperation and coordination arrangements with other countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Whether the government of the country extradites persons charged with acts of severe forms of trafficking in persons on substantially the same terms and to substantially the same extent as persons charged with other serious crimes (or, to the extent such extradition would be inconsistent with the laws of such country or with international agreements to which the country is a party, whether the government is taking all appropriate measures to modify or replace such laws and treaties so as to permit such extradition).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Whether the government of the country monitors immigration and emigration patterns for evidence of severe forms of trafficking in persons and whether law enforcement agencies of the country respond to any such evidence in a manner that is consistent with the vigorous investigation and prosecution of acts of such trafficking, as well as with the protection of human rights of victims and the internationally recognized human right to leave any country, including one’s own, and to return to one’s own country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Whether the government of the country vigorously investigates, prosecutes, convicts, and sentences public officials, including diplomats and soldiers, who participate in or facilitate severe forms of trafficking in persons, including nationals of the country who are deployed abroad as part of a diplomatic, peacekeeping, or other similar mission who engage in or facilitate severe forms of trafficking in persons or exploit victims of such trafficking, and takes all appropriate measures against officials who condone or enable such trafficking. A government’s failure to appropriately address public allegations against such public officials, especially once such officials have returned to their home countries, shall be considered inaction under these criteria. After reasonable requests from the Department of State for data regarding such investigations, prosecutions, convictions, and sentences, a government which does not provide such data, consistent with a demonstrably increasing capacity of such government to obtain such data, shall be presumed not to have vigorously investigated, prosecuted, convicted, or sentenced such acts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Whether the percentage of victims of severe forms of trafficking in the country that are non-citizens of such countries is insignificant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<chapeau> Whether the government has entered into effective, transparent partnerships, cooperative arrangements, or agreements that have resulted in concrete and measurable outcomes with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> domestic civil society organizations, private sector entities, or international nongovernmental organizations, or into multilateral or regional arrangements or agreements, to assist the government’s efforts to prevent trafficking, protect victims, and punish traffickers; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the United States toward agreed goals and objectives in the collective fight against trafficking.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Whether the government of the country, consistent with the capacity of such government, systematically monitors its efforts to satisfy the criteria described in paragraphs (1) through (8) and makes available publicly a periodic assessment of such efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Whether the government of the country achieves appreciable progress in eliminating severe forms of trafficking when compared to the assessment in the previous year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<chapeau> Whether the government of the country has made serious and sustained efforts to reduce the demand for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> commercial sex acts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> participation in international sex tourism by nationals of the country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 108</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1480</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2881</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 104(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII, § 1204</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 139</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–425, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2019-01-08">Jan. 8, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–427, § 5</ref>, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5505</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7107.</num>
<heading> Actions against governments failing to meet minimum standards</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States not to provide nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance to any government that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> does not comply with minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is not making significant efforts to bring itself into compliance with such standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than June 30 of each year, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the anti-trafficking efforts of the United States and foreign governments according to the minimum standards and criteria enumerated in <ref>section 7106 of this title</ref>, and the nature and scope of trafficking in persons in each country and analysis of the trend lines for individual governmental efforts. The report shall, to the extent concurrent reporting data is available, cover efforts and activities taking place during the period between April 1 of the year preceding the report and March 31 of the year in which the report is made, and should include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a list of those countries, if any, to which the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking are applicable and whose governments fully comply with such standards based only on concrete actions taken by the country that are recorded during the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a list of those countries, if any, to which the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking are applicable and whose governments do not yet fully comply with such standards but are making significant efforts to bring themselves into compliance based only on concrete actions taken by the country (excluding any commitments by the country to take additional future steps during the next year) that are recorded during the reporting period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a list of those countries, if any, to which the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking are applicable and whose governments do not fully comply with such standards and are not making significant efforts to bring themselves into compliance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> information on the measures taken by the United Nations, the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and, as appropriate, other multilateral organizations in which the United States participates, to prevent the involvement of the organization’s employees, contractor personnel, and peacekeeping forces in trafficking in persons or the exploitation of victims of trafficking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> reporting and analysis on the emergence or shifting of global patterns in human trafficking, including data on the number of victims trafficked to, through, or from major source and destination countries, disaggregated by nationality, gender, and age, to the extent possible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> emerging issues in human trafficking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a section entitled “Promising Practices in the Eradication of Trafficking in Persons” to highlight effective practices and use of innovation and technology in prevention, protection, prosecution, and partnerships, including by foreign governments, the private sector, and domestic civil society actors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> for each country included in a different list than the country had been placed in the previous annual report, a detailed explanation of how the concrete actions (or lack of such actions) undertaken (or not undertaken) by the country during the previous reporting period contributed to such change, including a clear linkage between such actions and the minimum standards enumerated in <ref>section 7106 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special watch list</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of list</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than the date on which the determinations described in subsections (c) and (d) are submitted to the appropriate congressional committees in accordance with such subsections, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of countries that the Secretary determines requires special scrutiny during the following year. The list shall be composed of the following countries:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Countries that have been listed pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) in the current annual report and were listed pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) in the previous annual report.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Countries that have been listed pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) pursuant to the current annual report and were listed pursuant to paragraph (1)(C) in the previous annual report.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> Countries that have been listed pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) pursuant to the current annual report, where—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the estimated number of victims of severe forms of trafficking is very significant or is significantly increasing and the country is not taking proportional concrete actions; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> there is a failure to provide evidence of increasing efforts to combat severe forms of trafficking in persons from the previous year, including increased investigations, prosecutions and convictions of trafficking crimes, increased assistance to victims, and decreasing evidence of complicity in severe forms of trafficking by government officials.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than February 1st of each year, the Secretary of State shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees an assessment of the progress that each country on the special watch list described in subparagraph (A) has made since April 1 of the previous year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relation of special watch list to annual trafficking in persons report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A determination that a country shall not be placed on the special watch list described in subparagraph (A) shall not affect in any way the determination to be made in the following year as to whether a country is complying with the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking or whether a country is making significant efforts to bring itself into compliance with such standards.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Countries on special watch list for 2 consecutive years</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Except as provided under clause (ii), a country that is included on the special watch list described in subparagraph (A) for 2 consecutive years after <date date="2008-12-23">December 23, 2008</date>, shall be included on the list of countries described in paragraph (1)(C).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exercise of waiver authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">The President may waive the application of clause (i) for up to 1 year if the President determines, and reports credible evidence to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, that such a waiver is justified because—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the country has a written plan to begin making significant efforts to bring itself into compliance with the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the plan, if implemented, would constitute making such significant efforts; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the country is devoting sufficient resources to implement the plan.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after notifying Congress of each country determined to have met the requirements under subclauses (I) through (III) of subparagraph (D)(ii), the Secretary of State shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> provide a detailed description of the credible information supporting such determination on a publicly available website maintained by the Department of State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> offer to brief the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives on any written plan submitted by the country under subparagraph (D)(ii)(I), with an opportunity to review the written plan.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain countries on special watch list that are downgraded and reinstated on special watch list</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Notwithstanding subparagraphs (D) and (E), a country may not be included on the special watch list described in subparagraph (A)(iii) for more than 1 consecutive year after the country—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> was included on the special watch list described in subparagraph (A)(iii) for—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 2 consecutive years after <date date="2008-12-23">December 23, 2008</date>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any additional years after such date of enactment as a result of the President exercising the waiver authority under subparagraph (D)(ii); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> was subsequently included on the list of countries described in paragraph (1)(C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Significant efforts</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In determinations under paragraph (1) or (2) as to whether the government of a country is making significant efforts to bring itself into compliance with the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking, the Secretary of State shall consider—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the extent to which the country is a country of origin, transit, or destination for severe forms of trafficking;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the extent of noncompliance with the minimum standards by the government and, particularly, the extent to which officials or employees of the government have participated in, facilitated, condoned, or are otherwise complicit in severe forms of trafficking;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> what measures are reasonable to bring the government into compliance with the minimum standards in light of the resources and capabilities of the government.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proof of failure to make significant efforts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In addition to the considerations described in clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of subparagraph (A), in determinations under paragraph (1)(C) as to whether the government of a country is not making significant efforts to bring itself into compliance with the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking, the Secretary of State shall consider, as proof of failure to make significant efforts, a government policy or pattern of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> trafficking;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> trafficking in government-funded programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> forced labor (in government-affiliated medical services, agriculture, forestry, mining, construction, or other sectors);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> sexual slavery in government camps, compounds, or outposts; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> employing or recruiting child soldiers.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002372">1</ref> the extent to which the government of the country is devoting sufficient budgetary resources—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to investigate and prosecute acts of severe trafficking in persons;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to convict and sentence persons responsible for such acts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to obtain restitution for victims of human trafficking;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> the extent to which the government of the country is devoting sufficient budgetary resources—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to protect and support victims of trafficking in persons; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to prevent severe forms of trafficking in persons; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the extent to which the government of the country has consulted with domestic and international civil society organizations that resulted in concrete actions to improve the provision of services to victims of trafficking in persons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action plans for countries upgraded to tier 2 watchlist</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after the release of the annual Trafficking in Persons Report, the Secretary of State, acting through the Ambassador-at-Large of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking and the Assistant Secretary of the appropriate regional bureau, in consultation with appropriate officials from the government of each country described in paragraph (2)(A)(ii), and with the assistance of the United States Ambassador or Charge d’Affaires in each country, shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> prepare an action plan for each country upgraded from Tier 3 to Tier 2 Watchlist to further improve such country’s tier ranking under this subsection; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> present the relevant action plan to the government of each such country.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Each action plan prepared under this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall include specific concrete actions to be taken by the country to substantively address deficiencies preventing the country from meeting Tier 2 standards, based on credible information; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> should be focused on short-term and multi-year goals.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Briefings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Ambassador-at-Large of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking and all appropriate regional Assistant Secretaries shall make themselves available to brief the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives on the implementation of each action plan prepared under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings provision</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed as modifying—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking under <ref>section 7106 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the actions against governments failing to meet minimum standards under this section or the criteria for placement on the Special Watch List under paragraph (2).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not less than 45 days or more than 90 days after the submission, on or after <date date="2003-01-01">January 1, 2003</date>, of an annual report under subsection (b)(1), or an interim report under subsection (b)(2), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a notification of one of the determinations listed in subsection (d) with respect to each foreign country whose government, according to such report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> does not comply with the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not making significant efforts to bring itself into compliance, as described in subsection (b)(1)(C).</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential determinations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The determinations referred to in subsection (c) are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding of nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President has determined that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the United States will not provide nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance to the government of the country for the subsequent fiscal year until such government complies with the minimum standards or makes significant efforts to bring itself into compliance; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a country whose government received no nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance from the United States during the previous fiscal year, the United States will not provide such assistance to the government of the country for the subsequent fiscal year and will not provide funding for participation by officials or employees of such governments in educational and cultural exchange programs for the subsequent fiscal year until such government complies with the minimum standards or makes significant efforts to bring itself into compliance; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the President will instruct the United States Executive Director of each multilateral development bank and of the International Monetary Fund to vote against, and to use the Executive Director’s best efforts to deny, any loan or other utilization of the funds of the respective institution to that country (other than for humanitarian assistance, for trade-related assistance, or for development assistance which directly addresses basic human needs, is not administered by the government of the sanctioned country, and confers no benefit to that government) for the subsequent fiscal year until such government complies with the minimum standards or makes significant efforts to bring itself into compliance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ongoing, multiple, broad-based restrictions on assistance in response to human rights violations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President has determined that such country is already subject to multiple, broad-based restrictions on assistance imposed in significant part in response to human rights abuses and such restrictions are ongoing and are comparable to the restrictions provided in paragraph (1). Such determination shall be accompanied by a description of the specific restriction or restrictions that were the basis for making such determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State has determined that the government of the country has come into compliance with the minimum standards or is making significant efforts to bring itself into compliance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuation of assistance in the national interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding the failure of the government of the country to comply with minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking and to make significant efforts to bring itself into compliance, the President has determined that the provision to the country of nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance or funding for participation in educational and cultural exchange programs, or the multilateral assistance described in paragraph (1)(B), or both, would promote the purposes of this chapter or is otherwise in the national interest of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exercise of waiver authority</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The President may exercise the authority under paragraph (4) with respect to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> all nonhumanitarian, nontrade-related foreign assistance or funding for participation in educational and cultural exchange programs to a country;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all multilateral assistance described in paragraph (1)(B) to a country; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> one or more programs, projects, or activities of such assistance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Avoidance of significant adverse effects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The President shall exercise the authority under paragraph (4) when necessary to avoid significant adverse effects on vulnerable populations, including women and children.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of multilateral development bank</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “multilateral development bank” refers to any of the following institutions: the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the International Development Association, the International Finance Corporation, the Inter-American Development Bank, the Asian Development Bank, the Inter-American Investment Corporation, the African Development Bank, the African Development Fund, the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, and the Multilateral Investment Guaranty Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Together with any notification under subsection (c), the President shall provide a certification by the Secretary of State that, with respect to any assistance described in clause (ii), (iii), or (v) of section 7102(8)(A) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002373">2</ref> of this title, or with respect to any assistance described in section 7102(8)(B) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002373">2</ref> of this title, no assistance is intended to be received or used by any agency or official who has participated in, facilitated, or condoned a severe form of trafficking in persons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent waiver authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After the President has made a determination described in subsection (d)(1) with respect to the government of a country, the President may at any time make a determination described in paragraphs (4) and (5) of subsection (d) to waive, in whole or in part, the measures imposed against the country by the previous determination under subsection (d)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 110</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(e)</ref>, (h), (i), <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2882</ref>, 2884; <ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 104(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3565</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title I</ref>, §§ 107(a), (b), 108(b), <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5049</ref>, 5051; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII</ref>, §§ 1205, 1212(b)(2)(A)(i), <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 139</ref>, 143; <ref>Pub. L. 115–425, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2019-01-08">Jan. 8, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5482</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–427, § 6</ref>, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5505</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299R(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4027</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7108.</num>
<heading> Actions against significant traffickers in persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to sanction significant traffickers in persons</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President may exercise the authorities set forth in <ref>section 1702 of title 50</ref> without regard to <ref>section 1701 of title 50</ref>, or <ref>section 10102 of this title</ref>, in the case of any of the following persons:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any foreign person that plays a significant role in a severe form of trafficking in persons, directly or indirectly in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Foreign persons that materially assist in, or provide financial or technological support for or to, or provide goods or services in support of, activities of a significant foreign trafficker in persons identified pursuant to subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Foreign persons that are owned, controlled, or directed by, or acting for or on behalf of, a significant foreign trafficker identified pursuant to subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Officials of a foreign government who participate in, facilitate, or condone severe forms of trafficking in persons for significant financial gain.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The penalties set forth in <ref>section 1705 of title 50</ref> apply to violations of any license, order, or regulation issued under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress on identification and sanctioning of significant traffickers in persons</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Upon exercising the authority of subsection (a), the President shall report to the appropriate congressional committees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identifying publicly the foreign persons that the President determines are appropriate for sanctions pursuant to this section and the basis for such determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> detailing publicly the sanctions imposed pursuant to this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of sanctions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon suspending or terminating any action imposed under the authority of subsection (a), the President shall report to the committees described in paragraph (1) on such suspension or termination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of classified information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Reports submitted under this subsection may include an annex with classified information regarding the basis for the determination made by the President under paragraph (1)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Law enforcement and intelligence activities not affected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section prohibits or otherwise limits the authorized law enforcement or intelligence activities of the United States, or the law enforcement activities of any State or subdivision thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation of authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may delegate any authority granted by this section, including the authority to designate foreign persons under paragraphs (1)(B) and (1)(C) of subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Promulgation of rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The head of any agency, including the Secretary of Treasury, is authorized to take such actions as may be necessary to carry out any authority delegated by the President pursuant to paragraph (1), including promulgating rules and regulations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Opportunity for review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Such rules and regulations shall include procedures affording an opportunity for a person to be heard in an expeditious manner, either in person or through a representative, for the purpose of seeking changes to or termination of any determination, order, designation or other action associated with the exercise of the authority in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of foreign persons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “foreign person” means any citizen or national of a foreign state or any entity not organized under the laws of the United States, including a foreign government official, but does not include a foreign state.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed as precluding judicial review of the exercise of the authority described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 111</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1484</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–425, title I, § 124</ref>, <date date="2019-01-08">Jan. 8, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5479</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7109.</num>
<heading> Strengthening prosecution and punishment of traffickers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amendment to the Sentencing Guidelines</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Pursuant to its authority under <ref>section 994 of title 28</ref> and in accordance with this section, the United States Sentencing Commission shall review and, if appropriate, amend the sentencing guidelines and policy statements applicable to persons convicted of offenses involving the trafficking of persons including component or related crimes of peonage, involuntary servitude, slave trade offenses, and possession, transfer or sale of false immigration documents in furtherance of trafficking, and the Fair Labor Standards Act [<ref>29 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.] and the Migrant and Seasonal Agricultural Worker Protection Act [<ref>29 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In carrying out this subsection, the Sentencing Commission shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> take all appropriate measures to ensure that these sentencing guidelines and policy statements applicable to the offenses described in paragraph (1) of this subsection are sufficiently stringent to deter and adequately reflect the heinous nature of such offenses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> consider conforming the sentencing guidelines applicable to offenses involving trafficking in persons to the guidelines applicable to peonage, involuntary servitude, and slave trade offenses; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> consider providing sentencing enhancements for those convicted of the offenses described in paragraph (1) of this subsection that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> involve a large number of victims;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> involve a pattern of continued and flagrant violations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> involve the use or threatened use of a dangerous weapon; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> result in the death or bodily injury of any person.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Commission may promulgate the guidelines or amendments under this subsection in accordance with the procedures set forth in section 21(a) of the Sentencing Act of 1987, as though the authority under that Act had not expired.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 112</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1486</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7109a.</num>
<heading> Research on domestic and international trafficking in persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President, acting through the Council of Economic Advisors, the National Research Council of the National Academies, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Attorney General, the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and the Director of National Intelligence, shall carry out research, including by providing grants to nongovernmental organizations, as well as relevant United States Government agencies and international organizations, which furthers the purposes of this chapter and provides data to address the problems identified in the findings of this chapter. Such research initiatives shall, to the maximum extent practicable, include, but not be limited to, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The economic causes and consequences of trafficking in persons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The effectiveness of programs and initiatives funded or administered by Federal agencies to prevent trafficking in persons and to protect and assist victims of trafficking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The interrelationship between trafficking in persons and global health risks, particularly HIV/AIDS.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (b), the interrelationship between trafficking in persons and terrorism, including the use of profits from trafficking in persons to finance terrorism.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> An effective mechanism for quantifying the number of victims of trafficking on a national, regional, and international basis, which shall include, not later than 2 years after <date date="2008-12-23">December 23, 2008</date>, the establishment and maintenance of an integrated database within the Human Smuggling and Trafficking Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The abduction and enslavement of children for use as soldiers, including steps taken to eliminate the abduction and enslavement of children for use as soldiers and recommendations for such further steps as may be necessary to rapidly end the abduction and enslavement of children for use as soldiers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Role of Human Smuggling and Trafficking Center</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The research initiatives described in paragraphs (4) and (5) of subsection (a) shall be carried out by the Human Smuggling and Trafficking Center, established under <ref>section 1777 of title 8</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Database</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The database described in subsection (a)(5) shall be established by combining all applicable data collected by each Federal department and agency represented on the Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking, consistent with the protection of sources and methods, and, to the maximum extent practicable, applicable data from relevant international organizations, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> improve the coordination of the collection of data related to trafficking in persons by each agency of the United States Government that collects such data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promote uniformity of such data collection and standards and systems related to such collection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> undertake a meta-analysis of patterns of trafficking in persons, slavery, and slave-like conditions to develop and analyze global trends in human trafficking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> identify emerging issues in human trafficking and establishing integrated methods to combat them; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> identify research priorities to respond to global patterns and emerging issues.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The database established in accordance with paragraph (2) shall be maintained in consultation with the Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons of the Department of State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 to the Human Smuggling and Trafficking Center for each of the fiscal years 2022 through 2027 to carry out the activities described in this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> AIDS</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “AIDS” means the acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> HIV</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “HIV” means the human immunodeficiency virus, the pathogen that causes AIDS.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> HIV/AIDS</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “HIV/AIDS” means, with respect to an individual, an individual who is infected with HIV or living with AIDS.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 112A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2883</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 104(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title I, § 108(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5050</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII, § 1251(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 155</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–393, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title I, § 105(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7109b.</num>
<heading> Presidential Award for Extraordinary Efforts To Combat Trafficking in Persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of award</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is authorized to establish an award, to be known as the “Presidential Award for Extraordinary Efforts To Combat Trafficking in Persons”, for extraordinary efforts to combat trafficking in persons. To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary of State shall present the award annually to not more than 5 individuals or organizations, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> individuals who are United States citizens or foreign nationals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> United States or foreign nongovernmental organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall establish procedures for selecting recipients of the award authorized under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ceremony</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall host an annual ceremony for recipients of the award authorized under subsection (a) as soon as practicable after the date on which the Secretary submits to Congress the report required under <ref>section 7107(b)(1) of this title</ref>. The Secretary of State may pay the travel costs of each recipient and a guest of each recipient who attends the ceremony.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated, for each of the fiscal years 2022 through 2027, such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 112B</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5051</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title I, § 105(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7110.</num>
<heading> Authorizations of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations in support of the task force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State, for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2021, $13,822,000 for Diplomatic and Consular Programs of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons, which shall be used to carry out sections 7103(e), 7103(f),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002374">1</ref> and 7107 of this title, including for additional personnel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of Health and Human Services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for benefits and assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out the purposes of sections 7104(b) and 7105(b) of this title and <ref>section 628c of title 42</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services $19,500,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2021, of which $3,500,000 is authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year for the National Human Trafficking Hotline.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional benefits for trafficking victims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out the purposes of section 7105(f) <sup>1</sup> of this title, there are authorized to be appropriated $8,000,000 to the Secretary of Health and Human Services for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grants for State improvements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out the purposes of <ref>section 20705a of title 34</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated $4,000,000 to the Secretary of Health and Human Services for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of State</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to combat trafficking</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State, for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2021, $65,000,000, which shall be used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to carry out sections 7104 and 7105(a) of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to carry out <ref>section 2152d of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to assist countries in meeting the minimum standards described in <ref>section 7106 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> for programs and activities on prevention, protection, and prosecution to combat all forms of trafficking in persons internationally, including training activities for law enforcement officers, prosecutors, and members of the judiciary with respect to trafficking in persons at the International Law Enforcement Academies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation of annual country reports on human rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out the purposes of sections 2151n(f) and 2304(h) of this title, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State such sums as may be necessary to include the additional information required by that section in the annual Country Reports on Human Rights Practices.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations to Attorney General</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility for benefits and assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out the purposes of <ref>section 7105(b) of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General $77,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2021.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to foreign countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out the purposes of <ref>section 2152d of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President, acting through the Attorney General and the Secretary of State, $250,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2011 to carry out training activities for law enforcement officers, prosecutors, and members of the judiciary with respect to trafficking in persons at the International Law Enforcement Academies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional benefits for trafficking victims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out the purposes of section 7105(f) <sup>1</sup> of this title, there are authorized to be appropriated $11,000,000 to the Attorney General for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations to President</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign victim assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out the purposes of <ref>section 7104 of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President $7,500,000 for each of the fiscal years 2014 through 2017.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to foreign countries to meet minimum standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out the purposes of <ref>section 2152d of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President $7,500,000 for each of the fiscal years 2014 through 2017.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To carry out the purposes of <ref>section 7109a of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President $2,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2022 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of Labor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out the purposes of <ref>section 7105(b) of this title</ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Labor $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restriction on programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No funds made available to carry out this chapter, or any amendment made by this chapter, may be used to promote, support, or advocate the legalization or practice of prostitution. Nothing in the preceding sentence shall be construed to preclude assistance designed to promote the purposes of this Act by ameliorating the suffering of, or health risks to, victims while they are being trafficked or after they are out of the situation that resulted from such victims being trafficked.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restriction on organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No funds made available to carry out this chapter, or any amendment made by this chapter, may be used to implement any program that targets victims of severe forms of trafficking in persons described in section 7102(9)(A) <sup>1</sup> of this title through any organization that has not stated in either a grant application, a grant agreement, or both, that it does not promote, support, or advocate the legalization or practice of prostitution. The preceding sentence shall not apply to organizations that provide services to individuals solely after they are no longer engaged in activities that resulted from such victims being trafficked.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations to Director of the FBI</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation $15,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2008 through 2011, to remain available until expended, to investigate severe forms of trafficking in persons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of Homeland Security</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Homeland Security,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002375">2</ref> $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2028, to remain available until expended, of which $2,000,000 shall be made available each fiscal year for the establishment of a labor trafficking investigation team within the Department of Homeland Security Center for Countering Human Trafficking, and the remaining funds shall be used for investigations by the Bureau of Immigration and Customs Enforcement of severe forms of trafficking in persons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 113</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1490</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title VI, § 682(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1410</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–193, § 7</ref>, <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2884</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title II, § 213(a)(2)</ref>, title III, § 301, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5065</ref>, 5085; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII</ref>, §§ 1212(b)(2)(A)(ii), 1251(2), <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 143</ref>, 155; <ref>Pub. L. 115–392, § 21</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5259</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–393, title III, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5271</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–425, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, title III, § 301, <date date="2019-01-08">Jan. 8, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5474</ref>, 5487; <ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title I</ref>, §§ 104(b), 105(d)(3), <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6203</ref>, 6204; <ref>Pub. L. 117–348, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7111.</num>
<heading> Report by Secretary of State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">At least 15 days prior to voting for a new or reauthorized peacekeeping mission under the auspices of the United Nations, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, or any other multilateral organization in which the United States participates (or in an emergency, as far in advance as is practicable), the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and any other appropriate congressional committee a report that contains—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of measures taken by the organization to prevent the organization’s employees, contractor personnel, and peacekeeping forces serving in the peacekeeping mission from trafficking in persons, exploiting victims of trafficking, or committing acts of sexual exploitation or abuse, and the measures in place to hold accountable any such individuals who engage in any such acts while participating in the peacekeeping mission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an analysis of the effectiveness of each of the measures referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 104(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–457, title III, § 304(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7112.</num>
<heading> Additional activities to monitor and combat forced labor and child labor</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities of the Department of State</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Congress finds that in the report submitted to Congress by the Secretary of State in June 2005 pursuant to <ref>section 7107(b) of this title</ref>, the list of countries whose governments do not comply with the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking and are not making significant efforts to bring themselves into compliance was composed of a large number of countries in which the trafficking involved forced labor, including the trafficking of women into domestic servitude.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">It is the sense of Congress that the Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking of the Department of State should intensify the focus of the Office on forced labor in the countries described in paragraph (1) and other countries in which forced labor continues to be a serious human rights concern.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information sharing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall, on a regular basis, provide information relating to child labor and forced labor in the production of goods in violation of international standards to the Department of Labor to be used in developing the list described in subsection (b)(2)(C).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities of the Department of Labor</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of Labor, acting through the head of the Bureau of International Labor Affairs of the Department of Labor, shall carry out additional activities to monitor and combat forced labor and child labor in foreign countries as described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional activities described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The additional activities referred to in paragraph (1) are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to monitor the use of forced labor and child labor in violation of international standards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide information regarding trafficking in persons for the purpose of forced labor to the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking of the Department of State for inclusion in trafficking in persons report required by <ref>section 7107(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to develop and make available to the public a list of goods from countries that the Bureau of International Labor Affairs has reason to believe are produced by forced labor or child labor in violation of international standards, including, to the extent practicable, goods that are produced with inputs that are produced with forced labor or child labor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to work with persons who are involved in the production of goods on the list described in subparagraph (C) to create a standard set of practices that will reduce the likelihood that such persons will produce goods using the labor described in such subparagraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to consult with other departments and agencies of the United States Government to reduce forced and child labor internationally and ensure that products made by forced labor and child labor in violation of international standards are not imported into the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2014-12-01">December 1, 2014</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary of Labor shall submit the list developed under paragraph (2)(C) to Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 3566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII</ref>, §§ 1232, 1233, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 146</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–425, title I, § 133(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-08">Jan. 8, 2019</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7113.</num>
<heading> Accountability</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For fiscal year 2013, and each fiscal year thereafter, all grants awarded by the Attorney General under this title or an Act amended by this title shall be subject to the following accountability provisions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit requirement</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “unresolved audit finding” means an audit report finding in the final audit report of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice that the grantee has used grant funds for an unauthorized expenditure or otherwise unallowable cost that is not closed or resolved during the 12-month period beginning on the date on which the final audit report is issued <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002376">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Beginning in the first fiscal year beginning after <date date="2013-03-07">March 7, 2013</date>, and in each fiscal year thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall conduct audits of recipients of grants under this title or an Act amended by this title to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse of funds by grantees. The Inspector General shall determine the appropriate number of grantees to be audited each year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory exclusion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A recipient of grant funds under this title or an Act amended by this title that is found to have an unresolved audit finding shall not be eligible to receive grant funds under this title or an Act amended by this title during the first 2 fiscal years beginning after the end of the 12-month period described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In awarding grants under this title or an Act amended by this title, the Attorney General shall give priority to eligible applicants that did not have an unresolved audit finding during the 3 fiscal years before submitting an application for a grant under this title or an Act amended by this title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If an entity is awarded grant funds under this title or an Act amended by this title during the 2-fiscal-year period during which the entity is barred from receiving grants under subparagraph (C), the Attorney General shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> deposit an amount equal to the amount of the grant funds that were improperly awarded to the grantee into the General Fund of the Treasury; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> seek to recoup the costs of the repayment to the fund from the grant recipient that was erroneously awarded grant funds.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonprofit organization requirements</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph and the grant programs under this title or an Act amended by this title, the term “nonprofit organization” means an organization that is described in <ref>section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref> and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Attorney General may not award a grant under this title or an Act amended by this title to a nonprofit organization that holds money in offshore accounts for the purpose of avoiding paying the tax described in <ref>section 511(a) of title 26</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each nonprofit organization that is awarded a grant under this title or an Act amended by this title and uses the procedures prescribed in regulations to create a rebuttable presumption of reasonableness for the compensation of its officers, directors, trustees and key employees, shall disclose to the Attorney General, in the application for the grant, the process for determining such compensation, including the independent persons involved in reviewing and approving such compensation, the comparability data used, and contemporaneous substantiation of the deliberation and decision. Upon request, the Attorney General shall make the information disclosed under this subparagraph available for public inspection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conference expenditures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Justice under this title or an Act amended by this title may be used by the Attorney General, or by any individual or entity awarded discretionary funds through a cooperative agreement under this title or an Act amended by this title, to host or support any expenditure for conferences that uses more than $20,000 in funds made available to the Department of Justice, unless the Deputy Attorney General or the appropriate Assistant Attorney General, Director, or principal deputy (as designated by the Deputy Attorney General) provides prior written authorization that the funds may be expended to host the conference.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Written approval</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Written approval under subparagraph (A) shall include a written estimate of all costs associated with the conference, including the cost of all food, beverages, audio-visual equipment, honoraria for speakers, and entertainment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Deputy Attorney General shall submit an annual report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives on all conference expenditures approved under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual certification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Beginning in the first fiscal year beginning after <date date="2013-03-07">March 7, 2013</date>, the Attorney General shall submit, to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, an annual certification indicating whether—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all audits issued by the Office of the Inspector General under paragraph (1) have been completed and reviewed by the appropriate Assistant Attorney General or Director;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all mandatory exclusions required under paragraph (1)(C) have been issued;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> all reimbursements required under paragraph (1)(E) have been made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> includes a list of any grant recipients excluded under paragraph (1) from the previous year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application to additional grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), for fiscal year 2018, and each fiscal year thereafter, the term “grant awarded by the Attorney General under this title or an Act amended by this title” includes a grant under any of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content><ref>Section 20333 of title 34</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The program under <ref>section 20709c of title 34</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII, § 1236</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–393, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 5278</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7114.</num>
<heading> Efforts to end modern slavery</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions by the Secretary of Defense</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2016-12-23">December 23, 2016</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on the policies and guidance of the Department of Defense with respect to the education and training on human slavery and the appropriate role of the United States Armed Forces in combatting trafficking in persons that is received by personnel of the Armed Forces, including uniformed personnel and civilians engaged in partnership with foreign nations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The briefing required under paragraph (1) shall address—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> resources available for Armed Forces personnel who become aware of instances of human slavery or trafficking in persons while deployed overseas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> guidance on the requirement to make official reports through the chain of command, the roles and responsibilities of military and civilian officials of the United States Armed Forces and host nations, circumstances in which members of the Armed Forces are authorized to take immediate action to prevent loss of life or serious injury, and the authority to use appropriate force to stop or prevent sexual abuse or exploitation of children.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State is authorized to make a grant or grants of funding to provide support for transformational programs and projects that seek to achieve a measurable and substantial reduction of the prevalence of modern slavery in targeted populations within partner countries (or jurisdictions thereof).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Monitoring and evaluation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any grantee shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop specific and detailed criteria for the monitoring and evaluation of supported projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> implement a system for measuring progress against baseline data that is rigorously designed based on international corporate and nongovernmental best practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensure that each supported project is regularly and rigorously monitored and evaluated, on a not less than biennial basis, by an independent monitoring and evaluation entity, against the specific and detailed criteria established pursuant to paragraph (1), and that the progress of the project towards its stated goals is measured by such entity against baseline data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> support the development of a scientifically sound, representative survey methodology for measuring prevalence with reference to existing research and experience, and apply the methodology consistently to determine the baseline prevalence in target populations and outcomes in order to periodically assess progress in reducing prevalence; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> establish, and revise on a not less than annual basis, specific and detailed criteria for the suspension and termination, as appropriate, of projects supported by the grantee that regularly or consistently fail to meet the criteria required by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Auditing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any grantee shall be subject to the same auditing, recordkeeping, and reporting obligations required under subsections (e), (f), (g), and (i) of <ref>section 4413 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comptroller General audit authority</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Comptroller General of the United States may evaluate the financial transactions of the grantee as well as the programs or activities the grantee carries out pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any grantee shall provide the Comptroller General, or the Comptroller General’s duly authorized representatives, access to such records as the Comptroller General determines necessary to conduct evaluations authorized by this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any grant recipient shall submit a report to the Secretary of State annually and the Secretary shall transmit it to the appropriate congressional committees within 30 days. Such report shall include the names of each of the projects or sub-grantees receiving such funding pursuant to this section and the amount of funding provided for, along with a detailed description of, each such project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction regarding availability of fiscal year 2016 appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The enactment of this section is deemed to meet the condition of the first proviso of paragraph (2) of section 7060(f) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Appropriations <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002377">1</ref> Act, 2016 (division K of <ref>Public Law 114–113</ref>), and the funds referred to in such paragraph shall be made available in accordance with, and for the purposes set forth in, such paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations; sunset</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations for fiscal years 2017 through 2020</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State for the purpose of making a grant or grants authorized under this section, for each fiscal year from 2017 through 2020, $37,500,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sunset</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The authorities of subsections (b) through (f) shall expire on <date date="2020-09-30">September 30, 2020</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Comptroller General review of existing programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2018-09-30">September 30, 2018</date>, and <date date="2020-09-30">September 30, 2020</date>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on all of the programs conducted by the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of Labor, the Department of Defense, and the Department of the Treasury that address human trafficking and modern slavery, including a detailed analysis of the effectiveness of such programs in limiting human trafficking and modern slavery and specific recommendations on which programs are not effective at reducing the prevalence of human trafficking and modern slavery and how the funding for such programs may be redirected to more effective efforts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consideration of report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Comptroller General of the United States shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the report submitted under paragraph (1). The appropriate congressional committees shall review and consider the reports and shall, as appropriate, consider modifications to authorization levels and programs within the jurisdiction of such committees to address the recommendations made in the report.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1298</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2563</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7115.</num>
<heading> Ensuring protection and confidentiality for survivors of human trafficking</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “covered grant” means a grant from the Attorney General or the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 7104(b), 7105(b), or 7105(f) of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “covered recipient” means a grantee or subgrantee receiving funds under a covered grant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Covered grants and covered recipients shall be subject, at the election of the Attorney General or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as applicable, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the conditions under section 40002(b)(2) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<ref>34 U.S.C. 12291(b)(2)</ref>) that apply with respect to grants under such Act and grantees and subgrantees for such grants; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the conditions under section 306(c)(5) of the Family Violence Prevention and Services Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 10406(c)(5)</ref>) that apply with respect to grants under such Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 10401</ref> et seq.] and grantees and subgrantees for such grants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of Justice-sponsored research</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit a covered recipient from sharing personally identifying information with researchers seeking the information for the purposes of conducting research—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that is funded by the Department of Justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for which protections are in place in accordance with the requirements under part 22 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto, and <ref>section 10231(a) of title 34</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> for which a current privacy certificate is on file documenting how the researchers intend to fulfill the obligations under such part 22.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 114</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–347, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 6200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>