<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 62—</num>
<heading>INTERNATIONAL FINANCIAL POLICY</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>EXCHANGE RATES AND INTERNATIONAL ECONOMIC POLICY CO­ORDINATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5301.</num>
<heading> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter may be cited as the “Exchange Rates and International Economic Policy Coordination Act of 1988”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3001</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1372</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5302.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the macroeconomic policies, including the exchange rate policies, of the leading industrialized nations require improved coordination and are not consistent with long-term economic growth and financial stability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> currency values have a major role in determining the patterns of production and trade in the world economy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the rise in the value of the dollar in the early 1980’s contributed substantially to our current trade deficit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> exchange rates among major trading nations have become increasingly volatile and a pattern of exchange rates has at times developed which contribute to substantial and persistent imbalances in the flow of goods and services between nations, imposing serious strains on the world trading system and frustrating both business and government planning;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> capital flows between nations have become very large compared to trade flows, respond at times quickly and dramatically to policy and economic changes, and, for these reasons, contribute significantly to uncertainty in financial markets, the volatility of exchange rates, and the development of exchange rates which produce imbalances in the flow of goods and services between nations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> policy initiatives by some major trading nations that manipulate the value of their currencies in relation to the United States dollar to gain competitive advantage continue to create serious competitive problems for United States industries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a more stable exchange rate for the dollar at a level consistent with a more appropriate and sustainable balance in the United States current account should be a major focus of national economic policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> procedures for improving the coordination of macroeconomic policy need to be strengthened considerably; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> under appropriate circumstances, intervention by the United States in foreign exchange markets as part of a coordinated international strategic intervention effort could produce more orderly adjustment of foreign exchange markets and, in combination with necessary macroeconomic policy changes, assist adjustment toward a more appropriate and sustainable balance in current accounts.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3002</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1372</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5303.</num>
<heading> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States and the other major industrialized countries should take steps to continue the process of coordinating monetary, fiscal, and structural policies initiated in the Plaza Agreement of September 1985;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the goal of the United States in international economic negotiations should be to achieve macroeconomic policies and exchange rates consistent with more appropriate and sustainable balances in trade and capital flows and to foster price stability in conjunction with economic growth;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the United States, in close coordination with the other major industrialized countries should, where appropriate, participate in international currency markets with the objective of producing more orderly adjustment of foreign exchange markets and, in combination with necessary macroeconomic policy changes, assisting adjustment toward a more appropriate and sustainable balance in current accounts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the accountability of the President for the impact of economic policies and exchange rates on trade competitiveness should be increased.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3003</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5304.</num>
<heading> International negotiations on exchange rate and economic policies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multilateral negotiations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall seek to confer and negotiate with other countries—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to achieve—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> better coordination of macroeconomic policies of the major industrialized nations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> more appropriate and sustainable levels of trade and current account balances, and exchange rates of the dollar and other currencies consistent with such balances; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to develop a program for improving existing mechanisms for coordination and improving the functioning of the exchange rate system to provide for long-term exchange rate stability consistent with more appropriate and sustainable current account balances.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bilateral negotiations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall analyze on an annual basis the exchange rate policies of foreign countries, in consultation with the International Monetary Fund, and consider whether countries manipulate the rate of exchange between their currency and the United States dollar for purposes of preventing effective balance of payments adjustments or gaining unfair competitive advantage in international trade. If the Secretary considers that such manipulation is occurring with respect to countries that (1) have material global current account surpluses; and (2) have significant bilateral trade surpluses with the United States, the Secretary of the Treasury shall take action to initiate negotiations with such foreign countries on an expedited basis, in the International Monetary Fund or bilaterally, for the purpose of ensuring that such countries regularly and promptly adjust the rate of exchange between their currencies and the United States dollar to permit effective balance of payments adjustments and to eliminate the unfair advantage. The Secretary shall not be required to initiate negotiations in cases where such negotiations would have a serious detrimental impact on vital national economic and security interests; in such cases, the Secretary shall inform the chairman and the ranking minority member of the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and of the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives of his determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3004</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5305.</num>
<heading> Reporting requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In furtherance of the purpose of this chapter, the Secretary, after consultation with the Chairman of the Board, shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, on or before October 15 of each year, a written report on international economic policy, including exchange rate policy. The Secretary shall provide a written update of developments six months after the initial report. In addition, the Secretary shall appear, if requested, before both committees to provide testimony on these reports.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall contain—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an analysis of currency market developments and the relationship between the United States dollar and the currencies of our major trade competitors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the factors in the United States and other economies that underlie conditions in the currency markets, including developments in bilateral trade and capital flows;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a description of currency intervention or other actions undertaken to adjust the actual exchange rate of the dollar;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> an assessment of the impact of the exchange rate of the United States dollar on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the ability of the United States to maintain a more appropriate and sustainable balance in its current account and merchandise trade account;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> production, employment, and noninflationary growth in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the international competitive performance of United States industries and the external indebtedness of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> recommendations for any changes necessary in United States economic policy to attain a more appropriate and sustainable balance in the current account;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the results of negotiations conducted pursuant to <ref>section 5304 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> key issues in United States policies arising from the most recent consultation requested by the International Monetary Fund under article IV of the Fund’s Articles of Agreement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a report on the size and composition of international capital flows, and the factors contributing to such flows, including, where possible, an assessment of the impact of such flows on exchange rates and trade flows.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3005(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1374</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5306.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Board” means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3006</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1375</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>INTERNATIONAL DEBT</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Findings, Purposes, and Statement of Policy</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5321.</num>
<heading> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter may be cited as the “International Debt Management Act of 1988”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3101</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1375</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5322.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the international debt problem threatens the safety and soundness of the international financial system, the stability of the international trading system, and the economic development of the debtor countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> orderly reduction of international trade imbalances requires very substantial growth in all parts of the world economy, particularly in the developing countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> growth in developing countries with substantial external debts has been significantly constrained over the last several years by a combination of high debt service obligations and insufficient new flows of financial resources to these countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> substantial interest payment outflows from debtor countries, combined with inadequate net new capital inflows, have produced a significant net transfer of financial resources from debtor to creditor countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> negative resource transfers at present levels severely depress both investment and growth in the debtor countries, and force debtor countries to reduce imports and expand exports in order to meet their debt service obligations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> current adjustment policies in debtor countries, which depress domestic demand and increase production for export, help to depress world commodity prices and limit the growth of export markets for United States industries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the United States has borne a disproportionate share of the burden of absorbing increased exports from debtor countries, while other industrialized countries have increased their imports from developing countries only slightly;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> current approaches to the debt problem should not rely solely on new lending as a solution to the debt problem, and should focus on other financing alternatives including a reduction in current debt service obligations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> new international mechanisms to improve the management of the debt problem and to expand the range of financing options available to developing countries should be explored; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> industrial countries with strong current account surpluses have a disproportionate share of the world’s capital resources, and bear an additional responsibility for contributing to a viable long-term solution to the debt problem.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3102</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1375</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5323.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this subchapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to expand the world trading system and raise the level of exports from the United States to the developing countries in order to reduce the United States trade deficit and foster economic expansion and an increase in the standard of living throughout the world;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to alleviate the current international debt problem in order to make the debt situation of developing countries more manageable and permit the resumption of sustained growth in those countries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to increase the stability of the world financial system and ensure the safety and soundness of United States depository institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3103</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5324.</num>
<heading> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> increasing growth in the developing world is a major goal of international economic policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> it is necessary to broaden the range of options in dealing with the debt problem to include improved mechanisms to restructure existing debt;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> active consideration of a new multilateral authority to improve the management of the debt problem and to share the burdens of adjustment more equitably must be undertaken; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> countries with strong current account surpluses bear a major responsibility for providing the financial resources needed for growth in the developing world.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3104</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">International Debt Management Authority</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5331.</num>
<heading> International initiative</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Directive</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of the Treasury shall study the feasibility and advisability of establishing the International Debt Management Authority described in this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Explanation of determinations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary of the Treasury determines that initiation of international discussions with regard to such authority would (A) result in material increase in the discount at which sovereign debt is sold, (B) materially increase the probability of default on such debt, or (C) materially enhance the likelihood of debt service failure or disruption, the Secretary shall include in his interim reports to the Congress an explanation in detail of the reasons for such determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initiation of discussions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Unless such a determination is made, the Secretary of the Treasury shall initiate discussions with such industrialized and developing countries as the Secretary may determine to be appropriate with the intent to negotiate the establishment of the International Debt Management Authority, which would undertake to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> purchase sovereign debt of less developed countries from private creditors at an appropriate discount;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> enter into negotiations with the debtor countries for the purpose of restructuring the debt in order to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> ease the current debt service burden on the debtor countries; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide additional opportunities for economic growth in both debtor and industrialized countries; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assist the creditor banks in the voluntary disposition of their Third World loan portfolio.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Objectives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In any discussions initiated under subsection (a), the Secretary should include the following specific proposals:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> That any loan restructuring assistance provided by such an authority to any debtor nation should involve substantial commitments by the debtor to (A) economic policies designed to improve resource utilization and minimize capital flight, and (B) preparation of an economic management plan calculated to provide sustained economic growth and to allow the debtor to meet its restructured debt obligations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> That support for such an authority should come from industrialized countries, and that greater support should be expected from countries with strong current account surpluses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> That such an authority should have a clearly defined close working relationship with the International Monetary Fund and the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development and the various regional development banks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> That such an authority should be designed to operate as a self-supporting entity, requiring no routine appropriation of resources from any member government, and to function subject to the prohibitions contained in the first sentence of <ref>section 5332(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> That such an authority should have a defined termination date and a clear proposal for the restoration of creditworthiness to debtor countries within this timeframe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the end of the 6-month period beginning on <date date="1988-08-23">August 23, 1988</date>, and at the end of the 12-month period beginning on <date date="1988-08-23">August 23, 1988</date>, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit a report on the progress being made on the study or in discussions described in subsection (a) to the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and shall consult with such committees after submitting each such report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On the conclusion of the study or of discussions described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall transmit a report containing a detailed description thereof to the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, together with such recommendations for legislation which the Secretary may determine to be necessary or appropriate for the establishment of the International Debt Management Authority.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3111</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5332.</num>
<heading> Actions to facilitate creation of Authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No funds, appropriations, contributions, callable capital, financial guarantee, or any other financial support or obligation or contingent support or obligation on the part of the United States Government may be used for the creation, operation, or support of the International Debt Management Authority specified in <ref>section 5331 of this title</ref>, without the express approval of the Congress through subsequent law, nor shall any expenses associated with such authority, either directly or indirectly, accrue to any United States person without the consent of such person. Except as restricted in the preceding sentence, the Secretary of the Treasury shall review all potential resources available to the multilateral financial institutions which could be used to support the creation of the International Debt Management Authority. In the course of this review, the Secretary shall direct—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States Executive Director of the International Monetary Fund to determine the amount of, and alternative methods by which, gold stock of the Fund which, subject to action by its Board of Governors, could be pledged as collateral to obtain financing for the activities of the authority specified in <ref>section 5331 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States Executive Director to the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development to determine the amount of, and alternative methods by which, liquid assets controlled by such Bank and not currently committed to any loan program which, subject to action by its Board of Governors, could be pledged as collateral for obtaining financing for the activities of the authority specified in <ref>section 5331 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall include a report on the results of the review in the first report submitted under <ref>section 5331(c) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction of section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not be construed to affect any provision of the Articles of Agreement of the International Monetary Fund or of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development or any agreement entered into under either of such Agreements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3112</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1378</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5333.</num>
<heading> IMF-World Bank review</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> IMF review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Executive Director of the International Monetary Fund shall request the management of the International Monetary Fund to prepare a review and analysis of the debt burden of the developing countries, with particular attention to alternatives for dealing with the debt problem including new lending instruments, rescheduling and refinancing of existing debt, securitization and debt conversion techniques, discounted debt repurchases, and the International Debt Management Authority described in <ref>section 5331 of this title</ref> no later than 1 year after <date date="1988-08-23">August 23, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> World Bank review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Executive Director to the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development shall request the management of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development to prepare a review and analysis of the debt burden of the developing countries, with particular attention to alternatives for dealing with the debt problem including new lending instruments, rescheduling and refinancing of existing debt, securitization and debt conversion techniques, discounted debt repurchases, and the International Debt Management Authority described in <ref>section 5331 of this title</ref> no later than 1 year after <date date="1988-08-23">August 23, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3113</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1378</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PRIMARY DEALERS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5341.</num>
<heading> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter may be cited as the “Primary Dealers Act of 1988”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3501</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1386</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5342.</num>
<heading> Requirement of national treatment in underwriting government debt instruments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> United States companies can successfully compete in foreign markets if they are given fair access to such markets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a trade surplus in services could offset the deficit in manufactured goods and help lower the overall trade deficit significantly;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in contrast to the barriers faced by United States firms in Japan, Japanese firms generally have enjoyed access to United States financial markets on the same terms as United States firms; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> United States firms seeking to compete in Japan face or have faced a variety of discriminatory barriers effectively precluding such firms from fairly competing for Japanese business, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> limitations on membership on the Tokyo Stock Exchange;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> high fixed commission rates (ranging as high as 80 percent) which must be paid to members of the exchange by nonmembers for executing trades;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> unequal opportunities to participate in and act as lead manager for equity and bond underwritings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> restrictions on access to automated teller machines;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> arbitrarily applied employment requirements for opening branch offices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> long delays in processing applications and granting approvals for licenses to operate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> restrictions on foreign institutions’ participation in Ministry of Finance policy advisory councils.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of certain persons as primary dealers prohibited</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Neither the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System nor the Federal Reserve Bank of New York may designate, or permit the continuation of any prior designation of, any person of a foreign country as a primary dealer in government debt instruments if such foreign country does not accord to United States companies the same competitive opportunities in the underwriting and distribution of government debt instruments issued by such country as such country accords to domestic companies of such country.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain prior acquisitions excepted</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the continuation of the prior designation of a company as a primary dealer in government debt instruments if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such designation occurred before <date date="1987-07-31">July 31, 1987</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> before <date date="1987-07-31">July 31, 1987</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> control of such company was acquired from a person (other than a person of a foreign country) by a person of a foreign country; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in conjunction with a person of a foreign country, such company informed the Federal Reserve Bank of New York of the intention of such person to acquire control of such company.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for countries having or negotiating bilateral agreements with United States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (b) shall not apply to any person of a foreign country if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that country, as of <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, was negotiating a bilateral agreement with the United States under the authority of <ref>section 2112(b)(4)(A) of title 19</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that country has a bilateral free trade area agreement with the United States which entered into force before <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Person of a foreign country” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, a person is a “person of a foreign country” if that person, or any other person which directly or indirectly owns or controls that person, is a resident of that country, is organized under the laws of that country, or has its principal place of business in that country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect 12 months after <date date="1988-08-23">August 23, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3502</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1386</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>FINANCIAL REPORTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5351.</num>
<heading> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This subchapter may be cited as the “Financial Reports Act of 1988”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3601</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5352.</num>
<heading> Quadrennial reports on foreign treatment of United States financial institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not less frequently than every 4 years, beginning <date date="1990-12-01">December 1, 1990</date>, the Secretary of the Treasury, in conjunction with the Secretary of State, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Securities and Exchange Commission, and the Department of Commerce, shall report to the Congress on (1) the foreign countries from which foreign financial services institutions have entered into the business of providing financial services in the United States, (2) the kinds of financial services which are being offered, (3) the extent to which foreign countries deny national treatment to United States banking organizations and securities companies, and (4) the efforts undertaken by the United States to eliminate such discrimination. The report shall focus on those countries in which there are significant denials of national treatment which impact United States financial firms. The report shall also describe the progress of discussions pursuant to <ref>section 5353 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3602</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5353.</num>
<heading> Fair trade in financial services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discussions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">When advantageous the President or his designee shall conduct discussions with the governments of countries that are major financial centers, aimed at:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> ensuring that United States banking organizations and securities companies have access to foreign markets and receive national treatment in those markets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> reducing or eliminating barriers to, and other distortions of, international trade in financial services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> achieving reasonable comparability in the types of financial services permissible for financial service companies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> developing uniform supervisory standards for banking organizations and securities companies, including uniform capital standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation before discussions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before entering into those discussions, the President or his designee shall consult with the committees of jurisdiction in the Senate and the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After completing those discussions and after consultation with the committees of jurisdiction, the President shall transmit to the Congress any recommendations that have emerged from those discussions. Any recommendations for changes in United States financial laws or practices shall be accompanied by a description of the changes in foreign financial laws or practices that would accompany action by the Congress, and by an explanation of the benefits that would accrue to the United States from adoption of the recommendations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Construction of section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section may be construed as prior approval of any legislation which may be necessary to implement any recommendations resulting from discussions under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3603</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1387</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5354.</num>
<heading> Banks loan loss reserves</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Federal Reserve Board shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the issues raised by including loan loss reserves as part of banks’ primary capital for regulatory purposes by <date date="1989-03-31">March 31, 1989</date>. Such report shall include a review of the treatment of loan loss reserves and the composition of primary capital of banks in other major industrialized countries, and shall include an analysis as to whether loan loss reserves should continue to be counted as primary capital for regulatory purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3604</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>