<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 30—</num>
<heading>INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION IN HEALTH AND MEDICAL RESEARCH</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2101.</num>
<heading> Statement of purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to advance the status of the health sciences in the United States and thereby the health of the American people through cooperative endeavors with other countries in health research, and research training; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to advance the international status of the health sciences through cooperative enterprises in health research, research planning, and research training.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–610, § 2</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 364</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2102.</num>
<heading> Authority of Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of health research and research training resources</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out the purposes of clause (1) of <ref>section 2101 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare (hereafter referred to as the “Secretary”) may in the exercise of his responsibilities under the Vocational Rehabilitation Act, sections 191 to 194 of title 42, and any other provision of law, to conduct and support health research and research training, including research and research training relating to the rehabilitation of the handicapped, make such use of health research and research training resources in participating foreign countries as he may deem necessary and desirable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fellowships; equipment, meetings and conferences; interchange of scientists and experts; consultants; compensation and travel expenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To carry out his responsibilities under this section the Secretary may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish and maintain fellowships in the United States and in participating foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make grants to public institutions or agencies and to nonprofit private institutions or agencies in the United States and in participating foreign countries for the purpose of establishing and maintaining fellowships;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make grants or loans of equipment, medical, biological, physical, or chemical substances or other materials, for use by public institutions or agencies, or nonprofit private institutions or agencies, or by individuals, in participating foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> participate and otherwise cooperate in any international health or medical research or research training meetings, conferences, or other activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> facilitate the interchange between the United States and participating foreign countries, and among participating foreign countries, of research scientists and experts who are engaged in experiments and programs of research or research training, and in carrying out such purpose may pay per diem compensation, subsistence, and travel for such scientists and experts when away from their places of residence at rates not to exceed those provided in <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in the Government service intermittently employed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> procure, in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>, the temporary or intermittent services of experts or consultants; individuals so employed shall receive compensation at a rate to be fixed by the Secretary, but not in excess of $50 per diem, including travel time, and while away from their homes or regular places of business may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “health research” shall include, but not be limited to, research, investigations, and studies relating to causes and methods of prevention of accidents, including but not limited to highway and aviation accidents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “participating foreign countries” means those foreign countries which cooperate with the United States in carrying out the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–610, § 4</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 365</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2103.</num>
<heading> Authority of President</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of foreign currencies and credits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the President should use his authority under the Constitution and laws of the United States to accomplish the purposes of <ref>section 2101 of this title</ref> and in accomplishing such purposes (1) use to the fullest extent practicable foreign currencies or credits available for utilization by the United States, (2) enter into agreements to use foreign currencies and credits available to other nations for use with the agreement of the United States, and (3) use any other foreign currencies and credits which may be made available by participating foreign countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disease and health deficiency investigations, experiments, and studies; rehabilitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To carry out the purposes of <ref>section 2101 of this title</ref> the President, in cooperation with participating foreign countries, is authorized to encourage, support, and promote the planning and conduct of, and training for, research investigations, experiments, and studies in the United States and in participating foreign countries relating to the causes, diagnosis, treatment, control, and prevention of diseases and impairments of mankind (including nutritional and other health deficiencies) or to the rehabilitation of the handicapped.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fellowships; equipment; technical assistance; interchange of scientists and experts; compensation and travel expenses; health science programs and projects; meetings and conferences; scientific publications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To carry out his responsibilities under this chapter the President may—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish and maintain fellowships in participating foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> make financial grants to establish and maintain fellowships, and for other purposes, to public institutions and agencies and to nonprofit private institutions and agencies, and to individuals in participating foreign countries, or contract with such institutions, agencies, or individuals without regard to section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31 and <ref>section 6101 of title 41</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make grants or loans of equipment, medical, biological, physical, or chemical substances or other materials, for use by such institutions, agencies, or individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> furnish technical assistance and advice to such institutions or agencies and in carrying out such purposes may pay the compensation and expenses of scientists and experts from the United States and other participating foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> facilitate the interchange among participating foreign countries of scientists and experts (including the payment of travel and subsistence for such scientists and experts when away from their places of residence);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> cooperate and assist in the planning and conduct of research, research planning, and research training programs and projects by groups engaged in, or concerned with, research or research training endeavors in the health sciences, and, through financial grants or other appropriate means, assist in special research, research planning, or research training projects conducted by or under the auspices of such groups where they can effectively carry out such activities contemplated by this joint resolution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> encourage and support international communication in the sciences relating to health by means of calling or cooperating in the convening, and financing or contributing to the financing of the expenses of, international scientific meetings and conferences; and provide, or arrange for the provision of, translating and other services, and issue or finance publications, leading to a more effective dissemination of relevant scientific information with respect to research conducted in the United States or participating foreign countries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Programs of an operational nature excepted from assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The activities authorized in this section shall not extend to the support of public health, medical care, or other programs of an operational nature as contrasted with research and research training nor shall any of the grants authorized by this section include grants for the improvement or extension of public health administration in other countries except for necessary research and research training in the science of public health and public health administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultants; advisory committees; compensation and travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized, to the extent he deems it necessary to carry out the purposes of <ref>section 2101 of this title</ref>, to employ experts and consultants or organizations thereof, as authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> and create a committee or committees to be composed entirely of persons who are citizens of the United States to advise him in the administration of this chapter, individuals so employed and members of committees shall be entitled to receive compensation at a rate to be fixed by the President, but not to exceed $50 per diem, including travel time, and while away from their homes or regular places of business they may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation of authority; regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may delegate any authority vested in him by this section to the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare. The Secretary may from time to time issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out any authority which is delegated to him under this section, and may delegate performance of any such authority to the Surgeon General of the Public Health Service, the Director of the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation, the Chief of the Children’s Bureau, or other subordinates acting under his direction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of foreign currencies and credits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to carry out the purposes of <ref>section 2101 of this title</ref>, and subject to <ref>section 1306 of title 31</ref>, the President may use or enter into agreements with foreign nations or organizations of nations to use the foreign currencies which accrue under title I of the Food for Peace Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.], and the Mutual Security Act of 1954, or which are otherwise available for utilization by the United States. The President is authorized to agree to the utilization by foreign nations, for programs designed to carry out the purposes of <ref>section 2101 of this title</ref> in cooperation with the United States, of amounts deposited in special accounts pursuant to section 142(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002087">1</ref> of the Mutual Security Act of 1954, to the extent that the amounts in such accounts exceed the requirements of other programs covered by such section 142(b). Such utilization of amounts in special accounts shall be without regard to the second proviso in clause (iii) of such section 142(b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title VI, § 601(a)(2)(F)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3286</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “health research” shall include, but not be limited to, research, investigations, and studies relating to causes and methods of prevention of accidents, including but not limited to highway and aviation accidents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “participating foreign countries” means those foreign countries which cooperate with the United States in carrying out the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–610, § 5</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 366</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–362, title VI, § 601(a)(2)(F)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(P), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2104.</num>
<heading> Authority of Federal officers and agencies unaffected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to repeal or restrict authority vested in the President, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, the Surgeon General of the Public Health Service, or any other officer or agency of the United States by any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 86–610, § 6</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 369</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>