<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 68A—</num>
<heading>COOPERATIVE THREAT REDUCTION WITH STATES OF FORMER SOVIET UNION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5951.</num>
<heading> Findings on cooperative threat reduction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that it is in the national security interest of the United States for the United States to do the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Facilitate, on a priority basis, the transportation, storage, safeguarding, and elimination of nuclear and other weapons of the independent states of the former Soviet Union, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the safe and secure storage of fissile materials derived from the elimination of nuclear weapons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the dismantlement of (i) intercontinental ballistic missiles and launchers for such missiles, (ii) submarine-launched ballistic missiles and launchers for such missiles, and (iii) heavy bombers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the elimination of chemical, biological and other weapons capabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Facilitate, on a priority basis, the prevention of proliferation of weapons (and components of weapons) of mass destruction and destabilizing conventional weapons of the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the establishment of verifiable safeguards against the proliferation of such weapons and components.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Facilitate, on a priority basis, the prevention of diversion of weapons-related scientific expertise of the independent states of the former Soviet Union to terrorist groups or third world countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Support (A) the demilitarization of the defense-related industry and equipment of the independent states of the former Soviet Union, and (B) the conversion of such industry and equipment to civilian purposes and uses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Expand military-to-military and defense contacts between the United States and the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XII, § 1202</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1777</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 5952, 5953.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1351(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3607</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5954.</num>
<heading> Funding for fiscal year 1994</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds authorized to be appropriated under section 301(21) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002327">1</ref> shall be available for cooperative threat reduction with states of the former Soviet Union under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Not more than $15,000,000 of the funds referred to in subsection (a) may be made available for programs authorized in subsection (b)(6) of section 5952 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not more than $20,000,000 of such funds may be made available for programs authorized in subsection (b)(7) of section 5952 <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Not more than $40,000,000 of such funds may be made available for grants to the Demilitarization Enterprise Fund designated pursuant to section 5953 <sup>1</sup> of this title and for related administrative expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of extension of availability of prior year funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent provided in appropriations Acts, the authority to transfer funds of the Department of Defense provided in section 9110(a) of the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 1993 (<ref>Public Law 102–396</ref>; <ref>106 Stat. 1928</ref>), and in <ref>section 108 of Public Law 102–229</ref> (<ref>105 Stat. 1708</ref>) shall continue to be in effect during fiscal year 1994.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XII, § 1205</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1781</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5955.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1351(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3607</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5956.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XIII, § 1308(g)(1)(A)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–343</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5957.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1351(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3607</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5958.</num>
<heading> Authorization for additional fiscal year 1993 assistance to independent states of the former Soviet Union</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 1993 for “Operation and Maintenance, Defense Agencies” the additional sum of $979,000,000, to be available for the purposes of providing assistance to the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of transfer of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense may, to the extent provided in appropriations Acts, transfer from the account “Operation and Maintenance, Defense Agencies” for fiscal year 1993 a sum not to exceed the amount appropriated pursuant to the authorization in subsection (a) to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> other accounts of the Department of Defense for the purpose of providing assistance to the independent states of the former Soviet Union; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> appropriations available to the Department of State and other agencies of the United States Government for the purpose of providing assistance to the independent states of the former Soviet Union for programs that the President determines will increase the national security of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative provisions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Amounts transferred under subsection (b) shall be available subject to the same terms and conditions as the appropriations to which transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The authority to make transfers pursuant to this section is in addition to any other transfer authority of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination of programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall coordinate the programs described in subsection (b) with those authorized in the other provisions of this chapter and in the provisions of the Freedom for Russia and Emerging Eurasian Democracies and Open Markets Support Act of 1992 (<ref>Public Law 102–511</ref>) so as to optimize the contribution such programs make to the national interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XII, § 1209</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1782</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5959.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1351(8)(C)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3607</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 5960, 5961.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1351(11)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3607</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5961a.</num>
<heading> Requirement for on-site managers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On-site manager requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before obligating any defense nuclear nonproliferation funds for a project described in subsection (b), the Secretary of Energy shall appoint one on-site manager for that project. The manager shall be appointed from among employees of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Projects covered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) applies to a project—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to be located in a state of the former Soviet Union;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> which involves dismantlement, destruction, or storage facilities, or construction of a facility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> with respect to which the total contribution by the Department of Energy is expected to exceed $50,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties of on-site manager</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The on-site manager appointed under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> develop, in cooperation with representatives from governments of countries participating in the project, a list of those steps or activities critical to achieving the project’s disarmament or nonproliferation goals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish a schedule for completing those steps or activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> meet with all participants to seek assurances that those steps or activities are being completed on schedule; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> suspend United States participation in a project when a non-United States participant fails to complete a scheduled step or activity on time, unless directed by the Secretary of Energy to resume United States participation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to manage more than one project</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Subject to paragraph (2), an employee of the Federal Government may serve as on-site manager for more than one project, including projects at different locations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If such an employee serves as on-site manager for more than one project in a fiscal year, the total cost of the projects for that fiscal year may not exceed $150,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Steps or activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Steps or activities referred to in subsection (c)(1) are those activities that, if not completed, will prevent a project from achieving its disarmament or nonproliferation goals, including, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Identification and acquisition of permits (as defined in subsection (g)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Verification that the items, substances, or capabilities to be dismantled, secured, or otherwise modified are available for dismantlement, securing, or modification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Timely provision of financial, personnel, management, transportation, and other resources.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case in which the Secretary of Energy directs an on-site manager to resume United States participation in a project under subsection (c)(4), the Secretary shall concurrently notify Congress of such direction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permit defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “permit” means any local or national permit for development, general construction, environmental, land use, or other purposes that is required in the state of the former Soviet Union in which the project is being or is proposed to be carried out.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall take effect six months after <date date="2003-11-24">November 24, 2003</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3125</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 5962, 5963.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1351(11)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3607</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 5964, 5965.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1351(12)(B)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3607</ref></heading>
</section>
</chapter>