<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 29A—</num>
<heading>INTER-AMERICAN CULTURAL AND TRADE CENTER</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2081.</num>
<heading> United States participation in Inter-American Cultural and Trade Center; purposes of Interama</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is authorized, through such department or agency in the executive branch of the Government as he may designate, to provide for United States participation in the Inter-American Cultural and Trade Center (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as “Interama”). In providing for United States participation, the President shall cooperate with the Inter-American Center Authority (an agency of the State of Florida). The purposes of Interama are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide a permanent international center which will serve as a meeting ground for the governments and industries of the Western Hemisphere and of other areas of the world;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to facilitate broad and continuous exchanges of ideas, persons, and products through cultural, educational, and other exchanges; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by other appropriate means, to promote mutual understanding between the peoples of the Western Hemisphere and to strengthen the ties which unite the United States with other nations of the free world.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–355, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-02-19">Feb. 19, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 5</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2082.</num>
<heading> Participation in Interama by States and foreign countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized, by proclamation or in such other manner as he may deem proper, to invite the several States of the United States and foreign countries to take part in Interama, except that no Communist de facto government holding any people in subjugation shall be invited to participate.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–355, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-02-19">Feb. 19, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 6</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2083.</num>
<heading> Commissioner for Interama; procurement and appointment of personnel; powers and duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There shall be in the designated department or agency a Commissioner for Interama who shall be appointed by the President. Subject to the direction of the head of the designated department or agency, the Commissioner for Interama shall perform such duties as the President may prescribe to carry out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In order to carry out the provisions of this chapter, the head of the designated department or agency is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to appoint and fix the compensation of such persons as he deems necessary without regard to the civil service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5; except that no person so appointed shall receive compensation at a rate in excess of that received by persons under chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 for the performance of comparable duties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to procure temporary and intermittent services in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to enter into contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to select, purchase, rent, construct, or otherwise acquire exhibits, including materials and equipment therefor, and to provide for the transportation, insurance, display, maintenance, and dismantling thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to incur such other expenses as may be necessary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to accept donations of money, property, and services and the loan of property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–355, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-02-19">Feb. 19, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 6</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–83, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2084.</num>
<heading> Cooperation of other Federal departments, agencies, and instrumentalities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of each department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to cooperate with the head of the designated department or agency with respect to determining the manner in which and the extent to which the United States shall be a participant in and an exhibitor at Interama; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to make available to the head of the designated department or agency, on a reimbursable basis, such personnel as may be necessary to assist him in carrying out his functions under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–355, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-02-19">Feb. 19, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 6</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2085.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $7,500,000 to provide for United States participation in Interama under this chapter, of which not to exceed $250,000 shall be available for expenditure in connection with the preparation of the report required to be submitted to the Congress under section 2(b) of this Act. Sums appropriated under this subsection shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In addition to the amount authorized in subsection (a), there is authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $1,000,000 annually for each of the fiscal years 1968 and 1969 for the maintenance of United States installations and activities at Interama.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–355, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-02-19">Feb. 19, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 7</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>