<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 53—</num>
<heading>AUTHORITIES RELATING TO THE REGULATION OF FOREIGN MISSIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4301.</num>
<heading> Congressional declaration of findings and policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress finds that the operation in the United States of foreign missions and public international organizations and the official missions to such organizations, including the permissible scope of their activities and the location and size of their facilities, is a proper subject for the exercise of Federal jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress declares that it is the policy of the United States to support the secure and efficient operation of United States missions abroad, to facilitate the secure and efficient operation in the United States of foreign missions and public international organizations and the official missions to such organizations, and to assist in obtaining appropriate benefits, privileges, and immunities for those missions and organizations and to require their observance of corresponding obligations in accordance with international law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of foreign missions in United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The treatment to be accorded to a foreign mission in the United States shall be determined by the Secretary after due consideration of the benefits, privileges, and immunities provided to missions of the United States in the country or territory represented by that foreign mission, as well as matters relating to the protection of the interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 201, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 283</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 127(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 418</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4302.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> “benefit” (with respect to a foreign mission) means any acquisition, or authorization for an acquisition, in the United States by or for a foreign mission, including the acquisition of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> real property by purchase, lease, exchange, construction, or otherwise,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> public services, including services relating to customs, importation, and utilities, and the processing of applications or requests relating to public services,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> supplies, maintenance, and transportation,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> locally engaged staff on a temporary or regular basis,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> travel and related services,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> protective services, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> financial and currency exchange services,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">and includes such other benefits as the Secretary may designate;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “chancery” means the principal offices of a foreign mission used for diplomatic or related purposes, and annexes to such offices (including ancillary offices and support facilities), and includes the site and any building on such site which is used for such purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> “foreign mission” means any mission to or agency or entity in the United States which is involved in the diplomatic, consular, or other activities of, or which is substantially owned or effectively controlled by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a foreign government, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an organization (other than an international organization, as defined in <ref>section 4309(b) of this title</ref>) representing a territory or political entity which has been granted diplomatic or other official privileges and immunities under the laws of the United States or which engages in some aspect of the conduct of the international affairs of such territory or political entity,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">including any real property of such a mission and including the personnel of such a mission;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> “real property” includes any right, title, or interest in or to, or the beneficial use of, any real property in the United States, including any office or other building;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> “sending State” means the foreign government, territory, or political entity represented by a foreign mission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> “United States” means, when used in a geographic sense, the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Determinations with respect to the meaning and applicability of the terms used in subsection (a) shall be committed to the discretion of the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 202, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 283</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 127(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 418</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–569, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3204</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 153(e)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(1), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 409</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4303.</num>
<heading> Authorities of Secretary of State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall carry out the following functions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Assist agencies of Federal, State, and municipal government with regard to ascertaining and according benefits, privileges, and immunities to which a foreign mission may be entitled.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Provide or assist in the provision of benefits for or on behalf of a foreign mission in accordance with <ref>section 4304 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> As determined by the Secretary, dispose of property acquired in carrying out the purposes of this chapter.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002299">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> As determined by the Secretary, designate an office within the Department of State to carry out the purposes of this chapter.<sup>1</sup> If such an office is established, the President may appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, a Director, with the rank of ambassador. Of the Director and the next most senior person in the office, one should be an individual who has served in the Foreign Service and the other should be an individual who has served in the United States intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Perform such other functions as the Secretary may determine necessary in furtherance of the policy of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 203, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 284</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–164, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1043</ref>, 1044; <ref>Pub. L. 98–618, title VI, § 601(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3303</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 173(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1360</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–246, title I, § 116(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(2), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 409</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4304.</num>
<heading> Provision of benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request by foreign mission; terms and conditions as approved by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of a foreign mission, benefits may be provided to or for that foreign mission by or through the Secretary on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may approve.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benefits through Secretary as mandatory; compliance with terms and conditions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that such action is reasonably necessary on the basis of reciprocity or otherwise—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to facilitate relations between the United States and a sending State,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to protect the interests of the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to adjust for costs and procedures of obtaining benefits for missions of the United States abroad,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to assist in resolving a dispute affecting United States interests and involving a foreign mission or sending State, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> subject to subsection (f), to implement an exchange of property between the Government of the United States and the government of a foreign country, such property to be used by each government in the respective receiving state for, or in connection with, diplomatic or consular establishments,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the Secretary may require a foreign mission (A) to obtain benefits from or through the Secretary on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may approve, or (B) to forego the acceptance, use, or relation of any benefit or to comply with such terms and conditions as the Secretary may determine as a condition to the execution or performance in the United States of any contract or other agreement, the acquisition, retention, or use of any real property, or the application for or acceptance of any benefit (including any benefit from or authorized by any Federal, State, or municipal governmental authority, or any entity providing public services).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surcharge or fee; waiver of recourse</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Terms and conditions established by the Secretary under this section may include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a requirement to pay to the Secretary a surcharge or fee, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a waiver by a foreign mission (or any assignee of or person deriving rights from a foreign mission) of any recourse against any governmental authority, any entity providing public services, any employee or agent of such an authority or entity, or any other person, in connection with any action determined by the Secretary to be undertaken in furtherance of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agent for waiver of recourse</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of effectuating a waiver of recourse which is required under this section, the Secretary may designate any officer of the Department of State as the agent of a foreign mission (or of any assignee of or person deriving rights from a foreign mission). Any such waiver by an officer so designated shall for all purposes (including any court or administrative proceeding) be deemed to be a waiver by the foreign mission (or the assignee of or other person deriving rights from a foreign mission).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secret Service protection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to preclude or limit in any way the authority of the United States Secret Service to provide protective services pursuant to section 3056 or 3056A of title 18 at a level commensurate with protective requirements as determined by the United States Secret Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In-kind exchange of properties with foreign government; transfer of funds; reciprocal agreement; regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Upon a determination in each specific case by the Secretary of State or the Secretary’s designee that the purpose of the Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 292</ref> et seq.], can best be met on the basis of an in-kind exchange of properties with a foreign country pursuant to subsection (b)(5), the Secretary of State may transfer funds made available under the heading “Acquisition and Maintenance of Buildings Abroad” (including funds held in the Foreign Service Buildings Fund) for such purpose to the Working Capital Fund, as provided in <ref>section 4308(h)(1) of this title</ref>. Except for funds that may be provided by a foreign government for the purchase of property, only funds transferred under the preceding sentence may be used for the purposes of subsection (b)(5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Secretary of State may acquire property in the United States for the purposes of subsection (b)(5) only in the context of a specific reciprocal agreement with a specified foreign government. Property acquired by the United States in the foreign country through such an exchange shall benefit the United States at least to the same extent as the property acquired in the United States benefits the foreign government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of State shall prescribe regulations for the implementation of any in-kind exchange of properties pursuant to subsection (b)(5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> At least 15 days before entering into any reciprocal agreement for the exchange of property with another foreign government, the Secretary of State shall notify the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Public Works and Transportation of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Proceeds from the disposition of properties acquired pursuant to this subsection shall be credited to the Foreign Service Buildings Fund (referred to in section 9 of the Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 300</ref>]).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The authority to spend proceeds received under subparagraph (A) may be exercised only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in an appropriation Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 204, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 284</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–93, title I</ref>, §§ 126(b), 127(c), <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 418</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–246, title I, § 116(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(3), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 410</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–415, § 1(cc)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title VI, § 605(d)(2)</ref>, (e)(2)(B), <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4304a.</num>
<heading> Enforcement of compliance with liability insurance requirements</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice to Secretary by head of foreign mission of lapse or termination of coverage; report to Secretary by head of foreign mission respecting motor vehicles, vessels and aircraft registered in United States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The head of a foreign mission shall notify promptly the Secretary of the lapse or termination of any liability insurance coverage held by a member of the mission, by a member of the family of such member, or by an individual described in section 19 of the Convention on Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations of <date date="1946-02-13">February 13, 1946</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Not later than February 1 of each year, the head of each foreign mission shall prepare and transmit to the Secretary a report including a list of motor vehicles, vessels, and aircraft registered in the United States by members of the mission, members of the families of such members, individuals described in section 19 of the Convention on Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations of <date date="1946-02-13">February 13, 1946</date>, and by the mission itself. Such list shall set forth for each such motor vehicle, vessel, or aircraft—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the jurisdiction in which it is registered;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the name of the insured;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the name of the insurance company;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the insurance policy number and the extent of insurance coverage; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> such other information as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surcharge or fee covering unsatisfied part of judgment; preconditions for imposition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary finds that a member of a foreign mission, a member of the family of such member, or an individual described in section 19 of the Convention on Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations of <date date="1946-02-13">February 13, 1946</date>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is at fault for personal injury, death, or property damage arising out of the operation of a motor vehicle, vessel, or aircraft in the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is not covered by liability insurance, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has not satisfied a court-rendered judgment against him or is not legally liable,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall impose a surcharge or fee on the foreign mission of which such member or individual is a part, amounting to the unsatisfied portion of the judgment rendered against such member or individual or, if there is no court-rendered judgment, an estimated amount of damages incurred by the victim. The payment of any such surcharge or fee shall be available only for compensation of the victim or his estate.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “head of a foreign mission” has the same meaning as is ascribed to the term “head of a mission” in Article 1 of the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations of <date date="1961-04-18">April 18, 1961</date> (T.I.A.S. numbered 7502; 23 U.S.T. 3227); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the terms “members of a mission” and “family” have the same meanings as is ascribed to them by paragraphs (1) and (2) of <ref>section 254a of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 204A, as added <ref>Pub. L. 98–164, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1042</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(4), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 410</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4304b.</num>
<heading> Crimes committed by diplomats</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report concerning diplomatic immunity</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall prepare and submit to the Congress, annually, a report concerning diplomatic immunity entitled “Report on Cases Involving Diplomatic Immunity”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Content of report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to such other information as the Secretary of State may consider appropriate, the report under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The number of persons residing in the United States who enjoy full immunity from the criminal jurisdiction of the United States under laws extending diplomatic privileges and immunities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Each case involving an alien described in subparagraph (A) in which an appropriate authority of a State, a political subdivision of a State, or the United States reported to the Department of State that the authority had reasonable cause to believe the alien committed a serious criminal offense within the United States, and any additional information provided to the Secretary relating to other serious criminal offenses that any such authority had reasonable cause to believe the alien committed before the period covered by the report. The Secretary may omit from such report any matter the provision of which the Secretary reasonably believes would compromise a criminal investigation or prosecution or which would directly compromise law enforcement or intelligence sources or methods.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Each case described in subparagraph (B) in which the Secretary of State has certified that a person enjoys full immunity from the criminal jurisdiction of the United States under laws extending diplomatic privileges and immunities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The number of United States citizens who are residing in a receiving state and who enjoy full immunity from the criminal jurisdiction of such state under laws extending diplomatic privileges and immunities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Each case involving a United States citizen under subparagraph (D) in which the United States has been requested by the government of a receiving state to waive the immunity from criminal jurisdiction of the United States citizen.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Whether the Secretary has made the notifications referred to in subsection (c) during the period covered by the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Serious criminal offense” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For the purposes of this section, the term “serious criminal offense” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any felony under Federal, State, or local law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any Federal, State, or local offense punishable by a term of imprisonment of more than 1 year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any crime of violence as defined for purposes of <ref>section 16 of title 18</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> driving under the influence of alcohol or drugs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> reckless driving; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> driving while intoxicated.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States policy concerning reform of diplomatic immunity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the Secretary of State should explore, in appropriate fora, whether states should enter into agreements and adopt legislation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide jurisdiction in the sending state to prosecute crimes committed in the receiving state by persons entitled to immunity from criminal jurisdiction under laws extending diplomatic privileges and immunities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide that where there is probable cause to believe that an individual who is entitled to immunity from the criminal jurisdiction of the receiving state under laws extending diplomatic privileges and immunities committed a serious crime, the sending state will waive such immunity or the sending state will prosecute such individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of diplomatic corps</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary should periodically notify each foreign mission of United States policies relating to criminal offenses committed by individuals with immunity from the criminal jurisdiction of the United States under laws extending diplomatic privileges and immunities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 204B, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–375, § 1</ref>, <date date="1998-11-12">Nov. 12, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 3385</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4305.</num>
<heading> Property of foreign missions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proposed acquisition, sale, or other disposition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary shall require any foreign mission, including any mission to an international organization (as defined in <ref>section 4309(b)(2) of this title</ref>), to notify the Secretary prior to any proposed acquisition, or any proposed sale or other disposition, of any real property by or on behalf of such mission. The foreign mission (or other party acting on behalf of the foreign mission) may initiate or execute any contract, proceeding, application, or other action required for the proposed action—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> only after the expiration of the 60-day period beginning on the date of such notification (or after the expiration of such shorter period as the Secretary may specify in a given case); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> only if the mission is not notified by the Secretary within that period that the proposal has been disapproved; however, the Secretary may include in such a notification such terms and conditions as the Secretary may determine appropriate in order to remove the disapproval.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of this section, “acquisition” includes any acquisition or alteration of, or addition to, any real property or any change in the purpose for which real property is used by a foreign mission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Divesture</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may require any foreign mission to divest itself of, or forgo the use of, any real property determined by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not to have been acquired in accordance with this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to exceed limitations placed on real property available to a United States mission in the sending State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> where otherwise necessary to protect the interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cessation of diplomatic, consular, and other governmental activities in United States; protecting power or other agent; disposition of property</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If a foreign mission has ceased conducting diplomatic, consular, and other governmental activities in the United States and has not designated a protecting power or other agent approved by the Secretary to be responsible for the property of that foreign mission, the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> until the designation of a protecting power or other agent approved by the Secretary, may protect and preserve any property of that foreign mission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may dispose of such property at such time as the Secretary may determine after the expiration of the one-year period beginning on the date that the foreign mission ceased those activities, and may remit to the sending State the net proceeds from such disposition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection from future hostile intelligence activities in United States</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> After <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>, real property in the United States may not be acquired (by sale, lease, or other means) by or on behalf of the foreign mission of a foreign country described in paragraph (4) if, in the judgment of the Secretary of Defense (after consultation with the Secretary of State), the acquisition of that property might substantially improve the capability of that country to intercept communications involving United States Government diplomatic, military, or intelligence matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> After <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>, real property in the United States may not be acquired (by sale, lease, or other means) by or on behalf of the foreign mission of a foreign country described in paragraph (4) if, in the judgment of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (after consultation with the Secretary of State), the acquisition of that property might substantially improve the capability of that country to engage in intelligence activities directed against the United States Government, other than the intelligence activities described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Secretary of State shall inform the Secretary of Defense and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation immediately upon notice being given pursuant to subsection (a) of this section of a proposed acquisition of real property by or on behalf of the foreign mission of a foreign country described in paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> For the purposes of this subsection, the term “foreign country” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any country listed as a Communist country in <ref>section 2370(f) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any country determined by the Secretary of State, for purposes of section 4605(j) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002300">1</ref> of title 50, to be a country which has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other country which engages in intelligence activities in the United States which are adverse to the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> As used in this section, the term “substantially improve” shall not be construed to prevent the establishment of a foreign mission by a country which, on <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> does not have a mission in the United States, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to a city in the United States, did not maintain a mission in that city.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 205, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 285</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 127(d)</ref>, (e), <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 418</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 161</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(5), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 410</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4306.</num>
<heading> Location of foreign missions in the District of Columbia</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Section as governing location, replacement, or expansion</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The location, replacement, or expansion of chanceries in the District of Columbia shall be subject to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Acceptable areas; limitations and conditions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A chancery shall be permitted to locate as a matter of right in any area which is zoned commercial, industrial, waterfront, or mixed-use (CR).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> A chancery shall also be permitted to locate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in any area which is zoned medium-high or high density residential, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any other area, determined on the basis of existing uses, which includes office or institutional uses, including but not limited to any area zoned mixed-use diplomatic or special purpose,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">subject to disapproval by the District of Columbia Board of Zoning Adjustment in accordance with this section.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In each of the areas described in paragraphs (1) and (2), the limitations and conditions applicable to chanceries shall not exceed those applicable to other office or institutional uses in that area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of application with Board of Zoning Adjustment; publication of notice; public participation; final determination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If a foreign mission wishes to locate a chancery in an area described in subsection (b)(2), or wishes to appeal an administrative decision relating to a chancery based in whole or in part upon any zoning map or regulation, it shall file an application with the Board of Zoning Adjustment which shall publish notice of that application in the District of Columbia Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Regulations issued to carry out this section shall provide appropriate opportunities for participation by the public in proceedings concerning the location, replacement, or expansion of chanceries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A final determination concerning the location, replacement, or expansion of a chancery shall be made not later than six months after the date of the filing of an application with respect to such location, replacement, or expansion. Such determination shall not be subject to the administrative proceedings of any other agency or official except as provided in this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for determination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any determination concerning the location of a chancery under subsection (b)(2), or concerning an appeal of an administrative decision with respect to a chancery based in whole or in part upon any zoning regulation or map, shall be based solely on the following criteria:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The international obligation of the United States to facilitate the provision of adequate and secure facilities for foreign missions in the Nation’s Capital.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Historic preservation, as determined by the Board of Zoning Adjustment in carrying out this section; and in order to ensure compatibility with historic landmarks and districts, substantial compliance with District of Columbia and Federal regulations governing historic preservation shall be required with respect to new construction and to demolition of or alteration to historic landmarks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The adequacy of off-street or other parking and the extent to which the area will be served by public transportation to reduce parking requirements, subject to such special security requirements as may be determined by the Secretary, after consultation with Federal agencies authorized to perform protective services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The extent to which the area is capable of being adequately protected, as determined by the Secretary, after consultation with Federal agencies authorized to perform protective services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The municipal interest, as determined by the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Federal interest, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consistency of regulations, proceedings, and other actions; review and comment by National Planning Commission</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Regulations, proceedings, and other actions of the National Capital Planning Commission, the Zoning Commission for the District of Columbia, and the Board of Zoning Adjustment affecting the location, replacement, or expansion of chanceries shall be consistent with this section (including the criteria set out in subsection (d)) and shall reflect the policy of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Proposed actions of the Zoning Commission concerning implementation of this section shall be referred to the National Capital Planning Commission for review and comment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule-making nature of proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Regulations issued to carry out this section shall provide for proceedings of a rule-making and not of an adjudicatory nature.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compliance with District of Columbia building and related codes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall require foreign missions to comply substantially with District of Columbia building and related codes in a manner determined by the Secretary to be not inconsistent with the international obligations of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of Board of Zoning Adjustment or Zoning Commission not required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Approval by the Board of Zoning Adjustment or the Zoning Commission or, except as provided in <ref>section 4305 of this title</ref>, by any other agency or official is not required—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the location, replacement, or expansion of a chancery to the extent that authority to proceed, or rights or interests, with respect to such location, replacement, or expansion were granted to or otherwise acquired by the foreign mission before <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for continuing use of a chancery by a foreign mission to the extent that the chancery was being used by a foreign mission on <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership on Zoning Commission and Board of Zoning Adjustment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President may designate the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Interior, or the Administrator of General Services (or such alternate as such official may from time to time designate) to serve as a member of the Zoning Commission in lieu of the Director of the National Park Service whenever the President determines that the Zoning Commission is performing functions concerning the implementation of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Whenever the Board of Zoning Adjustment is performing functions regarding an application by a foreign mission with respect to the location, expansion, or replacement of a chancery—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the representative from the Zoning Commission shall be the Director of the National Park Service or if another person has been designated under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the person so designated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the representative from the National Capital Planning Commission shall be the Executive Director of that Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Provisions of law (other than this chapter) applicable with respect to the location, replacement, or expansion of real property in the District of Columbia shall apply with respect to chanceries only to the extent that they are consistent with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 206, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 286</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4307.</num>
<heading> Preemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law, no act of any Federal agency shall be effective to confer or deny any benefit with respect to any foreign mission contrary to this chapter. Nothing in section 4302, 4303, 4304, or 4305 of this title may be construed to preempt any State or municipal law or governmental authority regarding zoning, land use, health, safety, or welfare, except that a denial by the Secretary involving a benefit for a foreign mission within the jurisdiction of a particular State or local government shall be controlling.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 207, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4308.</num>
<heading> General provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance of regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may issue such regulations as the Secretary may determine necessary to carry out the policy of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discharge of obligation; liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Compliance with any regulation, instruction, or direction issued by the Secretary under this chapter shall to the extent thereof be a full acquittance and discharge for all purposes of the obligation of the person making the same. No person shall be held liable in any court or administrative proceeding for or with respect to anything done or omitted in good faith in connection with the administration of, or pursuant to and in reliance on, this chapter, or any regulation, instruction, or direction issued by the Secretary under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of employees from other Federal agencies; experts and consultants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of administering this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary may accept details and assignments of employees of Federal agencies to the Department of State on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis (with any such reimbursements to be credited to the appropriations made available for the salaries and expenses of officers and employees of the employing agency); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary may, to the extent necessary to obtain services without delay, exercise his authority to employ experts and consultants under <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> without requiring compliance with such otherwise applicable requirements for that employment as the Secretary may determine, except that such employment shall be terminated after 60 days if by that time those requirements are not complied with.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracts and subcontracts for supplies and services; advertisement; factors considered</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Contracts and subcontracts for supplies or services, including personal services, made by or on behalf of the Secretary shall be made after advertising, in such manner and at such times as the Secretary shall determine to be adequate to ensure notice and opportunity for competition, except that advertisement shall not be required when (1) the Secretary determines that it is impracticable or will not permit timely performance to obtain bids by advertising, or (2) the aggregate amount involved in a purchase of supplies or procurement of services does not exceed $10,000. Such contracts and subcontracts may be entered into without regard to laws and regulations otherwise applicable to solicitation, negotiation, administration, and performance of government contracts. In awarding contracts, the Secretary may consider such factors as relative quality and availability of supplies or services and the compatibility of the supplies or services with implementation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer or loan of property to or from Department of State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The head of any Federal agency may, for purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> transfer or loan any property to, and perform administrative and technical support functions and services for the operations of, the Department of State (with reimbursements to agencies under this paragraph to be credited to the current applicable appropriation of the agency concerned); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> acquire and accept services from the Department of State, including (whenever the Secretary determines it to be in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter) acquisitions without regard to laws normally applicable to the acquisition of services by such agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attachment, execution, etc., of assets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Assets of or under the control of the Department of State, wherever situated, which are used by or held for the use of a foreign mission shall not be subject to attachment, execution, injunction, or similar process, whether intermediate or final.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretion of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, any determination required under this chapter shall be committed to the discretion of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer and credit of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In order to implement this chapter, the Secretary may transfer to the working capital fund established by <ref>section 2684 of this title</ref> such amounts available to the Department of State as may be necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> All revenues, including proceeds from gifts and donations, received by the Secretary in carrying out this chapter may be credited to the working capital fund established by <ref>section 2684 of this title</ref> and shall be available for purposes of this chapter in accordance with that section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Only amounts transferred or credited to the working capital fund established by <ref>section 2684 of this title</ref> may be used in carrying out the functions of the Secretary or the Director under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 208, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 288</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(6), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 410</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4309.</num>
<heading> Application to public international organizations and official missions to such organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make <ref>section 4306 of this title</ref>, or any other provision of this chapter, applicable with respect to an international organization to the same extent that it is applicable with respect to a foreign mission if the Secretary determines that such application is necessary to carry out the policy set forth in <ref>section 4301(b) of this title</ref> and to further the objectives set forth in <ref>section 4304(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “International organization” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, “international organization” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a public international organization designated as such pursuant to the International Organizations Immunities Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 288</ref>—288f–2) or a public international organization created pursuant to a treaty or other international agreement as an instrument through or by which two or more foreign governments engage in some aspect of their conduct of international affairs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an official mission (other than a United States mission) to such a public international organization,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">including any real property of such an organization or mission and including the personnel of such an organization or mission.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 209, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 289</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4309a.</num>
<heading> United States responsibilities for employees of the United Nations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> pursuant to the Agreement Between the United States and the United Nations Regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations (authorized by <ref>Public Law 80–357</ref> (<ref>22 U.S.C. 287</ref> note)), the United States has accepted—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the obligation to permit and to facilitate the right of individuals, who are employed by or are authorized by the United Nations to conduct official business in connection with that organization or its agencies, to enter into and exit from the United States for purposes of conducting official activities within the United Nations Headquarters District, subject to regulation as to points of entry and departure; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the implied obligation to permit and to facilitate the acquisition of facilities in order to conduct such activities within or in proximity to the United Nations Headquarters District, subject to reasonable regulation including regulation of the location and size of such facilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> taking into account paragraph (1) and consistent with the obligation of the United States to facilitate the functioning of the United Nations, the United States has no additional obligation to permit the conduct of any other activities, including nonofficial activities, by such individuals outside of the United Nations Headquarters District.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities of United Nations employees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The conduct of any activities, or the acquisition of any benefits (as defined in <ref>section 4301(a)(1) of this title</ref>), outside the United Nations Headquarters District by any individual employed by, or authorized by the United Nations to conduct official business in connection with, that organization or its agencies, or by any person or agency acting on behalf thereof, may be permitted or denied or subject to reasonable regulation, as determined to be in the best interests of the United States and pursuant to this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 139(26)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 399</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall report to the Congress—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not later than 30 days after <date date="1985-08-16">August 16, 1985</date>, on the plans of the Secretary for implementing this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not later than 6 months thereafter, on the actions taken pursuant to those plans.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States nationals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply with respect to any United States national.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “United Nations Headquarters District” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “United Nations Headquarters District” means the area within the United States which is agreed to by the United Nations and the United States to constitute such a district, together with such other areas as the Secretary of State may approve from time to time in order to permit effective functioning of the United Nations or missions to the United Nations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 209A, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 141</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 423</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 139(26)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 399</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4310.</num>
<heading> Privileges and immunities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to limit the authority of the United States to carry out its international obligations, or to supersede or limit immunities otherwise available by law. No act or omission by any foreign mission, public international organization, or official mission to such an organization, in compliance with this chapter shall be deemed to be an implied waiver of any immunity otherwise provided for by law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 210, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4311.</num>
<heading> Enforcement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benefits to foreign missions contrary to this chapter; standing of United States to bring action for compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to make available any benefits to a foreign mission contrary to this chapter. The United States, acting on its own behalf or on behalf of a foreign mission, has standing to bring or intervene in an action to obtain compliance with this chapter, including any action for injunctive or other equitable relief.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advice of Secretary concerning transactions with foreign missions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of any Federal agency, any State or local government agency, or any business or other person that proposes to enter into a contract or other transaction with a foreign mission, the Secretary shall advise whether the proposed transaction is prohibited by any regulation or determination of the Secretary under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 211, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4312.</num>
<heading> Presidential guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authorities granted to the Secretary pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall be exercised in accordance with procedures and guidelines approved by the President.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 212, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4313.</num>
<heading> Severability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the remainder of this chapter and the application of such provision to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 213, as added <ref>Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4314.</num>
<heading> Extraordinary protective services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may provide extraordinary protective services for foreign missions directly, by contract, or through State or local authority to the extent deemed necessary by the Secretary in carrying out this chapter, except that the Secretary may not provide under this section any protective services for which authority exists to provide such services under subsections (a)(7) and (d) of <ref>section 3056A of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of extraordinary circumstances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may provide funds to a State or local authority for protective services under this section only if the Secretary has determined that a threat of violence, or other circumstances, exists which requires extraordinary security measures which exceed those which local law enforcment <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002301">1</ref> agencies can reasonably be expected to take.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 139(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 397</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of the funds made available for obligation under this section in any fiscal year—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not more than 20 percent may be obligated for protective services within any single State during that year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not less than 15 percent shall be retained as a reserve for protective services provided directly by the Secretary or for expenditures in local jurisdictions not otherwise covered by an agreement for protective services under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The limitations on funds available for obligation in this subsection shall not apply to unobligated funds during the final quarter of any fiscal year.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of agreement with State or local authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any agreement with a State or local authority for the provision of protective services under this section shall be for a period of not to exceed 90 days in any calendar year, but such agreements may be renewed after review by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Contracts may be entered into in carrying out this section only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Working capital fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Amounts used to carry out this section shall not be subject to <ref>section 4308(h) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 214, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 126(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 417</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 139(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 397</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–177, title VI, § 605(d)(3)</ref>, (e)(2)(C), <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4315.</num>
<heading> Use of foreign mission in manner incompatible with its status as foreign mission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of limitation on certain uses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A foreign mission may not allow an unaffiliated alien the use of any premise of that foreign mission which is inviolable under United States law (including any treaty) for any purpose which is incompatible with its status as a foreign mission, including use as a residence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Temporary lodging</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the term “residence” does not include such temporary lodging as may be permitted under regulations issued by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may waive subsection (a) with respect to all foreign missions of a country (and may revoke such a waiver) 30 days after providing written notification of such a waiver, together with the reasons for such waiver (or revocation of such a waiver), to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the Congress concerning the implementation of this section and shall submit such other reports to the Congress concerning changes in implementation as may be necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “foreign mission” includes any international organization as defined in <ref>section 4309(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “unaffiliated alien” means, with respect to a foreign country, an alien who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is admitted to the United States as a nonimmigrant, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not a member, or a family member of a member, of a foreign mission of that foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 215, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 128(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1343</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4316.</num>
<heading> Application of travel restrictions to personnel of certain countries and organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall apply the same generally applicable restrictions to the travel while in the United States of the individuals described in subsection (b) as are applied under this chapter to the members of the missions of the Soviet Union in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individuals subject to restrictions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The restrictions required by subsection (a) shall be applied with respect to those individuals who (as determined by the Secretary) are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the personnel of an international organization, if the individual is a national of any foreign country whose government engages in intelligence activities in the United States that are harmful to the national security of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the personnel of a mission to an international organization, if that mission is the mission of a foreign government that engages in intelligence activities in the United States that are harmful to the national security of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the family members or dependents of an individual described in paragraphs (1) and (2);</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">and who are not nationals or permanent resident aliens of the United States.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waivers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, after consultation with the Director of Central Intelligence and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, may waive application of the restrictions required by subsection (a) if the Secretary determines that the national security and foreign policy interests of the United States so require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 139(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 397</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “generally applicable restrictions” means any limitations on the radius within which unrestricted travel is permitted and obtaining travel services through the auspices of the Office of Foreign Missions for travel elsewhere, and does not include any restrictions which unconditionally prohibit the members of missions of the Soviet Union in the United States from traveling to designated areas of the United States and which are applied as a result of particular factors in relations between the United States and the Soviet Union.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002302">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “international organization” means an organization described in <ref>section 4309(b)(1) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the term “personnel” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> officers, employees, and any other staff member, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any individual who is retained under contract or other arrangement to serve functions similar to those of an officer, employee, or other staff member.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 216, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 162(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1357</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 139(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 397</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>