<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 74—</num>
<heading>FOREIGN AFFAIRS AGENCIES CONSOLIDATION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6501.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to strengthen—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the coordination of United States foreign policy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the leading role of the Secretary of State in the formulation and articulation of United States foreign policy;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to consolidate and reinvigorate the foreign affairs functions of the United States within the Department of State by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> abolishing the United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, the United States Information Agency, and the United States International Development Cooperation Agency, and transferring the functions of these agencies to the Department of State while preserving the special missions and skills of these agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transferring certain functions of the Agency for International Development to the Department of State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> providing for the reorganization of the Department of State to maximize the efficient use of resources, which may lead to budget savings, eliminated redundancy in functions, and improvement in the management of the Department of State;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to ensure that programs critical to the promotion of United States national interests be maintained;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to assist congressional efforts to balance the Federal budget and reduce the Federal debt;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to ensure that the United States maintains effective representation abroad within budgetary restraints; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to encourage United States foreign affairs agencies to maintain a high percentage of the best qualified, most competent United States citizens serving in the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XI, § 1102, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–765</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6502.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> ACDA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “ACDA” means the United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> AID</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “AID” means the United States Agency for International Development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency; Federal agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “agency” or “Federal agency” means an Executive agency as defined in <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on International Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “covered agency” means any of the following agencies: ACDA, USIA, IDCA, and AID.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Department” means the Department of State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Function</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “function” means any duty, obligation, power, authority, responsibility, right, privilege, activity, or program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> IDCA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “IDCA” means the United States International Development Cooperation Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “office” includes any office, administration, agency, institute, unit, organizational entity, or component thereof.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> USIA</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “USIA” means the United States Information Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XI, § 1103, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–766</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6503.</num>
<heading> Report on budgetary cost savings resulting from reorganization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall submit a report, together with the congressional presentation document for the budget of the Department of State for each of the fiscal years 2000 and 2001, to the appropriate congressional committees describing the total anticipated and achieved cost savings in budget outlays and budget authority related to the reorganization implemented under this chapter, including cost savings by each of the following categories:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Reductions in personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Administrative consolidation, including procurement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Program consolidation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Consolidation of real properties and leases.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XI, § 1104, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–767</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES ARMS CONTROL AND DISARMAMENT AGENCY</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Abolition and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6511.</num>
<heading> Abolition of United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency is abolished.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1211, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–767</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6512.</num>
<heading> Transfer of functions to Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are transferred to the Secretary of State all functions of the Director of the United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, and all functions of the United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency and any office or component of such agency, under any statute, reorganization plan, Executive order, or other provision of law, as of the day before the effective date of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1212, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–767</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Miscellaneous Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6521.</num>
<heading> References</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in section 1223 or 1225, any reference in any statute, reorganization plan, Executive order, regulation, agreement, determination, or other official document or proceeding to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Director of the United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, the Director of the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, or any other officer or employee of the United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency or the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency shall be deemed to refer to the Secretary of State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency or the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency shall be deemed to refer to the Department of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1221, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–768</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES INFORMATION AGENCY</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Abolition and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6531.</num>
<heading> Abolition of United States Information Agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Information Agency (other than the Broadcasting Board of Governors and the International Broadcasting Bureau) is abolished.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1311, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–776</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6532.</num>
<heading> Transfer of functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are transferred to the Secretary of State all functions of the Director of the United States Information Agency and all functions of the United States Information Agency and any office or component of such agency, under any statute, reorganization plan, Executive order, or other provision of law, as of the day before the effective date of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) does not apply to the Broadcasting Board of Governors, the International Broadcasting Bureau, or any function performed by the Board or the Bureau.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1312, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–776</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6533.</num>
<heading> Abolition of Office of Inspector General of United States Information Agency and transfer of functions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abolition of Office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Inspector General of the United States Information Agency is abolished.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (d) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are transferred to the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service the functions that the Office of Inspector General of the United States Information Agency exercised before the effective date of this subchapter (including all related functions of the Inspector General of the United States Information Agency).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1314, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–776</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">International Broadcasting</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6541.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declaration of purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> it is the policy of the United States to promote the right of freedom of opinion and expression, including the freedom “to seek, receive, and impart information and ideas through any media and regardless of frontiers”, in accordance with Article 19 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> open communication of information and ideas among the peoples of the world contributes to international peace and stability, and the promotion of such communication is in the interests of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> it is in the interest of the United States to support broadcasting to other nations consistent with the requirements of this part and the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 6201</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> international broadcasting is, and should remain, an essential instrument of United States foreign policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1321, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–777</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6542.</num>
<heading> Transfer of broadcasting related funds, property, and personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer and allocation of property and appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The assets, liabilities (including contingent liabilities arising from suits continued with a substitution or addition of parties under <ref>section 6543(d) of this title</ref>), contracts, property, records, and unexpended balance of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, held, used, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with the functions and offices of USIA transferred to the Broadcasting Board of Governors by this part shall be transferred to the Broadcasting Board of Governors for appropriate allocation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the transfers made under paragraph (1), there shall be transferred to the Chairman of the Broadcasting Board of Governors the assets, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balance of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds, as determined by the Secretary, in concurrence with the Broadcasting Board of Governors, to support the functions transferred by this part.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of personnel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> except as provided in subsection (c), all personnel and positions of USIA employed or maintained to carry out the functions transferred by this part to the Broadcasting Board of Governors shall be transferred to the Broadcasting Board of Governors at the same grade or class and the same rate of basic pay or basic salary rate and with the same tenure held immediately preceding transfer; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the personnel and positions of USIA, as determined by the Secretary of State, with the concurrence of the Broadcasting Board of Governors and the Director of USIA, to support the functions transferred by this part shall be transferred to the Broadcasting Board of Governors, including the International Broadcasting Bureau, at the same grade or class and the same rate of basic pay or basic salary rate and with the same tenure held immediately preceding transfer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer and allocation of property, appropriations, and personnel associated with Worldnet</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">USIA personnel responsible for carrying out interactive dialogs with foreign media and other similar overseas public diplomacy programs using the Worldnet television broadcasting system, and funds associated with such personnel, shall be transferred to the Department of State in accordance with the provisions of subchapter VI of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incidental transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, when requested by the Broadcasting Board of Governors, is authorized to make such incidental dispositions of personnel, assets, liabilities, grants, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds held, used, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with functions and offices transferred from USIA, as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1326, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–782</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6543.</num>
<heading> Savings provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing legal force and effect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">All orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, agreements, grants, contracts, certificates, licenses, registrations, privileges, and other administrative actions—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that have been issued, made, granted, or allowed to become effective by the President, any Federal agency or official thereof, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, in the performance of functions exercised by the Broadcasting Board of Governors of the United States Information Agency on the day before the effective date of this subchapter, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that are in effect at the time this subchapter takes effect, or were final before the effective date of this subchapter and are to become effective on or after the effective date of this subchapter,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall continue in effect according to their terms until modified, terminated, superseded, set aside, or revoked in accordance with law by the President, the Broadcasting Board of Governors, or other authorized official, a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pending proceedings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of this part, or amendments made by this part, shall not affect any proceedings, including notices of proposed rulemaking, or any application for any license, permit, certificate, or financial assistance pending before the Broadcasting Board of Governors of the United States Information Agency at the time this subchapter takes effect, with respect to functions exercised by the Board as of the effective date of this subchapter but such proceedings and applications shall be continued.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Orders, appeals, and payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Orders shall be issued in such proceedings, appeals shall be taken therefrom, and payments shall be made pursuant to such orders, as if this part had not been enacted, and orders issued in any such proceedings shall continue in effect until modified, terminated, superseded, or revoked by a duly authorized official, by a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be deemed to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any such proceeding under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such proceeding could have been discontinued or modified if this part had not been enacted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonabatement of proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No suit, action, or other proceeding commenced by or against any officer in the official capacity of such individual as an officer of the Broadcasting Board of Governors, or any commission or component thereof, shall abate by reason of the enactment of this part. No cause of action by or against the Broadcasting Board of Governors, or any commission or component thereof, or by or against any officer thereof in the official capacity of such officer, shall abate by reason of the enactment of this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuation of proceedings with substitution of parties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substitution of parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, before the effective date of this subchapter, USIA or the Broadcasting Board of Governors, or any officer thereof in the official capacity of such officer, is a party to a suit which is related to the functions transferred by this part, then effective on such date such suit shall be continued with the Broadcasting Board of Governors or other appropriate official of the Board substituted or added as a party.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of the Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall participate in suits continued under paragraph (1) where the Broadcasting Board of Governors or other appropriate official of the Board is added as a party and shall be liable for any judgments or remedies in those suits or proceedings arising from the exercise of the functions transferred by this part to the same extent that USIA would have been liable if such judgment or remedy had been rendered on the day before the abolition of USIA.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative actions relating to promulgation of regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any administrative action relating to the preparation or promulgation of a regulation by the Broadcasting Board of Governors relating to a function exercised by the Board before the effective date of this subchapter may be continued by the Board with the same effect as if this part had not been enacted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> References</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Reference in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or relating to the Broadcasting Board of Governors of the United States Information Agency with regard to functions exercised before the effective date of this subchapter, shall be deemed to refer to the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1327, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6544.</num>
<heading> Report on privatization of RFE/RL, Incorporated</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than March 1 of each year, the Broadcasting Board of Governors shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the progress of the Board and of RFE/RL, Incorporated, on any steps taken to further the policy declared in <ref>section 6211(a) of this title</ref>. The report under this subsection shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Efforts by RFE/RL, Incorporated, to terminate individual language services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A detailed description of steps taken with regard to <ref>section 6211(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> An analysis of prospects for privatization over the coming year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An assessment of the extent to which United States Government funding may be appropriate in the year 2000 and subsequent years for surrogate broadcasting to the countries to which RFE/RL, Incorporated, broadcast during the year. This assessment shall include an analysis of the environment for independent media in those countries, noting the extent of government control of the media, the ability of independent journalists and news organizations to operate, relevant domestic legislation, level of government harassment and efforts to censor, and other indications of whether the people of such countries enjoy freedom of expression.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1328, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–784</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part C—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Conforming Amendments</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6551.</num>
<heading> References</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, any reference in any statute, reorganization plan, Executive order, regulation, agreement, determination, or other official document or proceeding to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Director of the United States Information Agency or the Director of the International Communication Agency shall be deemed to refer to the Secretary of State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States Information Agency, USIA, or the International Communication Agency shall be deemed to refer to the Department of State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing references to USIA or Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply to section 4069a(f), 4069b(g), or 4069c(f) of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1331, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–785</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6552.</num>
<heading> Application of certain laws</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application to functions of Department of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 1461 of this title</ref>, <ref>section 1461–1 of this title</ref>, and <ref>section 1461–1a of this title</ref> shall not apply to public affairs and other information dissemination functions of the Secretary of State as carried out prior to any transfer of functions pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application to functions transferred to Department of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0"><ref>Section 1461 of this title</ref>, <ref>section 1461–1 of this title</ref>, and <ref>section 1461–1a of this title</ref> shall apply only to public diplomacy programs of the Director of the United States Information Agency as carried out prior to any transfer of functions pursuant to this chapter to the same extent that such programs were covered by these provisions prior to such transfer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in <ref>section 1461 of this title</ref> and <ref>section 1461–1a of this title</ref>, funds specifically authorized to be appropriated for such public diplomacy programs, identified as public diplomacy funds in any Congressional Presentation Document described in subsection (e), or reprogrammed for public diplomacy purposes, shall not be used to influence public opinion in the United States, and no program material prepared using such funds shall be distributed or disseminated in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in paragraph (1) may be construed (A) to interfere with the integration of administrative resources between public diplomacy and other functions of the Department of State or to prevent the occasional performance of functions other than public diplomacy by officials or employees of the Department of State who are primarily assigned to public diplomacy, provided there is no substantial resulting diminution in the amount of resources devoted to public diplomacy below the amounts described in paragraph (1), or (B) to supersede reprogramming procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The report submitted pursuant to <ref>section 6601(f) of this title</ref> shall include a detailed statement of the manner in which the special mission of public diplomacy carried out by USIA prior to the transfer of functions under this chapter shall be preserved within the Department of State, including the planned duties and responsibilities of any new bureaus that will perform such public diplomacy functions. Such report shall also include the best available estimates of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amounts expended by the Department of State for public affairs programs during fiscal year 1998, and on the personnel and support costs for such programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amounts expended by USIA for its public diplomacy programs during fiscal year 1998, and on the personnel and support costs for such programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amounts, including funds to be transferred from USIA and funds appropriated to the Department, that will be allocated for the programs described in paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively, during the fiscal year in which the transfer of functions from USIA to the Department occurs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional Presentation Document</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Department of State’s Congressional Presentation Document for fiscal year 2000 and each fiscal year thereafter shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the aggregated amounts that the Department will spend on such public diplomacy programs and on costs of personnel for such programs, and a detailed description of the goals and purposes for which such funds shall be expended; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of funds allocated to and the positions authorized for such public diplomacy programs, including bureaus to be created upon the transfer of functions from USIA to the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1333, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–785</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title III, § 304]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–434.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6553.</num>
<heading> Continuation of United States Advisory Commission on Public Diplomacy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Advisory Commission on Public Diplomacy, established under <ref>section 1469 of this title</ref> and section 8 of Reorganization Plan Numbered 2 of 1977, shall continue to exist and operate under such provisions of law.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1334, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–786</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title IV, § 404(a)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–446; <ref>Pub. L. 107–77, title IV, § 407(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-28">Nov. 28, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 790</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–108, title IV, § 410</ref>, <date date="2005-11-22">Nov. 22, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2327</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–21, § 1</ref>, <date date="2007-05-02">May 2, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 87</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–70, § 1</ref>, <date date="2009-10-09">Oct. 9, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2057</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XII, § 1280(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2033</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–323, title VII, § 702(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1940</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–159, div. A, § 168</ref>, <date date="2020-10-01">Oct. 1, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 723</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. E, title LVI, § 5604</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2379</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT COOPERATION AGENCY</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Abolition and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6561.</num>
<heading> Abolition of United States International Development Cooperation Agency</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except for the components specified in subsection (b), the United States International Development Cooperation Agency (including the Institute for Scientific and Technological Cooperation) is abolished.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> AID and OPIC exempted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) does not apply to the Agency for International Development or the Overseas Private Investment Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIV, § 1411, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–790</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6562.</num>
<heading> Transfer of functions and authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation to the Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds made available under the categories of assistance deemed allocated to the Director of the International Development Cooperation Agency under section 1–801 of Executive Order No. 12163 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2381</ref> note) as of <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>, shall be allocated to the Secretary of State on and after the effective date of this subchapter without further action by the President.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures for reallocations or transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State may allocate or transfer as appropriate any funds received under paragraph (1) in the same manner as previously provided for the Director of the International Development Cooperation Agency under section 1–802 of that Executive Order, as in effect on <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> With respect to Overseas Private Investment Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are transferred to the Administrator of the Agency for International Development all functions of the Director of the United States International Development Cooperation Agency as of the day before the effective date of this subchapter with respect to the Overseas Private Investment Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authorities and functions transferred to the United States International Development Cooperation Agency or the Director of that Agency by section 6 of Reorganization Plan Numbered 2 of 1979 shall, to the extent such authorities and functions have not been repealed, be transferred to those agencies or heads of agencies, as the case may be, in which those authorities and functions were vested by statute as of the day before the effective date of such reorganization plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIV, § 1412, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–790</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6563.</num>
<heading> Status of AID</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless abolished pursuant to the reorganization plan submitted under <ref>section 6601 of this title</ref>, and except as provided in <ref>section 6562 of this title</ref>, there is within the Executive branch of Government the United States Agency for International Development as an entity described in <ref>section 104 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Retention of officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall require the reappointment of any officer of the United States serving in the Agency for International Development of the United States International Development Cooperation Agency as of the day before the effective date of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIV, § 1413, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–791</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Miscellaneous Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6571.</num>
<heading> References</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, any reference in any statute, reorganization plan, Executive order, regulation, agreement, determination, or other official document or proceeding to the United States International Development Cooperation Agency (IDCA) or to the Director or any other officer or employee of IDCA—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> insofar as such reference relates to any function or authority transferred under <ref>section 6562(a) of this title</ref>, shall be deemed to refer to the Secretary of State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> insofar as such reference relates to any function or authority transferred under <ref>section 6562(b) of this title</ref>, shall be deemed to refer to the Administrator of the Agency for International Development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> insofar as such reference relates to any function or authority transferred under <ref>section 6562(c) of this title</ref>, shall be deemed to refer to the head of the agency to which such function or authority is transferred under such section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> insofar as such reference relates to any function or authority not transferred by this subchapter, shall be deemed to refer to the President or such agency or agencies as may be specified by Executive order.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIV, § 1421, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–791</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>AGENCY FOR INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Reorganization and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6581.</num>
<heading> Reorganization of Agency for International Development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Agency for International Development shall be reorganized in accordance with this chapter and the reorganization plan transmitted pursuant to <ref>section 6601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions to be transferred</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The reorganization of the Agency for International Development shall provide, at a minimum, for the transfer to and consolidation with the Department of State of the following functions of AID:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Press office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Certain administrative functions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XV, § 1511, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–793</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Authorities of Secretary of State</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6591.</num>
<heading> “United States assistance” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this part, the term “United States assistance” means development and other economic assistance, including assistance made available under the following provisions of law:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Chapter 1 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.] (relating to development assistance).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> et seq.] (relating to the economic support fund).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Chapter 10 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2293</ref> et seq.] (relating to the Development Fund for Africa).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Chapter 11 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2295</ref> et seq.] (relating to assistance for the independent states of the former Soviet Union).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Support for East European Democracy Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 5401</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XV, § 1521, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–794</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6592.</num>
<heading> Administrator of AID reporting to Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Agency for International Development, appointed pursuant to <ref>section 2384(a) of this title</ref>, shall report to and be under the direct authority and foreign policy guidance of the Secretary of State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XV, § 1522, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–794</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6593.</num>
<heading> Assistance programs coordination and oversight</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary of State</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Under the direction of the President, the Secretary of State shall coordinate all United States assistance in accordance with this section, except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Export promotion activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Coordination of activities relating to promotion of exports of United States goods and services shall continue to be primarily the responsibility of the Secretary of Commerce.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International economic activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Coordination of activities relating to United States participation in international financial institutions and relating to organization of multilateral efforts aimed at currency stabilization, currency convertibility, debt reduction, and comprehensive economic reform programs shall continue to be primarily the responsibility of the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorities and powers of the Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The powers and authorities of the Secretary provided in this part are in addition to the powers and authorities provided to the Secretary under any other Act, including section 101(b) and section 622(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151(b)</ref>, 2382(c)).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Coordination activities of the Secretary of State under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> approving an overall assistance and economic cooperation strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensuring program and policy coordination among agencies of the United States Government in carrying out the policies set forth in the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], the Arms Export Control Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.], and other relevant assistance Acts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> pursuing coordination with other countries and international organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> resolving policy, program, and funding disputes among United States Government agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section may be construed to lessen the accountability of any Federal agency administering any program, project, or activity of United States assistance for any funds made available to the Federal agency for that purpose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to provide personnel of Agency for International Development</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the Agency for International Development is authorized to detail to the Department of State on a nonreimbursable basis such personnel employed by the Agency as the Secretary of State may require to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XV, § 1523, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–794</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>TRANSITION</heading>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part A—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Reorganization Plan</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6601.</num>
<heading> Reorganization plan and report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Submission of plan and report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1998-10-21">October 21, 1998</date>, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a reorganization plan and report regarding—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the abolition of the United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, the United States Information Agency, and the United States International Development Cooperation Agency in accordance with this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with respect to the Agency for International Development, the consolidation and streamlining of the Agency and the transfer of certain functions of the Agency to the Department in accordance with <ref>section 6581 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the termination of functions of each covered agency as may be necessary to effectuate the reorganization under this chapter, and the termination of the affairs of each agency abolished under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the transfer to the Department of the functions and personnel of each covered agency consistent with the provisions of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the consolidation, reorganization, and streamlining of the Department in connection with the transfer of such functions and personnel in order to carry out such functions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The agencies covered by this section are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The United States Information Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The United States International Development Cooperation Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Agency for International Development.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The plan transmitted under subsection (a) shall contain, consistent with this chapter, such elements as the President deems appropriate, including elements that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify the functions of each covered agency that will be transferred to the Department under the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> specify the steps to be taken by the Secretary of State to reorganize internally the functions of the Department, including the consolidation of offices and functions, that will be required under the plan in order to permit the Department to carry out the functions transferred to it under the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> specify the funds available to each covered agency that will be transferred to the Department as a result of the transfer of functions of such agency to the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> specify the proposed allocations within the Department of unexpended funds transferred in connection with the transfer of functions under the plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> specify the proposed disposition of the property, facilities, contracts, records, and other assets and liabilities of each covered agency in connection with the transfer of the functions of such agency to the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reorganization plan of Agency for International Development</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to applicable provisions of subsection (c), the reorganization plan transmitted under this section for the Agency for International Development—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may provide for the abolition of the Agency for International Development and the transfer of all its functions to the Department of State; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in lieu of the abolition and transfer of functions under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall provide for the transfer to and consolidation within the Department of the functions set forth in <ref>section 6581 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> may provide for additional consolidation, reorganization, and streamlining of AID, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the termination of functions and reductions in personnel of AID;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the transfer of functions of AID, and the personnel associated with such functions, to the Department; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the consolidation, reorganization, and streamlining of the Department upon the transfer of such functions and personnel in order to carry out the functions transferred.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may, on the basis of consultations with the appropriate congressional committees, modify or revise any part of the plan transmitted under subsection (a) until that part of the plan becomes effective in accordance with subsection (g).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The report accompanying the reorganization plan for the Department and the covered agencies submitted pursuant to this section shall describe the implementation of the plan and shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a detailed description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the actions necessary or planned to complete the reorganization,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the anticipated nature and substance of any orders, directives, and other administrative and operational actions which are expected to be required for completing or implementing the reorganization, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any preliminary actions which have been taken in the implementation process;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of personnel and positions of each covered agency (including civil service personnel, Foreign Service personnel, and detailees) that are expected to be transferred to the Department, separated from service with such agency, or eliminated under the plan, and a projected schedule for such transfers, separations, and terminations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the number of personnel and positions of the Department (including civil service personnel, Foreign Service personnel, and detailees) that are expected to be transferred within the Department, separated from service with the Department, or eliminated under the plan, and a projected schedule for such transfers, separations, and terminations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a projected schedule for completion of the implementation process; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> recommendations, if any, for legislation necessary to carry out changes made by this chapter relating to personnel and to incidental transfers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The reorganization plan described in this section, including any modifications or revisions of the plan under subsection (e), shall become effective on the earlier of the date for the respective covered agency specified in paragraph (2) or the date announced by the President under paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory effective dates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The effective dates under this paragraph for the reorganization plan described in this section are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><date date="1999-04-01">April 1, 1999</date>, with respect to functions of the Agency for International Development described in <ref>section 6581 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><date date="1999-04-01">April 1, 1999</date>, with respect to the abolition of the United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency and the United States International Development Cooperation Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>, with respect to the abolition of the United States Information Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date by Presidential determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An effective date under this paragraph for a reorganization plan described in this section is such date as the President shall determine to be appropriate and announce by notice published in the Federal Register, which date may be not earlier than 90 calendar days after the President has transmitted the reorganization plan to the appropriate congressional committees pursuant to subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to require the transfer of functions, personnel, records, balance of appropriations, or other assets of a covered agency on a single date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supersedes existing law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall apply notwithstanding <ref>section 905(b) of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The reorganization plan described in this section shall be printed in the Federal Register after the date upon which it first becomes effective.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XVI, § 1601, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–795</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num class="small-caps">Part B—</num>
<heading class="small-caps">Reorganization Authority</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6611.</num>
<heading> Reorganization authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized, subject to the requirements of this chapter, to allocate or reallocate any function transferred to the Department under any subchapter of this chapter, and to establish, consolidate, alter, or discontinue such organizational entities within the Department as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out any reorganization under this chapter, but this subsection does not authorize the Secretary to modify the terms of any statute that establishes or defines the functions of any bureau, office, or officer of the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements and limitations on reorganization plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The reorganization plan transmitted under <ref>section 6601 of this title</ref> may not have the effect of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> creating a new executive department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> continuing a function beyond the period authorized by law for its exercise or beyond the time when it would have terminated if the reorganization had not been made;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> authorizing a Federal agency to exercise a function which is not authorized by law at the time the plan is transmitted to Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> creating a new Federal agency which is not a component or part of an existing executive department or independent agency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> increasing the term of an office beyond that provided by law for the office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XVI, § 1611, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–798</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6612.</num>
<heading> Transfer and allocation of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the assets, liabilities (including contingent liabilities arising from suits continued with a substitution or addition of parties under <ref>section 6615(e) of this title</ref>), contracts, property, records, and unexpended balance of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, held, used, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with the functions and offices, or portions thereof, transferred by any subchapter of this chapter shall be transferred to the Secretary for appropriate allocation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of transferred funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (c), unexpended and unobligated funds transferred pursuant to any subchapter of this chapter shall be used only for the purposes for which the funds were originally authorized and appropriated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funds to facilitate transition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds transferred pursuant to subsection (a) may be available for the purposes of reorganization subject to notification of the appropriate congressional committees in accordance with the procedures applicable to a reprogramming of funds under <ref>section 2706 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Funds in any account appropriated to the Department of State may be transferred to another such account for the purposes of reorganization, subject to notification of the appropriate congressional committees in accordance with the procedures applicable to a reprogramming of funds under <ref>section 2706 of this title</ref>. The authority in this paragraph is in addition to any other transfer authority available to the Secretary of State and shall expire <date date="2000-09-30">September 30, 2000</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XVI, § 1612, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–798</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6613.</num>
<heading> Transfer, appointment, and assignment of personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of personnel from ACDA and USIA</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in subchapter III—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not later than the date of abolition of ACDA, all personnel and positions of ACDA, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not later than the date of abolition of USIA, all personnel and positions of USIA,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be transferred to the Department of State at the same grade or class and the same rate of basic pay or basic salary rate and with the same tenure held immediately preceding transfer.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of personnel from AID</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in subchapter III, not later than the date of transfer of any function of AID to the Department of State under this chapter, all AID personnel performing such functions and all positions associated with such functions shall be transferred to the Department of State at the same grade or class and the same rate of basic pay or basic salary rate and with the same tenure held immediately preceding transfer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, for a period of not more than 6 months commencing on the effective date of the transfer to the Department of State of personnel under subsections (a) and (b), is authorized to assign such personnel to any position or set of duties in the Department of State regardless of the position held or duties performed by such personnel prior to transfer, except that, by virtue of such assignment, such personnel shall not have their grade or class or their rate of basic pay or basic salary rate reduced, nor their tenure changed. In carrying out the reorganization under this Act, the Secretary shall ensure that the advances made in increasing the number and status of women and minorities within the foreign affairs agencies of the Federal Government, in terms of representation within the agencies as well as relative rank, are not undermined by discrimination within the newly reorganized Department of State. The Secretary shall consult with the relevant exclusive representatives (as defined in <ref>section 4102 of this title</ref> and in <ref>section 7103 of title 5</ref>) with regard to the exercise of this authority. This subsection does not authorize the Secretary to assign any individual to any position that by law requires appointment by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Superseding other provisions of law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsections (a) through (c) shall be exercised notwithstanding any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XVI, § 1613, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–799</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title III, § 341]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–444.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6614.</num>
<heading> Incidental transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, when requested by the Secretary, is authorized to make such incidental dispositions of personnel, assets, liabilities, grants, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds held, used, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with such functions, as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of any subchapter of this chapter. The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Secretary, shall provide for the termination of the affairs of all entities terminated by this chapter and for such further measures and dispositions as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of any subchapter of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XVI, § 1614, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–799</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6615.</num>
<heading> Savings provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing legal force and effect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">All orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, agreements, grants, contracts, certificates, licenses, registrations, privileges, and other administrative actions—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that have been issued, made, granted, or allowed to become effective by the President, any Federal agency or official thereof, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, in the performance of functions that are transferred under any subchapter of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that are in effect as of the effective date of such subchapter, or were final before the effective date of such subchapter and are to become effective on or after the effective date of such subchapter,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall continue in effect according to their terms until modified, terminated, superseded, set aside, or revoked in accordance with law by the President, the Secretary, or other authorized official, a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pending proceedings</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of any subchapter of this chapter shall not affect any proceedings, including notices of proposed rulemaking, or any application for any license, permit, certificate, or financial assistance pending on the effective date of any subchapter of this chapter before any Federal agency, commission, or component thereof, functions of which are transferred by any subchapter of this chapter. Such proceedings and applications, to the extent that they relate to functions so transferred, shall be continued.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Orders, appeals, payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Orders shall be issued in such proceedings, appeals shall be taken therefrom, and payments shall be made pursuant to such orders, as if this chapter had not been enacted. Orders issued in any such proceedings shall continue in effect until modified, terminated, superseded, or revoked by the Secretary, by a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any such proceeding under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such proceeding could have been discontinued or modified if this chapter had not been enacted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary is authorized to promulgate regulations providing for the orderly transfer of proceedings continued under this subsection to the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No effect on judicial or administrative proceedings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (e) and <ref>section 6543(d) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the provisions of this chapter shall not affect suits commenced prior to the effective dates of the respective subchapters of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in all such suits, proceedings shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered in the same manner and effect as if this chapter had not been enacted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonabatement of proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No suit, action, or other proceeding commenced by or against any officer in the official capacity of such individual as an officer of any Federal agency, or any commission or component thereof, functions of which are transferred by any subchapter of this chapter, shall abate by reason of the enactment of this chapter. No cause of action by or against any Federal agency, or any commission or component thereof, functions of which are transferred by any subchapter of this chapter, or by or against any officer thereof in the official capacity of such officer shall abate by reason of the enactment of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuation of proceeding with substitution of parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, before the effective date of any subchapter of this chapter, any Federal agency, or officer thereof in the official capacity of such officer, is a party to a suit, and under this chapter any function of such department, agency, or officer is transferred to the Secretary or any other official of the Department, then effective on such date such suit shall be continued with the Secretary or other appropriate official of the Department substituted or added as a party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reviewability of orders and actions under transferred functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Orders and actions of the Secretary in the exercise of functions transferred under any subchapter of this chapter shall be subject to judicial review to the same extent and in the same manner as if such orders and actions had been by the Federal agency or office, or part thereof, exercising such functions immediately preceding their transfer. Any statutory requirements relating to notice, hearings, action upon the record, or administrative review that apply to any function transferred by any subchapter of this chapter shall apply to the exercise of such function by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XVI, § 1615, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–800</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6616.</num>
<heading> Authority of Secretary of State to facilitate transition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter, the Secretary of State, with the concurrence of the head of the appropriate Federal agency exercising functions transferred under this chapter, may transfer the whole or part of such functions prior to the effective dates established in this chapter, including the transfer of personnel and funds associated with such functions.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XVI, § 1616, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–801</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6617.</num>
<heading> Final report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2001-01-01">January 1, 2001</date>, the President, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report which provides a final accounting of the finances and operations of the agencies abolished under this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XVI, § 1617, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–801</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
</chapter>