<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 35—</num>
<heading>ARMS CONTROL AND DISARMAMENT</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2551.</num>
<heading> Congressional statement of purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An ultimate goal of the United States is a world which is free from the scourge of war and the dangers and burdens of armaments; in which the use of force has been subordinated to the rule of law; and in which international adjustments to a changing world are achieved peacefully. It is the purpose of this chapter to provide impetus toward this goal by addressing the problem of reduction and control of armaments looking toward ultimate world disarmament.</p>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State must have the capacity to provide the essential scientific, economic, political, military, psychological, and technological information upon which realistic arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament policy must be based. The Secretary shall have the authority, under the direction of the President, to carry out the following primary functions:</p>
<p class="indent1">(1) The preparation for and management of United States participation in international negotiations and implementation fora in the arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament field.</p>
<p class="indent1">(2) The conduct, support, and coordination of research for arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament policy formulation.</p>
<p class="indent1">(3) The preparation for, operation of, or direction of, United States participation in such control systems as may become part of United States arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament activities.</p>
<p class="indent1">(4) The dissemination and coordination of public information concerning arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title I, § 102</ref>, formerly § 2, <date date="1961-09-26">Sept. 26, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–141, title I, § 144</ref>, <date date="1975-11-29">Nov. 29, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 758</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII</ref>, §§ 703, 719(a), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 491</ref>, 501; renumbered § 102 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(1), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–768</ref>, 2681–772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2552.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The terms “arms control” and “disarmament” mean the identification, verification, inspection, limitation, control, reduction, or elimination, of armed forces and armaments of all kinds under international agreement including the necessary steps taken under such an agreement to establish an effective system of international control, or to create and strengthen international organizations for the maintenance of peace.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent1">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The term “Government agency” means any executive department, commission, agency, independent establishment, corporation wholly or partly owned by the United States which is an instrumentality of the United States, or any board, bureau, division, service, office, officer, authority, administration, or other establishment in the executive branch of Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title I, § 103</ref>, formerly § 3, <date date="1961-09-26">Sept. 26, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 631</ref>; renumbered § 103 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(2), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–769</ref>, 2681–772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>SPECIAL REPRESENTATIVES AND VISITING SCHOLARS</heading>
<section>
<num>§§ 2561 to 2566.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1222, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–768</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2567.</num>
<heading> Presidential Special Representatives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, Special Representatives of the President for arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament matters. Each Presidential Special Representative shall hold the rank of ambassador. Presidential Special Representatives appointed under this section shall perform their duties and exercise their powers under the direction of the President and the Secretary of State. The Department of State shall be the Government agency responsible for providing administrative support, including funding, staff, and office space, to all Presidential Special Representatives.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title II, § 201</ref>, formerly § 27, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–108, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 871</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–202, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-12-02">Dec. 2, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1382</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–216, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1853</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 708(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 493</ref>; renumbered § 201 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(4), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–769</ref>, 2681–772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2568.</num>
<heading> Program for visiting scholars</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A program for visiting scholars in the fields of arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament shall be established by the Secretary of State in order to obtain the services of scholars from the faculties of recognized institutions of higher learning. The purpose of the program will be to give specialists in the physical sciences and other disciplines relevant to the Department of State’s activities an opportunity for active participation in the arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament activities of the Department of State and to gain for the Department of State the perspective and expertise such persons can offer. Each fellow in the program shall be appointed for a term of one year, except that such term may be extended for a 1-year period.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title II, § 202</ref>, formerly § 28, as added <ref>Pub. L. 98–202, § 3</ref>, <date date="1983-12-02">Dec. 2, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1381</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 719(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 501</ref>; renumbered § 202 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(5), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–769</ref>, 2681–772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>FUNCTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2571.</num>
<heading> Research, development and other studies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State is authorized and directed to exercise his powers in this subchapter in such manner as to ensure the acquisition of a fund of theoretical and practical knowledge concerning disarmament and nonproliferation. To this end, the Secretary of State is authorized and directed, under the direction of the President, (1) to ensure the conduct of research, development, and other studies in the fields of arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament; (2) to make arrangements (including contracts, agreements, and grants) for the conduct of research, development, and other studies in the fields of arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament by private or public institutions or persons; and (3) to coordinate the research, development, and other studies conducted in the fields of arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament by or for other Government agencies. In carrying out his responsibilities under this chapter, the Secretary of State shall, to the maximum extent feasible, make full use of available facilities, Government and private. The authority of the Secretary under this chapter with respect to research, development, and other studies concerning arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament shall be limited to participation in the following:</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Control, reduction and elimination of armed forces and armaments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">the detection, identification, inspection, monitoring, limitation, reduction, control, and elimination of armed forces and armaments, including thermonuclear, nuclear, missile, conventional, bacteriological, chemical, and radiological weapons:</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Weapon detection and identification tests</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">the techniques and systems of detecting, identifying, inspecting, and monitoring of tests of nuclear, thermonuclear, and other weapons;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Analysis of national budgets and economic indicators</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">the analysis of national budgets, levels of industrial production, and economic indicators to determine the amounts spent by various countries for armaments <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002178">1</ref> and of all aspects of anti-satellite activities;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Space, earth’s surface and underwater regions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">the control, reduction, and elimination of armed forces and armaments in space, in areas on and beneath the earth’s surface, and in underwater regions;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Structure and operation of international control</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">the structure and operation of international control and other organizations useful for arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training of control system personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">the training of scientists, technicians, and other personnel for manning the control systems which may be created by international arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament agreements;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Danger of war from accident, miscalculation, or surprise attack</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">the reduction and elimination of the danger of war resulting from accident, miscalculation, or possible surprise attack, including (but not limited to) improvements in the methods of communications between nations;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic and political consequences of disarmament</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">the economic and political consequences of arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament, including the problems of readjustment arising in industry and the reallocation of national resources;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disarmament implications of foreign and national security policies of United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">the arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament implications of foreign and national security policies of the United States with a view to a better understanding of the significance of such policies for the achievement of arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National security and foreign policy implications of disarmament</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">the national security and foreign policy implications of arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament proposals with a view to a better understanding of the effect of such proposals upon national security and foreign policy;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methods for maintenance of peace and security during stages of disarmament</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">methods for the maintenance of peace and security during different stages of arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> War prevention factors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">the scientific, economic, political, legal, social, psychological, military, and technological factors related to the prevention of war with a view to a better understanding of how the basic structure of a lasting peace may be established; and</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other related problems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">such related problems as the Secretary of State may determine to be in need of research, development, or study in order to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title III, § 301</ref>, formerly § 31, <date date="1961-09-26">Sept. 26, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 633</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–186, § 5</ref>, <date date="1963-11-26">Nov. 26, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 342</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–108, § 3</ref>, <date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 871</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–339, § 4</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1636</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 719(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 501</ref>; renumbered § 301 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(6), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–769</ref>, 2681–772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2572.</num>
<heading> Patents; availability to general public; protection of background rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All research within the United States contracted for, sponsored, cosponsored, or authorized under authority of this chapter, shall be provided for in such manner that all information as to uses, products, processes, patents, and other developments resulting from such research developed by Government expenditure will (with such exceptions and limitations, if any, as the Secretary of State may find to be necessary in the public interest) be available to the general public. This section shall not be so construed as to deprive the owner of any background patent relating thereto of such rights as he may have thereunder.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title III, § 302</ref>, formerly § 32, <date date="1961-09-26">Sept. 26, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 634</ref>; renumbered § 302 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(7), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–769</ref>, 2681–772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2573.</num>
<heading> Policy formulation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Formulation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall prepare for the President, and the heads of such other Government agencies as the President may determine, recommendations and advice concerning United States arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament policy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No action shall be taken pursuant to this chapter or any other Act that would obligate the United States to reduce or limit the Armed Forces or armaments of the United States in a militarily significant manner, except pursuant to the treaty-making power of the President set forth in Article II, Section 2, Clause 2 of the Constitution or unless authorized by the enactment of further affirmative legislation by the Congress of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statutory construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to authorize any policy or action by any Government agency which would interfere with, restrict, or prohibit the acquisition, possession, or use of firearms by an individual for the lawful purpose of personal defense, sport, recreation, education, or training.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title III, § 303</ref>, formerly § 33, <date date="1961-09-26">Sept. 26, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 634</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–186, § 3</ref>, <date date="1963-11-26">Nov. 26, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 342</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 709</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 494</ref>; renumbered § 303 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(8), (21), subdiv. B, title XXVI, § 2602, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–769</ref>, 2681–772, 2681–839.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2574.</num>
<heading> Negotiation management</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, under the direction of the President, shall have primary responsibility for the preparation, conduct, and management of United States participation in all international negotiations and implementation fora in the field of arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament. In furtherance of these responsibilities, Special Representatives of the President appointed pursuant to <ref>section 2567 of this title</ref>, shall, as directed by the President, serve as United States Government representatives to international organizations, conferences, and activities relating to the field of nonproliferation, such as the preparations for and conduct of the review relating to the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to formulate plans and make preparations for the establishment, operation, and funding of inspections and control systems which may become part of the United States arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as authorized by law, to put into effect, direct, or otherwise assume United States responsibility for such systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title III, § 304</ref>, formerly § 34, <date date="1961-09-26">Sept. 26, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 634</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 710</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 494</ref>; renumbered § 304 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(9), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–769</ref>, 2681–772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2575.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1222, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–768</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2576.</num>
<heading> Arms control information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to assist the Secretary of State in the performance of his duties with respect to arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament policy and negotiations, any Government agency preparing any legislative or budgetary proposal for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any program of research, development, testing, engineering, construction, deployment, or modernization with respect to nuclear armaments, nuclear implements of war, military facilities or military vehicles designed or intended primarily for the delivery of nuclear weapons,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> any program of research, development, testing, engineering, construction, deployment, or modernization with respect to armaments, ammunition, implements of war, or military facilities, having—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an estimated total program cost in excess of $250,000,000, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an estimated annual program cost in excess of $50,000,000, or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any other program involving technology with potential military application or weapons systems which such Government agency or the Secretary of State believes may have a significant impact on arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament policy or negotiations,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall, on a continuing basis, provide the Secretary of State with full and timely access to detailed information with respect to the nature, scope, and purpose of such proposal.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title III, § 305</ref>, formerly § 36, as added <ref>Pub. L. 94–141, title I, § 146</ref>, <date date="1975-11-29">Nov. 29, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 758</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–338, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-08-08">Aug. 8, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 458</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII</ref>, §§ 704(1), 719(e), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 492</ref>, 501; renumbered § 305 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(10), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–770</ref>, 2681–772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2577.</num>
<heading> Verification of compliance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to ensure that arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament agreements can be verified, the Secretary of State shall report to Congress, on a timely basis, or upon request by an appropriate committee of the Congress—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of any arms control, nonproliferation, or disarmament agreement that has been concluded by the United States, the determination of the Secretary of State as to the degree to which the components of such agreement can be verified;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of any arms control, nonproliferation, or disarmament agreement that has entered into force, any significant degradation or alteration in the capacity of the United States to verify compliance of the components of such agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amount and percentage of research funds expended by the Department of State for the purpose of analyzing issues relating to arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament verification; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the number of professional personnel assigned to arms control verification on a full-time basis by each Government agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessments upon request</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of the chairman or ranking minority member of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate or the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives, in case of an arms control, nonproliferation, or disarmament proposal presented to a foreign country by the United States or presented to the United States by a foreign country, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the Committee on the degree to which elements of the proposal are capable of being verified.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standard for verification of compliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making determinations under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall assume that all measures of concealment not expressly prohibited could be employed and that standard practices could be altered so as to impede verification.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided for by law, nothing in this section may be construed as requiring the disclosure of sensitive information relating to intelligence sources or methods or persons employed in the verification of compliance with arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament agreements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title III, § 306</ref>, formerly § 37, as added <ref>Pub. L. 95–108, § 4</ref>, <date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 871</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 712</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 495</ref>; renumbered § 306 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(11), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–770</ref>, 2681–772; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. B, title XI, § 1115]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–489.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2577a.</num>
<heading> Arms control verification</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of working group</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President should establish a working group—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to examine verification approaches to a strategic arms reduction agreement and other arms control agreements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to assess the relevance for such agreements of the verification provisions of the Treaty Between the United States and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Elimination of Their Intermediate-Range and Shorter-Range Missiles (signed at Washington, <date date="1987-12-08">December 8, 1987</date>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information and data base</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Agency shall allocate sufficient resources to develop and maintain a comprehensive information and data base on verification concepts, research, technologies, and systems. The Agency shall collect, maintain, analyze, and disseminate information pertaining to arms control verification and monitoring, including information regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all current United States bilateral and multilateral arms treaties; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> proposed, prospective, and potential bilateral or multilateral arms treaties in the areas of nuclear, conventional, chemical, and space weapons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Agency shall seek to improve United States verification and monitoring activities through the monitoring and support of relevant research and analysis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Agency shall provide detailed information on the activities pursuant to this section in its annual report to the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–216, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1854</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2578.</num>
<heading> Negotiating records</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preparation of records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall establish and maintain records for each arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament agreement to which the United States is a party and which was under negotiation or in force on or after <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, which shall include classified and unclassified materials such as instructions and guidance, position papers, reporting cables and memoranda of conversation, working papers, draft texts of the agreement, diplomatic notes, notes verbal, and other internal and external correspondence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Negotiating and implementation records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In particular, the Secretary of State shall establish and maintain a negotiating and implementation record for each such agreement, which shall be comprehensive and detailed, and shall document all communications between the parties with respect to such agreement. Such records shall be maintained both in hard copy and magnetic media.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title III, § 307</ref>, formerly § 38, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 713(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 496</ref>; renumbered § 307 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(12), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–770</ref>, 2681–772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2579.</num>
<heading> Omitted</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2581.</num>
<heading> General authority of Secretary of State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to any authorities otherwise available, the Secretary of State in the performance of functions under this chapter is authorized to—</chapeau>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Utilization of other Federal agencies; transfers of supplies, equipment, and surplus property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">utilize or employ the services, personnel, equipment, or facilities of any other Government agency, with the consent of the agency concerned, to perform such functions on behalf of the Department of State as may appear desirable. Any Government agency is authorized, notwithstanding any other provision of law, to transfer to or to receive from the Secretary of State, without reimbursement, supplies and equipment other than administrative supplies or equipment. Transfer or receipt of excess property shall be in accordance with the provisions of chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment of personnel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">appoint and fix the compensation of employees possessing specialized technical expertise without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service and the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, if the Secretary of State ensures that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> any employee who is appointed under this subsection is not paid at a rate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in excess of the rate payable for positions of equivalent difficulty or responsibility, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> exceeding the maximum rate payable for grade 15 of the General Schedule; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of employees appointed under this subsection shall not exceed 10 percent of the Department of State’s full-time-equivalent positions allocated to carry out the purpose of this chapter.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002179">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detail of other agency personnel without prejudice to status or advancement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">enter into agreements with other Government agencies, including the military departments through the Secretary of Defense, under which officers or employees of such agencies may be detailed to the Department of State for the performance of service pursuant to this chapter without prejudice to the status or advancement of such officers or employees within their own agencies;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Experts and consultants; stenographic reporting services; compensation and travel expenses; limitation on period of employment; renewal of employment contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">procure services of experts and consultants or organizations thereof, including stenographic reporting services, as authorized by <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> and to pay in connection therewith travel expenses of individuals, including transportation and per diem in lieu of subsistence while away from their homes or regular places of business, as authorized by section 5703 of such title: <i>Provided</i>, That no such individual shall be employed for more than 130 days in any fiscal year unless the President certifies that employment of such individual in excess of such number of days is necessary in the national interest: <i>And provided further</i>, That such contracts may be renewed annually;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment of outstanding personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">employ individuals of outstanding ability without compensation in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 4560(b) of title 50</ref> and regulations issued thereunder;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of scientific and policy advisory board; compensation and expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">establish a scientific and policy advisory board to advise with and make recommendations to the Secretary of State on United States arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament policy and activities. A majority of the board shall be composed of individuals who have a demonstrated knowledge and technical expertise with respect to arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament matters and who have distinguished themselves in any of the fields of physics, chemistry, mathematics, biology, or engineering, including weapons engineering. The members of the board may receive the compensation and reimbursement for expenses specified for consultants by subsection (d) of this section;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Oaths and sworn statements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">administer oaths and take sworn statements in the course of an investigation made pursuant to the Secretary of State’s responsibilities under this chapter;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delegation of functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">delegate, as appropriate, to the Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security or other officers of the Department of State, any authority conferred upon the Secretary of State by the provisions of this chapter; and</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">make, promulgate, issue, rescind, and amend such rules and regulations as may be necessary or desirable to the exercise of any authority conferred upon the Secretary of State by the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title IV, § 401</ref>, formerly § 41, <date date="1961-09-26">Sept. 26, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 635</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–332, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-07-08">July 8, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–108, § 5</ref>, <date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 872</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–228, title IV, § 401(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1698</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 715</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 498</ref>; renumbered § 401 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(13), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–770</ref>, 2681–772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 2582, 2583.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1222, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–768</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2584.</num>
<heading> Dual compensation exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Members of advisory boards and consultants may serve as such without regard to any Federal law limiting the reemployment of retired officers or employees or governing the simultaneous receipt of compensation and retired pay or annuities, subject to section 5532 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002180">1</ref> of title 5. This section shall apply only to individuals carrying out activities related to arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title IV, § 402</ref>, formerly § 44, <date date="1961-09-26">Sept. 26, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 636</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–448, title IV, § 401(d)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-19">Aug. 19, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 490</ref>; renumbered § 402 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(14), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–771</ref>, 2681–772.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 2585 to 2588.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1222, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–768</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 2589, 2590.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 717(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 498</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2591.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1222, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–768</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2592.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 704(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 492</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 2592a, 2592b.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 103–199, title IV, § 403(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2325</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2593.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1222, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–768</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2593a.</num>
<heading> Annual report to Congress</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than April 15 of each year, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report prepared by the Secretary of State with the concurrence of the Director of Central Intelligence and in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, and the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff on the status of United States policy and actions with respect to arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament. Such report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a detailed statement concerning the arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament objectives of the executive branch of Government for the forthcoming year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a detailed assessment of the status of any ongoing arms control, nonproliferation, or disarmament negotiations, including a comprehensive description of negotiations or other activities during the preceding year and an appraisal of the status and prospects for the forthcoming year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a detailed assessment of adherence of the United States to obligations undertaken in arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament agreements, including information on the policies and organization of each relevant agency or department of the United States to ensure adherence to such obligations, a description of national security programs with a direct bearing on questions of adherence to such obligations and of steps being taken to ensure adherence, and a compilation of any substantive questions raised during the preceding year and any corrective action taken;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> a detailed assessment of the adherence of other nations to obligations undertaken in all arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament agreements or commitments, including the Missile Technology Control Regime, to which the United States is a participating state, including information on actions taken by each nation with regard to the size, structure, and disposition of its military forces in order to comply with arms control, nonproliferation, or disarmament agreements or commitments, and shall include, in the case of each agreement or commitment about which compliance questions exist—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of each significant issue raised and efforts made and contemplated with the other participating state to seek resolution of the difficulty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an assessment of damage, if any, to the United States security and other interests; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recommendations as to any steps that should be considered to redress any damage to United States national security and to reduce compliance problems;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> a discussion of any material noncompliance by foreign governments with their binding commitments to the United States with respect to the prevention of the spread of nuclear explosive devices (as defined in <ref>section 6305(4) of this title</ref>) by non-nuclear-weapon states (as defined in <ref>section 6305(5) of this title</ref>) or the acquisition by such states of unsafeguarded special nuclear material (as defined in <ref>section 6305(8) of this title</ref>), including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a net assessment of the aggregate military significance of all such violations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a statement of the compliance policy of the United States with respect to violations of those commitments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> what actions, if any, the President has taken or proposes to take to bring any nation committing such a violation into compliance with those commitments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a specific identification, to the maximum extent practicable in unclassified form, of each and every question that exists with respect to compliance by other countries with arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament agreements with the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Classification of report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report required by this section shall be submitted in unclassified form, with classified annexes, as appropriate. The portions of this report described in paragraphs (4) and (5) of subsection (a) shall summarize in detail, at least in classified annexes, the information, analysis, and conclusions relevant to possible noncompliance by other nations that are provided by United States intelligence agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting consecutive noncompliance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the President in consecutive reports submitted to the appropriate congressional committees under this section reports that any designated nation is not in full compliance with its binding nonproliferation commitments to the United States, then the President shall include in the second such report an assessment of what actions are necessary to compensate for such violations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each report required by this section shall include a discussion of each significant issue described in subsection (a)(6) that was contained in a previous report issued under this section during 1995, or after <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, until the question or concern has been resolved and such resolution has been reported in detail to the appropriate committees of Congress (as defined in section 1102(1) of the Arms Control, Non-Proliferation, and Security Assistance Act of 1999).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than June 15 of each year described in paragraph (2), the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains a detailed assessment, consistent with the provision of classified information and intelligence sources and methods, of the adherence of other nations to obligations undertaken in all arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament agreements or commitments to which the United States is a party, including information of cases in which any such nation has behaved inconsistently with respect to its obligations undertaken in such agreements or commitments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered year</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A year described in this paragraph is a year in which the President fails to submit the report required by subsection (a) by not later than April 15 of such year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex if necessary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title IV, § 403</ref>, formerly § 51, as added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 717(a)(3)</ref>, title VIII, § 828(a), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 498</ref>, 520; renumbered § 403 and amended, <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(15), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–771</ref>, 2681–772; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. B, title XI, § 1113]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–487; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XI, § 1103</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1426</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XII, § 1247</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 924</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XII, § 1272</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1076</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2593b.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. E, title LI, § 5114(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2352</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§§ 2593c, 2593d.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1222, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–768</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2593e.</num>
<heading> Measures against persons involved in activities that violate arms control treaties or agreements with the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports on persons that violate treaties or agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after the submittal to Congress of an annual report on the status of United States policy and actions with respect to arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament pursuant to <ref>section 2593a of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report, consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods, identifying every person with respect to whom there is credible information indicating that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the person—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is an individual who is a citizen, national, or permanent resident of a country described in paragraph (2); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is an entity organized under the laws of a country described in paragraph (2); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> has engaged in any activity that contributed to or is a significant factor in the President’s or the Secretary of State’s determination that such country is not in full compliance with its obligations as further described in paragraph (2); or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the person has provided material support for such non-compliance to a person described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Country described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A country described in this paragraph is a country (other than a country described in paragraph (3)) that the President or the Secretary of State has determined, in the most recent annual report described in paragraph (1), to be not in full compliance with its obligations undertaken in all arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament agreements or commitments to which the United States is a participating state.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excluded countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The following countries are not described for purposes of paragraph (2):</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any country determined by the Director of National Intelligence to be closely cooperating in intelligence matters with the United States in the period covered by the most recent annual report described in paragraph (1), regardless of the extent of the compliance of such country with the obligations described in paragraph (2) during such period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition of measures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in subsections (d), (e), and (f), the President shall impose the measures described in subsection (c) with respect to each person identified in a report under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Measures described</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The measures to be imposed with respect to a person under subsection (b) are the head of any executive agency (as defined in <ref>section 133 of title 41</ref>) may not enter into, renew, or extend a contract for the procurement of goods or services with the person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for major routes of supply</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The requirement to impose measures under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any contract for the procurement of goods or services along a major route of supply to a zone of active combat or major contingency operation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to revise regulations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2016-12-23">December 23, 2016</date>, the Federal Acquisition Regulation, the Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement, and the Uniform Administrative Requirements, Cost Principles, and Audit Requirements for Federal Awards shall be revised to implement paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The revisions to the Federal Acquisition Regulation under subparagraph (A) shall include a requirement for a certification from each person that is a prospective contractor that the person, and any person owned or controlled by the person, does not engage in any activity described in subsection (a)(1)(A)(ii).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remedies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If the head of an executive agency determines that a person has submitted a false certification under subparagraph (B) on or after the date on which the applicable revision of the Federal Acquisition Regulation required by this paragraph becomes effective—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the head of that executive agency shall terminate a contract with such person or debar or suspend such person from eligibility for Federal contracts for a period of not less than 2 years;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any such debarment or suspension shall be subject to the procedures that apply to debarment and suspension under the Federal Acquisition Regulation under subpart 9.4 of part 9 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the Administrator of General Services shall include on the List of Parties Excluded from Federal Procurement and Nonprocurement Programs maintained by the Administrator under part 9 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation each person that is debarred, suspended, or proposed for debarment or suspension by the head of an executive agency on the basis of a determination of a false certification under subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver for lack of knowing violation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President may waive the application of measures on a case-by-case basis under subsection (b) with respect to a person if the President—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> in the case of a person described in subsection (a)(1)(A), the person did not knowingly engage in any activity described in such subsection;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in the case of a person described in subsection (a)(1)(B), the person conducted or facilitated a transaction or transactions with, or provided financial services to, a person described in subsection (a)(1)(A) that did not knowingly engage in any activity described in such subsection; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> in the case of a person described in subsection (a)(1)(A) or (a)(1)(B), the person has terminated the activity for which otherwise covered by such subsection or has provided verifiable assurances that the person will terminate such activity; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the waiver is in the national security interest of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the determination and the reasons for the determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report required by paragraph (1)(B) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver to prevent disclosure of intelligence sources and methods</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may waive the application of measures on a case-by-case basis under subsection (b) with respect to a person if the President—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> determines that the waiver is necessary to prevent the disclosure of intelligence sources or methods; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report, consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods, on the determination and the reasons for the determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing of imposition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the President shall immediately impose measures under subsection (b) against a person described in subsection (a)(1) upon the submittal to Congress of the report identifying the person pursuant to subsection (a)(1) unless the President determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the government of the country concerned has taken specific and effective actions, including, as appropriate, the imposition of appropriate penalties, to terminate the involvement of the person in the activities that resulted in the identification of the person in the report.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delay</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The President may delay the imposition of measures against a person for up to 120 days after the date of the submittal to Congress of the report identifying the person pursuant to subsection (a)(1) if the President initiates consultations with the government concerned with respect to the taking of actions described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional delay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The President may delay the imposition of measures for up to an additional 120 days after the delay authorized by subparagraph (A) if the President determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the government concerned is in the process of taking the actions described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after the submittal to Congress of the report identifying a person pursuant to subsection (a)(1), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the status of consultations, if any, with the government concerned under this subsection, and the basis for any determination under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination through compliance of country with arms control and other agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The measures imposed with respect to a person under subsection (b) shall terminate on the date on which the President submits to Congress a subsequent annual report pursuant to <ref>section 2593a of this title</ref> that does not contain a determination of the President that the country described in subsection (a)(2) with respect to which the measures were imposed with respect to the person is a country that is not in full compliance with its obligations undertaken in all arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament agreements or commitments to which the United States is a participating state.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination through cessation by person of violating activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to termination provided for by paragraph (1), the measures imposed with respect to a person under subsection (b) in connection with a particular activity shall terminate upon a determination of the President that the person has ceased such activity. The termination of measures imposed with respect to a person in connection with a particular activity pursuant to this paragraph shall not result in the termination of any measures imposed with respect to the person in connection with any other activity for which measures were imposed under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1290</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>ON-SITE INSPECTION ACTIVITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2595.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> under this chapter, the Department of State is charged with the “formulation and implementation of United States arms control and disarmament policy in a manner which will promote the national security”;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the On-Site Inspection Agency was established in 1988 pursuant to the INF Treaty to implement, on behalf of the United States, the inspection provisions of the INF Treaty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> on-site inspection activities under the INF Treaty include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> inspections in Russia, Ukraine, Kazakhstan, Belarus, Turkmenistan, Uzbekistan, the Czech Republic, and Germany,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> escort duties for teams visiting the United States and the Basing Countries,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> establishment and operation of the Portal Monitoring Facility in Russia, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> support for the inspectors at the Portal Monitoring Facility in Utah;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the On-Site Inspection Agency has additional responsibilities to those specified in paragraph (3), including the monitoring of nuclear tests pursuant to the Threshold Test Ban Treaty and the Peaceful Nuclear Explosions Treaty and the monitoring of the inspection provisions of such additional arms control agreements as the President may direct;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the personnel of the On-Site Inspection Agency include civilian technical experts, civilian support personnel, and members of the Armed Forces; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the senior officials of the On-Site Inspection Agency include representatives from the Department of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title V, § 501</ref>, formerly § 61, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–216, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1855</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–228, title IV, § 402(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1699</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–199, title IV, § 401(d)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2324</ref>; renumbered and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(17), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–772</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2595a.</num>
<heading> Policy coordination concerning implementation of on-site inspection provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interagency coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">OSIA should receive policy guidance which is formulated through an interagency mechanism established by the President.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Role of Secretary of Defense</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense should provide to OSIA appropriate policy guidance formulated through the interagency mechanism described in subsection (a) and operational direction, consistent with <ref>section 113(b) of title 10</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Role of Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State should provide to the interagency mechanism described in subsection (a) appropriate recommendations for policy guidance to OSIA consistent with sections 2551(3) and 2574(b) of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title V, § 502</ref>, formerly § 62, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–216, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1855</ref>; renumbered § 502 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(18), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–772</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2595b.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1222, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–768</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2595b–1.</num>
<heading> Review of certain reprogramming notifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any notification submitted to the Congress with respect to a proposed transfer, reprogramming, or reallocation of funds from or within the budget of OSIA shall also be submitted to the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and shall be subject to review by those committees.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title V, § 503</ref>, formerly § 64, as added <ref>Pub. L. 102–228, title IV, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1699</ref>; renumbered § 503 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(19), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–772</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2595c.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “INF Treaty” means the Treaty Between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Elimination of Their Intermediate-Range and Shorter-Range Missiles (signed at Washington, <date date="1987-12-08">December 8, 1987</date>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “OSIA” means the On-Site Inspection Agency established by the President, or such other agency as may be designated by the President to carry out the on-site inspection provisions of the INF Treaty;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “Peaceful Nuclear Explosions Treaty” means the Treaty Between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on Underground Nuclear Explosions for Peaceful Purposes (signed at Washington and Moscow, <date date="1976-05-28">May 28, 1976</date>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “Threshold Test Ban Treaty” means the Treaty Between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Limitation of Underground Nuclear Weapons Tests (signed at Moscow, <date date="1974-07-03">July 3, 1974</date>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–297, title V, § 504</ref>, formerly § 64, as added <ref>Pub. L. 101–216, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 1856</ref>; renumbered § 65 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 102–228, title IV, § 402(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1699</ref>; renumbered § 504 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(20), (21), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–772</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2595d.</num>
<heading> Annual report on comprehensive nuclear-test-ban treaty sensors</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2021-12-27">December 27, 2021</date>, and not later than September 1 of each subsequent year, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the sensors used in the international monitoring system of the Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty Organization. Each such report shall include, with respect to the period covered by the report—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number of incidents where such sensors are disabled, turned off, or experience “technical difficulties”; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to each such incident—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the location of the sensor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the duration of the incident; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> whether the Secretary determines there is reason to believe that the incident was a deliberate act on the part of the host nation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XIII, § 1335</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2011</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>