<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 86—</num>
<heading>CLIMATE CHANGE TECHNOLOGY DEPLOYMENT IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7901.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Carbon sequestration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “carbon sequestration” means the capture of carbon dioxide through terrestrial, geological, biological, or other means, which prevents the release of carbon dioxide into the atmosphere.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Greenhouse gas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “greenhouse gas” means carbon dioxide, methane, nitrous oxide, hydrofluorocarbons, perfluorocarbons, and sulfur hexafluoride.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Greenhouse gas intensity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “greenhouse gas intensity” means the ratio of greenhouse gas emissions to economic output.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–240, title VII, § 731</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7902.</num>
<heading> Reduction of greenhouse gas intensity</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lead agency</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Department of State shall act as the lead agency for integrating into United States foreign policy the goal of reducing greenhouse gas intensity in developing countries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate authorizing and appropriating committees of Congress an initial report, based on the most recent information available to the Secretary from reliable public sources, that identifies the 25 developing countries that are the largest greenhouse gas emitters, including for each country—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an estimate of the quantity and types of energy used;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an estimate of the greenhouse gas intensity of the energy, manufacturing, agricultural, and transportation sectors;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a description <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002394">1</ref> the progress of any significant projects undertaken to reduce greenhouse gas intensity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a description of the potential for undertaking projects to reduce greenhouse gas intensity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> a description of any obstacles to the reduction of greenhouse gas intensity; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> a description of the best practices learned by the Agency for International Development from conducting previous pilot and demonstration projects to reduce greenhouse gas intensity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Update</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 18 months after the date on which the initial report is submitted under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate authorizing and appropriating committees of Congress, based on the best information available to the Secretary, an update of the information provided in the initial report.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary of State shall use the initial report submitted under subparagraph (A) to establish baselines for the developing countries identified in the report with respect to the information provided under clauses (i) and (ii) of that subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary of State shall use the annual reports prepared under subparagraph (B) and any other information available to the Secretary to track the progress of the developing countries with respect to reducing greenhouse gas intensity.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in coordination with Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall (directly or through agreements with the World Bank, the International Monetary Fund, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, and other development institutions) provide assistance to developing countries specifically for projects to reduce greenhouse gas intensity, including projects to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> leverage, through bilateral agreements, funds for reduction of greenhouse gas intensity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> increase private investment in projects and activities to reduce greenhouse gas intensity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> expedite the deployment of technology to reduce greenhouse gas intensity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Focus</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In providing assistance under subsection (b), the Secretary of State shall focus on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promoting the rule of law, property rights, contract protection, and economic freedom; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> increasing capacity, infrastructure, and training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In providing assistance under subsection (b), the Secretary of State shall give priority to projects in the 25 developing countries identified in the report submitted under subsection (a)(2)(A).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–240, title VII, § 732</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1113</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. F, title VI, § 1470(q)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3518</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7903.</num>
<heading> Technology inventory for developing countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce, shall conduct an inventory of greenhouse gas intensity reducing technologies that are developed, or under development in the United States, to identify technologies that are suitable for transfer to, deployment in, and commercialization in the developing countries identified in the report submitted under <ref>section 7902(a)(2)(A) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after the completion of the inventory under subsection (a), the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Energy shall jointly submit to Congress a report that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> includes the results of the completed inventory;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> identifies obstacles to the transfer, deployment, and commercialization of the inventoried technologies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> includes results from previous Federal reports related to the inventoried technologies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> includes an analysis of market forces related to the inventoried technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–240, title VII, § 733</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1114</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7904.</num>
<heading> Trade-related barriers to export of greenhouse gas intensity reducing technologies</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, the United States Trade Representative shall (as appropriate and consistent with applicable bilateral, regional, and mutual trade agreements)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify trade-relations barriers maintained by foreign countries to the export of greenhouse gas intensity reducing technologies and practices from the United States to the developing countries identified in the report submitted under <ref>section 7902(a)(2)(A) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> negotiate with foreign countries for the removal of those barriers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after the date on which a report is submitted under subsection (a)(1) and annually thereafter, the United States Trade Representative shall submit to Congress a report that describes any progress made with respect to removing the barriers identified by the United States Trade Representative under subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–240, title VII, § 734</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1115</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7905.</num>
<heading> Greenhouse Gas Intensity Reducing Technology Export Initiative</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is established an interagency working group to carry out a Greenhouse Gas Intensity Reducing Technology Export Initiative to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote the export of greenhouse gas intensity reducing technologies and practices from the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> identify developing countries that should be designated as priority countries for the purpose of exporting greenhouse gas intensity reducing technologies and practices, based on the report submitted under <ref>section 7902(a)(2)(A) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> identify potential barriers to adoption of exported greenhouse gas intensity reducing technologies and practices based on the reports submitted under <ref>section 7904 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> identify previous efforts to export energy technologies to learn best practices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The working group shall be composed of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary of State, who shall act as the head of the working group;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the United States Trade Representative;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a designee of the Secretary of Energy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a designee of the Secretary of Commerce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a designee of the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance reviews and reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, and each year thereafter, the interagency working group shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> conduct a performance review of actions taken and results achieved by the Federal Government (including each of the agencies represented on the interagency working group) to promote the export of greenhouse gas intensity reducing technologies and practices from the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> submit to the appropriate authorizing and appropriating committees of Congress a report that describes the results of the performance reviews and evaluates progress in promoting the export of greenhouse gas intensity reducing technologies and practices from the United States, including any recommendations for increasing the export of the technologies and practices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–240, title VII, § 735</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1115</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7906.</num>
<heading> Technology demonstration projects</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall promote the adoption of technologies and practices that reduce greenhouse gas intensity in developing countries in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Demonstration projects</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretaries and the Administrator shall plan, coordinate, and carry out, or provide assistance for the planning, coordination, or carrying out of, demonstration projects under this section in at least 10 eligible countries, as determined by the Secretaries and the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A country shall be eligible for assistance under this subsection if the Secretaries and the Administrator determine that the country has demonstrated a commitment to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> just governance, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> promoting the rule of law;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> respecting human and civil rights;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> protecting private property rights; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> combating corruption; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> economic freedom, including economic policies that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> encourage citizens and firms to participate in global trade and international capital markets;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> promote private sector growth and the sustainable management of natural resources; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> strengthen market forces in the economy.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In determining which eligible countries to provide assistance to under paragraph (1), the Secretaries and the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the opportunity to reduce greenhouse gas intensity in the eligible country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the opportunity to generate economic growth in the eligible country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Types of projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Demonstration projects under this section may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coal gasification, coal liquefaction, and clean coal projects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> carbon sequestration projects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> cogeneration technology initiatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> renewable projects; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> lower emission transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–240, title VII, § 736</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1116</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7907.</num>
<heading> Fellowship and exchange programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall carry out fellowship and exchange programs under which officials from developing countries visit the United States to acquire expertise and knowledge of best practices to reduce greenhouse gas intensity in their countries.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–240, title VII, § 737</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7908.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–240, title VII, § 738</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7909.</num>
<heading> Authorization for the Clean Technology Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For fiscal year 2010, up to $300,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated for a United States contribution to the Clean Technology Fund (the Fund).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limits on country access</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall use the voice and vote of the United States to ensure that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Fund does not provide more than 15 percent of Fund resources to any one country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Prior to the obligation of funds, recipient countries submit to the governing body of the Fund, and the governing body of the Fund appropriately reviews and considers, an investment plan that will achieve significant net reductions in national-level greenhouse gas emissions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The investment plan for a recipient country, whose borrowing status is classified by the World Bank as “International Development Association (IDA) blend”, shall have at least 15 percent of its total cost for public sector activities contributed from the public funds of the recipient country, and any recipient country whose borrowing status is classified by the World Bank as “International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) Only” status, shall have at least 25 percent of its total cost for public sector activities contributed from public funds of the recipient country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Assistance made available by the Fund is used exclusively to support the deployment of clean energy technologies in developing countries (including, where appropriate, through the provision of technical support or support for policy or institutional reforms) in a manner that achieves substantial net reductions in greenhouse gas emissions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. K, title VII, § 7034(i)</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 514</ref></heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Net reductions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “net reductions” refers to the extent to which a project or program supported under this section results in lower greenhouse gas emissions than would be emitted by the same entity or sector in the same country in the absence of the Fund’s project, taking into account, unless impracticable, effects beyond the physical boundaries of the project or program that result from project or program activities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public sector activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “public sector activities” may include sovereign loans assumed by the recipient country to contribute to the financing of the investment plan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Clean energy technology</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “clean energy technology” means a technology that, as compared with technologies being deployed at that time for widespread commercial use in the country involved—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> achieves substantial reductions in greenhouse gas emissions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> does not result in significant incremental adverse effects on public health or the environment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> does one or more of the following:</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> generates electricity or useful thermal energy from a renewable resource;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> substantially increases the energy efficiency of buildings, industrial, or agricultural processes, or of electricity transmission, distribution, or end-use consumption; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> substantially increases the energy efficiency of the transportation system or increases utilization of transportation fuels that have lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions that are substantially lower than those attributable to fossil fuel-based alternatives.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 111–117, div. F, title VII, § 7081(g)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-16">Dec. 16, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3398</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–76, div. K, title VII, § 7034(i)</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 514</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>