<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 84—</num>
<heading>MILLENNIUM CHALLENGE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7701.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to provide United States assistance for global development through the Millennium Challenge Corporation, as described in <ref>section 7703 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide such assistance in a manner that promotes economic growth and the elimination of extreme poverty and strengthens good governance, economic freedom, and investments in people.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 211</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on International Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Board” means the Board of Directors of the Corporation established pursuant to <ref>section 7703(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Candidate country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “candidate country” means a country that meets the requirements of <ref>section 7705 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chief Executive Officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Chief Executive Officer” means the chief executive officer of the Corporation appointed pursuant to <ref>section 7703(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compact</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Compact” means a Millennium Challenge Compact described in <ref>section 7708 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Corporation” means the Millennium Challenge Corporation established by <ref>section 7703(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “eligible country” means a candidate country that is determined, under <ref>section 7706 of this title</ref>, to be an eligible country to receive assistance under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investments in the people</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “investments in the people” means government policies or programs of an eligible country that promote the health, education, and other factors which contribute to the well-being and productivity of their people, such as decent, affordable housing for all.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 211</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. D, title V, § 534(q)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3008</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7703.</num>
<heading> Establishment and management of the Millennium Challenge Corporation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the executive branch a corporation to be known as the “Millennium Challenge Corporation” that shall be responsible for carrying out this chapter. The Corporation shall be a government corporation, as defined in <ref>section 103 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chief Executive Officer</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There shall be in the Corporation a Chief Executive Officer who shall be responsible for the management of the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Chief Executive Officer shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim CEO</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The members of the Board of Directors described in subsection (c)(3)(A) may designate by unanimous consent in writing an individual who is an officer within any Federal department or agency (and who has been appointed to such position by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate) to carry out the duties described in this subsection until the Chief Executive Officer is appointed pursuant to subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief Executive Officer shall report to and be under the direct authority of the Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation and rank</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Chief Executive Officer shall be compensated at the rate provided for level II of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5313 of title 5</ref> and shall have the equivalent rank of Deputy Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorities and duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief Executive Officer shall be responsible for the management of the Corporation and shall exercise the powers and discharge the duties of the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to appoint officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In consultation and with approval of the Board, the Chief Executive Officer shall appoint all officers of the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board of Directors</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There shall be in the Corporation a Board of Directors.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall perform the functions specified to be carried out by the Board in this chapter and may prescribe, amend, and repeal bylaws, rules, regulations, and procedures governing the manner in which the business of the Corporation may be conducted and in which the powers granted to it by law may be exercised.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Board shall consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation, and the United States Trade Representative; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> four other individuals with relevant international experience who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, of which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> one individual should be appointed from among a list of individuals submitted by the majority leader of the House of Representatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> one individual should be appointed from among a list of individuals submitted by the minority leader of the House of Representatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> one individual should be appointed from among a list of individuals submitted by the majority leader of the Senate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> one individual should be appointed from among a list of individuals submitted by the minority leader of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Officers of the Federal Government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Each member of the Board described in paragraph (3)(A) shall serve for a term that is concurrent with the term of service of the individual’s position as an officer within the other Federal department or agency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Each member of the Board described in paragraph (3)(B)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be appointed for a term of 3 years;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> may be reappointed for a term of an additional 2 years; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> may continue to serve in each such appointment until the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the date on which his or her successor is appointed; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the date that is 1 year after the expiration of his or her appointment or reappointment, as the case may be.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A vacancy in the Board shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There shall be a Chairperson of the Board. The Secretary of State shall serve as the Chairperson.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum, which, except with respect to a meeting of the Board during the 135-day period beginning on <date date="2004-01-23">January 23, 2004</date>, shall include at least one member of the Board described in paragraph (3)(B).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board shall meet at the call of the Chairperson.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Officers of the Federal Government</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A member of the Board described in paragraph (3)(A) may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of the member’s service on the Board.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Each such member of the Board shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other members</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Except as provided in clause (ii), a member of the Board described in paragraph (3)(B)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> shall be paid compensation out of funds made available for the purposes of this chapter at the daily equivalent of the highest rate payable under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref> for each day (including travel time) during which the member is engaged in the actual performance of duties as a member of the Board; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> while away from the member’s home or regular place of business on necessary travel in the actual performance of duties as a member of the Board, shall be paid per diem, travel, and transportation expenses in the same manner as is provided under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">A member of the Board may not be paid compensation under clause (i)(II) for more than 90 days in any calendar year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 212</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–167, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2018-04-23">Apr. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7704.</num>
<heading> Authorization of assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than a provision of this chapter), the Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer, is authorized to provide assistance under this section for each country that enters into a Millennium Challenge Compact with the United States pursuant to <ref>section 7708 of this title</ref> to support policies and programs that advance the progress of the country in achieving lasting economic growth and poverty reduction and are in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Assistance under this section may be provided in the form of grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts to or with eligible entities described in subsection (c). Assistance under this section may not be provided in the form of loans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible entities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An eligible entity referred to in subsection (b) is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the national government of the eligible country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> regional or local governmental units of the country; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a nongovernmental organization or a private entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer, in consultation with the Board and working with eligible countries selected by the Board for negotiation of Compacts, should develop and recommend procedures for considering solicited and unsolicited proposals in Compacts prior to an approval of the Compacts by the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on military assistance and training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Assistance under this section may not include military assistance or military training for a country.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on assistance relating to United States job loss or production displacement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Assistance under this section may not be provided for any project that is likely to cause a substantial loss of United States jobs or a substantial displacement of United States production.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on assistance relating to environmental, health, or safety hazards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Assistance under this section may not be provided for any project that is likely to cause a significant environmental, health, or safety hazard.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on use of funds for abortions and involuntary sterilizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The prohibitions on use of funds contained in paragraphs (1) through (3) of section 104(f) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151b(f)(1)</ref>–(3)) shall apply to funds made available to carry out this section to the same extent and in the same manner as such prohibitions apply to funds made available to carry out part I of such Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.]. The prohibition on use of funds contained in any provision of law comparable to the eleventh and fourteenth provisos under the heading “Child Survival and Health Programs Fund” of division E of <ref>Public Law 108–7</ref> (<ref>117 Stat. 162</ref>) shall apply to funds made available to carry out this section for fiscal year 2004.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provision of assistance under this section shall be coordinated with other United States foreign assistance programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 214</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7705.</num>
<heading> Candidate countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A country shall be a candidate country for purposes of eligibility to receive assistance under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref> if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the per capita income of the country in a fiscal year is equal to or less than the World Bank threshold for initiating the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development graduation process for the fiscal year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> subject to subsection (b), the country is not ineligible to receive United States economic assistance under part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.) by reason of the application of any provision of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.] or any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of determining whether a country is eligible, pursuant to subsection (a)(2), to receive assistance under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref>, the exercise by the President, the Secretary of State, or any other officer or employee of the United States Government of any waiver or suspension of any provision of law referred to in subsection (a)(2), and notification to the appropriate congressional committees in accordance with such provision of law, shall be construed as satisfying the requirements under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination by the Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall determine whether a country is a candidate country for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 606</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 215</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–167, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2018-04-23">Apr. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1278</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LI, § 5122(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2430</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7706.</num>
<heading> Eligible countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination by the Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board shall determine whether a candidate country is an eligible country for purposes of this section. Such determination shall be based, to the maximum extent possible, upon objective and quantifiable indicators of a country’s demonstrated commitment to the criteria in subsection (b), and shall, where appropriate, take into account and assess the role of women and girls. A determination whether a country is eligible for a subsequent, non-concurrent Millennium Challenge Compact shall also be based, to the extent practicable, on significantly improved performance across the criteria in subsection (b) that, at a minimum, are relevant to the preceding Compact, compared to the country’s performance with respect to such criteria when selected for such preceding Compact.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A candidate country should be considered to be an eligible country for purposes of this section if the Board determines that the country has demonstrated a commitment to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> just and democratic governance, including a demonstrated commitment to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> promote political pluralism, equality, and the rule of law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> respect human and civil rights, including the rights of people with disabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> protect private property rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> encourage transparency and accountability of government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> combat corruption; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the quality of the civil society enabling environment;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> economic freedom, including a demonstrated commitment to economic policies that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> encourage citizens and firms to participate in global trade and international capital markets;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> promote private sector growth;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> strengthen market forces in the economy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> respect worker rights, including the right to form labor unions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> investments in the people of such country, particularly women and children, including programs that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> promote broad-based primary education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> strengthen and build capacity to provide quality public health and reduce child mortality; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> promote the protection of biodiversity and the transparent and sustainable management and use of natural resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection by the Board</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the time the Board determines eligible countries under this section for a fiscal year, the Board shall select those eligible countries with respect to which the United States will initially seek to enter into a Millennium Challenge Compact pursuant to <ref>section 7708 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In selecting eligible countries under paragraph (1), the Board shall prioritize need and impact by considering the following factors:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The extent to which the country clearly meets or exceeds the eligibility criteria.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The opportunity to reduce poverty and generate economic growth in the country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The availability of amounts to carry out this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting on treatment of civil society</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the 7-year period beginning on <date date="2018-04-23">April 23, 2018</date>, before the Board selects an eligible country for a Compact under subsection (c), the Corporation shall provide information to the Board regarding the country’s treatment of civil society, including classified information, as appropriate. The information shall include an assessment and analysis of factors including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any relevant laws governing the formation or establishment of a civil society organization, particularly laws intended to curb the activities of foreign civil society organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any relevant laws governing the operations of a civil society organization, particularly those laws seeking to define or otherwise regulate the actions of foreign civil society organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> laws relating to the legal status of civil society organizations, including laws which effectively discriminate against foreign civil society organizations as compared to similarly situated domestic organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> laws regulating the freedom of expression and peaceful assembly; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> laws regulating the usage of the Internet, particularly by foreign civil society organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of criteria and methodology</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The criteria and methodology submitted by the Board to Congress and published in the Federal Register under <ref>section 7707(b)(2) of this title</ref> with respect to a fiscal year shall remain fixed for purposes of eligibility determinations for such year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual modification of criteria and methodology</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As appropriate, the Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer, shall review the eligibility criteria and methodology and modify such criteria and methodology in subsequent years consistent with <ref>section 7707(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 607</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 216</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. J, title VI, § 699I(a)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2372</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–167, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2018-04-23">Apr. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1279</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LI, § 5122(d)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2431</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7707.</num>
<heading> Congressional and public notification of candidate countries, eligibility criteria, and eligible countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of candidate countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days prior to the date on which the Board determines eligible countries under <ref>section 7706 of this title</ref> for a fiscal year, the Chief Executive Officer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall prepare and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains a list of all candidate countries identified under <ref>section 7705 of this title</ref>, and all countries that would be candidate countries if the countries met the requirement contained in <ref>section 7705(a)(2) of this title</ref>, for the fiscal year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall publish in the Federal Register the information contained in the report described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of eligibility criteria and methodology</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 60 days prior to the date on which the Board determines eligible countries under <ref>section 7706 of this title</ref> for a fiscal year, the Chief Executive Officer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall prepare and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains a list of the criteria and methodology described in subsections (a) and (b) of <ref>section 7706 of this title</ref> that will be used to determine eligibility for each candidate country identified under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall publish in the Federal Register the information contained in the report described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may conduct one or more public hearings on the eligibility criteria and methodology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public comment and congressional consultation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public comment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief Executive Officer shall, for the 30-day period beginning on the date of publication in the Federal Register of the information contained in the report described in subsection (b)(1), accept public comment and consider such comment for purposes of determining eligible countries under <ref>section 7706 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief Executive Officer shall consult with the appropriate congressional committees on the extent to which the candidate countries meet the criteria described in <ref>section 7706(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Identification of eligible countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 5 days after the date on which the Board determines eligible countries under <ref>section 7706 of this title</ref> for a fiscal year, the Chief Executive Officer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall prepare and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains a list of all such eligible countries, an identification of those countries on such list with respect to which the Board will seek to enter into a Compact under <ref>section 7708 of this title</ref>, and a justification for such eligibility determination and selection for Compact negotiation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall publish in the Federal Register the information contained in the report described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 608</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 217</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LI, § 5122(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2430</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7708.</num>
<heading> Millennium Challenge Compact</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compact</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation, may provide assistance for an eligible country only if the country enters into an agreement with the United States, to be known as a “Millennium Challenge Compact”, that establishes a multi-year plan for achieving shared development objectives in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Compact should take into account the national development strategy of the eligible country and shall contain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the specific objectives that the country and the United States expect to achieve during the term of the Compact;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the responsibilities of the country and the United States in the achievement of such objectives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> regular benchmarks to measure, where appropriate, progress toward achieving such objectives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an identification of the intended beneficiaries, disaggregated by income level, gender, and age, to the maximum extent practicable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a multi-year financial plan, including the estimated amount of contributions by the Corporation and the country and proposed mechanisms to implement the plan and provide oversight, that describes how the requirements of subparagraphs (A) through (D) will be met, including identifying the role of civil society in the achievement of such requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> where appropriate, a description of the current and potential participation of other donors in the achievement of such objectives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a plan to ensure appropriate fiscal accountability for the use of assistance provided under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> where appropriate, a process or processes for consideration of solicited proposals under the Compact as well as a process for consideration of unsolicited proposals by the Corporation and national, regional, or local units of government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a requirement that open, fair, and competitive procedures are used in a transparent manner in the administration of grants or cooperative agreements or the procurement of goods and services for the accomplishment of objectives under the Compact;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> the strategy of the eligible country to sustain progress made toward achieving such objectives after expiration of the Compact; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> a description of the role of the United States Agency for International Development in any design, implementation, and monitoring of programs and activities funded under the Compact.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Country contributions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the elements described in subparagraphs (A) through (K) of paragraph (1), the Compact shall identify a contribution, as appropriate, from the country relative to its national budget, taking into account the prevailing economic conditions, toward meeting the objectives of the Compact. Any such contribution should be in addition to government spending allocated for such purposes in the country’s budget for the year immediately preceding the establishment of the Compact and should continue for the duration of the Compact.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “national development strategy” means any strategy to achieve market-driven economic growth and eliminate extreme poverty that has been developed by the government of the country in consultation with a wide variety of civic participation, including nongovernmental organizations, private and voluntary organizations, academia, women’s and student organizations, local trade and labor unions, and the business community.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional provision relating to prohibition on taxation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the elements described in subsection (c), each Compact shall contain a provision that states that assistance provided by the United States under the Compact shall be exempt from taxation by the government of the eligible country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local input</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In entering into a Compact, the United States shall seek to ensure that the government of an eligible country—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> takes into account the local-level perspectives of the rural and urban poor, including women, in the eligible country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consults with private and voluntary organizations, the business community, and other donors in the eligible country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During any discussions with a country for the purpose of entering into a Compact with the country, officials of the Corporation participating in such discussions shall, at a minimum, consult with appropriate officials of the United States Agency for International Development, particularly with those officials responsible for the appropriate region or country on development issues related to the Compact.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with other donors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the maximum extent feasible, activities undertaken to achieve the objectives of the Compact shall be undertaken in coordination with the assistance activities of other donors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance for development of compact</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Chief Executive Officer may enter into contracts or make grants for any eligible country for the purpose of facilitating the development and implementation of the Compact between the United States and the country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for approval by the Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each Compact shall be approved by the Board before the United States enters into the Compact.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Increase or extension of assistance under a Compact</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 15 days after making a determination to increase or extend assistance under a Compact with an eligible country, the Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall prepare and transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a written report and justification that contains a detailed summary of the proposed increase in or extension of assistance under the Compact and a copy of the full text of the amendment to the Compact; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall publish a detailed summary, full text, and justification of the proposed increase in or extension of assistance under the Compact in the Federal Register and on the Internet website of the Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of Compact</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The duration of a Compact shall not exceed 5 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concurrent Compacts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An eligible country that has entered into and has in effect a Compact under this section may enter into and have in effect at the same time not more than one additional Compact in accordance with the requirements of this chapter if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> one or both of the Compacts are or will be for purposes of regional economic integration, increased regional trade, or cross-border collaborations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Board determines that the country is making considerable and demonstrable progress in implementing the terms of the existing Compact and supplementary agreements thereto.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent Compacts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An eligible country and the United States may enter into one or more subsequent Compacts in accordance with the requirements of this chapter after the expiration of the existing Compact.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 609</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 218</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–167, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-04-23">Apr. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1280</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LI, § 5122(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2431</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7709.</num>
<heading> Congressional and public notification</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional consultations and notifications</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer, shall consult with and notify the appropriate congressional committees not later than 15 days before taking any of the actions described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The actions described in this paragraph are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing assistance for an eligible country under <ref>section 7708(g) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> commencing negotiations with an eligible country to provide assistance for—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a Compact under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an agreement under <ref>section 7715 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> signing such a Compact or agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> terminating assistance under such a Compact or agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic justification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any notification relating to the intent to negotiate or sign a Compact shall include a report describing the projected economic justification for the Compact, including, as applicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the expected economic rate of return of the Compact;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a cost-benefit analysis of the Compact;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of the impact on beneficiary populations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the likelihood that the investment will catalyze private sector investments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any other applicable economic factors that justify each project to be funded under such a Compact to the extent practicable and appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Risk management plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 60 days before signing each concurrent Compact, as authorized under <ref>section 7708 of this title</ref>, the Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer, shall consult with and provide to the appropriate congressional committees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> an assessment and, as appropriate, the identification of potential measures to mitigate risks, of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the countries’ commitment to regional integration and cross-border cooperation and capacity to carry out commitments;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> political and policy risks, including risks that could affect country eligibility;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> risks associated with realizing economic returns;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> time and completion risks; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> cost and financial risks; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> an assessment of measures to be taken to mitigate any identified risks, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> securing other potential donors to finance projects or parts of projects as needed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> partnering with regional organizations to support and oversee effective cross-border cooperation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional and public notification after entering into a Compact</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 10 days after entering into a Compact with an eligible country, the Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer, shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> publish the text of the Compact on the website of the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide the appropriate congressional committees with a detailed summary of the Compact and, upon request, the text of the Compact; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> publish in the Federal Register a detailed summary of the Compact and a notice of availability of the text of the Compact on the website of the Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 610</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 220</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–167, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2018-04-23">Apr. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7710.</num>
<heading> Suspension and termination of assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension and termination of assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">After consultation with the Board, the Chief Executive Officer may suspend or terminate assistance in whole or in part for a country or entity under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref> if the Chief Executive Officer determines that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the country or entity is engaged in activities which are contrary to the national security interests of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the country or entity has engaged in a pattern of actions inconsistent with the criteria used to determine the eligibility of the country or entity, as the case may be; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the country or entity has failed to adhere to its responsibilities under the Compact.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reinstatement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer may reinstate assistance for a country or entity under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref> only if the Chief Executive Officer determines that the country or entity has demonstrated a commitment to correcting each condition for which assistance was suspended or terminated under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 3 days after the date on which the Chief Executive Officer suspends or terminates assistance under subsection (a) for a country or entity, or reinstates assistance under subsection (b) for a country or entity, the Chief Executive Officer shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the determination of the Chief Executive Officer under subsection (a) or subsection (b), as the case may be.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority to suspend or terminate assistance under this section includes the authority to suspend or terminate obligations and sub-obligations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 611</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 220</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7711.</num>
<heading> Disclosure</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for timely disclosure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after the last day of each fiscal quarter, the Corporation shall make available to the public the following information:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For assistance provided under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of each entity to which assistance is provided;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount of assistance provided to the entity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> a description of the program or project, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of whether the program or project was solicited or unsolicited; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a detailed description of the objectives and measures for results of the program or project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For funds allocated or transferred under <ref>section 7718(b) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name of each United States Government agency to which such funds are transferred or allocated;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount of funds transferred or allocated to such agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a description of the program or project to be carried out by such agency with such funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dissemination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer, shall make the information required to be disclosed under subsection (a) available to the public—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by publishing it on the website of the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by providing notice of the availability of such information in the Federal Register; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> by any other methods that the Board determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 612</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 221</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–167, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2018-04-23">Apr. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7712.</num>
<heading> Annual report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than the third Friday of December of each year, the Chief Executive Officer shall submit a report to Congress describing the assistance provided pursuant to <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref> during the most recently concluded fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The report shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The amount of obligations and expenditures for assistance provided to each eligible country during the prior fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For each eligible country, an assessment of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the progress made during each year by the country toward achieving the objectives set out in any Compact entered into by the country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the extent to which assistance provided under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref> has been effective in helping the country to achieve such objectives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A description of the coordination of assistance provided under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref> with other United States foreign assistance and related trade policies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A description of the coordination of assistance provided under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref> with assistance provided by other donor countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Any other information the President considers relevant with respect to assistance provided under <ref>section 7704 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 613</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 221</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–167, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-04-23">Apr. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1280</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LI, § 5122(e)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2431</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7713.</num>
<heading> Powers of the Corporation; related provisions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Powers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Corporation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall have perpetual succession unless dissolved by a law enacted after <date date="2004-01-23">January 23, 2004</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may adopt, alter, and use a seal, which shall be judicially noticed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may make and perform such contracts, grants, and other agreements with any person or government however designated and wherever situated, as may be necessary for carrying out the functions of the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> may determine and prescribe the manner in which its obligations shall be incurred and its expenses allowed and paid, including expenses for representation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> may lease, purchase, or otherwise acquire, improve, and use such real property wherever situated, as may be necessary for carrying out the functions of the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> may accept cash gifts or donations of services or of property (real, personal, or mixed), tangible or intangible, for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> may use the United States mails in the same manner and on the same conditions as the executive departments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> may contract with individuals for personal services, who shall not be considered Federal employees for any provision of law administered by the Office of Personnel Management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> may hire or obtain passenger motor vehicles; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> shall have such other powers as may be necessary and incident to carrying out this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal office</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Corporation shall maintain its principal office in the metropolitan area of Washington, District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Positions with foreign governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When approved by the Chief Executive Officer, for purposes of implementing a Compact, employees of the Corporation (including individuals detailed to the Corporation) may accept and hold offices or positions to which no compensation is attached with governments or governmental agencies of foreign countries or with international organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except to the extent inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter, the administrative authorities contained in the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2651a</ref> et seq.) and the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.) shall apply to the implementation of this chapter to the same extent and in the same manner as such authorities apply to the implementation of those Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability of Government Corporation Control Act</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Corporation shall be subject to chapter 91 of subtitle VI of title 31, except that the Corporation shall not be authorized to issue obligations or offer obligations to the public.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inspector General</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Inspector General of the United States Agency for International Development shall serve as Inspector General of the Corporation, and, in acting in such capacity, may conduct reviews, investigations, and inspections of all aspects of the operations and activities of the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of the Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out the responsibilities under this subsection, the Inspector General shall report to and be under the general supervision of the Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement and authorization of services</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Corporation shall reimburse the United States Agency for International Development for all expenses incurred by the Inspector General in connection with the Inspector General’s responsibilities under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization for services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Of the amount authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 7718(a) of this title</ref> for a fiscal year, up to $5,000,000 is authorized to be made available to the Inspector General of the United States Agency for International Development to conduct reviews, investigations, and inspections of operations and activities of the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief Executive Officer is authorized to contract with any nongovernmental organization (including a university, independent foundation, or other organization) in the United States or in a candidate country, and, where appropriate, directly with a governmental agency of any such country, that is undertaking research aimed at improving data related to eligibility criteria under this chapter with respect to the country.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Of the amount authorized to be appropriated under <ref>section 7718(a) of this title</ref> for a fiscal year, up to $5,000,000 is authorized to be made available to carry out paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 614</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7714.</num>
<heading> Coordination with United States Agency for International Development</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for coordination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer shall consult with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development in order to coordinate the activities of the Corporation with the activities of the Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> USAID programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall seek to ensure that appropriate programs of the Agency play a primary role in preparing candidate countries to become eligible countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 615</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 224</ref>.)———*</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7715.</num>
<heading> Assistance to certain candidate countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer, is authorized to provide assistance to a candidate country described in subsection (b) for the purpose of assisting such country to become an eligible country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Candidate country described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A candidate country referred to in subsection (a) is a candidate country that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> satisfies the requirements contained in <ref>section 7705(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> demonstrates a significant commitment to meet the requirements of <ref>section 7706(b) of this title</ref> but fails to meet such requirements (including by reason of the absence or unreliability of data).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Assistance under this section may be provided through the United States Agency for International Development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not more than 10 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this chapter for a fiscal year may be made available to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restriction relating to assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">None of the funds authorized to carry out the purposes of this chapter shall be available for assistance under this section to a country that does not qualify as a candidate country under <ref>section 7705 of this title</ref> for the fiscal year during which such assistance is provided.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 616</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 224</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–13, div. A, title II, § 2109</ref>, <date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 268</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–167, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2018-04-23">Apr. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LI, § 5122(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2431</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7716.</num>
<heading> General personnel authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detail of personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon request of the Chief Executive Officer, the head of an agency may detail any employee of such agency to the Corporation on a reimbursable basis. Any employee so detailed remains, for the purpose of preserving such employee’s allowances, privileges, rights, seniority, and other benefits, an employee of the agency from which detailed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reemployment rights</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An employee of an agency who is serving under a career or career conditional appointment (or the equivalent), and who, with the consent of the head of such agency, transfers to the Corporation, is entitled to be reemployed in such employee’s former position or a position of like seniority, status, and pay in such agency, if such employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is separated from the Corporation for any reason, other than misconduct, neglect of duty, or malfeasance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> applies for reemployment not later than 90 days after the date of separation from the Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An employee who satisfies paragraph (1) is entitled to be reemployed (in accordance with such paragraph) within 30 days after applying for reemployment and, on reemployment, is entitled to at least the rate of basic pay to which such employee would have been entitled had such employee never transferred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hiring authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Of persons employed by the Corporation, not to exceed 30 persons may be appointed, compensated, or removed without regard to the civil service laws and regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basic pay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer may fix the rate of basic pay of employees of the Corporation without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 of title 5 (relating to the classification of positions), subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title (relating to General Schedule pay rates), except that no employee of the Corporation may receive a rate of basic pay that exceeds the rate for level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of such title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “agency” means an executive agency, as defined by <ref>section 105 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “detail” means the assignment or loan of an employee, without a change of position, from the agency by which such employee is employed to the Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 617</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7717.</num>
<heading> Personnel outside the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assignment to United States embassies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employee of the Corporation, including an individual detailed to or contracted by the Corporation, may be assigned to a United States diplomatic mission or consular post or a United States Agency for International Development field mission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Privileges and immunities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall seek to ensure that an employee of the Corporation, including an individual detailed to or contracted by the Corporation, and the members of the family of such employee, while the employee is performing duties in any country or place outside the United States, enjoy the privileges and immunities that are enjoyed by a member of the Foreign Service, or the family of a member of the Foreign Service, as appropriate, of comparable rank and salary of such employee, if such employee or a member of the family of such employee is not a national of or permanently resident in such country or place.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibility of chief of mission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An employee of the Corporation, including an individual detailed to or contracted by the Corporation, and a member of the family of such employee, shall be subject to <ref>section 3927 of this title</ref> in the same manner as United States Government employees while the employee is performing duties in any country or place outside the United States if such employee or member of the family of such employee is not a national of or permanently resident in such country or place.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 618</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 225</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7718.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this chapter such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2004 and 2005.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Corporation may allocate or transfer to any agency of the United States Government any of the funds available for carrying out this chapter. Such funds shall be available for obligation and expenditure for the purposes for which the funds were authorized, in accordance with authority granted in this chapter or under authority governing the activities of the United States Government agency to which such funds are allocated or transferred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Corporation shall notify the appropriate congressional committees not less than 15 days prior to an allocation or transfer of funds pursuant to paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 619</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 225</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>