<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 36—</num>
<heading>MIGRATION AND REFUGEE ASSISTANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 2601.</num>
<heading> Refugees and migration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States membership in International Organization for Migration; contributions to Organization</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The President is authorized to continue membership for the United States in the International Organization for Migration in accordance with the constitution of such organization approved in Venice, Italy, on <date date="1953-10-19">October 19, 1953</date>, as amended in Geneva, Switzerland, on <date date="1998-11-24">November 24, 1998</date>, upon entry into force of such amendments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For the purpose of assisting in the movement of refugees and migrants, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President such amounts as may be necessary from time to time for payment by the United States of its contributions to the International Organization for Migration and all necessary salaries and expenses incidental to United States participation in such organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriations for assistance to refugees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such amounts as may be necessary from time to time—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for contributions to the activities of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees for assistance to refugees under his mandate or persons on behalf of whom he is exercising his good offices, and for contributions to the International Organization for Migration, the International Committee of the Red Cross, and to other relevant international organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for assistance to or on behalf of refugees who are outside the United States designated by the President (by class, group, or designation of their respective countries of origin or areas of residence) when the President determines that such assistance will contribute to the foreign policy interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund; appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Whenever the President determines it to be important to the national interest he is authorized to furnish on such terms and conditions as he may determine assistance under this chapter for the purpose of meeting unexpected urgent refugee and migration needs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> There is established a United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund to carry out the purposes of this section. There is authorized to be appropriated to the President from time to time such amounts as may be necessary for the fund to carry out the purposes of this section, except that no amount of funds may be appropriated which, when added to amounts previously appropriated but not yet obligated, would cause such amounts to exceed $100,000,000. Amounts appropriated hereunder shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Whenever the President requests appropriations pursuant to this authorization he shall justify such requests to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, as well as to the Committees on Appropriations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information to Congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall keep the appropriate committees of Congress currently informed of the use of funds and the exercise of functions authorized in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continued availability of certain funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unexpended balances of funds made available under authority of the Mutual Security Act of 1954, as amended, and of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended, [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], and allocated or transferred for the purposes of sections 405(a), 405(c), 405(d) and 451(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002181">1</ref> of the Mutual Security Act of 1954, as amended [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1925(a)</ref>, (c), (d), 1951(c)], are authorized to be continued available for the purposes of this section and may be consolidated with appropriations authorized by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on foreign assistance not applicable to migration and refugee assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may furnish assistance and make contributions under this chapter notwithstanding any provision of law which restricts assistance to foreign countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–510, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–634, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1964-10-07">Oct. 7, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1021</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–141, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1975-11-29">Nov. 29, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 771</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–212, title III, § 312(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-03-17">Mar. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 410</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title IV, § 430(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 459</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title II, § 242</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1374</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2602.</num>
<heading> Presidential authorization</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of President to make loans, advances, grants, contracts, etc.; authority to use money, funds, property, services, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out the purpose of this chapter, the President is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to make loans, advances, and grants to, make and perform agreements and contracts with, or enter into other transactions with, any individual, corporation, or other body of persons, government or government agency, whether within or without the United States, and international and intergovernmental organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to accept and use money, funds, property, and services of any kind made available by gift, devise, bequest, grant, or otherwise for such purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Performance of functions without regard to specified provisions of law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the President determines it to be in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter, the functions authorized under this chapter may be performed without regard to such provisions of law (other than the Renegotiation Act of 1951), as amended, regulating the making, performance, amendment, or modification of contracts and the expenditure of funds of the United States Government as the President may specify.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–510, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 123</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2603.</num>
<heading> Delegation of powers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to designate the head of any department or agency of the United States Government, or any official thereof who is required to be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to perform any functions conferred upon the President by this chapter. If the President shall so specify, any individual so designated under this section is authorized to redelegate to any of his subordinates any functions authorized to be performed by him under this section, except the function of exercising the waiver authority specified in <ref>section 2602(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–510, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 123</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2604.</num>
<heading> Allocation, transfer and availability of funds; separate appropriation accounts on Treasury books</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may allocate or transfer to any agency of the United States Government any part of any funds available for carrying out the purposes of this chapter. Such funds shall be available for obligation and expenditure for the purposes for which authorized in accordance with authority granted in this chapter or under authority governing the activities of the agencies of the United States Government to which such funds are allocated or transferred. Funds allocated or transferred pursuant to this section to any such agency may be established in separate appropriation accounts on the books of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–510, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 123</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2605.</num>
<heading> Use of funds and personnel; savings provision</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Funds made available for the purposes of this chapter shall be available for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> compensation, allowances, and travel of personnel, including members of the Foreign Service whose services are utilized primarily for the purpose of this chapter, and without regard to the provisions of any other law, for printing and binding, and for expenditures outside the United States for the procurement of supplies and services and for other administrative and operating purposes (other than compensation of personnel) without regard to such laws and regulations governing the obligation and expenditure of Government funds as may be necessary to accomplish the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> employment or assignment of members of the Foreign Service serving under limited appointments for the duration of operations under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> exchange of funds without regard to section 3651 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002182">1</ref> of the Revised Statutes (<ref>31 U.S.C. 543</ref>), and loss by exchanges;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> expenses authorized by the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 3901</ref> et seq.], not otherwise provided for;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> expenses authorized by the Act of <date date="1956-08-01">August 1, 1956</date> (<ref>70 Stat. 890–892</ref>), as amended;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> contracting for personal services abroad, and individuals employed by contract to perform such services shall not be considered to be employees of the United States for purposes of any law administered by the Office of Personnel Management, except that the Secretary of State may determine the applicability to such individuals of section 2(f) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2669(f)</ref>) and of any other law administered by the Secretary concerning the employment of such individuals abroad; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> all other expenses determined by the President to be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Savings provision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as may be expressly provided to the contrary in this chapter, all determinations, authorizations, regulations, orders, contracts, agreements and other actions issued, undertaken, or entered into under authority of any provision of law repealed by this chapter shall continue in full force and effect until modified, revoked, or superseded under the authority of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Personnel funded pursuant to this section are authorized to provide administrative assistance to personnel assigned to the bureau charged with carrying out this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–510, § 5</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 123</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2206(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2162</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 112(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 410</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 164(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 411</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–415, § 1(ff)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2606.</num>
<heading> Audits of U.S. funds received by the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program audits</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Funds may not be available to the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) under this chapter or any other Act unless provision is made for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> annual program audits to determine the use of UNHCR funds, including the use of such funds by implementing partners; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such audits are made available through the Department of State for inspection by the Comptroller General of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> First program audit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The first program audit pursuant to subsection (a)(1) shall begin not later than <date date="1986-06-01">June 1, 1986</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 87–510, § 8</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 411</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–246, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 74</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1111(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref>109 Stat. 723</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>