<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 24A—</num>
<heading>MIDDLE EAST PEACE AND STABILITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1961.</num>
<heading> Economic assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to cooperate with and assist any nation or group of nations in the general area of the Middle East desiring such assistance in the development of economic strength dedicated to the maintenance of national independence.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–7, § 1</ref>, <date date="1957-03-09">Mar. 9, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 5</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1962.</num>
<heading> Military assistance; use of armed forces</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to undertake, in the general area of the Middle East, military assistance programs with any nation or group of nations of that area desiring such assistance. Furthermore, the United States regards as vital to the national interest and world peace the preservation of the independence and integrity of the nations of the Middle East. To this end, if the President determines the necessity thereof, the United States is prepared to use armed forces to assist any such nation or group of such nations requesting assistance against armed aggression from any country controlled by international communism: <i>Provided</i>, That such employment shall be consonant with the treaty obligations of the United States and with the Constitution of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–7, § 2</ref>, <date date="1957-03-09">Mar. 9, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 5</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1963.</num>
<heading> United Nations Emergency Force</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President should continue to furnish facilities and military assistance, within the provisions of applicable law and established policies, to the United Nations Emergency Force in the Middle East, with a view to maintaining the truce in that region.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–7, § 4</ref>, <date date="1957-03-09">Mar. 9, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 6</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1964.</num>
<heading> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall whenever appropriate report to the Congress his action hereunder.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–7, § 5</ref>, <date date="1957-03-09">Mar. 9, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 6</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. IV, § 705, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 463</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1965.</num>
<heading> Expiration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter shall expire when the President shall determine that the peace and security of the nations in the general area of the Middle East are reasonably assured by international conditions created by action of the United Nations or otherwise except that it may be terminated earlier by a concurrent resolution of the two Houses of Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 85–7, § 6</ref>, <date date="1957-03-09">Mar. 9, 1957</date>, <ref>71 Stat. 6</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>