<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 45—</num>
<heading>COMMISSION ON SECURITY AND COOPERATION IN EUROPE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3001.</num>
<heading> Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe; establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Commission”).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–304, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-06-03">June 3, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 661</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3002.</num>
<heading> Function and duties of Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized and directed to monitor the acts of the signatories which reflect compliance with or violation of the articles of the Final Act of the Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe, with particular regard to the provisions relating to human rights and Cooperation in Humanitarian Fields. The Commission is further authorized and directed to monitor and encourage the development of programs and activities of the United States Government and private organizations with a view toward taking advantage of the provisions of the Final Act to expand East-West economic cooperation and a greater interchange of people and ideas between East and West.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–304, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-06-03">June 3, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–7, § 2</ref>, <date date="1985-03-27">Mar. 27, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 19</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3003.</num>
<heading> Commission membership</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection and appointment of members</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall be composed of twenty-one members as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Nine Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives. Five Members shall be selected from the majority party and four Members shall be selected, after consultation with the minority leader of the House, from the minority party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nine Members of the Senate appointed by the President of the Senate. Five Members shall be selected from the majority party of the Senate, after consultation with the majority leader, and four Members shall be selected, after consultation with the minority leader of the Senate, from the minority party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> One member of the Department of State appointed by the President of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> One member of the Department of Defense appointed by the President of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> One member of the Department of Commerce appointed by the President of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission Chairman and Cochairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There shall be a Chairman and a Cochairman of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of Chairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the beginning of each odd-numbered Congress, the President of the Senate, on the recommendation of the majority leader, shall designate one of the Senate Members as Chairman of the Commission. At the beginning of each even-numbered Congress, the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall designate one of the House Members as Chairman of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of Cochairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the beginning of each odd-numbered Congress, the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall designate one of the House Members as Cochairman of the Commission. At the beginning of each even-numbered Congress, the President of the Senate, on the recommendation of the majority leader, shall designate one of the Senate Members as Cochairman of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–304, § 3</ref>, <date date="1976-06-03">June 3, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 661</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–7, § 1(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1985-03-27">Mar. 27, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 18</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3004.</num>
<heading> Testimony of witnesses, production of evidence; issuance of subpena; administration of oaths</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this chapter, the Commission may require, by subpena or otherwise, the attendance and testimony of such witnesses and the production of such books, records, correspondence, memorandums, papers, and documents as it deems necessary. Subpenas may be issued over the signature of the Chairman of the Commission or any member designated by him, and may be served by any person designated by the Chairman or such member. The Chairman of the Commission, or any member designated by him, may administer oaths to any witness.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–304, § 4</ref>, <date date="1976-06-03">June 3, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 661</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3005.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. E, title LI, § 5114(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2352</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3006.</num>
<heading> Commission report to Congress; periodic reports; expenditure of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized and directed to report to the House of Representatives and the Senate with respect to the matters covered by this chapter on a periodic basis and to provide information to Members of the House and Senate as requested. For each fiscal year for which an appropriation is made the Commission shall submit to Congress a report on its expenditures under such appropriation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–304, § 6</ref>, <date date="1976-06-03">June 3, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 662</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3007.</num>
<heading> Appropriations for Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization; disbursements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission for each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to enable it to carry out its duties and functions. Appropriations to the Commission are authorized to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> Appropriations to the Commission shall be disbursed on vouchers approved—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> jointly by the Chairman and the Cochairman, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by a majority of the members of the personnel and administration committee established pursuant to <ref>section 3008(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of foreign currencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of <ref>section 1754(b) of this title</ref>, the Commission shall be deemed to be a standing committee of the Congress and shall be entitled to use funds in accordance with such sections.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Official reception and representational expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not to exceed $6,000 of the funds appropriated to the Commission for each fiscal year may be used for official reception and representational expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign travel for official purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Foreign travel for official purposes by Commission members and staff may be authorized by either the Chairman or the Cochairman.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–304, § 7</ref>, <date date="1976-06-03">June 3, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–534</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2495</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–426, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1978-10-07">Oct. 7, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 992</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–60, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1979-08-15">Aug. 15, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 403</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–7</ref>, §§ 3, 4, <date date="1985-03-27">Mar. 27, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 19</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3008.</num>
<heading> Commission staff</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personnel and administration committee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall have a personnel and administration committee composed of the Chairman, the Cochairman, the senior Commission member from the minority party in the House of Representatives, and the senior Commission member from the minority party in the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Committee functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">All decisions pertaining to the hiring, firing, and fixing of pay of Commission staff personnel shall be by a majority vote of the personnel and administration committee, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Chairman shall be entitled to appoint and fix the pay of the staff director, and the Cochairman shall be entitled to appoint and fix the pay of his senior staff person; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Chairman and Cochairman each shall have the authority to appoint, with the approval of the personnel and administration committee, at least four professional staff members who shall be responsible to the Chairman or the Cochairman (as the case may be) who appointed them.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The personnel and administration committee may appoint and fix the pay of such other staff personnel as it deems desirable.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staff appointments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All staff appointments shall be made without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, and without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and general schedule pay rates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commission employees as congressional employees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For purposes of pay and other employment benefits, rights, and privileges and for all other purposes, any employee of the Commission shall be considered to be a congressional employee as defined in <ref>section 2107 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For purposes of section 3304(i)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002238">1</ref> of title 5, staff personnel of the Commission shall be considered as if they are in positions in which they are paid by the Secretary of the Senate or the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection shall be effective as of <date date="1976-06-03">June 3, 1976</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–304, § 8</ref>, <date date="1976-06-03">June 3, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–7, § 5</ref>, <date date="1985-03-27">Mar. 27, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 19</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 218(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1747</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–188, § 2(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3009.</num>
<heading> Printing and binding costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of costs relating to printing and binding, including the costs of personnel detailed from the Government Publishing Office, the Commission shall be deemed to be a committee of the Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 94–304, § 9</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 99–190, § 134</ref>, <date date="1985-12-19">Dec. 19, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1322</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>