<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 21A—</num>
<heading>SETTLEMENT OF INVESTMENT DISPUTES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1650.</num>
<heading> Appointments of representatives and panel members under Convention on the Settlement of Investment Disputes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may make such appointments of representatives and panel members as may be provided for under the convention.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–532, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-08-11">Aug. 11, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 344</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1650a.</num>
<heading> Arbitration awards under the Convention</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treaty rights; enforcement; full faith and credit; nonapplication of Federal Arbitration Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An award of an arbitral tribunal rendered pursuant to chapter IV of the convention shall create a right arising under a treaty of the United States. The pecuniary obligations imposed by such an award shall be enforced and shall be given the same full faith and credit as if the award were a final judgment of a court of general jurisdiction of one of the several States. The Federal Arbitration Act (<ref>9 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.) shall not apply to enforcement of awards rendered pursuant to the convention.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction; amount in controversy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The district courts of the United States (including the courts enumerated in <ref>section 460 of title 28</ref>) shall have exclusive jurisdiction over actions and proceedings under subsection (a) of this section, regardless of the amount in controversy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 89–532, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-08-11">Aug. 11, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 344</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>